<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32703174526.0" user="bendiboy23" delta="False">
    <text>I think more often than not, the issue with a lot of these debates is that its accepted that capitalism has issues, but never addressed why those issues are there and which parts of capitalism give rise to those issues and how. Like I'd think many would be surprised to know that economics classes in university, which has all its theory based on capitalism, actually provides a very simplistic answer to negative externalities such as global warming.

Like taking climate change for instance, it's what is known as "the tragedy of the commons" where since the environment and the air we breathe isn't owned by anyone, no one bothers to take care of it. This is the same reason why a park that isn't looked after by the local government will deteriorate into a heap of litter, since no one feels that they own it and thus feel no responsibility towards it. And since its impractical (quite dystopian imo) to privatise oxygen and the ozone layer, there will forever remain what as known as a "market failure" in this scenario, which is basically what economists say when free markets aren't able to efficiently fix or resolve an issue. This is also why its generally accepted that government (representative of the collective) needs to intervene on behalf of the collective community that owns the environment.

In regards, to your comments on terrible working conditions and etc, a lot of is it actually to do with globalisation...See developed countries have a very high living standard compared to the rest of the world and back in the 20th century when trade was less interconnected, companies had to hire mostly domestically. This meant when the economy was good, people had more money to spend and as a result, for companies to expand to take advantage of that demand, they had to hire more workers. But since your pool of potential workers were limited to your country, eventually workers would run out (unthinkable in our current economic climate) and companies would have to fight for employees by raising wages/benefits. This causes great economic prosperity for the country as profits for companies and wages/living standards rises.

However, with the advent of globalisation, it meant all of a sudden there was an oversupply of employees for unskilled labour such as mass producing iPhones/amazon workers, and soon capitalists found themselves to be the new commodity that was in demand and in shortage...They became the only girl at a boys high school prom, so to speak. And all of a sudden, manual labourers in America who were used to being able to afford a house at 50 now had to compete with kids in China, who were happy with a dollar a day.

This ironically meant the setting of a new type of equality, where the middle/lower class in developed countries were now going to be equalised in economic prosperity with the middle/lower class in third world countries, whilst the capitalists (the rich class) would benefit from being the rare commodity in a world of 7 billion potential workers...

That being said, economic theory recognises this as a problem for developed countries and which is why advocate, for proper taxation of big companies that have benefitted from globalisation eg. (google, apple, amazon) and using that money to retraining the middle/lower class from manual and blue collar labour to skilled/white collar labour so to minimise the loss of jobs and income, whilst keeping the benefits of lower costs for consumers as a result of globalisation...

However, this is easier said than done, and in practice comes with a lot of issues...such as the most obvious and common argument "how is a glass factory worker who never went to college, going to transition to become an software engineer?" to which economists still don't have a definitive answer.

That being said, don't lose all hope in capitalism, what we're seeing today is a natural progression (painful as it might be) that can be seen through the Kuznet's curve...A theory that posits with every new major economic development/technological innovation boom, there would be a sudden growth in inequality as capitalists take advantage of the new profit making opportunity (industrial revolution for example), followed by a decline in inequality as people on average live better (despite some groups falling behind) and demand better standards of living.

Imo, in regards to the capitalist vs socialist debate, capitalism works best in highly and competitive markets, where consumers can readily gain information about which product is better, but not so great in markets that are inefficient or complete failures (i.e car mechanics and environmental sustainability). But at the same time an inherent issue with socialism, is that while it can much readily fix major immediate issues like global warming as the collective decides on economic direction and doesn't have to wait for markets to get to the right equilibrium point, it also overly relies on the state to be all-knowing. This results in numerous cases of economic mismanagement, as in many fields, free markets are simply more efficient and a better automatic regulator since it relies on all participants to make decisions, than having a few people (government) decide what direction to take.

So imo to put it to a simple analogy, free markets ensures that in the long run the equilibrium (most efficient price for products) are reached, however it can take an ugly time to get there...

I.e if a hurricane came and destroys New Orleans, there will be a shortage of water...As a result people with water would price gouge those without into paying higher than the equilibrium, however some people would just not be able to afford it and die of thirst. As a result, there will be less demand for water since people died already, and this will force those with water to lower the price to the equilibrium to ensure maximum profits.

So in this scenario, in the long run the equilibrium (price with maximum benefit for everyone) was reached...but did people really have to die for price gougers to realise that their current price is inefficient and in disequilibrium or would it be better if the government just stepped it in and set an equilibrium price from the get-go?

Sorry if this was a little long but its just a major pet peeve of mine when Redditors debate capitalism in generalities of "poor people are being exploited by capitalism" or "capitalism gave us everything in our lives and we should be thankful"</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
