<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32702371973.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>China is a state-run economy, the world's largest polluter and is the place many countries run to for cheap labor.

Switzerland is a free market capitalist economy and one of the greenest nations in the world and has numerous protections for domestic workers.

I don't think you can blame capitalism for these ills and I think countries like Switzerland show that capitalism is compatible with things like green energy and labor protections and countries like China show that revolting against capitalism is no guarantee those ills would be better addressed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702391159.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're right in saying that there's no way it's just capitalism to blame. There's definitely a legislative aspect that would need to be addressed as well, but when our system supports the idea that politicians can be bought, these will stay intertwined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702620579.0" user="Ghost91818" delta="False">
    <text>You aren't talking about capitalism though. When politicians can be bought that's corporatism. When corporations and government are in the same bed together... It's bad government needs to get out the way and let actual capitalism flourish</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702624949.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but when our system supports the idea that politicians can be bought, these will stay intertwined.

In what way does that have to do with capitalism? Politicians could be bought in any system where wealth exists and has value, which is all of them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
