<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32707076588.0" user="High5Time" delta="False">
    <text>Some people are assholes and some people are greedy and worse. It doesn’t matter what system is in place if you don’t have transparent rules agreed upon by society that prevent people from fucking everyone else. A purely socialist society could turn to slavery and classism with an elite ruling class, no problem at all with the right motivation. 

Markets are amazing for resource allocation and technological progression. Planned economies are 100% doomed to fail, people just aren’t that smart or prescient. Markets works well because they take human behaviour into account and don’t try to force it to do unnatural things like communism does.

I think that most people with a brain at this point in time believes that a mix of a healthy market economy with private ownership paired with consumer, environmental and tax laws that protect people and ensure the wealth is distributed appropriately is the way to go.m if you want a country where everyone has potential and can participate. Something like the Scandinavian countries but not quite. We have a big problem with externalities being foisted on the shoulders of the people and the planet just so corporations can make big profits and people can buy cheap junk.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
