<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32702266437.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>East Germany was socialist. After the wall came down we found it to be an ecological disaster area, while the capitalist West Germany was doing much better for the environment. The capitalist West had to spend billions to clean it up and align industries with their environmental rules.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702284646.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>It seems fair to point out that East Germany was heavily influenced by the USSR, which clearly didn't have the best intentions for the people it was allegedly serving.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702344569.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>The USSR, another socialist country that really screwed up its environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702381242.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>The USSR was the most influential socialist country ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702725776.0" user="whimsyNena" delta="False">
    <text>It should also be pointed out that American capitalists don’t care about the environment, so this reasoning is invalid now but explains the prevalence of adoration today since this is where it was rooted. 

Imagine if America was a country that cared about the environment and spent billions to mitigate and reverse the damage done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32703711339.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The US environmental standards and it’s private conservation efforts utterly outmatch the policies of the USSR. There is no American Aral Sea or Chernobyl Exclusion Zone</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704473501.0" user="whimsyNena" delta="False">
    <text>You’ve never taken the time to understand the history of the US. 

Aral Sea? Have you heard of Kankakee? Massive wetland and lakes drained for agriculture. Or maybe the Salton Sea in California?

The dust bowl? Inappropriate farming procedures?

The dead zone in the Gulf? From agricultural run off. 

We don’t have an exclusion zone from a nuclear power plant disaster only because we’ve been lucky. 

We do, however, have radioactive test sites that no on can go to both on land and in the ocean. 

Ever heard of The Love Canal Tragedy? How about the Exxon-Valdez disaster? The Flint Water crisis? 

Maybe take some time to learn about the environmental history if the US beyond Roosevelt’s conservation efforts and privatized environmental groups.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704589903.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>The difference is most of that is done by private companies that were then stopped by the government. In the USSR, the government itself did that with no one to stop them. On purpose, with no one to stop them, they destroyed the fourth largest lake in the world, an area larger than West Virginia, and with it a diverse ecosystem. The former basin of the lake is now called the Aralkum desert, and it's bigger than Maryland. 

Ever heard of lake Karachay? The government just dumped its nuclear waste there out in the open, and it's now known as the most polluted place on Earth. You can literally get a lethal dose of radiation just being in the wrong place for a short while. This isn't like our sites, "Don't go there because the background radiation is a little higher," it's "The radiation *will kill you* in half an hour."

The Salton Sea wasn't an environmental disaster. Throughout history every few hundred years the Colorado River would create a lake in that basin, and it would eventually dry up. Our accident just created the lake again, and it became a haven for a lot of birds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704700721.0" user="whimsyNena" delta="False">
    <text>While I understand the magnitude of damage is substantially higher in the USSR, we shouldn’t be basing wether or not we’re doing a good job just because we aren’t literally dumping nuclear waste out in the open. 

The US Army Corp of Engineers as well as state-sanctioned projects contributed to the loss of over 50% of the Everglades, the effects of which we have yet to understand. 

The dust bowl was a direct result of the US government encouraging and facilitating inept farmers to move west where they destroyed the ecosystem - again with effects we still don’t fully understand including the extinction of species we never discovered. 

We have a president who wants to open up our national forests to loggers, lower emissions standards, disembowl the EPA, [and more](https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/climate/trump-environment-rollbacks.html). And he still has a [49% approval rating](https://news.gallup.com/poll/266906/trump-job-approval-ties-party-polarization-record.aspx), mostly Republican.

It shouldn’t take dumping nuclear waste and draining lakes to make you believe this country doesn’t care about the environment. That’s the extreme end of the spectrum, it doesn’t mean America is in the middle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704942644.0" user="DBDude" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;While I understand the magnitude of damage is substantially higher in the USSR, we shouldn’t be basing wether or not we’re doing a good job just because we aren’t literally dumping nuclear waste out in the open.

The question is whether capitalism is bad. I gave you the situation under the mainly known alternative, which turns out is far worse. 

&amp;gt;The US Army Corp of Engineers as well as state-sanctioned projects contributed to the loss of over 50% of the Everglades, the effects of which we have yet to understand.

That's not capitalism, that's government. 

&amp;gt;The dust bowl was a direct result of the US government encouraging and facilitating inept farmers to move west where they destroyed the ecosystem - again with effects we still don’t fully understand including the extinction of species we never discovered.

Again, government directive. But they were actually fooled by good rain for the prior decade, and then were hit with a severe drought. 

&amp;gt;We have a president who wants to open up our national forests to loggers, lower emissions standards, disembowl the EPA, and more. 

Again, government directives. When Kyoto was finalized, the carbon baseline was set at a time in the 80s. Because of the economic collapse at the fall of the USSR, coupled with ultra-high pollution under the USSR, the new Russian Federation had a shitload of carbon credits to sell around the world despite still polluting worse than the US and other capitalist countries. 

&amp;gt;That’s the extreme end of the spectrum

Which you can expect in any industrialized socialist country. Look at China.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32705393512.0" user="whimsyNena" delta="False">
    <text>Stop moving the bar. Do you want to talk about government or capitalism? Because they’re untwined here. The draining happened for agricultural and residential capitalistic endeavors. These government directives are driven by capitalistic greed - profits over environment. 

Stop trying to change the topic and then pretending things like capitalism and the American government are mutually exclusive. 

You have one optional alternative to capitalism and pointing out that corrupted communism is bad is pretty obvious. There is an unlimited number of alternative, limited only by our imagination, to the current system we have in place now. 

The dust bowl happened more than two centuries after this country was founded and people weren’t farming there before the country was colonized for a reason. It wasn’t even a lack of understanding that caused the problem, was the lack of desire to understand. Pure, blissful ignorance. 

Economic systems aren’t bad or evil they’re just systems. Capitalism isn’t ‘bad’ or evil, but what’s done under capitalism could be. Capitalism in the wrong era is bad. Capitalism beyond the Industrial Age and with a legacy of forced inequality is bad. It was useful and it was great, but it isn’t the same beast it was and we understand more about our world now which is what makes capitalism in America unethical. Because we know better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32705526181.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You only further my point, the US actually learns from and fixes the mistakes that it made environmentally and never had anything that matched the Aral Sea or Chernobyl in severity</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32704463196.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Imagine if America was a country that cared about the environment and spent billions to mitigate and reverse the damage done.


It does. There are hundreds of millions of dollars spent every year into research to improve the environment and produce products that are better for the environment... by private coorporations. 

Research into solar power and other energy sources, more energy efficient engines, cleaner fuel etc. etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32706795473.0" user="whimsyNena" delta="False">
    <text>Yes all done by privatized interests, mostly for profit. It wasn’t voted into place by the people or their representatives. Someone with preexisting wealth (or a collective of people with capital) decided there would be money in rehabilitation and repair. The exception is the non-profits. 

The EPA facilitates psuedo-sustainable practices and “protects” the natural environment this way. It wasn’t because someone thought it was a tragedy, it was because someone saw their profits being cut into. 

And we see the same thing today. Will we get off fossil fuels? Yes, but only once the capitalists decide there’s more money to be made in alternatives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32707044482.0" user="sclsmdsntwrk" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes all done by privatized interests, mostly for profit. It wasn’t voted into place by the people or their representatives.


It is voted into place by the people, consumers. Consumers decide where to spend their money. And corporations need that money in order to do the research.


&amp;gt; Someone with preexisting wealth (or a collective of people with capital) decided there would be money in rehabilitation and repair.


I don't even know what that means?


&amp;gt; Will we get off fossil fuels? Yes, but only once the capitalists decide there’s more money to be made in alternatives.


I don't know where you get this cartoonish idea of how corporations work. The corporation that develops a new engine or fuel that's significantly better for the environment to a competetive price is going to one of the most successful companies in history.

The company that develops a new battery that makes electric car viable to a broader market is going to be so so rich.


What exactly is it you think these companies are waiting for? Are they waiting for their competition to develop the next gen technology before them and take all the profits?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
