<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32703238276.0" user="keelan929" delta="False">
    <text>I’m curious to know your definition of the words “capitalism” and “socialism.” Do you consider Sweden to be a socialist country? What about China? I’ve found that Europeans use the terms “liberal” “capitalist” and “socialist” a bit differently from how Americans use them, so I’d like to clarify what you mean.

In response to your argument about capitalism, I want to point out that the economic growth produced by globalization has lead to the lowest poverty rates ever in world history (including factors like infant mortality rates, incidence of disease, access to potable water, literacy rates, etc). And it’s what enables Europe to fund their generous social programs, and the US to fund their somewhat less generous ones. All that said, I also have issues with many of the forms of labor abuse, environmental degradation, and widening inequalities produced in this system, but if you ask me, getting rid of it entirely risks throwing out the baby with the bathwater. Better to carefully craft institutions that mitigate these problems while taking advantage of the efficiency of markets. National collective labor bargaining systems, well funded social programs, and strong enforcement of antitrust laws are good places to start.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
