<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80229182.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1brl8e/i_think_people_who_hate_on_fedora_wearers_are_the/">
    <title>I think people who hate on fedora wearers are the ones with the problem. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>admiralfilgbo</original_poster>
    <original_post>I should mention I do not wear a fedora myself.  

However, when I read fedora-bashing comments on Reddit, to me, the vitriol that comes across is kind of scary.  Is it really that intimidating to these people that someone who might be a little socially awkward would want to use an accessory to help boost their confidence?  I suspect the loudest anti-fedora protestors to be the ones that most wish the freedom to don one themselves without fear of harsh judgement.

I understand that, perhaps years later, the fedora crowd might look back and cringe a little at the way they approached their appearance.  But I also think that looking back on one's own awkwardness is a nice healthy way to validate one's own personal growth, and that you need to commit mistakes in all ways of living in order to move on to something greater.  It is often true that people who take chances are ridiculed for their failures in the present, but if they keep sticking with it, eventually find their own unique way to surpass, or at least become accepted by, the status-quo crowd who mocked them.

Very few people are born with an innate sense of style, and even fewer can look back on a 20 year old picture and think "yeah this outfit would still look good today."  So who is anyone to mock anyone else's sense of style, when eventually it's going to all look like brown and orange striped 70's style wide lapels and powdered blue ruffle shirts anyway?

I will say that I have had a beard for many years, and for a very long time I did not properly trim it.  I really, really wish someone had come along and told me not to shave directly along my jaw line.  I wound up figuring that out on my own.  So I understand the benefit of good ADVICE.  Good advice would be to help a fedoran find the CORRECT hat.  Or to offer fashion advice in other ways.

Whenever I see people just losing their shit over the fashion accessories some total stranger is wearing, I just think that life is too short to start fuming over the way other people choose to look when they venture into the outside world.

This just comes up so often on reddit (and I'm sorry to add to the phenomenon here), I'm thinking maybe I'm missing something, and that I too should be personally offended by the way someone else dresses.  I am willing to change my view if I hear a good enough argument.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26681381205.0" user="pezz29" delta="False">
    <text>Fedoras are emblematic of a certain (infuriating) personality type [which is pretty good fodder for tumblr blogs](http://fedorasofokc.tumblr.com/).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26681461350.0" user="admiralfilgbo" delta="False">
    <text>My view here is "fedora-bashers are the ones with the problem."  

In this case, someone had such a problem with fedora wearers that he or she went to the trouble of *setting up a tumblr for it* where users hunt for the most cringeworthy examples of neckbearding.  either that or it's just a parody.  I've seen this before and never bothered to look any deeper.  

I understand that it evokes an emotion.  It's designed to.  

But, let's just take it on the surface and say those are real okc profiles.  I mean, who is the real asshole here, the people in the profiles who maybe remind us of an embarrassing part of ourselves that we'd rather not be reminded of, or the people culling those okc profiles off the internet and compiling them into an organized display of public  mockery?

and just because those profiles might not have been enough to merit a date with the local nerdy hot gamestop employee (or who knows, maybe the schtick worked?), doesn't mean there isn't a strong likelihood that there is a perfect and enthusiastic companion out there for each of those guys, who by the way were at least not trying to hide their awkwardness on their own personal okc profiles - a place where it's kind of a dick move to misrepresent yourself.

nice try, but it didn't change my view.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
