<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26686737415.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>just to clarify(so that i an anarchist can join in)

would u like everyone to be forced to give charity on this condition? or would u like the money stolen from u to be used this way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686753773.0" user="indigoviolet7" delta="False">
    <text>Please, comrade, I know your stance on spelling correctly but you do make good points and it actually hurts to read your posts. Most of the times you don't get responded to and it's likely that your posts convey no respect whatsoever to the reader that is why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686770227.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>1. why am i comrade?

2. i dont actually think my spelling harms my posts, its just a way for people to ignore my post if they didnt want to listen; i did a cmv and everything about this

3. i dont respect people till they prove to be respectable; i have a few well written comments but w/o fail they are after someone has proven to me that they are somewhat sensible and they they ask me to improve 

4. "that is why." is improper grammar :3</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686985058.0" user="tankfox" delta="False">
    <text>It does.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686998357.0" user="indigoviolet7" delta="False">
    <text>1. Comrade is my gender-neutral term for people.
2. If I state that your spelling harms your posts for me, your spelling harms your posts.
3. That's a stupid way to go about it, IMO, because I, personally, do not even ATTEMPT to interact with people who do not show me respect in the first place- and I extend the same courtesy to people I want to interact with.
(Unless I am bored and it's 89 degrees outside.)
4. "is improper grammar" is also improper grammar.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687036906.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>1. so is u; also its far from politically neutral; i would be prefer to be mistaken for female over a soviet

2. but u agree i bring up good points; i couldnt care less what people think of me im here to see if they can logically disagree w/ me

3. i extend common courtesy to everyone; even after they prove they aren't worth it; however proper spelling isnt common courtesy to me

4. and? i dont ask others to jump through hoops i dont wish to; however u did</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
