<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26686775485.0" user="UpsetChemist" delta="False">
    <text>Many people receive "government handouts" not just those on welfare.

Should students receiving financial aid be drug tested? I sure wouldn't want my tax dollars going to support lazy students who just smoke weed all day. Hell, I am paying for these students to go to school not to have fun. I want them to submit detailed time logs listing (with notarization) how they spent their time. If partying exceeds some threshold (that I am comfortable with), I would like their aid withheld.

Also, what about those assholes who have a mortgaged home in the suburbs and thus receive a tax break. Perhaps we should check to make sure that they aren't using that extra money for drugs.

Indeed, have you heard that people with children get some money back in taxes? We should really be checking up on them as well.

The issue that I am getting at here is that the government provides all sorts of aid to all sorts of people. Even waiving any moral considerations, it would be difficult (and expensive) to police every person who qualifies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687427489.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even waiving any moral considerations, it would be difficult (and expensive) to police every person who qualifies.

That's why I'm sticking to welfare for the sake of this argument.  Welfare recipients receive hard currency from the government simply for being poor.

I've addressed the issue of tax breaks in other comments.  Tax breaks are way different than issuing hard currency.  More importantly, you are awarded a tax break for doing something (usually something positive or charitable).  

Students who receive financial aid qualified for it and have to abide by a set of criteria in order to continue to receive aid (GPA, etc).  

You're right: many people receive government handouts, not just those on welfare; however, welfare has become a lifestyle rather than a safety net for many Americans and it disgusts me.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687459645.0" user="UpsetChemist" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's why I'm sticking to welfare for the sake of this argument. Welfare recipients receive hard currency from the government simply for being poor.

And all people with children receive tax breaks for just having children. I think that in order to defend your position you need to include all morally equivalent situations. You can't simply prune situations that you don't feel like addressing.

&amp;gt;Students who receive financial aid qualified for it and have to abide by a set of criteria in order to continue to receive aid (GPA, etc).

This is true. Although this is frequently quite low. Besides, what about if they are spending some of their money on drugs and still are maintaining an acceptable GPA? They are still spending *my* tax money on drugs. How is this different than welfare recipients spending it on drugs?

&amp;gt;welfare has become a lifestyle rather than a safety net for many Americans and it disgusts me.

Well here I think we have gotten to the crux of the issue. It seems that you are less concerned about what welfare recipients are spending money on and rather more concerned about the fact that they receive it at all. I would agree that the welfare system is not ideal but I find that many people have some misconceptions about welfare and welfare recipients. 

First, we should begin by noting that "welfare" is not a monolithic granting agency. There are a variety of programs which distribute money (either directly or through grants to states). One of the biggest of these is the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) which succeded the Aid for Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) in the late 90s.

People tend to overstate the long-term dependence on assistance. According to [HHS](http://aspe.hhs.gov/hsp/13/Indicators/rpt.pdf) in the 1998-2008 period only 1.1% of recipients had been receiving benefits for &amp;gt;9 years. A full 71.5% had been receiving them for 2 years or less.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687488495.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well here I think we have gotten to the crux of the issue. It seems that you are less concerned about what welfare recipients are spending money on and rather more concerned about the fact that they receive it at all.

You're right, the crux of my issue with welfare is that it is being abused.  I'm honestly not so wound up about whether they are or aren't using drugs; I just think that drug testing is a practical way to purge a lot of the abusers from the system.

You're also right that welfare is not a monolithic agency; however, the fact remains that total government spending on welfare (not including food stamps or unemployment) breaks $131.9 billion annually.  Add 46.5 million Americans on food stamps on top of that figure.  

My true and personal gripe is that we as a society have decided that it's okay to be on welfare and also that it's okay to be on welfare for *9 years*.  My father-in-law grew up absolutely dirt poor.  His mother took a welfare check, but he said that when he was growing up people were ashamed to be on welfare.  You didn't have the option of taking your food stamps to Walmart and buying ho-hos and ding-dongs or Dr. Thunder.  You had to take what they gave you which was usually rice, beans, and bread.  For that reason, and because people were ashamed to be on welfare, the program worked.  Nowadays welfare is a way of life, and I don't like the fact that we're continuing to feed the monster.  Reform is necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
