<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26687387626.0" user="abcLSD" delta="False">
    <text>Most people here are going for the "it's a violation of the fourth amendment" argument. And while I agree with that argument, I'm going to present a different one that I think will mesh with your motivation for wanting this condition implemented in the first place. From reading your comments it seems that you are in favor of requiring welfare recipients to undergo random drug testing because you want your tax dollars to be used "responsibly" and hope to reduce taxpayer costs by weeding out and denying benefits to those who are using that money to buy drugs instead of allocating it to other uses that you deem appropriate. 

Well, Florida tried out your suggestion and as it turns out, it costs a lot more tax payer dollars to drug test everyone receiving welfare than it does to just provide the benefits to those that do happen to be using the money to buy drugs - which actually ended up being a very small percentage of recipients. There really aren't that many, as you say, "irresponsible individuals who willfully abuse charity." Only 2.6% of welfare recipients tested positive for drugs, the majority of which was marijuana (so even among those using, there aren't many hardcore junkies among them). Implementing drug testing didn't reduce the number of people applying for assistance either.

The bottom line is that if you are for cheaper taxes and the responsible use of what you do pay, then you should be against drug testing welfare recipients because it will be costing you more money than it could ever save you. 

[Here](http://www.tcpalm.com/news/2012/may/04/editorial-drug-testing-of-florida-welfare-out-to/) and [here](http://www.tampabay.com/news/courts/florida-didnt-save-money-by-drug-testing-welfare-recipients-data-shows/1225721) are some articles backing up my claims. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687431069.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Your article is skewed.  Florida welfare applicants had to test on their own dollar.  Those applicants that tested negative for drugs were reimbursed for the cost of the test.  Only 2.6% tested positive because only 2.6% were dumb enough to spend their own money on a drug test when they were using drugs.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687468852.0" user="abcLSD" delta="False">
    <text>There was not a change in the number of applicants. If what you're claiming were true, there would have been a drop in the number of applicants after the policy was instated. That did not happen. 

&amp;gt;The program, though, probably reduced the number of applicants for public assistance because of a potential failure to pass the drug test, right? No, that didn't happen either.


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687477712.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>1,600 of 7,028 applicants refused to piss.

Source:  http://www.drugfree.org/join-together/community-related/almost-1600-welfare-applicants-in-florida-decline-to-undergo-drug-testing

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
