<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26686312388.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Should this apply to anyone receiving government funds or only the "poor"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686314950.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>For the sake of this discussion let's just stick to welfare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686315788.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's a poor way to frame the discussion, though.

Why only a particular segment of public spending and not the rest?

Where will the funds for this testing come from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686320224.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm trying to avoid having the discussion splinter off in 1,000 different directions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686321305.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Where will the funds for this testing come from and how will this testing cost less than the welfare benefits that are being tested over?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686329446.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Welfare recipients will pay for their own drug test and then receive reimbursement from the government if they pass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686330730.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>With what will they pay for this testing with if they are in need of public assistance for basics such as food, housing and toiletries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686334301.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Can't answer that one.  I personally think it's great motivation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686334918.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>"motivation" for what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686710700.0" user="DoctorBurger" delta="False">
    <text>This, fundamentally, is the problem with your idea. The people who receive assistance are:

1. Children
2. The disabled
3. Elderly

Source: http://www.americanprogress.org/issues/economy/report/2011/12/16/10767/the-facts-about-americans-who-receive-public-benefits/

Only a very small minority are able bodied adults who could be working, but for whatever reason, currently are not.

The vast majority of people who are on assistance, do not have any income outside welfare, and are not able to work. They can not afford to pay for a drug test, they can just barely afford the bare bones necessities. 

You have to acknowledge that the cost of the drug test would be paid for by you &amp;amp; me, the tax payers. 

Can you agree to this premise, that the cost of the drug test would be something tax money would need to pay for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687435112.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Let's look at some more recent, hard numbers instead: http://www.statisticbrain.com/welfare-statistics/

Welfare applicants pay for their own drug test out of pocket.  If they pass, the state reimburses them for the cost of the test.  I would happily pay for that.  I would happily pay, in other words, for a deserving individual to receive benefits over an abuser. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687456682.0" user="DoctorBurger" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing on that page addresses the age of the people receiving benefits; go back and actually read mine. It's children, the disabled, and the elderly. People who cannot afford your drug test in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686324787.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That's the problem with laws, they have to be consistent. If receiving government assistance is a reason to search someone for traces of drugs, would everyone who receives a cent from the government also be subject to the search? What about companies that receive huge subsidies? What about people who get tax breaks? What about publicly funded research? What about .... you get the picture. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686331072.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The difference between welfare and the other programs you mentioned, in my mind at least, is that individuals can receive welfare simply for earning less than X income per year.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686334572.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So the law wouldn't apply to you unless you make X amount? That doesn't sound like a very fair law. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686336403.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No no, I was explaining welfare in relation to the other programs you mentioned.  You get a tax break for doing something charitable (usually).  You get disability because you were injured while doing something (working).  You get welfare for simply earning less than X per year.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
