<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="807899525.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dd039h/cmv_hispaniclatino_should_be_dropped_from_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: "Hispanic/Latino" should be dropped from the US Census and "Mestizo" should be added instead.</title>
    <original_poster>rhymehouse</original_poster>
    <original_post>Imagine if I said that George Bush, Bobby Jindal, and Herman Cain were all the same race/ethnicity since they're "Anglos" who come from an English-speaking culture. That sounds ridiculous! It is clear that George Bush is White, Bobby Jindal is Indian (from India), and Herman Cain is Black. They look visually different and should not be granted the same affirmative action benefits due to each one facing different racial and sociological issues. But that is what this whole Hispanic/Latino identity is doing! It is claiming that [Cameron Diaz](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/81/Cameron_Diaz_WE_2012_Shankbone_4.JPG), [David Ortiz](https://cdn-s3.si.com/s3fs-public/styles/marquee_large_2x/public/2019/10/02/david-ortiz-fox-return.jpg?itok=HM9OFwy1), and [Evo Morales](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/51/Presidentes_del_Per%C3%BA_y_Bolivia_inauguran_Encuentro_Presidencial_y_III_Gabinete_Binacional_Per%C3%BA-Bolivia_%2836962597345%29_%28cropped%29.jpg) have a similar racial/ethnic background. Sure, you can argue that there are cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between the two, but there are also cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between White Americans and Black Americans and they don't get grouped up as the same ethnicity under some "British" identity.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

So this whole Hispanic/Latino thing has been this long running euphemistic attempt to avoid calling the brown people coming from Latin America what most of them really are, mixed-race and instead you have this obfuscating "Hispanic" neologism that arbitrarily groups individuals of different races together just because of nationality and inadvertently gives minority representation to a bunch of people who are genetically 95+% European instead of the dark-skinned ones who really need it. White Hispanics should just identify as White and nothing else. Yeah they're different from your typical White Anglo-Saxon Protestant, but so are Italian Americans and Greek Americans and they don't get their own category, they are just White too. On all American racial censuses, the multiracial and brown-skinned immigrants that come from the Mestizo majority places like Mexico, Central America, Puerto Rico, etc. should mark the new Mestizo category, which would signify a mixed-race person of non-English speaking origins. Mulattoes (Half-Black and Half-White people) from Cuba, Dominican Republic, etc. can either also choose the Mestizo category, or just mark Black and White (Multiracial) on the US Census. Black Latinos should just mark Black on racial censuses. Again they are culturally different from African-Americans, but so are Jamaican-Americans and Nigerian-Americans and they mark Black too. Fully Amerindian Latinos can just mark Native or "Some Other Race" if they're not comfortable with that.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To change my view, you have to stipulate either why Hispanic/Latino is a better term to categorize people than Mestizo is, or you have to explain a better solution you have than adding the Mestizo category.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32795106346.0" user="CaptainHMBarclay" delta="False">
    <text>Mestizo is a pretty old school way to refer to mixed-race, and some find it genuinely offensive, mulatto in particular. 

Race and culture are very closely intertwined, and it's a defining feature of many ethnic groups, which makes a white Hispanic different enough from other whites. This is the kind of data that is the most useful for resource and policy development.

We already have the multi racial category, so no need to add another. It's not going to enhance data collection in this context.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795186768.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Mestizo is a pretty old school way to refer to mixed-race, and some find it genuinely offensive, mulatto in particular. 

It might be offensive to some, but Mestizo and Mulatto are literally the official way to refer to multiracial people in many Latin American countries (on their censuses and everything). Some groups of people find being called "Black" offensive, but that doesn't stop Black from being an official race in the USA.

&amp;gt; Race and culture are very closely intertwined, and it's a defining feature of many ethnic groups, which makes a white Hispanic different enough from other whites. This is the kind of data that is the most useful for resource and policy development. 

I mean this is all good in theory, but when the media or politicians talk about Latino immigration or incoming undocumented people, individuals that look like Cameron Diaz or Ted Cruz are not what the American public has in mind (someone with George Lopez or Danny Trejo phenotype is more accurate).  Similarly, if I am talking to a police officer and stated that I saw a Hispanic lady suspect running down an alley last night, the cop is not going to look for a person with the physical appearance close to Jessica Alba. It is called the "Browning of America" for a very good reason. This whole Latino identity is trying to intermingle the lives of [Mestizo Americans](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mestizos_in_the_United_States) with [White Hispanics](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_Hispanic_and_Latino_Americans) when they are actually two very different groups (studies actually show that White Hispanics align closer romantically and politically with Non-Hispanic Whites than they do with Non-white Hispanics). 

And like I said earlier, it is only White Hispanics who gain this benefit of getting minority representation and affirmative action despite being White just because the government treats them and Mestizos very similarly. Eastern European Americans don't get any special categorization or privileges despite their cultural and economic differences with the White American population. 

&amp;gt; We already have the multi racial category, so no need to add another. It's not going to enhance data collection in this context. 

This I could agree with if it weren't for the fact that Amerindians from south of the border or mixed-race people from those countries never mark the Native category even if they are part Indigenous American. This is because only the Native Americans indigenous to the United States territories and the ones are the Dawes Roll are supposed to mark the Native category. If Mestizos marked the Native and White category instead of my Mestizo idea, that is perfectly fine too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795252287.0" user="CaptainHMBarclay" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;It might be offensive to some,

It behooves us to keep the census, which is an official government form of the United States, as uninflammatory as possible. The goal is to get people to actually fill it out not give them another reason not to.

&amp;gt; but Mestizo and Mulatto are literally the official way to refer to multiracial people in many Latin American countries (on their censuses and everything). 

Well, the United States is not a Latin American country, and there's no reason for us to follow the example of a foreign census with different demographics.


&amp;gt;I mean this is all good in theory, but when the media or politicians talk about Latino immigration or incoming undocumented people, individuals that look like Cameron Diaz or Ted Cruz are not what the American public has in mind (someone with George Lopez or Danny Trejo phenotype is more accurate). 




&amp;gt;Similarly, if I am talking to a police officer and stated that I saw a Hispanic lady suspect running down an alley last night, the cop is not going to look for a person with the physical appearance close to Jessica Alba. 


Hey now, we're not talking about law enforcement. Your CMV is about the Census, not the local police describing a suspect over the radio, of which they have their own training.

&amp;gt;It is called the "Browning of America" for a very good reason. This whole Latino identity is trying to intermingle the lives of Mestizo Americans with White Hispanics when they are actually two very different groups (studies actually show that White Hispanics align closer romantically and politically with Non-Hispanic Whites than they do with Non-white Hispanics).  

&amp;gt;And like I said earlier, it is only White Hispanics who gain this benefit of getting minority representation and affirmative action despite being White just because the government treats them and Mestizos very similarly. Eastern European Americans don't get any special categorization or privileges despite their cultural and economic differences with the White American population. 

My father's side of the family are Poles. They lived a small town, and shared many of the same old country cultural experiences with their other Slavic American neighbors. But in the greater mainstream, there was no true cultural or economic difference. Because they're white. In the US that's how we have historically divvied up race, it makes no sense to turn to foreign interpretations.

&amp;gt;This I could agree with if it weren't for the fact that Amerindians from south of the border or mixed-race people from those countries never mark the Native category even if they are part Indigenous American. This is because only the Native Americans indigenous to the United States territories and the ones are the Dawes Roll are supposed to mark the Native category. If Mestizos marked the Native and White category instead of my Mestizo idea, that is perfectly fine too.

Once again none of this information you propose to gather would enhance the purpose of the census in any way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795356873.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It behooves us to keep the census, which is an official government form of the United States, as uninflammatory as possible. The goal is to get people to actually fill it out not give them another reason not to. 

But is there evidence "Mestizo" or "Mulatto" are more inflammatory words than "Black" is?

&amp;gt; Well, the United States is not a Latin American country, and there's no reason for us to follow the example of a foreign census with different demographics. 

USA is not a Latin American country, but America is getting a lot of immigrants from Latin American countries, and a lot of these immigrants don't cleanly fit into the racial categories that the United States has set up, so it would not hurt to just add a new category which is a loanword from those Latin American nations.

&amp;gt; My father's side of the family are Poles. They lived a small town, and shared many of the same old country cultural experiences with their other Slavic American neighbors. **But in the greater mainstream, there was no true cultural or economic difference. Because they're white. In the US that's how we have historically divvied up race,** it makes no sense to turn to foreign interpretations. 

EXACTLY! THAT IS MY POINT! WHITE HISPANICS ARE WHITE FIRST! Everything you said about White Poles in the USA also applies to White Hispanics (the ones that are fully European genetically, not mixed people who claim that they are White). The cultural and economic differences between White Hispanics and Non-Hispanic Whites aren't any more significant than the economic and cultural differences between Polish Americans and Non-Polish Whites. The difference is that White Hispanics have their own specific category and for some reason, are the key role models and spokespersons for other Hispanics, many of whom are White at all.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Imagine if the main representatives of African-Americans were people who are technically part Black look fully White like Wentworth Miller, Ronda Rousey, and Pete Wentz. That would be stupid! People who potentially look Whiter than you are are benefiting from minority scholarships and affirmative action and other stuff just because of some shared "African descent" identity even though barely anybody would know they're Black if those celebrities didn't inform people. Imagine Ronda Rousey pretending she knows what the average African-American woman goes through in this country. That is dumb right? Well that is what this whole Hispanic/Latino identity is doing. I am sorry but the racial experiences of Marco Rubio and the racial experiences of Carlos Santana are completely different and nobody would pretend otherwise if the Nixon administration didn't come up with this Latino identity idea back in the 1970s.

&amp;gt; Once again none of this information you propose to gather would enhance the purpose of the census in any way. 

The US Census has racial categories for a reason. The Federal government doesn't just call pale people White and dark kinky-haired people Black just because the Feds like color-coding their citizens. There is political context involved in who identifies as what race and where specifically these people live. The big political context in this case is the skyrocketing Hispanic population in America which ignores the fact that a lot of these Hispanics are just typical White people who call themselves Hispanic because their grandmother was from Spain or something like that. The American census wasn't designed in a vacuum or free from the political issues of their time period.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32842885743.0" user="_roldie" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;It might be offensive to some

Nobody in latin america finds the term "mestizo" offensive. Nobody. I myself would identify as such.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
