<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="807899525.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dd039h/cmv_hispaniclatino_should_be_dropped_from_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: "Hispanic/Latino" should be dropped from the US Census and "Mestizo" should be added instead.</title>
    <original_poster>rhymehouse</original_poster>
    <original_post>Imagine if I said that George Bush, Bobby Jindal, and Herman Cain were all the same race/ethnicity since they're "Anglos" who come from an English-speaking culture. That sounds ridiculous! It is clear that George Bush is White, Bobby Jindal is Indian (from India), and Herman Cain is Black. They look visually different and should not be granted the same affirmative action benefits due to each one facing different racial and sociological issues. But that is what this whole Hispanic/Latino identity is doing! It is claiming that [Cameron Diaz](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/81/Cameron_Diaz_WE_2012_Shankbone_4.JPG), [David Ortiz](https://cdn-s3.si.com/s3fs-public/styles/marquee_large_2x/public/2019/10/02/david-ortiz-fox-return.jpg?itok=HM9OFwy1), and [Evo Morales](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/51/Presidentes_del_Per%C3%BA_y_Bolivia_inauguran_Encuentro_Presidencial_y_III_Gabinete_Binacional_Per%C3%BA-Bolivia_%2836962597345%29_%28cropped%29.jpg) have a similar racial/ethnic background. Sure, you can argue that there are cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between the two, but there are also cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between White Americans and Black Americans and they don't get grouped up as the same ethnicity under some "British" identity.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

So this whole Hispanic/Latino thing has been this long running euphemistic attempt to avoid calling the brown people coming from Latin America what most of them really are, mixed-race and instead you have this obfuscating "Hispanic" neologism that arbitrarily groups individuals of different races together just because of nationality and inadvertently gives minority representation to a bunch of people who are genetically 95+% European instead of the dark-skinned ones who really need it. White Hispanics should just identify as White and nothing else. Yeah they're different from your typical White Anglo-Saxon Protestant, but so are Italian Americans and Greek Americans and they don't get their own category, they are just White too. On all American racial censuses, the multiracial and brown-skinned immigrants that come from the Mestizo majority places like Mexico, Central America, Puerto Rico, etc. should mark the new Mestizo category, which would signify a mixed-race person of non-English speaking origins. Mulattoes (Half-Black and Half-White people) from Cuba, Dominican Republic, etc. can either also choose the Mestizo category, or just mark Black and White (Multiracial) on the US Census. Black Latinos should just mark Black on racial censuses. Again they are culturally different from African-Americans, but so are Jamaican-Americans and Nigerian-Americans and they mark Black too. Fully Amerindian Latinos can just mark Native or "Some Other Race" if they're not comfortable with that.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To change my view, you have to stipulate either why Hispanic/Latino is a better term to categorize people than Mestizo is, or you have to explain a better solution you have than adding the Mestizo category.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32796280645.0" user="Stup2plending" delta="False">
    <text>Latino and Mestizo are different so one flaw in your argument is that at a minimum both should be added.

Mestizo is not just a mixed race term but it's also a term used to describe the native Central and South Americans like the Incas or the Mayans. 

For example, in Colombia where I live, everyone is one of 4 racial identities (for lack of a better word): White/Hispanic, Mestizo (Inca or other indigenous peoples), Black, or a mix of 2 or more of them

Since the origins are different between Hispanic (who explored) and Mestizo (natives who were already there), it makes sense to have both or have the Mestizos identify as native americans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33770543469.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You are completely wrong on this these terms were developed by the Spanish to categories the population demographically as part of the Casta system. Mestizo means mixed race and in particular roughly half white and half indigenous. Cholo's are people who are roughly 75% indigenous and 25% white. Indio's to use the Spanish term are people who are almost wholly indigenous Amerindian. Then Castizo's are people who are 75% white and 25% Amerindian. Criollo's are people who are almost entirely white. There are of course more categories relating to Black admixture. For the US census they should just merge Criollo into white and merge Indio and Native American to make Amerindian then add the other 3 categories (Cholo, Mestizo, Castizo).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
