<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="807899525.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dd039h/cmv_hispaniclatino_should_be_dropped_from_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: "Hispanic/Latino" should be dropped from the US Census and "Mestizo" should be added instead.</title>
    <original_poster>rhymehouse</original_poster>
    <original_post>Imagine if I said that George Bush, Bobby Jindal, and Herman Cain were all the same race/ethnicity since they're "Anglos" who come from an English-speaking culture. That sounds ridiculous! It is clear that George Bush is White, Bobby Jindal is Indian (from India), and Herman Cain is Black. They look visually different and should not be granted the same affirmative action benefits due to each one facing different racial and sociological issues. But that is what this whole Hispanic/Latino identity is doing! It is claiming that [Cameron Diaz](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/81/Cameron_Diaz_WE_2012_Shankbone_4.JPG), [David Ortiz](https://cdn-s3.si.com/s3fs-public/styles/marquee_large_2x/public/2019/10/02/david-ortiz-fox-return.jpg?itok=HM9OFwy1), and [Evo Morales](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/51/Presidentes_del_Per%C3%BA_y_Bolivia_inauguran_Encuentro_Presidencial_y_III_Gabinete_Binacional_Per%C3%BA-Bolivia_%2836962597345%29_%28cropped%29.jpg) have a similar racial/ethnic background. Sure, you can argue that there are cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between the two, but there are also cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between White Americans and Black Americans and they don't get grouped up as the same ethnicity under some "British" identity.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

So this whole Hispanic/Latino thing has been this long running euphemistic attempt to avoid calling the brown people coming from Latin America what most of them really are, mixed-race and instead you have this obfuscating "Hispanic" neologism that arbitrarily groups individuals of different races together just because of nationality and inadvertently gives minority representation to a bunch of people who are genetically 95+% European instead of the dark-skinned ones who really need it. White Hispanics should just identify as White and nothing else. Yeah they're different from your typical White Anglo-Saxon Protestant, but so are Italian Americans and Greek Americans and they don't get their own category, they are just White too. On all American racial censuses, the multiracial and brown-skinned immigrants that come from the Mestizo majority places like Mexico, Central America, Puerto Rico, etc. should mark the new Mestizo category, which would signify a mixed-race person of non-English speaking origins. Mulattoes (Half-Black and Half-White people) from Cuba, Dominican Republic, etc. can either also choose the Mestizo category, or just mark Black and White (Multiracial) on the US Census. Black Latinos should just mark Black on racial censuses. Again they are culturally different from African-Americans, but so are Jamaican-Americans and Nigerian-Americans and they mark Black too. Fully Amerindian Latinos can just mark Native or "Some Other Race" if they're not comfortable with that.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To change my view, you have to stipulate either why Hispanic/Latino is a better term to categorize people than Mestizo is, or you have to explain a better solution you have than adding the Mestizo category.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32796018254.0" user="Caioterrible" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, you wouldn’t refer to an Indian person as an “Anglo” anyway, India is not a majority English-speaking country. 

But more importantly, don’t we already do this? You would quite happily say “white people” when talking about Germans, french, Irish, Scots and your average American, right?

Those cultures are wildly different with different histories, accents and even languages. 

And what about “black people”? You would use that for Nigerians, Zimbabweans, somalians and African Americans. Hell, even the term African American is poor, not all black Americans are descended from Africans and not all Africans are black!

Your proposal of changing Latino to mestizo is just pointless, it doesn’t make it any more accurate. Race is such a wide grouping that no one race is actually homogenous. Your issue isn’t with the terminology, it’s with the concept of race altogether.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32796836947.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>Wanna know the key difference between calling a Nigerian and an African-American “Black”, vs calling a White Mexican and an Indigenous Guatemalan “Hispanic”  is. The Nigerian and African-American has very similar skin tones, closely related phenotypes, and more importantly, would be equally be affected by the results of racist laws, racist actions, and racist people. The same cannot be said of both a typical White guy who happens to be from Mexico and a dark brown person who might not even speak Spanish but some indigenous language.

Race is not about culture at all. It is about appearance, and there is clearly a massive visual difference between Cameron Diaz, Evo Morales, and David Ortiz, and before the 1970s, all of them would just be White, Native, and Black respectively. 

Imagine that right now, Donald Trump has just announced he is combining Asian Americans with White Americans in a new “Fair-skinned” category. That would be a complete bs move because Asian Americans in the past and present have dealt with a lot of prejudice and discrimination that typical White Americans never have to deal it (in addition to East Asians being completely and easily distinguishable from White Europeans at first glance despite having fair skin). Replace Trump with Nixon and that is what pretty much happened with White Spanish-speakers and Mestizos in the 20th Century.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32796878735.0" user="Caioterrible" delta="False">
    <text>You’re literally picking and choosing what to be outraged about dude, you mention combining Asians and white Americans into “fair-skinned as unfair, but then why is combining Irish, Germanic and British people into “white” somehow fair? You can’t justify this logically, because it is no different. 

Your only justification is “because they look different” so you’re saying Irish people, German people and British people all look the same? Because no, they don’t. 

More importantly:

&amp;gt; A race is a grouping of humans based on shared physical or social qualities into categories generally viewed as distinct by society.

This is literally the opening sentence on the Wikipedia page of race, so no, race is not *just* about appearance. 

&amp;gt; Wanna know the key difference between calling a Nigerian and an African-American “Black”, vs calling a White Mexican and an Indigenous Guatemalan “Hispanic” is. The Nigerian and African-American has very similar skin tones, closely related phenotypes, and more importantly, would be equally be affected by the results of racist laws, racist actions, and racist people.

You also failed to account for something I mentioned earlier in the above paragraph, where I said:

&amp;gt; Hell, even the term African American is poor, not all black Americans are descended from Africans and not all Africans are black!

An “African American” might not even be from Africa and its very reasonable to call yourself an “African American” without even being black. So no, they’re clearly not all equally effected by racist laws/actions/people equally. 

This is the point I made to begin with, you’re upset with one specific racial grouping when that’s pretty irrelevant really. Your view shouldn’t be “we should have mestizo instead of Hispanic” but it should be “racial groups are not an effective way of categorising people and should be abandoned altogether”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32797333562.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You’re literally picking and choosing what to be outraged about dude, you mention combining Asians and white Americans into “fair-skinned as unfair, but then why is combining Irish, Germanic and British people into “white” somehow fair? You can’t justify this logically, because it is no different. 

There are plenty of differences, but the American government never cared about those cultural differences. In the end, what mattered in American society was not if you were a Western European, but if you could reasonably pass for your typical WASP. Irish, Germanic, Slavic, and Iberian people could, Africans, East Asians, and Native Americans cannot. When hate crimes are committed, the cultures of the victims are generally an afterthought. 

&amp;gt; Your only justification is “because they look different” so you’re saying Irish people, German people and British people all look the same? Because no, they don’t. 

Okay, here is a crowd of people at [Dublin Ireland.](https://c8.alamy.com/comp/EKR98E/dublin-ireland-13th-april-2015-a-crowd-of-people-watch-the-performance-EKR98E.jpg) Here is a crowd of people in[London England](https://c8.alamy.com/comp/B3W7FK/large-crowd-of-shoppers-on-oxford-street-london-england-uk-B3W7FK.jpg). And here is a crowd of people at [Berlin, Germany](https://c8.alamy.com/comp/XB1EPW/berlin-germany-the-crowd-at-the-love-parade-XB1EPW.jpg). What are the major phenotypical differences between all three groups? Now here is a crowd of people at [Tokyo, Japan](https://ak5.picdn.net/shutterstock/videos/18499465/thumb/1.jpg). And this is a crowd of people in [Lagos, Nigeria](https://travel.jumia.com/blog/ng/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/2ADA5EFC00000578-0-image-a-52_1437912017117-660x400.jpg). The visual differences are much more obvious this time.

&amp;gt; This is literally the opening sentence on the Wikipedia page of race, so no, race is not *just* about appearance. 

Cool, but the sociological definition of Race and the American definition of Race are much different (this should be obvious when freaking Middle Easterners and North Africans count as White in the USA, but I digress).

&amp;gt; An “African American” might not even be from Africa and its very reasonable to call yourself an “African American” without even being black. So no, they’re clearly not all equally effected by racist laws/actions/people equally. 

[I am referring to African-American, the ethnic group who are descended from slaves brought to the United States.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/African_americans) I am not talking about any person from Africa who lives in the USA. Words have multiple definitions.

&amp;gt; This is the point I made to begin with, you’re upset with one specific racial grouping when that’s pretty irrelevant really. Your view shouldn’t be “we should have mestizo instead of Hispanic” but it should be “racial groups are not an effective way of categorizing people and should be abandoned altogether” 

Which like I said, is a discussion for another thread which is a far more radical change.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
