<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="807899525.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dd039h/cmv_hispaniclatino_should_be_dropped_from_the_us/">
    <title>CMV: "Hispanic/Latino" should be dropped from the US Census and "Mestizo" should be added instead.</title>
    <original_poster>rhymehouse</original_poster>
    <original_post>Imagine if I said that George Bush, Bobby Jindal, and Herman Cain were all the same race/ethnicity since they're "Anglos" who come from an English-speaking culture. That sounds ridiculous! It is clear that George Bush is White, Bobby Jindal is Indian (from India), and Herman Cain is Black. They look visually different and should not be granted the same affirmative action benefits due to each one facing different racial and sociological issues. But that is what this whole Hispanic/Latino identity is doing! It is claiming that [Cameron Diaz](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/81/Cameron_Diaz_WE_2012_Shankbone_4.JPG), [David Ortiz](https://cdn-s3.si.com/s3fs-public/styles/marquee_large_2x/public/2019/10/02/david-ortiz-fox-return.jpg?itok=HM9OFwy1), and [Evo Morales](https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/51/Presidentes_del_Per%C3%BA_y_Bolivia_inauguran_Encuentro_Presidencial_y_III_Gabinete_Binacional_Per%C3%BA-Bolivia_%2836962597345%29_%28cropped%29.jpg) have a similar racial/ethnic background. Sure, you can argue that there are cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between the two, but there are also cultural, linguistic, and religious similarities between White Americans and Black Americans and they don't get grouped up as the same ethnicity under some "British" identity.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

So this whole Hispanic/Latino thing has been this long running euphemistic attempt to avoid calling the brown people coming from Latin America what most of them really are, mixed-race and instead you have this obfuscating "Hispanic" neologism that arbitrarily groups individuals of different races together just because of nationality and inadvertently gives minority representation to a bunch of people who are genetically 95+% European instead of the dark-skinned ones who really need it. White Hispanics should just identify as White and nothing else. Yeah they're different from your typical White Anglo-Saxon Protestant, but so are Italian Americans and Greek Americans and they don't get their own category, they are just White too. On all American racial censuses, the multiracial and brown-skinned immigrants that come from the Mestizo majority places like Mexico, Central America, Puerto Rico, etc. should mark the new Mestizo category, which would signify a mixed-race person of non-English speaking origins. Mulattoes (Half-Black and Half-White people) from Cuba, Dominican Republic, etc. can either also choose the Mestizo category, or just mark Black and White (Multiracial) on the US Census. Black Latinos should just mark Black on racial censuses. Again they are culturally different from African-Americans, but so are Jamaican-Americans and Nigerian-Americans and they mark Black too. Fully Amerindian Latinos can just mark Native or "Some Other Race" if they're not comfortable with that.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

To change my view, you have to stipulate either why Hispanic/Latino is a better term to categorize people than Mestizo is, or you have to explain a better solution you have than adding the Mestizo category.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32795222599.0" user="STAT_BY_STATWEST" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To change my view, you have to stipulate either why Hispanic/Latino is a better term to categorize people than Mestizo is, or you have to explain a better solution you have than adding the Mestizo category.

My “better solution” would be to simply eliminate these type of categorizations.  

What “problem” are they solving, anyway?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795281581.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>That is also a solution albeit a radical one. Racial censuses were originally made to keep track of free White vs enslaved Black populations for tax and representation purposes. Later on, knowing the races of people in a district ensures minority represenation and whether that community should recieve affirmative action benefits or not. 

If you want to completely get rid of race and ethnicity in censuses, you could argue for that point, but I feel that matter deserves its own thread.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795339960.0" user="STAT_BY_STATWEST" delta="False">
    <text>We’re not going to snap our fingers and get rid of everything. That’s not realistic. 


But we can work towards broadening and merging the existing categories more and more until it becomes obvious to most people that it’s no longer useful. 


What you’re proposing appears to be going in the opposite direction. You want to drill down even smaller and make more distinct divisions. 

Instead of working towards slowly fading away an already problematic ‘necessary evil’ — you want to double down and expand upon it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795378435.0" user="rhymehouse" delta="False">
    <text>I am not trying to add a brand new division though. I am just trying to make sure that the Latinos who need strong civil right protections (the darker-skinned ones) actually recieve it without the government handing out free privileges to typical White people who happen to speak Spanish. There are over 58 million Hispanics in the USA, but only 18.5 million Mestizos in the USA. That is a massive demographic and bureaucratic difference.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If you want to keep the status quo just because you know the categories are dumb but you think the whole idea of race on the census is even dumber, than you might as well cut out the middle man and start getting rid of categories then (maybe USA can just be divided into White vs Non-White).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32795405297.0" user="STAT_BY_STATWEST" delta="False">
    <text>In that case — wouldn’t this just make it easier for the government to discriminate against “the dark skinned ones” also?

Why do you assume the government being able to more accurately identfy these folks is going to be because they want to treat them better and not help white people as much anymore?

It could just make it even easier for the government to discriminate against them!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
