<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32833380242.0" user="bjankles" delta="False">
    <text>The concern with the Joker was less about the quantity and brutality of the violence, and more about the potential message of the violence. The Joker is an established character who has already unfortunately become something of a folk hero to a subset of self-identified losers/ outcasts. How you portray his actions in a film where he's something of a protagonist requires nuance.

I think the movie's portrayal of the Joker's violent actions, and how both he and the world respond, deserves some criticism. The Joker's first act of violence is against handsome, wealthy young men. It's actually an act of self-defense, but no one knows that. People see Joker as a hero for committing this act. 

Another act of violence sees the Joker killing another rich, powerful person who bullied him personally. This happens on live TV, with Joker delivering the line "You get what you fucking deserve." Again, how do the people in the film respond? They erupt into violence, some of them using these exact words as they commit murder of their own.

Compare this violence to an action scene in say, John Wick. John is killing a lot more people, often a lot more brutally. But it's mindless action. He's not inspiring anyone, there's no message or even real intent behind his killings. 

On the other hand, I think the Joker as a film does seem to tacitly endorse the lead character's actions, and seems to believe they're a fair response to the world as the Joker was experiencing it. And I think the film also wants to parallel or at least nod to issues in the real world, like how we treat the mentally ill, wealth inequality, and budget cuts to social programs. 

So put it all together: You've got a movie where a cult icon commits horrible acts of violence as a response to real world issues and inspires a city to do the same, and it feels an awful lot like the movie wants me to think "This is what you get, cruel world." Is this not a controversial message to put out into the world?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
