<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32835561007.0" user="Darkestknight05" delta="False">
    <text>From what I read of the news and having seen Joker, I don't think violence was the big problem that people had. Rather it was that a small amount of people might relate to the character of Joker, the lonely, depressed, antisocial, and mentally ill person, and then see him cause acts of violence and then they will feel justified to cause acts of violence. The violence itself was not so bad, but people might, and it's a very small might, relate to the guy who does it, which I think more people were afraid of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835649646.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>Just replied this but relevant to this reply)

I see what you mean, one of the things that does frustrate me is the idea that 1 idiot can ruin something for everyone

'The book was graphic'

'The game had guns'

'2 men kissed'

Should we just tell a story for the many or fear the few?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835874829.0" user="Darkestknight05" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that, a small subset people should not dictate what are we create. Though, honestly, if someone is concerned that a piece of art could give someone a reason to hurt others, I don't fault people for putting it out there, through the media or otherwise, that it could upset someone or goad someone to do something. The likelihood though is statistically low, given that no one's been hurt in 5 days it's been out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835923477.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>Its not like the Dark Knight was a particularly thought provoking film

Good but not ground-breaking.

The only connection is Batman!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32836022020.0" user="Darkestknight05" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know the motivation of the Aurora shooter, but I don't think it was due to the movie. I've read that it was just a rumour that he called himself Joker. And petty gripe, it was The Dark Knight Rises, an even less thought provoking film.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32836108261.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>Media needs to point blame!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
