<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32833464580.0" user="dcheesi" delta="False">
    <text>I thought Phoenix's performance rendered some of the otherwise mundane violence more disturbing. Over the top slasher/cartoon violence would have been less controversial; it's the sheer realism, especially in the context of an intimate character portrait, that makes it a bit shocking.

I also agree with other comments here, that it's the lack of a good-guy or any real come-uppeance for the main character that makes it controversial. Sure, &amp;gt;!he winds up in Arkham!&amp;lt;, but even then it's clear that he's enjoying himself; there's no sense of punishment or consequence there. And the final shot seems to be set in a comedic tone, not just from his perspective but for the audience's benefit as well, which is a bit unsettling as it seems to be affirming his perspective and thus in a sense his earlier actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833494048.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>I did like the break from the comeuppance narrative, it was the story of the creation of a monster and I thought they did that very well.

As the character (using the Batman trilogy as an example) it would make no sence to have him redeemed or killed as a result of his actions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835443510.0" user="WillieLikesMonkeys" delta="False">
    <text>It was a comedic tragedy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
