<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32833771382.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>There’s violence like you would find in Commando. It’s cartoonish and outlandish. The fact Schwarzenegger never got shot up is unbelievable. 

Joker is believable. Taxi Driver is believable. 

Believable violence holds more weight than cartoonish violence you’d see in early Schwarzenegger films. I saw the latest Rambo. Pretty meh, he should have died. But Jesus Christ was the story believable. 

My opinion: the news is more violent than Terminator or Demolition Man. The News assaults the senses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833878276.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>It is more believable than Rambo ect, a hit to the face can break a nose unlike getting hit by a tank in Rambo is an inconvenience.

Its nice to have films that do not treat the audience like children and give us realism sometimes.

Imagine if they toned down The Boy in the Stripped Pyjamas because it was too real?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833895353.0" user="anonoman925" delta="False">
    <text>Right. But violence can be used as a cartoon narrative or a story telling narrative. The Boy in the Striped pajamas is telling story. 

I’d categorize Joker as a drama. Not a superhero movie. I’d let my kids watch Commando at 10 before Goodfellas. 

But Joker touched on some tough subjects and took it to the extreme. A “possible” extreme. The only part I really had to suspend belief on is the very end. But murder on a TV show is one step removed from spree killing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32834087299.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>My daughter watched Alien at 11 and she didn't find it as scary as The Witches. Had to turn it off when they removed their faces

That film still gives me a squirm lol</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
