<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32833178089.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>The media wasn't criticising the amount of violence but how the violence was portrayed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833192510.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>Fight Club glorified it and there was no backlash from what I remember</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833266637.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>I think if that film came out today a lot of people would question or criticize the message of the film or the portrayal of a violent anarchist like Tyler Durden as a hero. 

Spoiler warning


Actually, the Ed Norton character resists Tyler Durden at the end. One could interpret the point of the film as however seductive Tyler Durden's message is, it's ultimately destructive and bad, and resisting him is good. The Joker also allows for multiple interpretations. 

One interpretation of the film is that the Joker isn't a villian but vigilante dispensing his own kind of violent justice to the people who have abused him and the system that oppresses everyone. Film critics are saying they don't like the idea of portraying the Joker's murders as somehow acts of Justice.

What did you think when you watched it? Did the folks he murdered deserve the Joker's wrath, or was he just deranged?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833436713.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>I wouldn't describe anyone as deserving, I thought the killing was more of a way to further the story about his mental health.

Fight Club did have the ending where the main character does grow from his experience in a way that could be described as positive where Jokers could be negative growth.

But I did find it a nice break from film norms</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32834026555.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But I did find it a nice break from film norms

I liked it for the most part. Criticising the film doesn't necessarily mean the film is bad.

&amp;gt;I wouldn't describe anyone as deserving, I thought the killing was more of a way to further the story about his mental health.

The only people who were sort of deserving were the first two guys on the subway. The film went out of its way to portray them as aggressive jerks who attacked the joker. On the other hand, the fight was kind of over when he shot the gun, and he went out of his way to hunt down the the third guy and execute him while he tried to get away. Not exactly self-defense. 

But then he kills his mother. His mother did horrible things to him, but she was also a victim herself and she was completely helpless when he killed her. Murray humiliated him on TV but then had him on his show and was nice to him backstage. While it's true everyone he killed harmed him in someway, I agree with you that as the film went on, the murders are less and less justified as his mental state goes down hill.

But at the end he is the hero of the people!  People cheer him on as dances on the car.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32834078687.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>At the time they did treat him heroically but its easier to cheer someone else doing something you would never do yourself.

If you consider (as far as I can tell from the film) the public no longer feels like the government cares for them, protesting was inevitable. Its very easy for any protest to turn violent .

I see it less of him inspiring it but setting alight what was there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835394776.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>So here's my attempt to change your view:

The media didn't hype the film because of the amount of violence or the graphic nature of the violence, but because concerns about how the audience would interpret the portrayal of violence. 

The film was ambiguous which isn't necessarily bad, but leaving its themes up to interpretation means that for sure some people would see the Joker as less villian then vigilante, dispensing justice to those who asssulted, abused, betrayed, or humiliated him. We don't see it that way but given the shear numbers of people who saw it, someone will. And that person may be someone who identifies with the Joker so much he imitates the violence.

That's concern, or fear-mongering, the media was raising. I didn't go into the film expecting a hyper violent slasher film, but a character study that might portray a deranged killer in a sympathetic light, and that expectation wasn't far off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32835581948.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>(I cant copy the triangle on my phone)

I see what you mean, one of the things that does frustrate me is the idea that 1 idiot can ruin something for everyone

'The book was graphic'

'The game had guns'

'2 men kissed'

Should we just tell a story for the many or fear the few?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32854345938.0" user="idiophage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Actually, the Ed Norton character resists Tyler Durden at the end. One could interpret the point of the film as however seductive Tyler Durden's message is, it's ultimately destructive and bad, and resisting him is good. 

I have to say this reading seems a little facile. Isn't the point of the movie that Norton's character is a kind of zombie of post-modernity, unalive, trapped in a cycle of empty consumption? He needs to integrate elements of Durden: vitality, sexual freedom, the ability to question social norms, and a connection to the primal. He ends up possessed by Durden's persona, but he is only free to exorcise Durden in the end *because* he has integrated those parts of Durden that held any worth. Marla is in the last scene, and she joins him: as a complete man, not the depressed loser at the start of the narrative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32855683704.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I have to say this reading seems a little facile. 

It's broad strokes comparison of the film to the Joker. 

&amp;gt;Isn't the point of the movie that Norton's character is a kind of zombie of post-modernity, unalive, trapped in a cycle of empty consumption? 

The film does a good job of portraying the angst and anxiety men like the Narrator and the fight club members feel as part as cogs in the machine with real purpose or direction, yes.

&amp;gt;He needs to integrate elements of Durden: vitality, sexual freedom, the ability to question social norms, and a connection to the primal.

It feels that way at first but by the time Robert Paulson dies and Durden is trying to kill Marla it's clear that Durden's project Mayhem isn't a solution to modern society but an equally dark and nihilistic obstacle he must over come in order to find meaning. 

You watch the Narrator sticking it to the man and feel excited for him but as the fight club transforms into project Mayhem it's clear the fun is over and things are going off the rails. 

Maybe certain aspects of Durden's personality helped the Narrator grow but I do not think the film portrays project Mayhem, Paulson's death, and the attempted murder of Marla as heroic. Neither do I think the Joker portrays murdering a television host who mocked your bad standup on live television is herioc, but other commentors disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32834333435.0" user="Quirderph" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Fight Club glorified it and there was no backlash from what I remember

[Roger Ebert wasn't to keen on it:](https://www.rogerebert.com/reviews/fight-club-1999)

&amp;gt; Although sophisticates will be able to rationalize the movie as an argument against the behavior it shows, my guess is that audience will like the behavior but not the argument. Certainly they'll buy tickets because they can see Pitt and Norton pounding on each other; a lot more people will leave this movie and get in fights than will leave it discussing Tyler Durden's moral philosophy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
