<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32832737743.0" user="Barnst" delta="False">
    <text>I haven’t seen the movie, so I’m only speaking to the “hype” as I’ve understood it.  People aren’t worried that the Joker a Jigsaw-like character, but a Tyler Durden-like character.  Or Travis Bickle.  Or Tony Montana.  Those characters who show up on the dorm room walls of dumb kids who thought the characters were cool because they either missed the point of the movie or didn’t care about it.

The issue isn’t that film is hyper violence, but that the violence is plausibly realistic and arguably morally excused within the film.

Something like Saw brings out the pearl clutching because of the gore, but it’s also easy to argue that it’s just escapist fantasy that’s totally unrelated to the real world.

The Joker takes a character who normally fits into that model of a literal comic character and re-frames him as a more serious “real” character with relatable motivations and desires.   It tries to understand and empathize with his violence in a way that almost makes him a protagonist, if not a hero.

The fear isn’t that someone is going to be inspired to replicate some horrific over-the-top violent act because they saw something hyperviolent, but that people who are already disturbed and facing their own personal issues will relate to this very realistically drawn character and draw motivation from him.    In a worst case, they’ll emulate his turn to nihilistic violence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32832776686.0" user="OrdinaMala" delta="False">
    <text>To add to this, I think the issue is that even though the violence may be quite graphic, if it is not placed into context, it loses its power, it becomes just a trope. Violence against someone who has treated a character badly is usually not morally reprehensible, it's catharthic. If the underdog brutally executes his assailants, then usually his actions are not condemned, even if in doing so they perpetuate a cycle of violence. 

Since the story is the story about an underdog, it's not necessary to be confronted, to having to wrestle with the implications of violence. It's not impossible, but it's not necessary (and from what I've read it's not done in this case). Think of (not as an example of where it is done particularly well but it's prominent) Anakin's turn to evil in the Star Wars Prequels. He killed a whole camp because they killed his mother. You are not rooting for him in this scenario, because he is confronted with his actions and you *know* that it is reprehensible and will lead to him becoming Darth Vader.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833330462.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>
&amp;gt;The issue isn’t that film is hyper violence, but that the violence is plausibly realistic and arguably morally excused within the film.

I have seen the film and I think you nailed it. The film is ambiguous and leaves it up to audience to decide whether the misunderstood loner was justified in lashing out or he's a pathetically deranged man. 

Good films can have ambiguous endings of force the audience to consider questions, but the ambiguity means that for sure some portion of the audience will decide fuck yes the Joker is justified and his victims were jerks who had it coming, and for sure some people who come to that conclusion are folks that see themselves as misunderstood loners who are already at risk of lashing out. 

I don't think we should avoid making art that some idiots might interpret the wrong way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32834287476.0" user="Quirderph" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's worth noting that this is *far* from the first time a film like this has gotten controversy. *Taxi Driver* was cited as an influence on *Joker.* You know, the same *Taxi Driver* which inspired the man who shot Ronald Reagan...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833400556.0" user="bjankles" delta="False">
    <text>Having seen the movie, I would argue that a person who walks away from The Joker thinking his acts of violence and the movement he inspired were justified didn't miss the point. As far as I can tell, that's pretty much what the movie is trying to say, and I think it's why the Joker is more deserving of criticism than the other films you mentioned, which are clearly being misinterpreted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833600890.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>I got the message that the state of society did not create him but indirectly furthered it. He is not a cause or solution to how bad Gotham is at the time.

He did make a bad situation worse in the city but I think it would have happened anyway without him</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833613710.0" user="bjankles" delta="False">
    <text>I'm speaking less to his impact on the city at large and more to the personal impact his actions have on himself as a character. He finally feels free and heard and becomes a hero to his fellow losers, and the movie seems to suggest that it makes sense that this would be his emotional response to his actions, and that his actions weren't really out of line.

He wasn't exactly wrong to do all this murdering, and the murdering brings him what he always wanted. Which is basically the mass shooter mindset to the letter. Yikes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
