<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="811176424.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/deybqg/cmv_joker_was_nowhere_near_as_violent_as_the_news/">
    <title>CMV: Joker was nowhere near as violent as the news claimed</title>
    <original_poster>buddamus</original_poster>
    <original_post>I did enjoy the film and liked the way they did his origin story (there are many in the comics).

But the media gave unrealistic expectations of the violence, I thought it was average and not 'terrifying' at all.
There was no 'gore' lile in something like Saw or anything over sexual

I think the media is being dishonest possibly even encouraged to hype it up to boost ticket sales

The French film Irréversible is what I would consider an overwhelming violent film and Joker did not come close to that.

CMV: Its not a particularly violent film and the media is hyping it up for no reason</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32832689563.0" user="Fuzzy_lines" delta="False">
    <text>Can you link to an example of a media report that you believe is exaggerated? I haven't seen any myself yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32832711613.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/entertainment-arts-49816205</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32832732296.0" user="OrdinaMala" delta="False">
    <text>I mean what would you like the BBC to have done here? The claims were not made by "the media" in this case, they merely reported Sandy Phillips' reaction to the movie (trailer), also citing the letter from Survivors Empowered: 

&amp;gt;When we learned that Warner Bros was releasing a movie called Joker that presents the character as a protagonist with a sympathetic origin story, it gave us pause.

As is cited further below, most criticism of the movie did not decry its violence but the ideology behind it, it being *'guilty of "aggressive and possibly irresponsible idiocy"'* and doing *'something that flirts with danger - it gives evil a clown-mask makeover, turning it into the sickest possible form of cool'*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32832826898.0" user="buddamus" delta="False">
    <text>I am completely against violence in real life but in movies and video games it is cool, escapism should excite us and let us experience the dark side of humanity without doing the act</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32832858762.0" user="OrdinaMala" delta="False">
    <text>...okay? I'm not sure I get what part of my comment you are referring to here but okay. Your view that violent "escapism should excite us and let us experience the dark side of humanity without doing the act" is only valid though if there were absolutely no correlation between the two and no behavioral influence from experiencing fictional violence. See for example [this study](https://www.mdpi.com/2075-4698/3/4/491/pdf) that talks about the catharsis theory where we believe that aggression is an emotion that needs venting, i.e. it should "excite us" and then we can be done with it, the belief of which is false. Continuously performing or being presented a violent (fictional) act does not reduce aggression but reinforce it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32833171915.0" user="JustOneVote" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but the article wasn't complaining violence, that's what the comment was pointing out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
