<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32895051968.0" user="theboeboe" delta="False">
    <text>Yea there is? Some people simply comment "I agree" or stuff like that. Not commenting on your change, and seeing a comment as "edited" will to many people, discredit what is stated in the comment

edit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896344410.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>And they're just supposed to trust that you didn't completely change the content?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896721668.0" user="TheLagDemon" delta="False">
    <text>People will think you may have completely changed the content whenever they see a comment was edited. If that edit comes without an explanation, then all a reader can do is speculate as to the reason for it. Adding an explanation of the edit at least provides one more piece of data for a reader to base their decision on. 

Consider the difference these two scenarios. One make an edit, do not draw attention to it, and provide no explanation for it. Or two, make an edit, acknowledge the fact you made an edit, and provide a reason for that edit. Which option would elicit more trust that nothing substantial was changed? I’d say the first scenario comes across as much less trustworthy than the second. 

Of course, it goes without saying that the only way to avoid speculation about what was changed is not to edit at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32897273233.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>In the latter case, while we do technically have evidence that the edit was only minor, is it *good* evidence? I think not. Better evidence would be to survey the content of the discussion overall, and gauge whether up to that point the poster had been conversing/debating in good faith. If there is no history to oversee, then unless the poster edits in a screenshot of the original post as proof of their edit, there is no good reason to simply leave a note saying "edit: typo". It's useless as far as evidence goes. 

Reddit should simply allow users to see the edit history on posts and comments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32897762634.0" user="palacesofparagraphs" delta="False">
    <text>I'd argue that while it's easy to lie about what you edited, the standard of explaining the edit benefits how we think about editing to begin with. To plenty of us, it never occurs to us that it's important to be clear about any changes you've made to a comment. But when you can make changes to the middle of a conversation, you can vastly alter how the rest of that conversation is read.

When I joined reddit, I quickly realized that if I made any changes to a published comment, even just fixing a spelling error, the standard was the leave a note saying I'd done so. I also realized that people who'd changed their position could add that to the end rather than changing the original text of their comment, which struck me as a positive behavior that promotes clarity.

Basically, the practice of putting things like "Edit: spelling" on a post creates an etiquette of being transparent. Can people still lie? Of course. But people can break all kinds of social conventions without reproach. That doesn't mean most people won't follow them, or that those social conventions don't have merit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32898157293.0" user="TheLagDemon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	In the latter case, while we do technically have evidence that the edit was only minor, is it good evidence? I think not . . .

I agree it’s not *good* evidence, just superior to the alternative of not acknowledging the edit at all, which can, for example, give the impression that the poster hopes the fact they made an edit will be overlooked. Keep in mind that even changing a single simple typo can dramatically change meaning. 

There *may* be other data points available too, but those will exist whether an edit is explained or not. I’d say more evidence is better than less. 

&amp;gt;	gauge whether up to that point the poster had been conversing/debating in good faith

I’d say that someone’s willingness to acknowledge their mistakes, even minor ones like grammar or spelling issues, is compelling evidence of good faith. And that’s especially true if they make a habit of practicing good reddiquette by explaining any edits they make. Whose post history appears more trustworthy the person who points out whenever they edit a comment, or someone who frequently edits with out ever offering an explanation? 


&amp;gt;	If there is no history to oversee  . . . It’s useless as far as evidence goes.

If someone claims they made a typo and corrected it, is “I don’t believe you” really your default reaction? It certainly might be, but if you put absolutely zero weight on people’s explanations I’d say that represents a depth of cynism that’s pretty unusual.  I think most people place some weight on other people’s claims, and in fact that they take the stance of giving the benefit of the doubt unless there is compelling proof otherwise. That’s a necessary social nicety for actually having a conversation. 

I think this might get to the heart of this CMV. If you are a particularly skeptical person, then consider that others are much more trusting. The reason someone would explain an edit in the first place is that they’d expect a reader would extend at least a little trust, because that’s what they’d do themselves. 



&amp;gt;	Reddit should simply allow users to see the edit history on posts and comments.

That would certainly be helpful but for the time being we have to work with what we’ve got.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32898926672.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>"I don't believe you" isn't the default reaction, of course. As I said, it depends on other factors - mainly how has this person conducted themselves up to this point? I'd also add that disbelief is not the same as believing a thing is not so. I may not believe it purely on the basis of the note, but I may believe it or not believe it for other reasons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32899813859.0" user="TheLagDemon" delta="False">
    <text>Do you put any weight on an explanation that someone offers after an edit?  

If you put absolutely no weight on the explanation offered then “I don’t believe you” is a fair assessment of your default reaction (and to be clear, I get that you mean “I don’t trust you” there, and not “I think that you’re lying.”). If there’s a scenario where you put any weight on the explanation at all, then that must mean it has some benefit. 


Actually, lets try approaching this scenario with a little Bayesian reasoning. Answer these questions, I think it will help hone in on some specifics. 

In general, what percentage of people who edit a comment only change typos or grammar? 

In general, what percentage of people who edit a comment and don’t explain the edit only change typos or grammar? 

And finally, in general, what percentage of people who edit a comment then claim they are only changing typos or grammar are lying?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902554545.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>First question: I don't know the answer, and without a proper wiki system where we can see what edits are made, I don't know how we can get to the answer. 

Second question: Same answer as the first. 

Third question: I'm not doing this on purpose and I'm not trying to dodge, but because of the answers to the last two questions, this one is also a big IDK. 

It's that ambiguity that leaves me feeling the tag is useless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32903446740.0" user="TheLagDemon" delta="False">
    <text>No worries. I phrased that poorly, I probably should have prefaced those questions by “what would you guess”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896799729.0" user="C-C-C-P" delta="False">
    <text>Yes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896972720.0" user="manjar" delta="False">
    <text>Are they supposed to trust your self-reported description of the changes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32897046866.0" user="stimpakish" delta="False">
    <text>This is the crux of the matter. Trust is automatically withheld in one case (only seeing the asterix) but automatically given if the asterix has an explanation attached.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32898260654.0" user="AXone1814" delta="False">
    <text>How do you see a comment is edited? I’ve never seen this. I edit 99% of my comments as I’m pretty bad at typing on a mobile device and I’m also a bit trigger happy on the send button so more often than not I need to edit typos/spelling once I read it back. It never occurred to me people would think I’d changed my content and discredit my post entirely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900299947.0" user="allthatwastedtime" delta="False">
    <text>I’m guessing it shows up on the website. I’ve never seen it on the iOS app I use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900337538.0" user="AXone1814" delta="False">
    <text>Yea another user replied and said it’s on the desktop/web version. I’ve only ever used the iOS app.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32898564354.0" user="AXone1814" delta="False">
    <text>How do you see a comment is edited? I’ve never seen this. I edit 99% of my comments as I’m pretty bad at typing on a mobile device and I’m also a bit trigger happy on the send button so more often than not I need to edit typos/spelling once I read it back. It never occurred to me people would think I’d changed my content and discredit my post entirely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32899812877.0" user="theboeboe" delta="False">
    <text>you can on pc, if you hold you mouse over the "time since posted". there will be an astrix</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32899832576.0" user="AXone1814" delta="False">
    <text>Ah ok thanks. I’ve only ever used the iOS app.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32898584749.0" user="TheSliceman" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;to many people

Yeah no.

Its not standard practice on anywhere else on the internet for a reason.

"edit a word" is a thousand times more annoying that thinking "I wonder why he edited it".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32899819488.0" user="theboeboe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Its not standard practice on anywhere else on the internet for a reason.

other places (like youtube) you can see the og comment</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900315971.0" user="TheSliceman" delta="False">
    <text>Its a practice that ONLY exists on Reddit. 

Its fucking retarded. Deal with it. 

Edit: a word</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32901052317.0" user="theboeboe" delta="False">
    <text>no it makes sense? the only reason we do this, is because it is impossible to see the unedited comment. Make me be able to see what the comment was, before it was edited, and i will agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32901504130.0" user="TheSliceman" delta="False">
    <text>How often do people edit comments to change the original meaning?

Once every 10,000 edits?

Something like that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900930461.0" user="Namika" delta="False">
    <text>Minor nitpick, but it's "yeah" not "yea"

Yea is another word entirely, and is pronounced "yay" as is "Please vote yea/nay"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900954162.0" user="theboeboe" delta="False">
    <text>Yea means yes dude.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
