<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32895585890.0" user="_drunk_pineapple" delta="False">
    <text>It's just a thing people do as a courtesy to assure readers that edits aren't distorting the original meaning of the text. This is because, unlike Facebook, Reddit doesn't allow you to view comments edit history. Just that they have been edited.

I'm sure you've seen cases a few times of users getting into heated discussion and then a user goes back and edits their comments to soften how they came off (however, it often makes the conversations make little sense and usually gets called out by others). Somebody ammending the text to say what they edited gives everyone some assurance of transparency. Giving some indication that editing is going on for the sake of clarity rather than retconning the conversation is useful for everyone involved.

You could argue that people will manipulate the editing system for manipulation either way, and sure you'd be correct, but most users tend to be better than that and unless Reddit implements a feature to see a comments edit history then it's a pretty good way for users to demonstrate that edits are made for respectable reasons.

Besides that, for mere spelling and grammar errors; what can I say? Some people are bothered when they write something and realise they've made a mistake. Sure it may not seem necessary to even acknowledge an edit of pretty minor typos or mistakes, but leaving a little reciept of what has been edited (no matter how minor) is still pretty good ettiquette for the reasons previously mentioned.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
