<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="39" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32898552108.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32901986017.0" user="Armadeo" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ZuyderSteyn – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+ZuyderSteyn&amp;amp;message=ZuyderSteyn+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/-/f42y59o/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.

Do not reply to this comment by clicking the reply button, instead message the moderators ..... responses to moderation notices in the thread may be removed without notice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
