<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32894263545.0" user="MOABchoochoo" delta="False">
    <text>It's to show that the comment has been edited for whatever reason listed. People do it so you know the reason they edit it. Otherwise someone could ask something like "who made the most positive effect in the last 500 years?", and you could give a good answer and get a few thousand upvotes and then edit your comment to change the name to Adolf Hitler to troll and make it look like everyone thinks it's a good answer. If someone edits it and cites the reason why, it looks more believable that they fixed whatever they said instead of changing the answer, granted they could still do it and leave a reason, I guess it's on more of the honor system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32894605868.0" user="drunkTurtle12" delta="False">
    <text>I mean if someone wants to troll they could change it to Adolf Hitler and add a note saying Edit: Fixed typo in the name.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896137593.0" user="XavierYourSavior" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly what I'm saying. It just shows how gullible they are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32903933014.0" user="FvHound" delta="False">
    <text>And? No one suggested a solution which stops trolls from being trolls.

It's about better identifying genuine people and their ideas/perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896135278.0" user="XavierYourSavior" delta="False">
    <text>Why is everyone saying this not keeping in mind that they could lie and have the same affect???</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896537312.0" user="MOABchoochoo" delta="False">
    <text>You could lie just the same, I guess it's more on the honor system that the edit you made is what you said, short of someone screenshotting you, theres not anything else to prove you didnt say something different and change it so that's all we can go off of</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896668248.0" user="drunkTurtle12" delta="False">
    <text>But why can’t the honor system then just be you editing it without changing anything that could change the meaning?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896691111.0" user="RajunCajun48" delta="False">
    <text>It should be, vast majority of the time I don't even notice someone edits something unless that tell on themselves with an edit note</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32900552045.0" user="MOABchoochoo" delta="False">
    <text>It could also work that way too, I guess people do it incase someone tries to bring it up because I dont really notice the edit mark right away compared to when people put it at the bottom of their post</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
