<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32895074450.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32895300103.0" user="Chiropteran22" delta="False">
    <text>What if someone made a joke on your spelling error? It also is a note that nothing else was changed, just spelling. I don't think it's always necessary but there's no reason to call people out  on something silly like this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32895711037.0" user="lilbunnfoofoo" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, but when I signed up for reddit they told me to do it. Am I supposed to just disregard the rules as if they were sections of the bible I dont feel like living my life around????</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32897553393.0" user="Richard_Thrust" delta="False">
    <text>Can't tell if serious</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32899890936.0" user="lilbunnfoofoo" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty much always 50/50 with me</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32897567396.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/purplealchemist – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+purplealchemist&amp;amp;message=purplealchemist+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/-/f40vlw2/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).

Do not reply to this comment by clicking the reply button, instead message the moderators ..... responses to moderation notices in the thread may be removed without notice.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
