<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32896426026.0" user="DigitalCoffee" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is someone can completely change their entire post leaving the comments on that post out of context.

Example: Someone writes a comment, "I really enjoy coffee in the morning."

Someone then comments: "I agree"

That someone then edits their post saying "I think coffee is disgusting." Thus making the following comments inaccurate of the writers actual position.

Coffee is a small example, you can easily change it to something much more unwelcome like "I think Hitler was right" or some shit.

I agree though that having to say you edited your post for small misspellings is lame, but the only way for someone to know that's all it was is with the "Edit" comment at the end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896528556.0" user="AnalForklift" delta="False">
    <text>If someone wanted to play that trick, the could still write "edit typos."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896584292.0" user="DigitalCoffee" delta="False">
    <text>You mean the responder could write that? They certainly could, but I don't think everyone who posts checks the exact message they responded too very often if at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896650252.0" user="AnalForklift" delta="False">
    <text>The person who edited their message. 

Someone could post, "I love sprinkles on my icecream." Wait for replies, then edit to say "icecream causes autism. Edit: typos."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896680051.0" user="DigitalCoffee" delta="False">
    <text>That's true. Not sure of a good way to remedy it other than make the writer's edit history public at all times.

Also it seems the asterisk showing the edit doesn't appear for a few minutes so that can cause quite a dispute. (or maybe it only appears when someone responds?)

Imma test

Edit: looks like 3 minutes, so if someone responds within the first 2 minutes and you change your message it won't be shown as an edit. Doesn't seem like a good idea tbh though I doubt this act is prevalent</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32896759009.0" user="AnalForklift" delta="False">
    <text>I use Reddit is Fun. I see an asterisk, but no way of seeing what the original post said.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
