<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818068356.0" index="49" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dj21l0/cmv_there_is_no_good_reason_to_leave_a_note_on_a/">
    <title>CMV: There is no good reason to leave a note on a comment after editing it for typos</title>
    <original_poster>wscuraiii</original_poster>
    <original_post>Is this some aspect of internet etiquette I missed out on at internet school? 

Too often, I'll be scrolling through comments on Reddit, and come across one with a footnote that reads:

EDIT: typos

Or even worse:

EDIT: a word

I understand and support leaving edit notes for developing stories or when *content* needs to be corrected after the fact. That makes sense.  But spelling? Seriously? When you turn in an essay or publish an article you wouldn't leave a footnote saying:

[1] All spelling errors have been corrected.

Who cares if you proofread your work? Why is that so special it deserves a footnote? Correct your typos and move on. You're *supposed* to proofread your work. It's assumed we all try to do so. Everyone makes typos, especially today when so many people are typing on mobile devices. I wrote this entire post using swipe text, for example. I'll be absolutely stunned if I don't find a few awkward typos in here. But I certainly won't let everybody know I corrected them. Because assuming I found them, of course I did. 

That's my view. Am I just uneducated? Is there something I missed? I've been meaning to make this post for a while now but kept forgetting, until I saw the "I fixed my typos" edit in three different comments today. I'm just trying to understand what the thought process could possibly be. 

EDIT: Did not find any typos, so none were corrected. Stunned.

EDIT 2, ELECTRIC BOOGALOO: Thanks for the silver, anonymous stranger!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32914399941.0" user="guinea_fowler" delta="False">
    <text>What if the correction changes the sense of the statement and someone comes back for a second read?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32914473742.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>My post says "unless there's a content change".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32914821183.0" user="guinea_fowler" delta="False">
    <text>Where do you draw the line between correction and content change?

I'm sure we could concoct a statement in which replacing one letter changes the sense, or in which the inclusion of one word clarifies some ambiguity which the poster wasn't initially aware of.

Like if you edited your post to replace "content" with "sense", I'd look like a dangus. But if you also wrote "Edit: word", I might look like a little less of a dangus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32915016875.0" user="wscuraiii" delta="False">
    <text>Correcting a typo versus adding a new thought. In either case the discussions I've had on this thread have resulted in the conclusion that Reddit needs to implement a wiki feature so we can see edit histories.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32915046547.0" user="guinea_fowler" delta="False">
    <text>Good idea. Get does on the phone! 😊</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
