<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818758978.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/djgugy/cmv_we_can_abolish_taxes_by_nationalizing_banks/">
    <title>CMV: We can abolish taxes by nationalizing banks</title>
    <original_poster>Nazbowling11</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface this idea relies entirely on Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) being a valid view of money and the government. For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is only limited by inflation and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation since there is too much money floating around. To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes. 

It works like this, imagine you could create money out of thin air and someone hands you $5. You don't need that $5 to buy anything since you can create money so you burn it deleting $5 from the economy. Even if you were to spend that $5 it's just money you didn't have to create, effectively deleting $5 that would have entered the economy. 

While taxation is one way to delete money, another way is to store money without reinvesting it. Lets say I bury $5 in my back yard, as far as the economy is concerned that money is deleted until I dig it back up and spend it again as it is no longer circulating through the economy.

My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy. As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation. Private banks won't do this since their incentive is to spend as much money as possible but the federal government does not have a profit incentive. This could also be used in tandem with taxation if necessary. 


This is an idea I've been floating around for awhile and I want to see if it's feasible or if it could be refined further. If anything is confusing I'll try to explain but I'm not an economist.

EDIT: I'm going to bed and will try to respond to more questions in the morning, but it seems I forgot to clarify something. Under this system nobody is stopping you from withdrawing and depositing money, that's not how my system works.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32902245588.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>This is too clever by half and is wildly over-using the ideas proposed in MMT.

First, let's think about the economy without money.  The government is a big entity that does a bunch of stuff.  It has an army, police officers, prison guards, judges, congresspeople, hospitals, post offices, etc.  In order to get people to do all the jobs at all those institutions, it has to gain command of their labor somehow.  It could do that by force, but slavery is generally frowned upon.  

It instead chooses to trade with those employees by giving them other stuff the government has.  That other stuff can be acquired by spending down govt assets, or the govt acquiring assets from some source.

Spending down government assets is of course long term unsustainable.  So to have a long term viable system, the government needs to acquire tradable assets.

---

So, the US Federal government has to acquire tradable assets worth [about 1/5 of the total economy](https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/FYONGDA188S) to fund current programs.

In order to obtain those resources under your plan, the government would need to either obtain profits from its banking operations to the tune of 20% of total economic output, or else be expanding the money supply by insane amounts each year.  That would of course cause runaway inflation.

You mention that the government could sanitize a lot of the inflation by not having the govt owned banks re-lend the money.

It's true they could do that, but it would annihilate the economy, because it would mean lending would grind to a halt.  If the government stopped giving out loans to stop inflation, it would kill the car industry, which relies on the large majority of buyers financing their vehicles.  It would kill the homebuilding industry, since the overwhelming majority of homebuyers take a mortgage.  And so on. 

MMT advocates do not call for abolishing taxes.  They think inflation is more manageable than traditional macroeconomics, but that's not to say they think the government can command 20% of the economy by just printing money.  It cannot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902293447.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The government is a big entity that does a bunch of stuff. It has an army, police officers, prison guards, judges, congresspeople, hospitals, post offices, etc. In order to get people to do all the jobs at all those institutions, it has to gain command of their labor somehow. It could do that by force, but slavery is generally frowned upon.

These people work for the government to obtain money printed by said government. This money is valuable because it is the only thing you can pay your taxes in. While in my system taxes are abolished, it would still be the only currency you can store in the US bank. 


&amp;gt;it would kill the car industry, which relies on the large majority of buyers financing their vehicles. It would kill the homebuilding industry, since the overwhelming majority of homebuyers take a mortgage. And so on.

I did not say that it would be stopped completely rather that it can be controlled to limit inflation. 

&amp;gt;MMT advocates do not call for abolishing taxes.

I know I'm just trying to work with their principles.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904139380.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I did not say that it would be stopped completely rather that it can be controlled to limit inflation.

The problem is scale.  Bank profits are not close to 20% of the economy.  The only "free" inflation reduction you'd get is from the amount of profit you'd forego by running the banks at zero profit.

Assuming that's 1% of the economy, you still are printing 19% of the economy worth of money each year, and will hyperinflate.  

If you want to cut down that part of inflation, you need to stop lending even at par.  That requires draconian regulation (to prevent black market banking) and will crush the economy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
