<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818758978.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/djgugy/cmv_we_can_abolish_taxes_by_nationalizing_banks/">
    <title>CMV: We can abolish taxes by nationalizing banks</title>
    <original_poster>Nazbowling11</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface this idea relies entirely on Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) being a valid view of money and the government. For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is only limited by inflation and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation since there is too much money floating around. To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes. 

It works like this, imagine you could create money out of thin air and someone hands you $5. You don't need that $5 to buy anything since you can create money so you burn it deleting $5 from the economy. Even if you were to spend that $5 it's just money you didn't have to create, effectively deleting $5 that would have entered the economy. 

While taxation is one way to delete money, another way is to store money without reinvesting it. Lets say I bury $5 in my back yard, as far as the economy is concerned that money is deleted until I dig it back up and spend it again as it is no longer circulating through the economy.

My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy. As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation. Private banks won't do this since their incentive is to spend as much money as possible but the federal government does not have a profit incentive. This could also be used in tandem with taxation if necessary. 


This is an idea I've been floating around for awhile and I want to see if it's feasible or if it could be refined further. If anything is confusing I'll try to explain but I'm not an economist.

EDIT: I'm going to bed and will try to respond to more questions in the morning, but it seems I forgot to clarify something. Under this system nobody is stopping you from withdrawing and depositing money, that's not how my system works.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32902248090.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>First, you've created a 100% wealth tax.  Your tax is paid entirely through the deflation of your money.  So instead of paying taxes based on how much income you got that year, it is based on how much cash you have.  Wealth taxes are pretty vicious for anyone trying to save up a great deal of money, say for someone that is trying to save up enough money to retire some day.  At some point, you may just get to the point where the amount you're trying to save doesn't even offset your losses from deflation, and so your savings account would be at best treading water as you keep dumping money into it. We have a couple of wealth taxes in the US (mainly property taxes), but they're used pretty infrequently.

Nobody is going to want to hold any cash, which is going to be a problem since cash is helpful for a lot of reasons from lowering transaction costs to decreasing risk and increasing solvency.  You might find so few people are holding onto cash that the value you can produce by printing more may be significantly diminished.

You're inflating the currency a LOT.  Adding up federal, state, and local government spending, government spending makes up [35.8% of GDP](https://www.usgovernmentspending.com/percent_gdp).  That is a huge amount of money to be printing each year and would cause a massive amount of inflation.

If you look at everything in terms of real dollars instead of nominal dollars, it washes away some of the problems.  For example, it's a huge problem if prices aren't reliable.  Stores needing to update their prices on a monthly basis is costly in many ways.

&amp;gt; As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation

So effectively they would be burying it in the yard?  That's the equivalent of just not doing anything with it.  As long as it is "money in the bank" as it were and it is money that I can withdraw, then it has an impact and it isn't just like it is gone like that.  You're just kinda suggesting to do nothing with it rather than something, which doesn't seem all that beneficial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902318051.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Your tax is paid entirely through the deflation of your money.

I do not want deflation, in fact some level of inflation is good for the economy since it incentives spending money. 

&amp;gt;. As long as it is "money in the bank" as it were and it is money that I can withdraw, then it has an impact and it isn't just like it is gone like that

It is money you can withdraw. What regular banks do is they take your deposit and invest as much of it as they can and rely on the fact that lots of people won't withdraw all their money at once, this is why you get interest on your deposit. In my version the federal government invests much less of this meaning that there is less money circulating through the economy. Granted just like a normal bank, a bank rush could cause severe problems but in that case you can just reinstate taxation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902373141.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I do not want deflation, in fact some level of inflation is good for the economy since it incentives spending money.

Sorry, that was a typo.  Your inflating prices.  Your plan would inflate them a LOT.  You're basically saying the government would, create from nothing through printing money about 7 trillion dollars a year. How would that not cause MASSIVE inflation?

ESPECIALLY given you think your plan will lower the money supply, which makes printing money cause even more inflation.  If the money supply is 7 trillion dollars and you print 7 trillion dollars, that is 100% inflation.  If the money supply is higher though, like 14 billion dollars, and you print 7 trillion dollars, well that is only a modest 50% annual inflation.  Currently the money supply (depending on which definition you use) is about 14 trillion dollars.  If you took a lot of that out of circulation before printing money, you'd get even worse inflation.

How is "less money circulating through the economy" a GOOD thing?  You've lowered the velocity of money (the ability of 1 dollar to be spend and then respent, and spent again, etc, is hugely helpful and causes a multiplicative benefit to the economy when money is spent), you've removed a huge source of loans for small businesses.

Suppose I give my money to the government run bank.  And they do nothing with it, as you suggested.  That accomplishes the exact same thing as me just not using the bank at all and putting it under my mattress.  Right? It doesn't matter if the government does nothing with it or I do nothing with it, it is still not circulating in the economy at this moment.  Either way, its money I plan on holding onto until I need to spend it and won't get spent until I was planning on spending it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902429684.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sorry, that was a typo. Your inflating prices. Your plan would inflate them a LOT. You're basically saying the government would, create from nothing through printing money about 7 trillion dollars a year. How would that not cause MASSIVE inflation?

The government already creates from nothing all money it spends. Also I'm confused as to where you're getting the 7 trillion number from. 

&amp;gt; ESPECIALLY given you think your plan will lower the money supply, which makes printing money cause even more inflation. If the money supply is 7 trillion dollars and you print 7 trillion dollars, that is 100% inflation. If the money supply is higher though, like 14 billion dollars, and you print 7 trillion dollars, well that is only a modest 50% annual inflation.

But that 7 trillion printed is going to have much less buying power if the money supply is at 14 billion. I don't get the point of this. 

&amp;gt;How is "less money circulating through the economy" a GOOD thing? You've lowered the velocity of money (the ability of 1 dollar to be spend and then respent, and spent again, etc, is hugely helpful and causes a multiplicative benefit to the economy when money is spent), you've removed a huge source of loans for small businesses.

Because this money is (theoretically) being used on a beneficial government program. I am only limiting the money supply to supplement an increase in the money supply through spending. 

&amp;gt;Suppose I give my money to the government run bank. And they do nothing with it, as you suggested. That accomplishes the exact same thing as me just not using the bank at all and putting it under my mattress. Right? 

Correct. 

&amp;gt;Either way, its money I plan on holding onto until I need to spend it and won't get spent until I was planning on spending it.

My system does not stop you from spending your money. When you deposit your money into a bank, that bank will invest nearly all of it an if you try to withdraw your money they'll just hand you someone else's money. In my system the government controls the bank and decides whether to invest the money you deposit or not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902479120.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also I'm confused as to where you're getting the 7 trillion number from.

The 7 trillion dollars is how much the government spends each year. Federal spending + state spending + local government spending.  You somehow have to figure out how to create 7 trillion dollars every single year using your system if you want to get rid of taxes entirely.

&amp;gt; The government already creates from nothing all money it spends.

The government does NOT create the 7 trillion dollars it spends each year from nothing.  That is what *you're* proposing and would cause massive inflation.  They tax that money and then spend what they took.  And they spend more than they took by going into debt by issuing bonds, but debt isn't the same as printing money either as it has to be paid back.

&amp;gt; But that 7 trillion printed is going to have much less buying power if the money supply is at 14 billion. I don't get the point of this.

(sorry, that billion was supposed to be trillion)

The point is if you're trying to print 7 trillion dollars worth of cash in an economy that only has 14 trillion dollars in money supply, you're going to get 50% inflation.

Nationalizing banks isn't going to change that calculation at all, at least not for the better.  

&amp;gt; My system does not stop you from spending your money. When you deposit your money into a bank, that bank will invest nearly all of it an if you try to withdraw your money they'll just hand you someone else's money. In my system the government controls the bank and decides whether to invest the money you deposit or not.

By doing this, you aren't "removing the need for taxation" you are UNDERMINING YOUR TAX BASE.  You are actively defeating your proposal.

If I'm the government, and I print a dollar in an economy that has $100, then each dollar is worth 1/101 of the economy, so I'm taking a little piece from every dollar in the economy.  If you first shrink the money supply, you have fewer dollars to take from.  Now you're printing a dollar in an economy that has $50.  Sure, you're going to get more bang out of your dollar, but it's also going to cause EVEN MORE INFLATION, because now you're increasing the money supply by 2% instead of 1%.

But your proposal involves increasing the money supply by something like 50% every single year.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902518761.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You somehow have to figure out how to create 7 trillion dollars every single year using your system if you want to get rid of taxes entirely.

The government already does this. When the government spends it just creates money. Taxation is the deletion of money. 

&amp;gt;They tax that money and then spend what they took

Except they don't. The government spends more than it takes in almost every year, there are only a few instances in the history of the US where this didn't happen. The government is not like you or I, they do not need to take in dollars to spend dollars. 

&amp;gt; but debt isn't the same as printing money either as it has to be paid back.

 This is a self imposed limitation to prevent inflation. There's nothing stopping the government from printing money to fund it's programs other than the fear of inflation. 

&amp;gt;By doing this, you aren't "removing the need for taxation" you are UNDERMINING YOUR TAX BASE. You are actively defeating your proposal.

The need for taxation is to limit the supply of money. My proposed system accomplishes this. 

&amp;gt;If I'm the government, and I print a dollar in an economy that has $100, then each dollar is worth 1/101 of the economy, so I'm taking a little piece from every dollar in the economy. If you first shrink the money supply, you have fewer dollars to take from. Now you're printing a dollar in an economy that has $50. Sure, you're going to get more bang out of your dollar, but it's also going to cause EVEN MORE INFLATION.

I'm well aware of what inflation does but I don't get what the point of this is. Too much money circulating through the economy is bad so I proposed a system to remove it that isn't taxation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904299847.0" user="Twin_Spoons" delta="False">
    <text>I think the important thing that your missing here is that taxation and government spending must fundamentally be about the redirection of *resources*, and any accounting system that's laid over top is just an abstraction of that. Try to conceptualize how the policy would work if it didn't use money at all. 

Taxation is relatively simple in that framework. The government decides that it needs a certain amount of labor, a certain amount of food for the army, etc. It acquires this by going around to citizens and taking those resources, then uses them as it sees fit. You cannot get around this by printing money. *Creating money does not create resources*. Your policy would still succeed in taking resources from the public and giving them to the government, but it wouldn't be costless to the public. By reducing the value of savings through inflation, you're essentially taking what you need from the public in proportion to their savings. This is why the original reply to this comment identified your policy as a wealth tax. Maybe you prefer wealth taxes, but it's still foolish to deny that your policy wouldn't cause distortions at least on par with the the ones caused by our current income/consumption tax-based system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904558340.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think the important thing that your missing here is that taxation and government spending must fundamentally be about the redirection of resources, and any accounting system that's laid over top is just an abstraction of that. 

I guess that's where we have to disagree. The government is perfectly capable of acquiring resources and labor through the printing of money. The value of money is based off the exchange rates of goods to eachother but that does not mean that the government can't get things done simply by printing money since there will away be demand for money.

&amp;gt;Try to conceptualize how the policy would work if it didn't use money at all.

The system requires money to function. This is a non starter. 

&amp;gt;Taxation is relatively simple in that framework. The government decides that it needs a certain amount of labor, a certain amount of food for the army, etc. It acquires this by going around to citizens and taking those resources, then uses them as it sees fit. You cannot get around this by printing money.

The government does not hand it's employees gold or other resources it hands them money, something it can create at will. The government does not need to collect resources to spend since the money it prints is valuable as both a tool of exchange and for the fact that it's the only thing you pay US taxes in. 

&amp;gt;Creating money does not create resources

If I print out a ton of money and use it to fund a mine is that not creating resources? What if I print out money to fund a hospital? You can use the demand for money to acquire resources and labor. 

&amp;gt;By reducing the value of savings through inflation, you're essentially taking what you need from the public in proportion to their savings.

Moderate inflation is good as it incentives spending and investment. Having your currency remain constant is fairly pointless and deflation is incredibly bad as your currency now becomes an investment in itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904973894.0" user="Twin_Spoons" delta="False">
    <text>The feasibility of a system that doesn't use money is irrelevant. It's just a useful thought experiment for understanding why printing money doesn't create value. Here's an alternative approach: consider feeding an army. It's a pretty mundane example, but it's actually precisely the thing that has caused a lot of questionable economic policy from desperate/dissolving governments in the past. 

My claim is that to feed the army, you need to take some other material good away from the populace. Let's consider all the strategies we could take for feeding the army:

1) Go around to everyone's house and demand they cook a meal for the army. In this case, it's obvious that resources are being transferred directly from the populace to the army.

2) Tax the populace and use the tax revenue to buy food for the army. This is also pretty obvious. People have less money to buy the stuff they like, so they buy less stuff. This will probably distort some prices, but there's a way to do it (like only taxing food purchases) that keeps everything the same. 

3) Print money and give it to the army. You can't eat money, but the soldiers can go spend it at the grocery store to buy food. This increases the demand for food, and hence the price of food. Other people (who didn't recieve any of the money you printed) can buy less at these higher prices. By handing the soldiers money (which, I'll repeat, you cannot eat), you've only given them a COUPON for food, but you haven't actually made any food. If they go and use that coupon, it means they're eating food that otherwise would have ended up with someone else. (There's a subtlety here, which is that the people in your army would have eaten even if they were civillians, but because they're in your army rather than working on farms, there's still less food available than there would be otherwise)

4) Have the army include people who work on farms and make food just for the army. You don't have to pay anyone anything for the food, BUT the people working on those farms are now no longer working on civilian farms or in other industries. The supply of those goods falls, driving up the price. As before, regular citizens now need to pay more to buy the same things. (This is the part you're missing when you say things like funding a hospital somehow magics resources into existence. What you're really doing is diverting resources into the hospital that would have been used elsewhere). 

?) I invite you to propose some alternative strategy that I have not considered here. 

Modern economies have all kinds of ways to create value. Innovation creates value. Market exchange creates value. Government programs, however, mostly just have the power to push value around. Sometimes that's worthwhile, but it's important to never lose sight of the limitations of policy and think that just because the government makes the coupons that they also make the goods those coupons can buy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32905125902.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>How the government currently works is a combination of 2 and 3, they print money for the soldiers and then to limit inflation they collect money in taxes. 

&amp;gt;Have the army include people who work on farms and make food just for the army. You don't have to pay anyone anything for the food, BUT the people working on those farms are now no longer working on civilian farms or in other industries. The supply of those goods falls, driving up the price

This critique applies to literally any government program. I understand that by funding government programs you pull labor from other sectors of the economy, but I believe this is a fair cost for things like government healthcare or similar programs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32905290070.0" user="Twin_Spoons" delta="False">
    <text>To your second point. Sure, I agree. I'm not a "taxation is theft" guy. I'm also not a "government spending is magic" guy. 

To your first point, it seems like you're just inserting a bunch of extra steps into the process of government finance to make your point. What matters is how much goes into the government and how much comes out. You can conceptualize that as taxing the populace and spending that money. You can conceptualize it as taxing the populace, destroying the taxes, and printing new money to replace it. I don't know why you would, but you could. 

At first I thought you were doing something similar in the original post. But then I read more carefully and saw that your idea is to replace taxation with a system that... intentionally uses people's savings inefficiently? You seem to be confused about the relationship between investment returns and inflation. Printing a lot of money will cause inflation for reasons we've already discussed and that have nothing to do with investment. One reason governments today can get away with printing a little bit of money is BECAUSE investment returns allow savings to keep up with inflation. Inflation (even a small amount) would be a lot more harmful to the average person if this was not true. Right now a 20 year old can save some money and expect the VALUE of that money to have grown substantially by the time he's ready to retire. That is, the money value of investments doesn't just increase because of inflation - it increases because investments are actually productive. Take away investment returns (while massively increasing inflation), and instead the value of that money shrinks. Once again, we've shifted value from a person (the saver) to the government. There's no getting around it. 

But your policy is extra harmful because investments are productive, and you're intentionally stopping them. You would be raising the cost of business/home/school loans for no good reason. To return to the feeding an army example, it's like you picked one of the ennumerated strategies, then tacked on a policy of burning half the crops in the country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904543892.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Taxation is the deletion of money.

Which counteracts inflation.

&amp;gt; This is a self imposed limitation to prevent inflation.

Exactly.

**Your proposal (without the nationalization of banks) would cause 50% inflation. With the nationalization of banks, it would cause MORE inflation.  This would be insanely damaging to the economy.**

Through silly tricks like deleting a bunch of money before creating a bunch of money and issuing debt, we can prevent insane amounts of inflation.

&amp;gt; Too much money circulating through the economy is bad

WHERE ARE YOU GETTING THIS FROM?!?  Money circulating through the economy is hugely beneficial.

&amp;gt; For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is **only limited by inflation** and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. **However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation** since there is too much money floating around. **To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes.**

You admitted that your plan of nationalizing banks is the equivalent of people just putting money under their mattresses.  This doesn't do anything to prevent the massive 50% inflation your plan would create, because you're LOWERING the money in circulation which would make the inflation worse.

You act like people using mattresses instead of banks would be able to counteract hyperinflation, which isn't at all accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904589134.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; WHERE ARE YOU GETTING THIS FROM?!? Money circulating through the economy is hugely beneficial.

You want low amounts of money circulating through the economy quickly, you do not want tons of money floating around due to inflation. 

&amp;gt;This doesn't do anything to prevent the massive 50% inflation your plan would create, because you're LOWERING the money in circulation which would make the inflation worse.

How does decreasing the amount of money increase inflation? You have the same amount of goods and services chasing less money how would that not lead to deflationary effects?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904644663.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How does decreasing the amount of money increase inflation?

If I'm the government, and I print a dollar in an economy that has $100, then each dollar is worth 1/101 of the economy, so I'm taking a little piece from every dollar in the economy. If you first shrink the money supply, you have fewer dollars to take from. Now you're printing a dollar in an economy that has $50. Sure, you're going to get more bang out of your dollar, but it's also going to cause EVEN MORE INFLATION, because now you're increasing the money supply by 2% instead of 1%.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904886595.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>Lets say in my system the government wants to spend $10 and there is $100 in the economy. While technically there will be $110 in the economy now, in my system the government selects $10 of this economy to stop circulating meaning that the number of dollars floating around is still $100 assuming there isn't a bank rush and everyone withdraws and spends their money all at once.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904718280.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You want low amounts of money circulating through the economy quickly, you do not want tons of money floating around due to inflation.

Your not doing that though.  You're just taking some money and intentionally slowing it down to a stand-still (and then pretending like you can just ignore that it's there as long as it is stopped, which clearly it isn't because it'll get withdrawn at some point too) and then taking other money and designating it as what gets to move.

The overall effect would be to slow money down because you now have small business that need loans that won't get them and won't be able to operate without them.

You're literally making sure money movement in the economy by not giving out loans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904844244.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>But as far as the economy is concerned that money is gone, it's not flowing around meaning that you have effectively decreased the money supply.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904875758.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>Lets take your idea to its logical extreme.  If I bury $5 in the back yard for a month, its deleted, right?

How about if I stick $5 in my pocket for a month? Or even 30 seconds?

Using your logic, why not just consider all money not currently involved in a transaction as deleted?

Then you're left with only two meaningful metrics:

* How much total transactions happens each day
* How much money people understand that they have

Your proposal doesn't do anything to the second bullet point.  And it has an effect on the first bullet point, which is to LOWER the total of transactions by denying loans to small businesses.

This doesn't do anything beneficial to the economy.  Your not deleting additional money, you're just lowering total transactions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904926522.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How about if I stick $5 in my pocket for a month? Or even 30 seconds?

There is obviously a time component here but can agree that never spending that money again would effectively be deleting it from the economy? Sure that dollar still exists but it is not, and will not be in the economy for the foreseeable future. 

&amp;gt;This doesn't do anything beneficial to the economy.

Obviously this is going to cause some harmful effects the question is if the decrease in taxes and government spending make up for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904970094.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is obviously a time component here but can agree that never spending that money again would effectively be deleting it from the economy? Sure that dollar still exists but it is not, and will not be in the economy for the foreseeable future.

Nothing in my bank account is "never going to be spent again" or "not in the foreseeable future". Worst case scenario, that money will be given to the people in my will when I die, which is a form of transaction.

Look, the definition of money supply is:

&amp;gt; The money supply (or money stock) is the total value of money available in an economy at a point of time. 

Unless the government is saying, "Hey, this money in your bank account? It's unavailable to you right now.  You're not going to have access to some of the funds in your account." you haven't decreased the money supply.

The money supply IS my second bullet point: "How much money people understand that they have".  It is the your bank account total, which is all available to spend.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32905046350.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nothing in my bank account is "never going to be spent again" or "not in the foreseeable future"

When you put savings into a private bank, they invest as much of it as they're allowed to. Your money is already gone and they're just banking on the fact that you don't come and withdraw it all at once. Even if you are constantly spending and doing things with it they're just moving money from someone's account to yours to make up for this. 

&amp;gt;The money supply IS my second bullet point: "How much money people understand that they have". It is the your bank account total, which is all available to spend.

If this is how it actually worked then our current banking model would not be feasible as it depends on people not withdrawing their money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32905158264.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>I know how reserve ratios and runs on the bank work.  The money in your bank account is still part of the money supply because it is available to you.  It is money that you have access to and can go withdraw 100% of it.

Go read the definition of M1 money supply.  It includes all checking account balances.  And that is the MOST restrictive money supply definition.  The money supply only increases from there and includes more things when you start looking at M2 and M3.

Your total checking account balance is part of money supply because it is all available to you.  You could withdraw 100% of it.  Just because not everyone could all withdraw 100% all at the same time doesn't really have an impact on anything because banks have made appropriate protections to make sure that limit isn't hit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32907220340.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Go read the definition of M1 money supply. It includes all checking account balances. And that is the MOST restrictive money supply definition. The money supply only increases from there and includes more things when you start looking at M2 and M3.

&amp;gt;Your total checking account balance is part of money supply because it is all available to you. You could withdraw 100% of it. Just because not everyone could all withdraw 100% all at the same time doesn't really have an impact on anything because banks have made appropriate protections to make sure that limit isn't hit.

Protections against what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32907387507.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>

&amp;gt;Your total checking account balance is part of money supply because it is all available to you. You could withdraw 100% of it. Just because not everyone could all withdraw 100% all at the same time doesn't really have an impact on anything because banks have made appropriate protections to make sure that limit isn't hit.

Protections against what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32907424208.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>Protections to make sure they can provide money to any account holders that request their funds.  Both backed by their internal reserve ratio and also things like FDIC insurance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32903430110.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Interestingly I didn't like OPs idea at all, but your argument makes it sound quite appealing. I really like the idea of a 100% wealth tax, something society desperately needs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32904557527.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>The 50%+ annual inflation rate that this proposal would create would be awful.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
