<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818758978.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/djgugy/cmv_we_can_abolish_taxes_by_nationalizing_banks/">
    <title>CMV: We can abolish taxes by nationalizing banks</title>
    <original_poster>Nazbowling11</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface this idea relies entirely on Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) being a valid view of money and the government. For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is only limited by inflation and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation since there is too much money floating around. To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes. 

It works like this, imagine you could create money out of thin air and someone hands you $5. You don't need that $5 to buy anything since you can create money so you burn it deleting $5 from the economy. Even if you were to spend that $5 it's just money you didn't have to create, effectively deleting $5 that would have entered the economy. 

While taxation is one way to delete money, another way is to store money without reinvesting it. Lets say I bury $5 in my back yard, as far as the economy is concerned that money is deleted until I dig it back up and spend it again as it is no longer circulating through the economy.

My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy. As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation. Private banks won't do this since their incentive is to spend as much money as possible but the federal government does not have a profit incentive. This could also be used in tandem with taxation if necessary. 


This is an idea I've been floating around for awhile and I want to see if it's feasible or if it could be refined further. If anything is confusing I'll try to explain but I'm not an economist.

EDIT: I'm going to bed and will try to respond to more questions in the morning, but it seems I forgot to clarify something. Under this system nobody is stopping you from withdrawing and depositing money, that's not how my system works.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32906068747.0" user="AOneAndOnly" delta="False">
    <text>I cannot help but notice a lack of numbers in your post. 

 Does the current banking system hold enough money to offset taxes? ￼
If we totaled up year over year deposits across all banks we would need this number to match government spending. 
Right think about this, if the government wants to spend 20 trillion, to prevent inflation they need to remove some percent of that out of the economy. I dont know what that number is, but let’s say it’s 50%. Your plan would require Americans to make an additional 10 trillion dollars in deposits every year. Quick google search suggests that the American banking system has only averaged &amp;lt;1 trillion net increase per year. Would you mandate more people deposit money?


How would people get loans/ do you prevent bank like institutions?
Currently if I want to buy a car or a house I can get a lone from a bank. If government banks are not issuing loans, I would turn to a nonbank. What’s to prevent these non banks from accepting investments and using that to find loans, then offering interest on those investments? Then basically functioning like a bank. This would cause people to not put money in their bank account causing inflation. Without any way to force money out of the economy this would presumably spiral out of control. If you ban loans all together how to people /businesses get the capital to start businesses and grow the economy?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
