<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818758978.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/djgugy/cmv_we_can_abolish_taxes_by_nationalizing_banks/">
    <title>CMV: We can abolish taxes by nationalizing banks</title>
    <original_poster>Nazbowling11</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface this idea relies entirely on Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) being a valid view of money and the government. For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is only limited by inflation and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation since there is too much money floating around. To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes. 

It works like this, imagine you could create money out of thin air and someone hands you $5. You don't need that $5 to buy anything since you can create money so you burn it deleting $5 from the economy. Even if you were to spend that $5 it's just money you didn't have to create, effectively deleting $5 that would have entered the economy. 

While taxation is one way to delete money, another way is to store money without reinvesting it. Lets say I bury $5 in my back yard, as far as the economy is concerned that money is deleted until I dig it back up and spend it again as it is no longer circulating through the economy.

My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy. As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation. Private banks won't do this since their incentive is to spend as much money as possible but the federal government does not have a profit incentive. This could also be used in tandem with taxation if necessary. 


This is an idea I've been floating around for awhile and I want to see if it's feasible or if it could be refined further. If anything is confusing I'll try to explain but I'm not an economist.

EDIT: I'm going to bed and will try to respond to more questions in the morning, but it seems I forgot to clarify something. Under this system nobody is stopping you from withdrawing and depositing money, that's not how my system works.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32903127924.0" user="Nacruno96" delta="False">
    <text>Most things would kind of work as you described it, but I think there are some things I would criticize. An economy needs money supply. This money supply usually arrives from banks. The problem with banks is that they aren’t good at supplying money. If they lend money towards people buying stocks or countries to the extent they put one percent of their bip into paying interest, then this will not be of great use for the economy. Instead of giving the banks the job of supplying money the government could supply money. The government might be able to supply money in away that benefits the poorest, which will of cause also trigger higher growth rates than supplying money to banks. But there are problems too. Governments are pretty bad in keeping a budget. And supplying money can get an addiction even though it’s not needed. And of course politics might end up evolving over who gets government money supply and who will get it beyond the realm of what an economy needs in terms of money supply. 

I think taxation isn’t a way to lower money supply after all the government pays for stuff with that money. I also don’t see why one should forbid banking. Banking will just start looking like banking of the 16 century, in which banks didn’t mint coins or paper money for the government. Also you won’t get a steady chunk of money to supply the economy with. It will be more or less depending on inflation. But if of course the government or an alternative institution than banks will be better at supplying money probably recessions will be a thing of the past as well.

Also i think private property rights are kind of forgotten in your system. If people aren’t sure that the money they have accumulated is secure they will make it secure. Also I think it’s immoral for a government to eliminate once property in such a way. 

All in all I would be in favor of a system in which a not electable office is created determining the money supply of the country and determining the amount of money the government gets to spend beside taxes. However I would not do away with property rights or banks. Also this system is untested. I could imagine a lot of problems. What if banks are better at choosing who to supply with money than a elected office which needs to get re-elected. Also money supply to some people will lead to more inflation than to others. It might be hard to calculate how much money one really needs towards having 2% inflation. I think one needs a bit of testing, before implementing on a great scale this kind of ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
