<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="818758978.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/djgugy/cmv_we_can_abolish_taxes_by_nationalizing_banks/">
    <title>CMV: We can abolish taxes by nationalizing banks</title>
    <original_poster>Nazbowling11</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface this idea relies entirely on Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) being a valid view of money and the government. For those who do not know what MMT is, in brief it is the idea that the government as a money creating entity can not enter debt and it is not financially limited by money, it is only limited by inflation and the material wealth of the country. Government spending is simply the creation of new money, it does not need to collect money to spend like you or I would. However if the government does this in excess we run into the problem of hyperinflation since there is too much money floating around. To solve this the government has to delete money from the economy through things like taxes. 

It works like this, imagine you could create money out of thin air and someone hands you $5. You don't need that $5 to buy anything since you can create money so you burn it deleting $5 from the economy. Even if you were to spend that $5 it's just money you didn't have to create, effectively deleting $5 that would have entered the economy. 

While taxation is one way to delete money, another way is to store money without reinvesting it. Lets say I bury $5 in my back yard, as far as the economy is concerned that money is deleted until I dig it back up and spend it again as it is no longer circulating through the economy.

My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy. As stated earlier since money that isn't reinvested is effectively deleted until spent again, all the government has to do is not invest with your money and it will be deleted from the economy thus limiting inflation and removing the need for taxation. Private banks won't do this since their incentive is to spend as much money as possible but the federal government does not have a profit incentive. This could also be used in tandem with taxation if necessary. 


This is an idea I've been floating around for awhile and I want to see if it's feasible or if it could be refined further. If anything is confusing I'll try to explain but I'm not an economist.

EDIT: I'm going to bed and will try to respond to more questions in the morning, but it seems I forgot to clarify something. Under this system nobody is stopping you from withdrawing and depositing money, that's not how my system works.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32902550419.0" user="ChadAdonis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;My idea is that rather than using taxation to limit the money supply we simply delete money from the economy by not reinvesting it and this is where nationalization of the banks comes in. By nationalizing the banks, the government controls how much of the money invested into it gets reinvested into the economy.

Why would anyone deposit money into a bank if it just gets gobbled up by the feds? Under this scenario, they'd just keep the money as cash and spend as needed. No one would make any deposits.

On the other end, the entire economy runs on credit. Millions of businesses rely on loans and debt instruments every single day to raise capital and continue operations. If your going to have the government make these lending decisions instead of free markets you're going to be in big trouble unless you move towards a communist system with a centrally planned economy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902623181.0" user="Nazbowling11" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why would anyone deposit money into a bank if it just gets gobbled up by the feds? Under this scenario, they'd just keep the money as cash and spend as needed. No one would make any deposits.

No part of my system prevents you from making deposits and withdrawals. When you deposit money into a bank, they invest as much of it as they can and keep very little of it in store banking on the fact that everyone won't withdraw their money at the same time. My system functions the same way except the government would invest less of your money than a private bank would. 

&amp;gt; Millions of businesses rely on loans and debt instruments every single day to raise capital and continue operations

And millions of citizens would benefit immensely from not having to pay taxes. Money has to come out of the economy somehow and I believe that it would be better for the people to just have the government invest less rather than garnish their wages for tax purposes. 

&amp;gt;If your going to have the government make these lending decisions instead of free markets you're going to be in big trouble unless you move towards a communist system with a centrally planned economy.

All economies are planned to some extent, the question is who's planning it and what for.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32902669484.0" user="ChadAdonis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No part of my system prevents you from making deposits and withdrawals. When you deposit money into a bank, they invest as much of it as they can and keep very little of it in store banking on the fact that everyone won't withdraw their money at the same time. My system functions the same way except the government would invest less of your money than a private bank would.

Ok where are my interest payments if the money isn't being invested elsewhere? Or is the government just going to print money for that purpose?

&amp;gt;And millions of citizens would benefit immensely from not having to pay taxes. Money has to come out of the economy somehow and I believe that it would be better for the people to just have the government invest less rather than garnish their wages for tax purposes.

Under your system, they wouldn't have to pay taxes regardless because they wouldn't have jobs. Businesses rely on credit markets to grow. When those credit markets shrink, so do businesses. That's why the economy froze during the financial crisis of 08... credit markets were frozen. MMT theories are usually presented with a federally backed jobs guarantee. There are no such provisions in your plan.

&amp;gt;All economies are planned to some extent, the question is who's planning it and what for.

The extent of control varies but you can't have free economic markets without free credit markets to serve them. If government is dictating credit availability based on maintaining a certain inflation rate, then it also needs to be dictating how many widgets the economy makes else there always will be a shortage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32906538961.0" user="ChadAdonis" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Nazbowling11 hey bud you gonna respond to this or are you giving up?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
