<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="826388770.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/do0dnm/cmv_its_better_not_to_try_than_to_try_and_fail/">
    <title>CMV: It's better not to try than to try and fail</title>
    <original_poster>randomanon43</original_poster>
    <original_post>So clearly this doesn't hold true in all situations because some situations are virtually risk-free/risk are minimal leaving no reason to not try. But for most other situations with moderate to significant risks I'm always hearing that "it's better to to try and fail than to not try at all" or "it's better to have loved and lost than to not have loved at all" or some variation of that expressing a similar sentiment. I think that's absolutely crap to have as a general rule. Sometimes the pain of that failure or that loved loss far exceeds any regret you'd possibly have for not trying in the first place. I prefer to wallow in the "what ifs" than the certainty of ineptitude, loss or impossibility


Edit: so I'm adding one of my comment response to another Redditer to elucidate my views (as a lot of the responses I'm seeing are fairly similar and seem to assume I'm assuming take no risk at all) 


So thanks for such a well thought out response, I'll try my best to do the same tho admittedly I feel you're plagued by cliches (which is inevitable so i'm not berating you for this). 

Firstly clearly I'm not speaking about the extremes as "general rules" tend to break down at these points and these situations must typically be judged on a case by case basis. So situations with enormous risk and situations with little to no risks are excluded from this discourse. So what I'm specifically taking about is the average situations(moderate to significant risk) examples of which included: getting into relationships, applications for positions/jobs, etc (hopefully this is clear now)

Secondly I hope you understand that I'm using " failure" and "loved loss" as expressions of the general sentiment I'm arguing against rather than speaking specifically about failure and loss of loved ones etc (just want to make sure this is clear, not saying you don't understand)

Now what I'm saying isnt that you should avoid all situations that has average risk (remember this is the sphere we are working in, extremes are already exlcuded). That would lead to you doing nothing at all (except for no risk/minimal risk things) What I'm saying is that it is wrong to say that GENERALLY it is better for you to attempt things with average risk than to not. That sentiment is false to me. What I think is true is that everything in this average risk category must be judged on a case by case basis. And if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure. Now i'd like you to note that I think it is up to the individual to chose the threshold necessary for action and what outcome of failure they view as significant. 

So looking at it through this lens, I'm not saying you should do nothing at all or that failure/loss should be avoided at all cost. Far from it, I just think a lot of suffering is unnecessary and is perpetuated by this "it is better to try and fail" mindset that I view is wrong. It is kinda reminiscent of the sunken cost fallacy that many people fall prey to. (I hope I was able to be clear)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32985821006.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It's better not to try than to try and fail

In most cases, a failure is not necessarily definitive though. What if the initial failure motivates you to try again, and you succeed at a later point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32986521205.0" user="randomanon43" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with you. That can happen. Which is why I'm not saying to avoid failure at all cost (see my updated post). Failure will inevitable occur once you are alive. I'm arguing against the need for some failures/loss. For example look at it like this.  Let's say you have a high stakes tennis match (just a random sport that came to mind) in 3 months time. Before the match you'll practice right? Some of these practice matches you'll lose. But that loss doesn't matter(low risk) so clearly I'm not telling you to avoid those. And if after practicing for 3 months you're adequate prepared for the match (let's say you have a 50/50 chance of winning) clearly I'm not saying to avoid that risk either because your preparation has adequately mitigated your chance of failure. How my argument would come into play, is if you aren't adequately prepared for your match (i.e. did not practice + phenomenally skilled opponent) and it's high stakes as I've already highlighted (so failure has an significant impact e.g loss of your title and public embarrassment) then in my opinion, it is not be to try fail (and learn something). It is clearly better to not try at all because you knew it likely result of the situation. If you decided to enter this match you knew you'd most likely lose and were just hoping to win. So you've just burdened yourself with an. Unnecessary loss. And lots of everyday situations are like this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32988138199.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>If you're the type who takes part in high-stakes tennis matches, then you need the competition experience in order to grow, *just as well* as you need practice matches. The circumstances of practice and competition matches will likely be very different as well. You can't defer all competitions until you're sure to have a high confidence of winning.

What I'm saying is that as a (professional) tennis player you'll probably lose some non-insignificant number of high-profile matches before you become good and start winning more high-profile matches over time. If all you ever had in life was one final tennis match, then you would be correct: it would be better to wait until you can win that match, because it will be your one and final experience. But in reality, that's hardly ever the case: you'll get many more chances to improve yourself. You just need to keep playing. It is through the experience of winning *and* losing that over time, you can get good.

Imagine if everyone applied this principle: to only play if they have a 50%+ chance of winning. There could only be competitions in sports where people get really good, and no one mediocre would ever play. Most of the soccer teams in the world would never take part in the World Championship etc.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
