<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="826388770.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/do0dnm/cmv_its_better_not_to_try_than_to_try_and_fail/">
    <title>CMV: It's better not to try than to try and fail</title>
    <original_poster>randomanon43</original_poster>
    <original_post>So clearly this doesn't hold true in all situations because some situations are virtually risk-free/risk are minimal leaving no reason to not try. But for most other situations with moderate to significant risks I'm always hearing that "it's better to to try and fail than to not try at all" or "it's better to have loved and lost than to not have loved at all" or some variation of that expressing a similar sentiment. I think that's absolutely crap to have as a general rule. Sometimes the pain of that failure or that loved loss far exceeds any regret you'd possibly have for not trying in the first place. I prefer to wallow in the "what ifs" than the certainty of ineptitude, loss or impossibility


Edit: so I'm adding one of my comment response to another Redditer to elucidate my views (as a lot of the responses I'm seeing are fairly similar and seem to assume I'm assuming take no risk at all) 


So thanks for such a well thought out response, I'll try my best to do the same tho admittedly I feel you're plagued by cliches (which is inevitable so i'm not berating you for this). 

Firstly clearly I'm not speaking about the extremes as "general rules" tend to break down at these points and these situations must typically be judged on a case by case basis. So situations with enormous risk and situations with little to no risks are excluded from this discourse. So what I'm specifically taking about is the average situations(moderate to significant risk) examples of which included: getting into relationships, applications for positions/jobs, etc (hopefully this is clear now)

Secondly I hope you understand that I'm using " failure" and "loved loss" as expressions of the general sentiment I'm arguing against rather than speaking specifically about failure and loss of loved ones etc (just want to make sure this is clear, not saying you don't understand)

Now what I'm saying isnt that you should avoid all situations that has average risk (remember this is the sphere we are working in, extremes are already exlcuded). That would lead to you doing nothing at all (except for no risk/minimal risk things) What I'm saying is that it is wrong to say that GENERALLY it is better for you to attempt things with average risk than to not. That sentiment is false to me. What I think is true is that everything in this average risk category must be judged on a case by case basis. And if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure. Now i'd like you to note that I think it is up to the individual to chose the threshold necessary for action and what outcome of failure they view as significant. 

So looking at it through this lens, I'm not saying you should do nothing at all or that failure/loss should be avoided at all cost. Far from it, I just think a lot of suffering is unnecessary and is perpetuated by this "it is better to try and fail" mindset that I view is wrong. It is kinda reminiscent of the sunken cost fallacy that many people fall prey to. (I hope I was able to be clear)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32985568819.0" user="GrumpyGuss" delta="False">
    <text>Obviously there are severe and obvious risks which far outweigh whatever reward might come from them. Jumping off of a cliff into unknown waters is an easy example, where the momentary rush is weighed against death or lifelong paralysis. 

However what you seem to be describing is avoiding even relatively slight risks. Failure does hurt. Losing a loved one does hurt. However there is much to be gained even from failure or heartbreak. Avoiding either denies you not only the pleasure, pride and exultation of success or love, it also denies you the growth and maturity that comes with experiencing that pain, and finding your own strength to recover from it and try again.

Rare indeed is the successful person who has never failed. Rare indeed are the couple who were each other's first and last kiss. Yet there are many who have found success after many failures, and many who have found love after years of searching.

Becoming someone who perseveres through hardship strengthens you. Becoming someone who doesn't even try because of the spectre of pain...it will lead you down a sad and lonely path through life which you will regret.

&amp;gt; I prefer to wallow in the "what ifs" than the certainty of ineptitude, loss or impossibility

From the sound of it, you already do. In avoiding pain, you have denied yourself pleasure as well, and yet you still suffer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32985808637.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32989215390.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/WonderfulHeron – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+WonderfulHeron&amp;amp;message=WonderfulHeron+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/do0dnm/-/f5iwcu5/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32985975631.0" user="randomanon43" delta="False">
    <text>So thanks for such a well thought out response, I'll try my best to do the same tho admittedly I feel you're plagued by cliches (which is inevitable so i'm not berating you for this). 

Firstly clearly I'm not speaking about the extremes as "general rules" tend to break down at these points and these situations must typically be judged on a case by case basis. So situations with enormous risk and situations with little to no risks are excluded from this discourse. So what I'm specifically taking about is the average situations(moderate to significant risk) examples of which included: getting into relationships, applications for positions/jobs, etc (hopefully this is clear now)

Secondly I hope you understand that I'm using " failure" and "loved loss" as expressions of the general sentiment I'm arguing against rather than speaking specifically about failure and loss of loved ones etc (just want to make sure this is clear, not saying you don't understand)

Now what I'm saying isnt that you should avoid all situations that has average risk (remember this is the sphere we are working in, extremes are already exlcuded). That would lead to you doing nothing at all (except for no risk/minimal risk things) What I'm saying is that it is wrong to say that GENERALLY it is better for you to attempt things with average risk than to not. That sentiment is false to me. What I think is true is that everything in this average risk category must be judged on a case by case basis. And if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure. Now i'd like you to note that I think it is up to the individual to chose the threshold necessary for action and what outcome of failure they view as significant. 

So looking at it through this lens, I'm not saying you should do nothing at all or that failure/loss should be avoided at all cost. Far from it, I just think a lot of suffering is unnecessary and is perpetuated by this "it is better to try and fail" mindset that I view is wrong. It is kinda reminiscent of the sunken cost fallacy that many people fall prey to. (I hope I was able to be clear)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32986395037.0" user="GrumpyGuss" delta="False">
    <text>Thank-you for re-formulating your cmv into a more objective argument. I agree, my initial response was fraught with cliches. 

The human body is adaptive and is designed to respond to stresses. This is most obvious in physical labor and exercise, in the callouses that form on your hands, the muscles that swell, and the keen reactions that are honed by doing the same thing over and over again. The ache after a hard day's work or workout is a form of pain, but it is the pain born of effort and is a reward in its own right.

It is my belief that mental and emotional effort, while not the same, are similar. We are strengthened and shaped by our experiences, even negative ones.

I'll extend this comparison a bit further: there are physical injuries which improve us, and physical injuries which disable us, either on a temporary if lengthy basis, or on a permanent basis. Some injuries are obvious and easily avoidable (e.g. my earlier cliff diving example). Some are difficult or impossible to anticipate because they are a freak accident or arise from circumstances outside of a person's control.

I think that last category: permanent injuries arising from circumstances outside of your control, is particularly interesting. Your argument hinges upon trying to control your life in order to prevent experiencing the negative consequences of a particular risk. I believe you are incorrectly classifying certain injuries as disabling rather than improving injuries.

These risks are present whether or not you are aware of them and whether or not you are actively avoiding them. You can perhaps lessen the likelihood, at great personal loss of opportunity, but you cannot prevent them entirely.

At some point, regardless of any avoidant behavior, you \*will\* experience loss. You \*will\* experience heartbreak. You \*will\* experience failure.

And in that moment, the avoidant behavior which has previously seemingly served you well will betray you. You can't stop what has just happened, and you will either find yourself woefully underprepared for the task of accepting and recovering from it having not strengthened yourself by overcoming lesser struggles, or you will actually discover that it wasn't that bad to begin with, and you've sacrificed a great deal of the richness of life for nothing.

The strategy that you are advocating isn't the wrong strategy if your goal is to survive life long enough to die. It is however a strategy which will deprive you of so many of the heights and experiences that can make life wondrous. 

Not only will you have missed out on the highs as well as the lows, you will have missed out on the preparatory experiences which allow you to grow. No one becomes successful without failing many times. Their failures aren't obstacles which were keeping them from their ultimate success, but rather the lessons they needed which eventually allowed them to succeed. 

One of those critical lessons is reframing failure from something world ending and ego destroying into something which they can overcome.

Similarly while the heartache of love lost can truly break a person, they can also learn their own strength and worth in those moments.

Failure or loss are only temporary, unless you let them be more than they are.

\&amp;gt; if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure.

If the outcome of the failure is \*perceived\* to be more significant than it is because you've framed it as such, then you can easily make this argument. However as I said at the start, the human body is adaptive and designed to respond to stress. 

If we talk more objective consequences, say putting your house down as collateral at the race track, then yes, I would completely agree that that would be an unwise decision. However when the consequences are emotional suffering, and the severity of their cost is amplified by the anxiety of inexperience, then no, I'd say that the outcome of failure not as bad as you think, and that your ability to cope with it increases with experience.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
