<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="826388770.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/do0dnm/cmv_its_better_not_to_try_than_to_try_and_fail/">
    <title>CMV: It's better not to try than to try and fail</title>
    <original_poster>randomanon43</original_poster>
    <original_post>So clearly this doesn't hold true in all situations because some situations are virtually risk-free/risk are minimal leaving no reason to not try. But for most other situations with moderate to significant risks I'm always hearing that "it's better to to try and fail than to not try at all" or "it's better to have loved and lost than to not have loved at all" or some variation of that expressing a similar sentiment. I think that's absolutely crap to have as a general rule. Sometimes the pain of that failure or that loved loss far exceeds any regret you'd possibly have for not trying in the first place. I prefer to wallow in the "what ifs" than the certainty of ineptitude, loss or impossibility


Edit: so I'm adding one of my comment response to another Redditer to elucidate my views (as a lot of the responses I'm seeing are fairly similar and seem to assume I'm assuming take no risk at all) 


So thanks for such a well thought out response, I'll try my best to do the same tho admittedly I feel you're plagued by cliches (which is inevitable so i'm not berating you for this). 

Firstly clearly I'm not speaking about the extremes as "general rules" tend to break down at these points and these situations must typically be judged on a case by case basis. So situations with enormous risk and situations with little to no risks are excluded from this discourse. So what I'm specifically taking about is the average situations(moderate to significant risk) examples of which included: getting into relationships, applications for positions/jobs, etc (hopefully this is clear now)

Secondly I hope you understand that I'm using " failure" and "loved loss" as expressions of the general sentiment I'm arguing against rather than speaking specifically about failure and loss of loved ones etc (just want to make sure this is clear, not saying you don't understand)

Now what I'm saying isnt that you should avoid all situations that has average risk (remember this is the sphere we are working in, extremes are already exlcuded). That would lead to you doing nothing at all (except for no risk/minimal risk things) What I'm saying is that it is wrong to say that GENERALLY it is better for you to attempt things with average risk than to not. That sentiment is false to me. What I think is true is that everything in this average risk category must be judged on a case by case basis. And if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure. Now i'd like you to note that I think it is up to the individual to chose the threshold necessary for action and what outcome of failure they view as significant. 

So looking at it through this lens, I'm not saying you should do nothing at all or that failure/loss should be avoided at all cost. Far from it, I just think a lot of suffering is unnecessary and is perpetuated by this "it is better to try and fail" mindset that I view is wrong. It is kinda reminiscent of the sunken cost fallacy that many people fall prey to. (I hope I was able to be clear)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32985841244.0" user="ChickenXing" delta="False">
    <text>I don't get why you want to wallow in the what ifs.  What if I don't respond to this thread and change one person's mind?

On multiple subs and threads for example, you hear from a lot of guys who fear rejection from women so they don't take the chance.  Similarly, some people report simply not applying to certain jobs because they might get rejected or someone else is more likely to get an jnterview. I could keep going with other examples.

Fine.  Stay where you are and do nothing.  I on the other hand will seize the moment and ask a girl out who I am interested in.  If I get rejected, I simply move on.  Rejection is a part of life - dating, job interviews, competitions. Elections, etc.  Some of the worst moments of my life is from where I took that risk and failed.  With every failure comes moments where you learn how to deal with these failures, rejections, and lots of other life lessons, including this one which I am passing on to you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
