<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="826388770.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/do0dnm/cmv_its_better_not_to_try_than_to_try_and_fail/">
    <title>CMV: It's better not to try than to try and fail</title>
    <original_poster>randomanon43</original_poster>
    <original_post>So clearly this doesn't hold true in all situations because some situations are virtually risk-free/risk are minimal leaving no reason to not try. But for most other situations with moderate to significant risks I'm always hearing that "it's better to to try and fail than to not try at all" or "it's better to have loved and lost than to not have loved at all" or some variation of that expressing a similar sentiment. I think that's absolutely crap to have as a general rule. Sometimes the pain of that failure or that loved loss far exceeds any regret you'd possibly have for not trying in the first place. I prefer to wallow in the "what ifs" than the certainty of ineptitude, loss or impossibility


Edit: so I'm adding one of my comment response to another Redditer to elucidate my views (as a lot of the responses I'm seeing are fairly similar and seem to assume I'm assuming take no risk at all) 


So thanks for such a well thought out response, I'll try my best to do the same tho admittedly I feel you're plagued by cliches (which is inevitable so i'm not berating you for this). 

Firstly clearly I'm not speaking about the extremes as "general rules" tend to break down at these points and these situations must typically be judged on a case by case basis. So situations with enormous risk and situations with little to no risks are excluded from this discourse. So what I'm specifically taking about is the average situations(moderate to significant risk) examples of which included: getting into relationships, applications for positions/jobs, etc (hopefully this is clear now)

Secondly I hope you understand that I'm using " failure" and "loved loss" as expressions of the general sentiment I'm arguing against rather than speaking specifically about failure and loss of loved ones etc (just want to make sure this is clear, not saying you don't understand)

Now what I'm saying isnt that you should avoid all situations that has average risk (remember this is the sphere we are working in, extremes are already exlcuded). That would lead to you doing nothing at all (except for no risk/minimal risk things) What I'm saying is that it is wrong to say that GENERALLY it is better for you to attempt things with average risk than to not. That sentiment is false to me. What I think is true is that everything in this average risk category must be judged on a case by case basis. And if the risk of failure is greater than chances of success AND the outcome of the failure (if it were to occur) is significant, then it is better to not try than to try it and risk failure. Now i'd like you to note that I think it is up to the individual to chose the threshold necessary for action and what outcome of failure they view as significant. 

So looking at it through this lens, I'm not saying you should do nothing at all or that failure/loss should be avoided at all cost. Far from it, I just think a lot of suffering is unnecessary and is perpetuated by this "it is better to try and fail" mindset that I view is wrong. It is kinda reminiscent of the sunken cost fallacy that many people fall prey to. (I hope I was able to be clear)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32985490449.0" user="funajudora" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure it's meant to be a universal truth in either direction. Like it's better to try skydiving and fail than to not try skydiving? Not many people would make that argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32985586333.0" user="randomanon43" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly I don't think anyone views it as a universal truth (i.e always true) but I feel like most people view it as a general truth (i.e. most times true). Secondly of course no one would make that argument because it's obviously a caricature. A more realistic version of your argument along the  try and fail sentiment is "if sky diving is really something you want to do, it's better you try it out and realize you don't like it/be scared shitless than to let the fear of what could happen prevent you from ever experiencing it at all". And where my argument comes in now would be me saying, no, it's not necessarily better to try it. Because Worst case scenario you die and even if you do survive the experience could be a really traumatic one that haunts you for years. Given that those possibilities exist (as unlikely as they may be), it may be better to forgo the experience completely. There are safer ways to get that high you want to experience (that's a more realistic version of the argument imo)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32985926941.0" user="FriendlyCraig" delta="False">
    <text>I think the sentiment is closer to "If you never try, you can never succeed." Success isn't guaranteed, but if you don't try, you're doomed to lose by default. If you want something, you need to try to get it. You can't expect it to just fall into your lap.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
