<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="82959521.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1de3z5/in_the_israel_v_palestine_conflict_israel_is_by/">
    <title>In the Israel v. Palestine conflict, Israel is by far in the wrong and the US should cut ties with the country. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>ironman2198</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems all that I've seen about the conflict, is Israel either taking over Palestinian territory that isn't rightfully there's, imprisoning innocent Palestinian people, and making Palestine out to be the bad guys.

To me, it seems like all of the violence caused by Palestine is just an attempt to raise attention to their cause. I would necessarily agree with that, but their point is still valid. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26708412243.0" user="moonluck" delta="False">
    <text>"Cutting ties" with a country with Nuclear Weapons doesn't seem like a good idea. Israel is in a very politically volatile time and I would doubt they could get out of this peacefully on their own. I would advocate the US stay on and help settle the conflict as opposed to doing a hands off approach. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708471216.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, lets appease the petulant child. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708695161.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>Israel or Palestine? 

There is no 'good side'  here.   There is no objectively right, both sides have broken law and done inexcusable things. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708827503.0" user="Zeta_Metroid" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah exactly - its not a clear-cut good vs. evil, its bad vs. less bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708987380.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>But one, Israel has done far more especially when measured by the number of people killed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709018206.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>Oh no doubt Israel has killed more people, but that is what happens when "guerrilla war" (I use the term loosely here, but a small, not well armed force uses terror, hiding, etc. to cause trouble for a more modernized one) occurs.  In Vietnam, the US lost many fewer men than the Vietnamese, it just eventually was too much for us.  In Afghanistan, the US's losses pale in comparison to those sustained by Afghan forces.  Comparing deaths is like saying hey, what would happen if a platoon of army rangers went up against a group of WWII soldiers.  Of course the rangers would have fewer losses, they are stronger, they are better armed.

Or better yet, here's a comparison: I am inside a tank.  You are a guy with an AK-47.  You start shooting me.  I ignore it, eventually it gets annoying.  Finally I shoot back, once, you are now dead.  That's just how much more advanced Israeli weapons are.  For every Israeli death, there are hundreds of failed attacks by Palestinian forces.

Now, that isn't to say that Israel is blameless, but comparing death toll is *stupid.*  It is a misleading statistic that doesn't look at the type of war that is being fought.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709029588.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, who gives a fuck about dead Palestinians. Right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709057205.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>Because that's exactly what I said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709067530.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>Well, you treated the deaths as just statistics, abstract concepts that you can treat with almost no respect. Doing this allows you to maintain the bias in your head which makes Israel the victim. 

I treated your comment with the same respect as you showed those killed in the conflict.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709079169.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>What bias? 

Is me saying "Israel is not the victim" enough proof? Or are you going to assume that because I don't share your opinion equating Israel with the devil that I'm some zionist superjew? 

Yes, I treated them a statistics. You did too. Name someone who has died in Palestine that hasn't been taken up by the media, and without using Google, and I'll cede the point to you willingly, but until then, they are just as much a statistic to you as me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709081517.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I used them as a statistic, no I don't know their names. The difference, you said their deaths aren't important to the discussion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709091776.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>No I didn't, I said the statistic you used was biased. There is a difference. The fact that people are dying is atrocious, but using misleading and inflammatory statistics doesn't help fix that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26709168535.0" user="VelvetOnion" delta="False">
    <text>A death is a fucking death, I don't give a shit about land ownership on either side. I just want less people die. 

Btw you said it was 'stupid', it conveys an attitude which is pretty callous.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
