<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="82959521.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1de3z5/in_the_israel_v_palestine_conflict_israel_is_by/">
    <title>In the Israel v. Palestine conflict, Israel is by far in the wrong and the US should cut ties with the country. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>ironman2198</original_poster>
    <original_post>It seems all that I've seen about the conflict, is Israel either taking over Palestinian territory that isn't rightfully there's, imprisoning innocent Palestinian people, and making Palestine out to be the bad guys.

To me, it seems like all of the violence caused by Palestine is just an attempt to raise attention to their cause. I would necessarily agree with that, but their point is still valid. 

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26708311400.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about that area, that in the 20th century alone, the ownership of the land changed about 4 times, depending on the specific area in question. At first, the Ottomans ruled, lost it to the British, then it was split between Israel and Palestine, with Israel gaining more and more over time.

Now I'm not going to argue the ethics, instead I'll focus on US since you brought up their support. US exists on lands that historically belonged to someone else. So did Canada. Through treaties that were forgotten or invasions, both countries grew.

Now barely anyone challenges the notion of American or Canadian territory. It is a standard that the countries with the existing boundaries exist. And the same can be said for people all around the world. 

So tell me, including historical context of how modern boundaries have been drawn up, what is Israel doing that nations in the past haven't? What defines land "rightfully theirs"? The fact is, and it is a really sad fact, that the weaker side almost always loses. The Palestinians with their rockets and suicide bombings have alienated western support, giving ammo to the Israelis to continue doing what they are doing. They are losing the war of perception themselves. 

One small hitch in the whole thing. With the Jewish Israeli population growth slowing down to a crawl, while the Arab Israeli population growth skyrocketing, it'll lead to an interesting (and hopefully not bloody) show down in the decades to come.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708372670.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It is a known fact that more Israelis die per year from peanut butter allergies than from Palestinians </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708431420.0" user="poorfag" delta="False">
    <text>That's because of Israel's massive defenses though, not because of lack of trying on the Palestinian side. Iron Dome, huge concrete wall in the borders, checkpoints, blockades and bomb shelters literally in every single house. While Palestine not only has nothing of the sort but actually hides its missiles in the middle of civilian towns. 

Before 2008 there wasn't a single year without suicide bombings. Think the Boston bombing every single year, with multiple bombings almost every year (reaching the hundreds in 2001). So only three people died in Boston, does that makes it acceptable? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708477642.0" user="uncannylizard" delta="False">
    <text>The Palestinians are denied political, social, economic, political, and human rights and their situation deteriorates every day that they are under Israeli oppression. They have no military capacity to speak of because of because of the siege on Gaza and the complete control over the West Bank by the Israeli military. 

Now you are saying "they should play fair and put their military installations away from civilian areas" or "stop targeting Israeli civilians and fight the Israeli army". In the world that the Palestinians live in, as soon as a military installation is separated from a civilian area it is destroyed. As soon as a militant attacks an Israeli soldier or army base he or she is killed inevitably with no chance of success. So what you are really saying is "stop fighting for your rights". 

We can't pretend that the Palestinians have the luxury like the Israelis do of choosing how to conduct their violence. They have no choice. Its either continue to be oppressed, colonized, and exploited, or fight back by the only means available. Gandhi, of course, would agree with you that the Palestinians should accept their fate. He actually recommended to the Jews to not resist the Holocaust and offer themselves to the Nazis. Of course the occupation of the Palestinian territories is not the same situation as the holocaust, but the principle is the same. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708702955.0" user="poorfag" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Now you are saying "they should play fair and put their military installations away from civilian areas" or "stop targeting Israeli civilians and fight the Israeli army". In the world that the Palestinians live in, as soon as a military installation is separated from a civilian area it is destroyed. As soon as a militant attacks an Israeli soldier or army base he or she is killed inevitably with no chance of success. So what you are really saying is "stop fighting for your rights". 

So what are you saying, that every Afghani/Iraqi person has the right (no, not the right, the duty) to bomb, kill and maim American civilians inside of the American mainland because they can't fight the US army that is occupying and killing them? Because the analogy is perfect

&amp;gt;We can't pretend that the Palestinians have the luxury like the Israelis do of choosing how to conduct their violence. They have no choice. Its either continue to be oppressed, colonized, and exploited, or fight back by the only means available.

There's a third choice: accept that you lost the war you declared and go for peace. Read about the Camp David negotiations that Arafat refused (I am on my phone and I can't quote it), for Palestine there are no such thing as negotiations and getting anything short of 100% of their claims is unacceptable. If Israel is lucky, Hamas for example doesn't claim the land after the 1967 war, Hamas claims ALL of Israel and has sworn to fight until that day comes. Which would be pretty funny if it wasn't for the fact that Palestinians die because of that retarded ideology. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708767058.0" user="uncannylizard" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So what are you saying, that every Afghani/Iraqi person has the right (no, not the right, the duty) to bomb, kill and maim American civilians inside of the American mainland because they can't fight the US army that is occupying and killing them? Because the analogy is perfect

There are two ways of looking at this question. The first looks at what is justified, the second looks at what will actually deterministically happen. 

If we are talking about what is justified, the Palestinian situation is not at all akin to the situation in Iraq or Afghanistan. The Americans in Iraq set up a consociational democracy that has not infringed upon the rights of its citizens. They have essentially devolved power to Kurdistan, and have a division of power between Sunnis and Shia at the central level which prevents the oppression of the Sunnis. The primary insurgencies against America there were an attempts to reestablish the dictatorial Ba'ath party and other groups tried to establish an Islamic state with Taliban-esque oppression. The bombing of American civilians to further those ends is clearly unjustified. We are no longer occupying the country and when we did we did not exploit or oppress any groups. We transitioned the government to self-rule as soon as was practical. In Afghanistan the Taliban wants to rule through authoritarianism, theocracy, and oppression. They have no grounds by which to lodge complaints of deprivation of rights by the Karzai government or its American backers. 

In Israel, however, we have a situation where an ethnocratic regime is denying rights to an ethnic group. They refuse to give them representation in the Knesset and they refuse to allow them to have viable self-rule. The Palestinians are being deprived to just above subsistence level in Gaza, and in the West Bank there is a whole manner of exploitation by means of claiming water rights, claiming land rights for settlers, flooding the markets with Israeli goods, denying them utilities and having Israeli companies provide them, having routine checkpoints between every city, disallowing them from having an airport, taking prisoners and denying them trial, shooting at protesters, defending and facilitating settlers who kill and terrorize Palestinians, and many more things. Every manner of rights is routinely violated and the Israelis block any attempts to allow the Palestinians to pursue their liberation by political means. This is not analogous to America's involvement in Afghanistan or Iraq in the slightest. 

If you want to leave the question of the morality or justification for resistance, there is the plain fact that resistance is inevitable. The PA in the West Bank has no capacity to stop their people from committing crimes against Israelis. In Hamas, they have official militants, but they also have a whole manner of private militias who oppose Hamas' ceasefires and fight on their own against Israel. These groups will fight for as long as Israel is systematically oppressing them as other oppressed people have done throughout history. 


&amp;gt;There's a third choice: accept that you lost the war you declared and go for peace. Read about the Camp David negotiations that Arafat refused (I am on my phone and I can't quote it), for Palestine there are no such thing as negotiations and getting anything short of 100% of their claims is unacceptable.

The negotiations at camp david, just like in Oslo, began with Palestine giving up all its claims to historical palestine and renouncing violence as a means to end the struggle. The palestinians walk into the talks with no leverage, and every minute that there is no deal, the Israelis take more and more land through settlements. Israel in Camp David demanded 10% of the West Bank with no land swaps and only gave very limited control over East Jerusalem to the Palestinians. In addition, it denied that the Palestinians had right to return and instead offered a donation box that Israel and some other nations would contribute to. It did not seriously consider what it means to have the right to return and it did not consider what level of compensation would be required to buy the right of return from the Palestinian refugees. These refugees fled their properties and land and live with very few rights in neighboring Arab countries. The Israelis didn't recognize that fact at all. 

Now about your claim that the Palestinians are unwilling to give less than 100%. The Israeli perspective sees it this way because the Israelis already have everything they want and made the Palestinians give up all their bargaining chips before they got to the negotiating table. Then the Israelis basically said 'make it worth my while' and demanded far more than historically had been formally complained.

Imagine if there were two armed men fighting over a treasure chest and one side made the other side give up their arms and claims to 80% of the treasure before starting to negotiate. Then the armed man said "okay, lets start negotiating. What are you going to give up to us in order for us to make peace?" and then declared another 20% was needed. That is what is happening in this situation. And each time they enter into negotiations the Israelis take more and more of the treasure and claim that the new 'reality on the ground' should be the starting point in negotiations. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708656449.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No , killing innocent people is not acceptable. 

http://www.ifamericansknew.org/stats/deaths.html


But using white phosphorous bombs on the most heavily concentrated area in the world, with 50% of its population being under the age of 18, is most definitely not acceptable. 

Cutting off humanitarian aid, turning it into an open air jail cell , is also not acceptable </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708652880.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>And the Boston Bombing killed 3 people. Yet due to the type of act, those 3 deaths, and 100+ injuries received more attention then drunk driving. Even though drunk driving kills so many more, and in my opinion, a bigger threat to human life than terrorism in the US. 

It's about optics. Believe me when I say that I agree with your sentiment about the dangers Israel is facing (or lack thereof). But I think you need to be pragmatic. What Palestine has done and is continuing to do just isn't working. They cannot win their own cause alone, and every time a bomb explodes in Tel Aviv, the Israelis can play the victim again, getting even more sympathy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708472225.0" user="uncannylizard" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So tell me, including historical context of how modern boundaries have been drawn up, what is Israel doing that nations in the past haven't? What defines land "rightfully theirs"? The fact is, and it is a really sad fact, that the weaker side almost always loses.

Yeah, and the American's used to own slaves so who are we to judge slavery right? The fact is that we have the capacity to recognize right and wrong even if we benefited from a wrong that happened a century ago. The Palestinians aren't asking for pre-1948 borders. They gave up on that a long time ago. They recognize the reality of the situation and have conceded that issue. They are trying to maintain some semblance of what is left of their land in the West Bank, Gaza, and East Jerusalem, about 20 something percent of the original land and none of the most valuable land. Right now Israel is refusing to negotiate a two state solution that is remotely acceptable to Palestinians while expanding settlements on palestinian land. Since the Oslo Accords the settler population has grown by millions through state funded immigration and through funded high birth rates. The settlements could not exist and grow if the Israeli state did not provide education, transportation, utilities, welfare, and security to these settlements. Now Netanyahu and his partners such as Naftali Bennet are planning an eventual annexation of the settlement territory, East Jerusalem, the land between the West Bank and Jordan, and giving the Palestinians "municipal autonomy" rather than citizenship of Israel or Palestine. Not only Gaza and the West Bank would be separated and not allowed to have airports, but the West Bank would also be bisected and towns would be isolated and connected through special roads with checkpoints. And none of this even comes close to finding a deal for the millions of refugees who are being denied a right of return or compensation for their refugee status. 

The point is that we aren't discussing a historical injustice that needs to be reversed. Nothing can (or should) be done about that. The problem is the ongoing colonization, exploitation, and oppression of the Palestinian people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708665542.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'll be blunt about this. What you said is boring. You know what makes the news? Pretty Israeli girls on the beach. Bombings in Tel Aviv showing a bus that could like it's in any other first world country, and it sends a chill up the spine of a western viewer. And finally, a video of Arabs celebrating on the streets, screaming death to America, death to Israel. 

That's what matters to people. Who looks friendly, and who looks scary. Why should anyone in the West give a damn about Palestine over other unfortunate people across the world, ones who don't chant death to America? Facts are boring, sensationalism is fun and entertaining.

Countries, including the US understand the value of propaganda. They've been trying to use that technique in Afghanistan with leaflets and such. The British use BBC World News in various different languages over radio to get a British perspective of the world across, including Iran where BBC is banned. 

As I said before, the stronger side has always won. Palestine cannot win this using bombs and bullets, and every time they try, Israel can fight back 10 fold and get away with it. If they don't try a different tact, they won't have any land to defend. They need to make their issue relatable to the powers that can pressure Israel. The problem that you've mentioned is a valid one. Now talk about a solution. But whatever that solution is, be realistic about it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708478416.0" user="Shoofy" delta="False">
    <text>It is true that United States citizens and Canadians have benefited from policies that modern-day society thinks of as immoral. That, however, does not justify the continued use of imperialist or expansionist policies. 

Furthermore, I don't think the rockets or suicide bombings are the reasons for low US support. I would instead point to the power of the Jewish lobby and the US need for an ally (especially with nuclear arms) in the Middle Easy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26708673167.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing ever justifies the use of continued use of imperialist or expansionist policies. But it has worked quite effectively before, so as long as no one is saying anything on the contrary, why stop?

Again, try to remember that this isn't a playground where everyone has to play fair and nice. This is the world, where "Nice" just doesn't exist. The only way a country ever stops fighting for more land is because it's just not worth their time/effort/resources. Not because it's unjust.

I know my comments might show otherwise, but I do support Palestine alongside Israel, as an independent nation. But Palestine does not have the military might to fight back. The only thing it can use is getting attention, the right kind of attention. The kind that will make people call their elected representative and demand a change. I don't see any other way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
