<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83215424.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1djlfk/i_dont_think_manslaughter_or_any_crime_committed/">
    <title>I dont think manslaughter or any crime committed accidentally should be considered a crime. At all. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>theconstipator</original_poster>
    <original_post>If it is proven that the offender had no intention of committing a crime, why should they be persecuted because the odds were against them? 


EDIT: Ok, many people have used the example of "what if a person is driving drunk and they kill someone?" I still think they should only be punished for driving drunk.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26710826196.0" user="sidekick62" delta="False">
    <text>We punish "accidental" crimes when the person who committed them was acting in a reckless manner. For instance, if you are driving while intoxicated and you kill someone, it's reasonable to assume you didn't *mean* to kill them. However, the fact that you were intoxicated means you didn't take reasonable precautions to *avoid* killing them. On the other hand, if you're driving responsibly and a little kid unexpectedly jumps out from behind a car and you kill them, you're likely to avoid punishment because there was no way you could have avoided the accident.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710844858.0" user="Purpledrank" delta="False">
    <text>Yet the OP is still right, you are still charged with a crime regardless. He says that it shouldn't be considered a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710856261.0" user="sidekick62" delta="False">
    <text>More of a formality for the justice system to work... the trial provides the proof that you weren't acting in a reckless/irresponsible manner, and therefore are not responsible. Manslaughter and other charges for unintentional crimes exist to punish reckless behavior... it prevents people from being absolved of responsibility by simply saying "I didn't *intend* for the consequences of my actions to happen." </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710921383.0" user="dowcet" delta="False">
    <text>I actually think the drunk driving example raises a bunch of problems for the OP that need to be addressed.

Is it still an accident if you are being reckless? If I accept the validity of the OP, I'm not sure if that means drunk driving should be legal, or not, and if it's illegal, whether the punishment should be identical regardless of whether you harm someone or not. It would be helpful to clarify these implications.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710970507.0" user="arewar" delta="False">
    <text>I think in the specific case of drunk driving, the driver broke the law against drunk driving, and breaking that law caused him to harm another person. So in that case, while the driver didn't intend to harm another person, he knew he was inviting those risks by breaking the first law.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711050963.0" user="Purpledrank" delta="False">
    <text>Yes that is a crime in progress. Similar to the difference between breaking and entering and burglary. Where one is just entry, the other is entry with the intent to commit a crime such as theft.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711065270.0" user="GoldandBlue" delta="False">
    <text>But he had no intention of committing the greater crime. Based on OP's post, the driver should only be charged with a DWI. He never intended to kill anyone, it was an accident. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711104308.0" user="arewar" delta="False">
    <text>But he committed a great act of negligence that he knew had the likely potential of resulting in that.

If I run around with a giant bowl of acid and spill it on someone, am I not responsible? Do you not expect me as a potential victim to take some basic steps to ensure public safety, like having a lid on the bowl or not be running?

There is a certain amount of responsibility we expect from grown adults. It's generally referred to in my area as common sense. When you put people in danger due to your own stupidity then you should be responsible for all crimes resulting in the stupid act.

There is a massive difference between killing someone in a car wreck due to drunk driving, and killing someone in a car wreck because a deer ran in front of you, or bad weather conditions, or a broken stoplight. Etc

Also see purpledrank's comment regarding a "crime in progress".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711113135.0" user="GoldandBlue" delta="False">
    <text>I am playing devil's advocate here because OP is MIA. But the death was an accident, he had no intention of killing anyone. The drunk driver did commit a crime and should be charged for the crime of DWI, but any deaths were an accident.         

Not saying that I agree with the stance but that is the conclusion I draw from it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711306127.0" user="arewar" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that but I addressed that point in my previous comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713229521.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So presumably, for the deterrent effect to remain, DWI would be charged much more severely in this world, whether an accident happened or not.

But people commit minor acts of recklessness every day which *could* result in severe consequences; we would have to start charging everyone for every conceivable bad result of any action they make. E.g., if I J-walk, a cyclist I didn't hear could swerve to avoid me, falling in the path of a truck who could slam on the brakes, causing a piece of rubble from their truck to roll onto a train track, causing the derailment of a train carrying dangerous chemicals, killing hundreds of children in a nearby playground. So, I would have to be charged with the potential deaths of hundreds of children every time I J-walked, whether anything actually happened or not. 

Or alternatively, if we decide that the sentences should be proportional to the likelihood of a bad outcome, we would have to give every murderer a get-out-of-jail free card by accepting that playing Russian-roulette with their victims isn't nearly as bad as shooting them with a fully loaded gun. "There was only a 1 in 6 chance of me shooting him! I should only get 1/6th of a life sentence!". Of course, what the defendant didn't tell the court in this case was that this was the 4th time he'd played Russian roulette this week, and they would never be able to prove that he had done. If you want to kill someone and only get a week in prison, just get a gun with more chambers and covertly fire at them over a longer period of time!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711712034.0" user="dowcet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; he knew he was inviting those risks

But it's still an accident, isn't it? If you think that drunk driving ought to be illegal, then you have to admit that you care about regulating people's actions because of the consequences, not just because of the intentions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711754636.0" user="arewar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But it's still an accident, isn't it?

Honestly in my opinion, it's not. An accident to me is something that happened by a random chance of events that were not in a person's control. 

A drunk driver put themselves in that situation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26711799924.0" user="dowcet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; An accident to me is something that happened by a random chance of events that were not in a person's control.

But how do we evaluate what is and is not in a person's control? for example some people drive, and some people don't drive. The people who don't drive, all else being equal, are far less likely to kill someone in an accident. Therefore, I might argue, the people who do drive should be punished. Otherwise, you either have to a) rather arbitrarily determine an acceptable threshold of risk to say that driving is not above the threshold of recklessness or b) prove that driving is never a choice and always a necessity of life. 

So the question I am raising then is: why exactly is driving drunk a crime and driving sober not? I think it is based on the (likely) outcome rather then purely on the intention, and that's how it should be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26712097924.0" user="arewar" delta="False">
    <text>This seems to me like you're making a huge reach to try to make an argument and already know the answer.

As it's been said before, it's due to common sense and negligence. People who drive are not being negligent unless their car hasn't been properly serviced/inspected, unless they don't have insurance, unless they are not legally allowed to drive, etc. None of these points are arbitrary, they are logically and usually already in the law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26712745263.0" user="dowcet" delta="False">
    <text>But defining the law purely on the concept of "negligence" is always going to be more subjective then defining it partially on that and partially on what actually occurs. 

If intention is all that matters, I can pretty much always say "well I didn't know" or "I didn't mean to", at least if it's a first time offense, and you can't prove me wrong. If I say it wasn't my intention, I know better then you do. But when you can say, "well look what happened", it's much more clear-cut and objective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710990194.0" user="NeilNeilOrangePeel" delta="False">
    <text>But you wouldn't be charged with 'accidentally running someone over', the crime you would be charged with is vehicular manslaughter or something similar. Then they'd have to demonstrate that you were negligently operating a vehicle.. in other words, it wasn't purely an 'accident'. So if you really do accidentally cause someone's death and you weren't negligent in any way it is already not a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
