<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83215424.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1djlfk/i_dont_think_manslaughter_or_any_crime_committed/">
    <title>I dont think manslaughter or any crime committed accidentally should be considered a crime. At all. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>theconstipator</original_poster>
    <original_post>If it is proven that the offender had no intention of committing a crime, why should they be persecuted because the odds were against them? 


EDIT: Ok, many people have used the example of "what if a person is driving drunk and they kill someone?" I still think they should only be punished for driving drunk.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26710886674.0" user="ezen" delta="False">
    <text>Can you imagine the number of people that would get away with murder just by making it look like it was an accident? And I don't mean in the "make it look like suicide" thing but all you'd have to do is prove that you guys were bodies looking at a gun together and then **BOOM** he's dead. But as long as you had no one to refute your testimony that it was an accident you'd get away free?

Seems like the road to anarchy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710892452.0" user="alecbenzer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Can you imagine the number of people that would get away with murder just by making it look like it was an accident?

Wouldn't you expect this to be comparable to the number of murderers who currently get murder charges replaced with manslaughter charges? Do you think this is currently an issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26710897801.0" user="ezen" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not really concerned with that as much as I am saying that manslaughter wouldn't exist anymore. There's a difference between saying "We can't get you for murder in the 1st degree because of lack of evidence so we're going to give you a lesser murder charge" and "We can't get you for murder in the 1st degree so you're free".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
