<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83464473.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1doxll/i_believe_that_prayer_does_nothing_to_change_the/">
    <title>I believe that prayer does nothing to change the world. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>waterbluesky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Prayer as an act of reaching to a deity for help or comfort has no appreciable effect beyond what can be achieved by normal positive thinking.

Praying to end world hunger or to get a job has no effect unless you or someone else makes the decision to achieve the goal. These goals could also just as easily be achieved without prayer.

Edit: I do not believe in the non corporeal nature of prayer. I do believe in the effects such as positive thinking giving someone a better understanding of who they are a what they can do.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713295078.0" user="Quetzalcoatls" delta="False">
    <text> Prayer isn't designed to directly change things but give people the strength to accomplish things themselves or set into motion the events that would allow them to do so.

Obviously this could change based on religion but the goal of prayer isn't to just "change" things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713310924.0" user="AlexReynard" delta="False">
    <text>Not true. http://bible-truth.org/msg54.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713465177.0" user="Tadhgo" delta="False">
    <text>Funny how he's replied to other replies but not this...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713317389.0" user="waterbluesky" delta="False">
    <text>Where does this strength come from or what sets something in motion? From what I understand the strength and the change is supposed to come from within as well as something from outside. The inside I can understand the outside or Deity part I do not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713335696.0" user="Quetzalcoatls" delta="False">
    <text>The strength comes from God and it is him who changes events. If you don't have faith though its very difficult to understand this though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713339108.0" user="waterbluesky" delta="False">
    <text>And that is why I am asking. I really would like to understand. Being able to understand what he does or does not do and how someone can see that in the world is mystifying to me. If I could understand prayer better I am hoping it will help me understand my religious fellow man.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713377310.0" user="Joined_Today" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you don't take a religious view of it, the placebo effect is very powerful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713470357.0" user="Tadhgo" delta="False">
    <text>'The strength comes from God' Which one?
'...changes events' - What events? I'd like one example where prayer was proven to change something.
'If you don't have faith though its very difficult to understand this though.' Nope. Circular logic doesn't work. You can't have the power of prayer as a premise when this is what you are trying to prove. We should believe in it based on evidence and logic rather than what tribe colonised my country thousands of years ago. 

Presuming rightly or wrongly you are Christian, you would more than likely believe in a different form of prayer were you born in Saudi Arabia or Jamaica.

If you want to change the view of people who don't believe that prayer works you're going to have to explain the intricate ins and out of it. How are the thoughts transmitted? Radio, TV, the internet can all be explained so why can't you explain prayer?

This might come across as passive-aggressive but i'd genuinely like answers. However, if you can't explain any of the 'science' behind prayer, why do you believe in it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713590937.0" user="DeZWIJGER" delta="False">
    <text>Let me google that! I bet the Internet has some interesting answers.

I think we can all agree that what we believe is dependant on our belief systems. Doesn't matter what your belief systems are-- Gnostic, Christian, Taoist, Atheist, you name it. Yup, even Atheists have a belief system!

So what IS a belief system, exactly? Well, according to Wikipedia...

&amp;gt; A belief system is a set of mutually supportive beliefs. The beliefs of any such system can be classified as religious, philosophical, ideological or a combination of these. Philosopher Jonathan Glover says that beliefs are always a part of a belief system, and that belief systems are difficult to completely revise.

Cool. Even though the entire article proceeds to become a Jonathan Glover fapfest, we got what we came for: an approachable concept. Let's talk about what the above statement means for me and you, though.

I have a certain perspective on the world around me at large. I have spent my entire life adjusting this world view as new experiences and information come to my understanding-- but each successive idea/experience comes to me through the filter of what I already know or have seen... or been told. With time, I become steadily more biased. That might mean there are certain people I trust as sources, more than others. It might mean that there are certain pieces of literature I value and others I disregard. It also means some people can read a bible and a biology textbook back to back and find both spiritually and emotionally edifying. It's about perspective. Your mileage may vary.

Do you know what Cognitive Dissonance is? Here's the layman's version: when something comes along and challenges my beliefs, my brain is built to revolt-- because otherwise, everything I know would fall apart. Why? Because my beliefs are all linked, and if you tug on any point on a string, the whole string moves to align itself, accordingly. That can be disruptive.

This subreddit is DEDICATED to this concept, actually: changing belief systems one idea at a time, no matter where they were founded.

Which is why I found your question so out of place.


**TLDR: Once upon a time, science told people that blacks are inferior human beings. People accepted the idea because it aligned with their beliefs. There are things in the so-called Good Books which are harmful, and some that are helpful. People take what is useful to them and move on. We are collectors.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713400084.0" user="Fairchild660" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Prayer isn't designed to directly change things but give people the strength to accomplish things themselves 

Then how does this differ from positive thinking?

&amp;gt;...or set into motion the events that would allow them to do so.

And how would it do that? If it's by influencing the mindset of the person praying, again; how does this differ from positive thinking?

If it's by changing facets of objective reality, then the statement's demonstrably false. A myriad of studies have been done into whether prayer has any effect on patients recovering from surgery. Some show a slight positive correlation; others a slight negative correlation; most show none. Overall, the studies show prayer has preformed no better than chance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713406686.0" user="Quetzalcoatls" delta="False">
    <text>You're ignoring the element of faith though. On a technical everything you say is right. However people pray because they obviously believe in a God. They clearly believe praying affects their outcome in life. You see "just positive thinking" and they see "an act of god". This clearly makes prayer valuable to believers and distinct from just thinking. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713474875.0" user="Fairchild660" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They clearly believe praying affects their outcome in life.

This thread is discussing the actual impact of prayer. Whether or not someone believes it to be more effective than positive thinking has no bearing on reality. It either is or is not.

On the other hand, perhaps you're asserting that the fact prayer is believed to have an objective effect - while positive thinking is acknowledged as a mental stimulus - somehow makes it a more potent motivator. In that case, the claim is unsupported.

&amp;gt;On a technical everything you say is right.

-

&amp;gt;You see "just positive thinking" and they see "an act of god".

So prayer does not influence objective reality, but those who pray believe it does. That would make the only difference between prayer and positive thinking the fact that people who practice the former are deluded.

I don't see that as a valid distinction when discussing the real-world effects of prayer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713482531.0" user="Tadhgo" delta="False">
    <text>'You're ignoring the element of faith' - Yeah, because when you are logically evaluating something you take 'faith' into account.

Well there seems to be no evidence that wearing white socks reduces the likelyhood of cancer... You're ignoring the faith element.

Your homemade remedy has not been shown to improve the patient...Youre ignoring the faith element...

I could go on. The faith element is irrelevant. Believing something doesn't make it true.  Using faith as an argument is fallacious on so many levels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713489215.0" user="Quetzalcoatls" delta="False">
    <text>You're applying logic to an area of research that you shouldn't. Logic isn't why people believe in a God. 

You clearly are not a man of faith. You aren't looking at this from the perspective of one with faith. You see statistics and they see the results of prayer.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
