<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83464473.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1doxll/i_believe_that_prayer_does_nothing_to_change_the/">
    <title>I believe that prayer does nothing to change the world. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>waterbluesky</original_poster>
    <original_post>Prayer as an act of reaching to a deity for help or comfort has no appreciable effect beyond what can be achieved by normal positive thinking.

Praying to end world hunger or to get a job has no effect unless you or someone else makes the decision to achieve the goal. These goals could also just as easily be achieved without prayer.

Edit: I do not believe in the non corporeal nature of prayer. I do believe in the effects such as positive thinking giving someone a better understanding of who they are a what they can do.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713747425.0" user="Faith32" delta="False">
    <text>I was taught that if you want to change anything you have to work for it. That my praying will do nothing if I do not act. Now when I pray for God to make something right I don't pray for Him to snap His fingers and resolve the issue. I pray so that I can be granted the strength to make things right myself.

Now for you and some others this might just be an example of wishful thinking or positive thinking. I believe that I was given the strength to continue fighting despite the circumstances. Now I can't prove that this came from a God, but that is what my faith tells me. 

So if you're saying that prayer alone does not and will not ever solve anything I agree. But I don't think that anyone is ever taught that prayer alone will solve anything (I might be wrong so please correct me).

Now you also say that "reaching to a deity for help or comfort has no appreciable effect beyond what can be achieved by normal positive thinking", so I'll tell you what my mother taught me. When someone is going through hell and they fight and work to make it better, sometimes it seems like no one cares. When someone feels like that and they wake up at 3 in the morning what can they do to make the situation better? It's the middle of the night and they feel as if they have been left to rot, so they pray to God (or another deity). When they pray maybe they feel like they aren't alone, like there is someone who cares about them. That regardless of how bad their lives are or how bad it will become they aren't really alone. That the pain they feel now means something, that it isn't useless. 

Praying to end world hunger will not do anything if that is all we do. We must act to end things like that, but it will be a long process. There will be many people who will die and suffer in the meantime. Those of us who must do something to change the situation watch as innocent people are hurting. And coupled with the obstacles that we must face it can be easy to lose hope and despair. For some the belief that those who have died will go to a better place, and that our prayers will do good for them in the hereafter, helps. We can move forward and continue the fight. 

I would say that the good done by prayer is a subtle one. Anyone who thinks that all they need to do is pray to make things better is being naive or lazy. And people who think that prayer is useless unless it offers an immediate solution to a problem, are to quick in dismissing something I don't think they understand. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
