<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83498388.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dpnro/i_believe_that_the_death_sentence_should_be/">
    <title>I believe that the death sentence should be automatic after a second serious offense and first time offenders should spend almost all of their sentence being educated. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Ozoning</original_poster>
    <original_post>Title says it all. would be glad to discuss with anyone. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713727847.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So here's what criminal law, and some experience has taught me: 

It's almost impossible to define your "serious offense." Murder (the unlawful killing of another), in many jurisdictions, has many layers: 1st degree, 2nd degree, Manslaughter, Negligent Homicide, the list goes on. Each is an unlawful killing. Is each a "serious offense"? Probably. But there is a huge potential difference between 1st degree murder (someone who intends to, plans and commits a murder) and negligent homicide (someone who is assaulted, but improperly uses deadly force under the belief they are acting in self defense.) 

You also mentioned assault below. Assault is a threat of injury, battery is actual injury. Assault with a deadly weapon, for instance, would be someone pulling out a gun and telling you to give them your money, or they'll shoot you. If you live, battery would be them shooting you (and the DA would probably spin it as attempted murder.) Regardless, under your rule "assault with a deadly weapon" might be a death penalty offense. 

Finally, each state in this country controls it's own criminal code. In California, people find themselves charged with a felony for simply stealing a certain $ value of goods. In olden days, felonies were all punished by death, but modernly there's a whole plethora of felonies that are non-violent, and labeled felonies due to the length of their sentence. They vary from state to state, so a national death sentence for felonies would be kind of crazy. 

Finally, there is no way to create a "truly blind" justice system, like you hope. In every courtroom, there are jurors and lawyers, and a judge, and witnesses, and all of these people's actions determine the outcome of the trial. There will be bias, emotion, confusion, inspiration and despair regardless of where you put that courtroom, or who you put in the juror's chairs. That's the reason why I admire trial lawyers - the best ones have an inexplicable gift of both manipulating information, conveying ideas to jurors and seeking justice for their clients. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
