<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83498388.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dpnro/i_believe_that_the_death_sentence_should_be/">
    <title>I believe that the death sentence should be automatic after a second serious offense and first time offenders should spend almost all of their sentence being educated. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Ozoning</original_poster>
    <original_post>Title says it all. would be glad to discuss with anyone. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713701479.0" user="Kush5150" delta="False">
    <text>What is the purpose of the death penalty in this situation, deterrent or 'getting rid of a problem'? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713714630.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see fear as an effective way to run a society, so I don't believe I'm saying it would deter people. Getting rid of a problem would suit my case a but more. saving the government money by not having to pay for his sentence and not being worried of another offense coming from the individual. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713729095.0" user="Kush5150" delta="False">
    <text>How can you be so sure that the convicted is *really* guilty. Your idea of bringing in people from other countries is just not feasible. People can and will *believe* things no matter what. There is an inordinate amount of time that experts spend on the witness stand explaining that a real crime scene investigation just doesn't work the way they see it on tv. 

Herd thinking is another factor you'd have to deal with. Not being related to the case doesn't effect basic human psychology. Ruthless prosecutors who ignore evidence that proves innocence and coerced confessions happen now!(see west Memphis three) 

The death penalty, which [costs](http://www.amnestyusa.org/our-work/issues/death-penalty/us-death-penalty-facts/death-penalty-cost) more than life imprisonment makes murders of us all not just the state. The state is there to represent the people. The state murders, the people murder.  Lethal injection(the most commonly used method is the U.S.) is known to be [cruel and unusual](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lethal_injection#Research).

The research states, **"In 2005, University of Miami researchers, in cooperation with an attorney representing death row inmates, published a research letter in the medical journal The Lancet. The article presented protocol information from Texas and Virginia which showed that executioners had no anesthesia training, drugs were administered remotely with no monitoring for anesthesia, data were not recorded and no peer-review was done. Their analysis of toxicology reports from Arizona, Georgia, North Carolina, and South Carolina showed that post-mortem concentrations of thiopental in the blood were lower than that required for surgery in 43 of 49 executed inmates (88%); 21 (43%) inmates had concentrations consistent with awareness.[46][47] This led the authors to conclude that there was a substantial probability that some of the inmates were aware and suffered extreme pain and distress during execution. "**

Do you think that you are okay with putting even **one** innocent person through that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
