<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83498388.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dpnro/i_believe_that_the_death_sentence_should_be/">
    <title>I believe that the death sentence should be automatic after a second serious offense and first time offenders should spend almost all of their sentence being educated. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Ozoning</original_poster>
    <original_post>Title says it all. would be glad to discuss with anyone. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713701304.0" user="RebelLumberjack" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with the death sentence is that you are giving a person or a body of people power over someone's life. You are giving someone the power to decide whether a person lives or dies. This power should never be given to anyone, for fear that it can be exploited or otherwise misused. I don't care if you plan to use that power on bad people, the concept at its core is twisted. It's usage can be twisted. If the definition of serious offense changes or if the governing body changes, what happens? There is always room for exploitation so why risk allowing someone to exploit the power of life and death?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713712549.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>I've always felt that an effective way to combat corruption and exploitation of something of that caliber would be to have a variety of people that have nothing to gain from the person dying or not. For example, if someone were to be a representative and be asked to take part in the trial, something like a salary that would be publicly stated and the ability for anyone to see his expenses and riches would help. once we know there is no reason a person would sway in a certain direction, we could have a fair trial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713721956.0" user="RebelLumberjack" delta="False">
    <text>I do not believe that any system could ever be fully un-exploitable. Your system can be exploited out of court as well, simply by changing what the government sees as a serious offense. Also you are giving the average person the power to decide whether a person lives or dies. I do not trust the average American with that power either. Hopefully a group of unbiased people will make the right call, but consensus is not always right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713734894.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>No, definitely not an average joe. specially not an American (fellow american here.)  But outside of a general consensus what is there? Trust me, I completely understand the faults in a systems where people have a say in it, but I just don't see any other way to handle it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26714235202.0" user="RebelLumberjack" delta="False">
    <text>Well here is where we differ. The only way I could justify allowing that power is if we had a fully fault proof system. But I also believe that that is impossible to achieve. Maybe I'm idealistic, but this is life and death here.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
