<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83498388.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dpnro/i_believe_that_the_death_sentence_should_be/">
    <title>I believe that the death sentence should be automatic after a second serious offense and first time offenders should spend almost all of their sentence being educated. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>Ozoning</original_poster>
    <original_post>Title says it all. would be glad to discuss with anyone. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26713655325.0" user="lobe44" delta="False">
    <text>So you believe in the death penalty to show people that killing is bad. OK got it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713683535.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>You're kind of assuming I do. if you kill a serial killer, or a serial rapist or whatever the case may be, you manage to get rid of a menace to society. it's not a senseless killing in part of the government. I wouldn't consider it teaching that killing is bad by killing, It's just a government that does what's best for its people.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713693700.0" user="lobe44" delta="False">
    <text>Well how does any one man or government decide that one persons life is worth less than another? Then there is the question of how do you determine beyond any doubt that the person is indeed guilty of the crimes you are accusing them of. Before the 1970s hangings and executions were a lot less regulated and hundreds of people were executed who were innocent. 

And even after the 1970s when capital punishment became MUCH more regulated at least 30 people from then to about 2010 have been released from death row because of new evidence showing they were not involved in the way they were accused of being involved or were not involved at all. 

And don't get me started on the cost of maintaining these special areas strictly for the worst of the worst criminals on death row. The cost of your average prisoner is about 50-60 grand a year, this is not including court costs so it is in reality much more than this. Now imagine that cost times 10 and you might get close to the cost of housing your average death row inmate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713705624.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>I will admit that i am ignorant of how death row inmates are kept as opposed to the general population. Why does the cost rise? I understand there are flaws in the justice systems, but they can be fixed. I believe that it's not one person deciding the fate, it should be a communal subject, discussed by chosen representatives of each contributing party. Refer to the my response to jake63 as to one of the ways I feel we would be able to fix the current system</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713712342.0" user="lobe44" delta="False">
    <text>Well first of all Death Row Inmates are all kept in solitary, meaning they all have rooms of their own. This adds to the cost of housing them, add in the fact that these are all considered the worst of the worst so the security precautions are much higher. Death Row Inmates may spend upwards of 30+ years on death row exhausting all potential evidence, it is not a quick process by ANY means. 

Also just because an opinion is popular does not make it right or truthful. This is where democracy fails; a poor decision chosen by a mob is still a poor decision. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713732671.0" user="Ozoning" delta="False">
    <text>What would be a better solution for it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26713777142.0" user="lobe44" delta="False">
    <text>No death penalty. Less focus on incarceration. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
