<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83951695.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dzdjj/i_believe_that_the_population_of_the_world_needs/">
    <title>I believe that the population of the world needs to be reduced drastically by any means necessary. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>gotagood_shirt</original_poster>
    <original_post>Devils advocate post, but really, in an era of an overpopulated world, peak oil, accelerating climate change and ever rising food prices, what other options are out there?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26718173249.0" user="Osric250" delta="False">
    <text>One of the fundamental laws of nature is that a population will rise to push the limit of current food supplies. We see this everywhere in nature and as we're at the top of the food chain the only limiting factor is the amount of food we can produce.

Even if we were to kill off a large number of people in a few generations we would be right back where we started. This is why world hunger can never be solved as the population will keep growing as long as food is the only limiting factor.

A lasting solution would have to be some other sort of population control but we are very bad at imposing those and any we chose would likely be disregarded completely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718183873.0" user="gotagood_shirt" delta="False">
    <text>Good answer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718200033.0" user="Osric250" delta="False">
    <text>I should clarify that the law of nature will always rise to meet the first limiting factor that it encounters. This is generally a combination of food per area and predators. The number of predators is regulated by their food supply, the prey, and the predators that they have.

The other major limiting factor is space, but that's generally lumped in with food per area since area is part of the equation. No matter how many people we pack into a tiny area the population will expanse until it hits a limiting factor.

Since humanity has no natural predators to keep our number down and since we've learned to produce and transport our own food area is no longer a factor and now we are purely limited by the amount of food that we can produce.

As our agriculture gets better we are better able to supply a larger population using a smaller area for food production. But inevitably we always hit the cap and because of that we can no longer continue to grow.

To create an artificial predator (which is what killing off a part of the population is) to be successful it would have to be a continuous application. Unless we plan to continue systematically killing off the excess population this is a band-aid and doesn't fix the actual problem. Since most people would be thoroughly offended and entirely against a reproduction limit (ex: China and they're 1 baby law) the only real limiting factor we have to keep the population in check is how much food we produce.

If you want the population to stay under control I suggest you find a way to keep agriculture from developing further.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
