<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="83951695.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1dzdjj/i_believe_that_the_population_of_the_world_needs/">
    <title>I believe that the population of the world needs to be reduced drastically by any means necessary. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>gotagood_shirt</original_poster>
    <original_post>Devils advocate post, but really, in an era of an overpopulated world, peak oil, accelerating climate change and ever rising food prices, what other options are out there?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26718176254.0" user="King_Kookie" delta="False">
    <text>We aren't overpopulated? I read that the entire world's population could live in Texas with the same living space as people of New York City. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718181774.0" user="gotagood_shirt" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah but how much food can be grown in New York City? Enough to feed everyone who lives there? Doubt it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718186287.0" user="King_Kookie" delta="False">
    <text>Whoa, who said anything about only the population in Texas as being habitable? We would still have the rest of the world for agriculture and production.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718202915.0" user="Osric250" delta="False">
    <text>And for how long? And that's just population itself, that doesn't include industry or agriculture or any of the things that we require as a population to survive. Those things are what take up most of the space on our planet.

All of those things require space. A lot of space. And while we could pack tighter and open up a lot of space in this world how long would that last? 3 generations? 5? 10? Eventually we would end up right back where we are now and we wouldn't be able to condense anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718623362.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>California would be capable of producing enough food to feed the planet if space and resources were utilized properly. If we could organize ourselves properly it would not be hard to maintain a population even several billion people larger than our current one, the only things that really get in our way are logistic issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718833792.0" user="Osric250" delta="False">
    <text>That number seems inaccurate to me. Depending on the type of food produced different amounts of space are required and if we're forced down to only eating a couple types of food have we really done ourselves a favor? The goal is not only to cram everyone together but also to keep quality if life up.

Food is merely one aspect and is nowhere near the only thing that needs to be produced. A large portion of our land is covered by industry. All of that industry is required to one extent or another. We could condense that too but again we're only delaying the inevitable. Since no matter what we do we're going to max out our supportable population we might as well do it earlier where we can keep most people with a high quality of life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718842718.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>It's mostly vegetable matter and relies on vertical farming techniques, but the numbers are correct. If you really want varied food, we would have the entire rest of the planet to develop other foods we wanted.

There are 57.5 million square miles of land on the planet, if we only need a little over 400,000 square miles of land to cover housing and necessary food we aren't exactly strapped for space to sustain industry and take care of "luxury" requirements for food (meaning beyond dietary necessity in this case). As I said before, it's a logistics problem not an actual sustainability problem. We have what we need, it just needs to be deployed appropriately.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26718621883.0" user="phoenixrawr" delta="False">
    <text>This is correct. For those interested in the math:

Assume living space of 2,500 sq ft with no vertical housing (i.e. we don't stack people's homes on top of one another). There are (5,280^2 ) = 27,878,400 square feet in a square mile, so we could have (27,878,400/2,500) = 11,150 homes per square mile. There are 268,581 square miles in Texas, allowing for (11,150 x 268,581) = 2,994,678,150 homes in the state of Texas. If we assigned 4 people to each home, we could house 11,978,712,600 people which is nearly 5 billion more than we currently have.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
