<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719686266.0" user="elusive_muse" delta="False">
    <text>The difficult part about Christianity and "rules" is oftentimes in churches, followers of Christianity are taught that while there are two "books" in the Bible (Old/New Testaments) that the Old Testament is considered "null and void" for the most part since Jesus' sacrifice "tore the curtain" separating the Holy of Holies from the common man. Therefore, logically, one would surmise that the rules and governances of the world of the Old Testament would no longer apply, and that the principles based in Jesus' teachings should be the new foundations for the "Christian" religion (bear in mind, the laws of the Old Testament are actually "Jewish" laws, seeing as Christ himself was a Jew and Christianity did not come forth until his ascension). So to hold a modern day "Christian" to any rules pre-dating the New Testament would be factually inaccurate, seeing as those rules are in fact, for the Jewish community prior to Jesus' birth. Jesus himself broke many of the Old Testament rules (thus instigating his eventual arrest and crucifixion) and thus to imagine that the rules on women's rights, or clothing, or what to eat or not eat would apply any longer would be inaccurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719694829.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I find it very disappointing and frustrating that we cannot hold a Christian to the rules of the Old Testament, yet a Christian can hold others accountable for crimes according to Old Testament rules. How many Christians quote leviticus, and Genesis, and Exodus, while the OT itself is null and void to Christianity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719715085.0" user="mysanityisrelative" delta="False">
    <text>Many people have a very poor understanding of theology leading them to not understand the implications. 

Many other sects hold to some of the tenants of Judaism.

Many others want to justify what they already do.

There are a *lot* of different kinds of Christian. Don't let the loudest make you think they are the only ones.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
