<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719379865.0" user="pezz29" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

So what about the Christians who were given the task of deciding which bits of scripture were canon then? What about the Christians who disagreed with their assessment? What about the Christians who weren't invited to the councils?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719382631.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>This argument will be slightly more challenging without exact passages from the bible in front of me, but are there really bits in the bible that are "rules that must be followed" that are left up for that level of interpretation? Should debates of which bits of scripture were canon not be left to the parts of the bible that were just storytelling? Or are there that many rules that aren't as blunt as "women cannot speak in church, and cannot hold a position of authority over men"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719383625.0" user="pezz29" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This argument will be slightly more challenging without exact passages from the bible in front of me, but are there really bits in the bible that are "rules that must be followed" that are left up for that level of interpretation?

There are like, 20 gospels that one of the councils decided just weren't canon, because frankly they weren't very good. I mean gospels were just written by random people. It's not like Jesus himself dipped his pen in the ink. So whether they 'commanded' Christians to do anything isn't particularly relevant. I'm not even Christians and I could 'command' Christians to do all sorts of things if I wanted. Doesn't mean they're theologically obliged to listen to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719388222.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I've always heard that a Christian is someone who accepts Christ as their lord and savior, and accepts the authority of the Bible. I understand the gospels have been debated on their canon relevance and the council got to pick and choose what went into the bible, but here we are in the end with... a bible. The bible that Christians claim to accept the authority of. The relevance of the canon has already been debated in the past and here you are with your holy book to which you claim to follow, and claim has authority. Christians then, after saying "yes, the bible is correct and I follow the authority of the bible and it's teachings" (especially the ones that can be quoted saying they believe and follow it "cover to cover") will still be able to believe and not believe the bible? follow and not follow it? Does every Christian who practices their religion do so with some sneaky fine-print? Yes, you can command someone and they may not listen, but these are the people who claim to be listening. They say they're listening to something that's already been debated, to something they've already claimed has some divine authority. And yet they still refuse to follow the rules set forth in the very first book of the New Testament! This is why I say that they are liars, and not true Christians. "Yes I follow, but not actually."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719502590.0" user="pezz29" delta="False">
    <text>If you're explicitly saying I follow *this* version cover to cover then yes I agree with you. But a lot of people don't and just because a guy with a funny hat says they should doesn't mean they aren't Christian. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719562438.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Then what does make them Christian? Or as I've been trying to word it, what makes them a "true Christian"? It can't be argued that there's no such thing because comparatively there are certainly people who really are fake Christians. The ones that take the name but do absolutely nothing to honor the tradition.

Also, I don't believe what you say about people following "*this* version cover to cover" has any value because... They don't. Every Christian who follows a certain interpretation of the bible is still rejecting many other parts of it. Many of them haven't even read the other parts, only the ones they were told to read. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
