<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719365063.0" user="talondearg" delta="False">
    <text>No Christians of this sort have ever existed. Even within the New Testament you see that Christians do not read the Bible in this kind of flat way, where it is just a bunch of rules that everyone must follow. The problem here isn't that no christians have ever existed of the sort that you suggest are real, it's that no Christians have ever recognised the kind of belief system you are suggesting is in fact Christianity, so no wonder they have never followed it.

Your post should be "As not-a-Christian I believe no one who fits my belief of what Christians should be has ever existed", because your understanding of Christianity does not correspond to any historical situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719370086.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>It's always bothered me that there's also never been *one* Christianity, just a plethora of cliques that all preach the same book. I just have trouble with the idea that someone can claim to take something so seriously, "cover to cover", and disregard such a vast amount of the content. What is "Christianity", if any sort of blanket description can be applied to the many conflicting groups, if not a religious bunch that follows the teachings of their own book?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719373177.0" user="talondearg" delta="False">
    <text>I think the question of diversity in Christianity is another question.

By your standard neither Jesus (who breaks the Sabbath) nor the Apostles are Christians, because they interpret the Old Testament Law as fulfilled in Jesus, and Peter breaks the OT dietary code. So I think either your view is moot - there were never Christians of the kind you suggest; or it's invalidated because your view of what Christians are is not related to any historical understanding of Christianity at all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719379642.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Then the question would stand as "what is a Christian, if not someone who truly follows the Christian Holy Book?"

Jesus was a Jew who broke Jewish law, through him Christianity was born, he was certainly not a Christian himself. Christians are, by my understanding of the definition, people who follow the Holy Bible and subscribe to the "Christian faith". My argument stands that Christians do precisely not that, and quite possibly never have, because they don't take the "authority" of that holy book (which is God's word) seriously, and follow only the parts they like and ignore the rest. Because of this, I argue that by definition, they are not "true Christians". So if you're not following the authority of your own holy book, what makes you a true Christian?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719383273.0" user="talondearg" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, here's your argument put in other words though:

Christians are those who follow the Holy Bible as a set of eternal commands that must be obeyed regardless of context and theological understanding.

That's the only way you get to a position where the list of things you put in your original post...
&amp;gt; I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church

...is a definition of how to read the Bible. 

Christianity has never functioned with that kind of interpretation. Even within the New Testament this is true. Paul's teaching is consistently that the OT Law is fulfilled in Jesus, and so no longer *functions in the same way* for Christians. That's why Christians do not object to cotton/polyester blends, and are free to eat pork. 

A better definition of a Christian, from a not-strictly-theological kind of angle, is that a Christian is someone who accepts the Bible as authoritative and seeks to follow it with a consistent and cohesive interpretation. 

This isn't about 'picking and choosing' - that is, honestly, an outside stereotype of the kinds of processes going on in Christian interpretation and application of the Bible. To be fair, some people are picking and choosing, but that is reflective of the majority of Christian traditions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719609603.0" user="paalmsread" delta="False">
    <text>The Bible really is not the word of God in the first place. Not many Christians actually believe it is, unlike the Islamic Hadith.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719818482.0" user="dave35" delta="False">
    <text>Christians have defined themselves somewhat consistently (with a few minor quibbles) using creeds that summarize the boundaries of Christianity. The simplest and best known is the Apostles' Creed, from about the second century. Christians disagree about many things, including how they ought to read the Bible, but mostly agree on fundamental ideas about Jesus. It is sensible to define Christianity as what Christians say it is (as a whole, historically) rather than what you think Christians ought to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719379139.0" user="FallToParadise" delta="False">
    <text>The thing about the guidance the bible, or any religious text, gives is that it isn't always clear, and can seem contradictory. The interpretation of this is what becomes important, and people are never going to agree on the interpretation. 

There is no such thing as a universal 'true christian', someone that would be accepted by everyone who follows the faith because every time someone reads it they see something different. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719710051.0" user="elusive_muse" delta="False">
    <text>You have to keep in mind that followers of religion are still HUMANS. We all can look at one color and argue about its shade. Taking a book as controversial as the Bible and expecting everyone who believes its worth to preach it in the same way with the same lines and definitions is just unrealistic. And yes, Christianity is an "umbrella" term... further delineated into "Protestant" and "Catholic" and then the delineations continue from there. Such is true with every other religion--people are going to believe THEIR interpretation of anything. To imagine that any content would NOT being disregarded in some way, shape, or form, is again--unfortunately--unrealistic.
I commiserate with your point, however. I wish there was a far more clear and evidence-based definition of "Christianity".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719411314.0" user="Kush5150" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, yes these christians have existed and it was called the dark ages. The crusades and the inquisition were true expressions of christianity if you read and follow the rules of the bible. Moderate christianity, like moderate islam is a perversion of the actual teachings of the holy texts. Read them. All the horrible and malicious things that people talk about are in them. People who pick and choose which parts they want to follow and call themselves"moderate" are only fooling themselves. Moderate interpretations come about because of secularism and the seperation of church and state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719416780.0" user="talondearg" delta="False">
    <text>I've read them, thanks. I'm also quite familiar with the history of the crusades and the inquisition, neither of which occurred in the so-called dark ages, a period of history that has more to do with barbarian migration and economic collapse than the rise of Christendom. 

I do not consider the Crusades a true expression of Christianity, largely because of the following features: (a) the nationalist identity of Israel in the OT is not reflected in the NT with a new national identity, but a trans-national body of Christians, whereas the Crusades constructed Islamic societies as the "other" in contrast to Europe as Christendom (b) it is difficult to construct a doctrine of just war out of the NT, despite significant attempts to do so; the Crusades were pitched as such, (c) the promises and values of the Crusades reflect a marriage of medieval nobility-ideals with theological values, in which I belief Christian imagery and metaphor was co-opted against its original intents.

If you want to continue this line, please provide a specific example of something that happened in these periods (I don't need a specific historical event, but at least a kind of behaviour), that you think is derived from the Bible.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
