<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719434136.0" user="ghebert001" delta="False">
    <text>Well, there's the Westboro Baptist Church...they're a bunch of hateful bigots, but they follow the bible more closely than anyone I can think of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719459536.0" user="SGDrummer7" delta="False">
    <text>Matthew 22

37 Jesus replied: “‘Love the Lord your God with all your heart and with all your soul and with all your mind.’[a] 38 This is the first and greatest commandment. 39 And the second is like it: ‘Love your neighbor as yourself.’[b] 40 All the Law and the Prophets hang on these two commandments.”

While they may follow the law, they fail at the love your neighbor part.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719621650.0" user="mysanityisrelative" delta="False">
    <text>As they see it they are loving their neighbor. If you sincerely believe that someone is going to burn in hell, isn't the most loving thing to do to try to get them to repent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719672552.0" user="SGDrummer7" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but there are more loving ways than "God hates fags" which is also untrue. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719712911.0" user="mysanityisrelative" delta="False">
    <text>I don't agree with them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719780316.0" user="SGDrummer7" delta="False">
    <text>Me either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719932723.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>"God hates faggy behavior" perhaps? Sure the terminology is *far* from politically correct, but the sentiment? Wasn't there a whole deal with that city where everyone loved butt-sex and then got nuked? Obviously I'm not well versed in this, but that story is pretty famous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719985303.0" user="ghebert001" delta="False">
    <text>So I guess like anyone else, they pick and choose but mainly the bad parts whereas most people pick and choose the good parts and maybe mix in a few of the bad. Either way you look at it the bible is full of contradictions and was clearly written by men and passed off as the word of god to control the poor and uneducated which at the time was just about everybody.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
