<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719492470.0" user="Ausfall" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, but, this is [fallacious reasoning](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/No_true_Scotsman).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719641605.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Well, this is no true Scotsman. Please tell me what the definition of a true Scotsman is, that I might escape this fallacious reasoning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719735700.0" user="hellosquirrel" delta="False">
    <text>Ausfall literally linked you to the definition. You had to click it to discover the term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719748588.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I know I was linked to the definition of fallacious reasoning, and I learned something new today. But I am still asking for someone to Change My View. Make me throw away my idea of a true Scotsman with a better understanding of the relevance of any form of truth in the argument of Christianity and the people who are following it. Don't worry, I'm getting quite close - loving the feedback I'm getting from a lot of the Redditors here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719807159.0" user="Ausfall" delta="False">
    <text>You're defining what you believe to be a Christian, and then accusing those who claim to fall under that word as not being "true" to what you think they should be.  You're assuming that your definition is absolute and that those who don't adhere to it 100% aren't really a part of it.

You're saying...

kyrostolar: "No Christian works on the sabbath."

Christian: "But I work on the sabbath."

kyrostolar: "No *true* Christian works on the sabbath."

---

You're assigning traits to people that aren't necessarily true and by extension you're ignoring what actually makes people Christian, which is that they attempt to follow or otherwise emulate Christ's teachings.  That is the only thing that makes anyone a **Christ**ian as opposed to another religion.

Also as a side note, all of the instances that you give as conditions for a Christian reside within the Old Testament, which many believe to be secondary to what Christ says in the New Testament.  I think most sane people can agree that their spirituality isn't a strict and rigorous prescription right from the pages of their holy texts word-for-word.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719839800.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the argument I've been making and thank you for showing me what a fallacious argument is. I only gave instances of Old Testament law as an example as the bible as a whole with some of its now ridiculous rules, and keeping in mind that though Christians do not like to follow Old Testament, they (some) still like to preach it. It can't be denied however that there is some similarly unfair rules in the New Testament that are also rejected and ignored. I still personally hold to the view that Jesus is a character in a book, as this book describes him to modern people far more than the man himself, should he have existed and was who the Bible and every Christian claims him to be. Being that Jesus is a character in a book who teaches the messages in that book, as an outside party it seems wrong to say that you follow the New Testament and its teachings when you don't. That is of course implying that it should be followed to a T. I'm beginning to understand now that the Old and New Testaments as a whole are almost irrelevant to Christianity, and are only the class textbook, not the lesson.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719870186.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Δ</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
