<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719609702.0" user="FeministNewbie" delta="False">
    <text>A little explanation on what the Bible is: the Bible is a collection of texts written by many people, for many different reasons, over 800+ years. Imagine if you gathered philosophical texts from 1200 until today into one big manual: those texts can contradict each others, and we use modern knowledge to discriminate the great ideas from the wrong one. In this example, a college of philosophers has revolutionized philosophy in the 1920-1950 and constitutes the last texts ("the Evangiles"). 

It makes no sense to believe *all* the texts, or to dismiss them all. Descartes' work has been discredited but some of his words are still important today. Similarly, Christians will trust Jesus over what is said in the old Testament. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719638513.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I know the Bible is a collection of stories and texts over many years. Let me ask you this then: What would you consider a true Christian then? If the Bible has been changed and translated so many times already, why hasn't anyone made a new bible that completely removes the parts that "don't apply" to their version of the beliefs? What is modern Christianity, with the religious text they subscribe to being manipulated so much over the years no one knows the original texts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719654884.0" user="FeministNewbie" delta="False">
    <text>We have a good ideas of what the original texts are, thanks to old sources such as the [Dead See Scrolls](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dead_Sea_Scrolls) and numerous academic researches on the topic. 

I'm returning you the question: would you in a field of knowledge exclude previous works as they have been disproved, even if these books mix correct ideas with wrong ones, even if these books have invaluable historical value, even if these books are about telling stories and not "the truth"? 

Should we ban every book mentioning creationism as being right, every book supporting slavery, every book arguing that the Earth rotates around the Sun, that the Universe doesn't expand or is contracting ? Wouldn't loose ton of knowledge in the process? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719679898.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>I've read many fictions and taken value from their pages while knowing that they are as a whole, a fiction. Those books were just stories for the sake of stories though. Is a Holy Book really a collection of stories, and not a claim for "the truth"? I've yet to ever hear otherwise, even with many of its stories disproved.

We certainly shouldn't ban these books in my opinion, as we would lose a ton of recorded knowledge, even with much of this 'knowledge' as a whole being false. Yes, I see your point. But again, these aren't about telling stories, are they?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719687989.0" user="FeministNewbie" delta="False">
    <text>Some parts. The correct telling of what happened is now thought to start with Abram. Stories before that are tales to explain the world (Adam&amp;amp;Eve, the Babel Tower, etc.). 

And history (for these ancient folks) wasn't focused on getting the exact truth. It was about telling the world, communicating values and ideas, creating a perception of an event. Even so, many parts of the Bible match in term of what we found of history (which is remarkable). 

What matters in term of Protestant faith is that Jesus is the son of God (even just spiritually) and that he resuscitated. Other elements are considered very important, but aren't as crucial. 

Jesus tells parabels (which of course didn't happen), but they teach ideas and concepts. That's what matters. And if the concept is shitty, we're still free of not following it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719927190.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Jesus tells parabels (which of course didn't happen), but they teach ideas and concepts. That's what matters. And if the concept is shitty, we're still free of not following it.

Can you clarify this? I was under the impression that following the teachings of Jesus was paramount?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719984008.0" user="FeministNewbie" delta="False">
    <text>Christianism is a huge religion with many different trends. And even interpreting the text is up to tons of debate. Aside from that, it differs. My protestant church follows Jesus' teaching but certain texts (especially the parabels), have very complicated meanings. 

I like the parabel of the workers ([read here](http://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Matthew+20&amp;amp;version=NIV)). At the end, the boss pay workers from last arrived to first arrived, and pays everybody the same amount. What does is mean? One of my pastors argued that he did so so that the first workers would be reassured to know that everybody won enough money to eat. Other interpretations exist and are valid. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26720003980.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>Complicated message indeed! I had to think for a minute what such an ending really implies. I can't say I agree with your pastor's interpretation, but then again, my own isn't very positive. I haven't gone very deeply into the parabels, but I can see how they can be widely (mis?)interpreted in a variety of ways. Thanks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26720579839.0" user="FeministNewbie" delta="False">
    <text>This interpretation was the result of 50+ years of working as a pastor. So yeah, interpretation isn't easy or unique, we can simply try to do our best and take responsibility for our actions. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
