<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719485087.0" user="TheophilusOmega" delta="False">
    <text>Before I start I should note that I am a Christian, just so you know where I am coming from. It's late for me so I'm not going to include references, I can get them to you in the morning if you like, but in the time being take my word for it that they are there.

I think the problem is that your definition of what a Christian is has some built in assumptions that are somewhat, well, misinformed. Most any Christian will agree that the essence of being a Christian is that you believe that Jesus is the one and only true God. Everything else in Christianity is built on that. It is because a Christian believes in Christ, he or she will be inspired to trust and obey the Bible. In your perspective a Christian is someone who believes and adheres to the Bible. The difference is subtle, but it is important. I should note here that there are many examples in the New Testament of people putting their faith in Christ without any prior knowledge of any part of the Bible (in fact much of it had yet to even be written) so first Christ, then the Bible.

The short version of your argument is that a real Christian would follow the Bible to the "T" or else they are no Christian at all. Well that is the problem with Judaism, but not Christianity. The Old Testament has several books of law that the Jews tried and failed to keep in totality. In fact the most devout Jews even made up extra-biblical laws to prevent themselves from accidentally sinning but it was all in vain, not one person could keep the entire Law for their whole lives. This is where Christ comes in, Jesus' role, in part, is to forgive sinners for breaking the law. Because no human is able to keep the law everyone must go to hell, unless someone who hasn't broken the law (Jesus) can take their place. So those that Christ has forgiven are no longer bound to the Law because their debt is paid for. Now Christians are no longer bound to rules, but are still to follow to principals. For example instead of the Old Testament law specifically commanding us not to murder, the New Testament principal is to love your enemy. It would be impossible to murder someone if you love them, the desired outcome is the same, but the method is different. There are some that take freedom from the law to mean they have a license to sin, and there are some that make up extra-biblical laws to prevent straying from biblical principals (we call them legalists), both extremes are preached against in the Bible. You are essentially taking the position of a legalist by insisting that Christians follow every word of the Bible at every moment, when the reality is that God Himself doesn't expect that, which is why he offers grace and mercy in the first place. A Christian should certainly do everything possible to follow the Bible, but sins will be forgiven. Christianity is more about following the spirit of the Law, Judaism is about the letter of the Law. Again, Christ first, then Bible.

A problem with deciding what to follow, and not to follow is that there is so much open to interpretation in the Bible. For starters keep in mind that the Bible is very, very old, written in ancient languages, by and to people of a very different culture, and in another land; understanding and translating it can be a massive challenge. Keep in mind that there are many genres of literature in the Bible from something as clerical as Law and genealogies, to poetry and prophecy. There are personal letters, history, advice, parables, sermons, love songs, and philosophy, each to be read with a different lens. On top of that each of the 66 books also has a target audience and it can be difficult to determine whether an instruction was meant just for them, or for everyone in all time. Think about how hotly debated the Second Amendment is; it seems so clear and simple but apparently it is not. In America we have the Supreme Court to settle differences in interpretation, but there is no such body in Christianity. So one preacher may read a passage and conclude X, another Y, and a third Z. This may appear like picking and choosing which parts they like and which parts they want to ignore, but in reality each is trying to understand and obey the text in they way they think is most accurate. The good thing is that the Bible allows this; Paul acknowledges that these differences will arise but instructs Christians to not let is affect our unity (whether or not this actually happens is a different topic). So the Bible has a lot of room for interpretation causing two different Christians to exercise their faith in two completely different ways, while both are following the Bible. 

Specifically addressing the examples you gave: Christians have no official Sabbath, it is a tradition borrowed from Judaism. Piercings and tattoos are never forbidden in scripture, that is mostly. Mixed cloth blends are only forbidden to Jews following the Law, not a Christian. Same-sex relationships are pretty clearly considered wrong, but I have read some scholarly works that claim those instances to all be mistranslation. Women speaking or teaching in church is hotly debated on how to apply this and whether Paul is making a universal rule, or a suggestion to one specific church.

Basically all of this is to say that a Christian is someone who follows Jesus, not someone who follows the Bible.

If you need clarification on anything let me know, it's past my bedtime and things can get fuzzy in my brain at these hours and I didn't proofread much. I hope this clears things up a bit</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719671403.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Almost missed this comment in my inbox, wish I had seen it sooner. My struggle and frustration was mostly with the armies of Christians I've seen arguing the laws of the bible. Making claims that "the bible says this, and it must be so!" and yet they themselves completely reject, and refuse to acknowledge the existence of several other laws/rules/etc that they themselves break, be it OT or NT. Westboro Baptist Church being an extreme case to use as an example, I suppose would be considered legalists as well then, do seem to try to follow the bible to the letter and treat all of it as law. Funny how strict 100% adherence to The Good Book makes you the most hated bunch around. That said, with their strict adherence to the religious text in which they follow, I figured they'd be the closest thing to a "real Christian" you could find. I also understood that people could "accept Jesus" with minimal to no knowledge of the Bible, but he is a character in the book. Jesus is a story, and the Bible is what tells it. Whether he was a real man or not, now he is a memory found in a book that has been mistranslated and manipulated for centuries.

Can it not then be said that Jesus and the Bible are necessarily hand-in-hand for Christianity, and one should not come first? A Christian cannot acknowledge the Bible and subscribe to Christian faith without accepting the message of Jesus, but you also cannot really subscribe to the faith through Jesus without actually knowing his story. It can be reasonably argued that the miracles of Jesus in the NT were only recorded by those writing it. No other philosophers or historians in that age record anything of the sort occurring in that time. It's because of this that I believe Jesus *is* the NT, and the NT is Jesus, as far as worship is concerned. They are absolutely necessary to each other. I know some people might not like the analogy, but there is little evidence for the existence of Christ *as told in the stories*, outside of the stories themselves. Jesus is to the New Testament what Harry Potter is to Harry Potter. The character exists in common knowledge, but short of a little hearsay, the character is absolutely meaningless without the story they're written in.

With all that said, my struggle is now really sitting on:
&amp;gt;Basically all of this is to say that a Christian is someone who follows Jesus, not someone who follows the Bible.

How is this reasonable as a Christian? Am I wrong that the character and his book are necessarily connected, and therefore equally necessary?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719789401.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How is this reasonable as a Christian? Am I wrong that the character and his book are necessarily connected, and therefore equally necessary?


The Bible wasn't written by Jesus. It basically nothing else just a collection of stories, to show you one way to be a better man/woman (this is poor wording, as you can be a good man without being a Christian but you get the idea). You don't have to follow it word by word. This is, where churches like the Westboro have gone in the wrong way. It isn't even the full story of Jesus. There are many known [Biblical apocrypha](http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Biblical_apocrypha), some which can be found in [Copt bibles](http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copts) others in [Ethiopian bibles](http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christianity_in_Ethiopia) and some people believe that, yet others are buried in the Vatican. The point I'm trying to make is, the Bible is not a unified book with strict rules but a guidance. Everyone has to find their own way because everyone is different.


Edited the links.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26720005230.0" user="TheophilusOmega" delta="False">
    <text>It is pretty widely considered historical fact that Jesus did live, how much of you believe is up to you. Considering the fact that Jesus was constantly followed by crowds shows that there were many witnesses to almost everything he did, it would be pretty hard to fabricate such unlikely stories if there were thousands of witnesses declaring the opposite. Even Jesus' fiercest antagonists at the time (the pharisees) never claimed any of his miracles or actions to be lies, they knew they happened, they just claimed he did them by powers of the Devil and not God. I should also point out the Roman historian Josephus did make note of Jesus. You can [read about it here](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Josephus_on_Jesus), check out the Testimonium Flavianum section in particular. It isn't much, but there is at least some acknowledgement of him by a non-Jewish/Christian at the time. Also notable is [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mara_Bar-Serapion_on_Jesus) and [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tacitus_on_Christ).

Now about your question, Christians believe in Christ as a living, loving, relational God, not merely a character in an old book. Some of our knowledge of Jesus does come from the Bible, but being a Christian means knowing Jesus on a personal, and spiritual level, not just book knowledge. You should know that Christians cite the ultimate author of the Bible to be God, who used men to actually physically pen the text, but the message is still from God. Now, you or I may really like Mark Twain and we could read all of his books, and the books written about Samuel Clemens and his books, but when it comes down to it we don't have a personal relationship with Mark Twain. Sadly, Mark Twain died long before we were born and we never had a chance to meet him. The difference between Mark Twain and Jesus is that Jesus is still alive, resurrected and alive. Because Jesus is still alive we can have a personal relationship with him, reading his books (the Bible) is a good way to understand more about him and his desires for us, but as we see with Mark Twain it is no substitute for a true relationship. A Christian is someone who knows Christ personally, the Bible just helps us to know him better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26720042549.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Good analogy, thanks. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26719869950.0" user="kyrostolar" delta="False">
    <text>Δ</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
