<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719433974.0" user="hodsonc" delta="False">
    <text>I am a "strong atheist". 

I recently went on an "Alpha Course" (see [here](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alpha_course) for more info). I did this to *try* to keep an open mind about what Christianity was and what in means to it's adherents. I will never believe it, but that doesn't mean I can't try to understand it, right?

It worked. In a room of 20 Christians, I learned that they all had very different faiths. Some believed verbatim in Adam &amp;amp; Eve, others did not. Some thought that Noah's Ark was a real event, others didn't. Some thought that when Jesus said "X" what he *really* meant was "Z", other thought is was more like "Y". Were any right while others were wrong? 

They all had one thing in common. They were all trying to find a way to tie up how they thought about the teaching of Christ, with what the bible tells them and how they feel connected to their God. Sometime these strands resulted in "Challenging feelings" and sometimes left them with "feelings of love and peace" in their hearts.

In the end, we all try to make our "model dependent world view" tie up with how we feel and what we know.

No one ever said that St Peter would be at the gate with a tick list. One of the great appeals of Christianity is that you can *always* be forgiven. Did you truly love God and Jesus in your heart? Then you are by "definition" (but not necessarily by action) a Christian. There is no such thing as a "real Christian", and there **never has been**,  but there are 1.2 billion people who self define themselves as "A real Christian".  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
