<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84074433.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1e208x/i_believe_real_christians_died_out_centuries_ago/">
    <title>I believe real Christians died out centuries ago, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>kyrostolar</original_poster>
    <original_post>That is to say, if real Christians ever existed in the first place. If you are a Christian, you must follow the teachings of the bible. You must follow the teachings of Christ. A real follower of any religion should follow that religion, not pick and choose what bits interest them. As soon as you can say "this works" and "this doesn't", you're not following the rules!

I believe anyone who works on the Sabbath, has piercings or tattoos, wears cotton/polyester blends, has a same-sex relationship, allows a woman to teach, or allows a woman to speak in church, etc. And says they're a Christian is lying.

I am certainly not saying that anyone should actually follow these rules, but I am convinced you are simply being dishonest if you call yourself a Christian, or a member of any religion, without following the rules that were clearly put out to you under that religion. Anyone that chooses to nit-pick the parts of their religion that they choose to follow is nothing more than a deist with a book they like. You are not a follower unless you are a follower!

Update: Between /u/TheophilusOmega and /u/Ausfall my view has changed. I feel the easiest way for me to word this is my analogy that the Bible is not a rulebook to Christians, but a textbook. They don't follow it to a T because they don't have to. Jesus' teachings is the lesson, and the Bible is the textbook in which his teachings and the Biblical historical relevance is told. Assuming that a Christian must follow the rules of the Bible exactly, else they are not a 'true' believer, is fallacious reasoning as shown by /u/ausfall, and between the two of them I've learned what actually separates following the Holy Book to following the Religion itself. I feel the points were put across strongest and clearest by these two Redditors, but thank you to everyone else who contributed.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26719654169.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>The bible itself talks about false claimants to membership, so it's not a new thing as other people have said, which means that if they don't exist now they also never died out some time ago, there may never have been someone who kept every precept every day of their life.  
That being said, to take away from theological underpinnings of the definition of a member of a religion, it is patently false to say that members of a label have died out if someone still uses the label, you say a follower isn't a follower unless they're a follower but a semantic point is that even a bad wife is still a wife.  
Also, any of the emotional or spiritual availabilities that have ever been available to a person for belief or what have you are still available, the context of human experience genetically hasn't changed on the whole for many tens of thousands of years.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
