<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84472687.0" index="15" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1eajjj/mod_post_welcome_to_all_new_readers/">
    <title>[Mod Post] Welcome to all new readers!</title>
    <original_poster>IAmAN00bie</original_poster>
    <original_post>**This is Mod post 22. You can read the previous Mod Post by clicking [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1e5yke/mod_post_looking_for_a_wiki_mod/), or by visiting the [Mod Post Archive](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modpostarchive) in our wiki.**  

---          

I noticed there was a HUGE influx of new users just now, and I was confused on where they were coming from. Well, I was tipped off by a friendly user that [AdviceAnimals had mentioned us] (http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1ea3h6/got_an_essay_due_im_sure_someones_done_this_before/) in one of their top rated posts! To all new users coming in from AdviceAnimals, welcome! We're a (relatively) small community compared to you, but we hope that your thankfully positive attention to us will bring in more good members!  

Since there are a lot of new members coming in, I would also like to remind people to please **read the sidebar!** Following the rules of this subreddit is essential in making sure that we have good, healthy discussion about all sorts of topics.  

Also, I want to plug our newly created IRC channel: #changemyview on Snoonet! [You can join us by following this link here] (https://kiwiirc.com/client/irc.snoonet.org/changemyview?settings=dd892af474749b032ba39bb88a8894d9).   

edit: **the subreddit is public again, I disabled submissions for 15 minutes so us mods can catch up with this traffic!**  

edit 2: **DELTA BOT HAS LIKELY CRASHED DUE TO THE OVERWHELMING ACTIVITY!** Don't worry, we'll catch all the missed delta awardings when the owner reboots the poor bot :(  

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26723623426.0" user="usrname42" delta="False">
    <text>Please, please search for your view before you post it. We already have a ridiculous number of posts with the same view (e.g. I don't like feminists cmv), and with a huge influx of users it will only get worse. Read through old threads on the topic and if none of the arguments persuade you, then make a post and explain why they didn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26723915483.0" user="Cultiststeve" delta="False">
    <text>Agreed. Its fine if you link to older posts and mention why the arguments haven't convinced you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
