<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84472687.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1eajjj/mod_post_welcome_to_all_new_readers/">
    <title>[Mod Post] Welcome to all new readers!</title>
    <original_poster>IAmAN00bie</original_poster>
    <original_post>**This is Mod post 22. You can read the previous Mod Post by clicking [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1e5yke/mod_post_looking_for_a_wiki_mod/), or by visiting the [Mod Post Archive](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modpostarchive) in our wiki.**  

---          

I noticed there was a HUGE influx of new users just now, and I was confused on where they were coming from. Well, I was tipped off by a friendly user that [AdviceAnimals had mentioned us] (http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1ea3h6/got_an_essay_due_im_sure_someones_done_this_before/) in one of their top rated posts! To all new users coming in from AdviceAnimals, welcome! We're a (relatively) small community compared to you, but we hope that your thankfully positive attention to us will bring in more good members!  

Since there are a lot of new members coming in, I would also like to remind people to please **read the sidebar!** Following the rules of this subreddit is essential in making sure that we have good, healthy discussion about all sorts of topics.  

Also, I want to plug our newly created IRC channel: #changemyview on Snoonet! [You can join us by following this link here] (https://kiwiirc.com/client/irc.snoonet.org/changemyview?settings=dd892af474749b032ba39bb88a8894d9).   

edit: **the subreddit is public again, I disabled submissions for 15 minutes so us mods can catch up with this traffic!**  

edit 2: **DELTA BOT HAS LIKELY CRASHED DUE TO THE OVERWHELMING ACTIVITY!** Don't worry, we'll catch all the missed delta awardings when the owner reboots the poor bot :(  

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26723387380.0" user="Qzone" delta="False">
    <text>I am very happy that the image from AdviceAnimals which made it to the front page led me here. I find this subreddit refreshingly intelligent, tolerant and open to all kinds of views. A place where people come ready to be contradicted and open to change their views if they find the right and convincing arguments - something I never thought could happen on the internet. 

I hope this sureddit grows and gets the right kind of members. I will try to contribute whenever I feel I can make a worthwhile contribution. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26723758130.0" user="PastorOfMuppets94" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;something I never thought could happen on the internet.

And now that your kind is here, it never will happen again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26723894333.0" user="baskandpurr" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it matter that a person looks at advice animals?  Your statement is snobbery.  As KoNy_BoLoGnA says above, the people who want to debate will stay, the people who want to argue won't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26723938604.0" user="PastorOfMuppets94" delta="False">
    <text>First, look at the front page of /r/cmv and tell me it isn't overflowing with Reddit  Bravery^TM . All the views are so hiveminded, *I believe we should have an aptitude test to reproduce*, *I believe religion has no place in modern society*, *I believe college should be free*. It's garbage.

Second, /r/adviceanimals is populated almost solely by 12 year olds. It's the fucking worst subreddit for intelligent discussion, and sort of discourse from popular thinking, and actual humor. 

This is how good subreddits die. Because of cancer like you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26724552013.0" user="PepperoniFire" delta="False">
    <text>Edgy!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26724639863.0" user="Qzone" delta="False">
    <text>FYI I don't visit that sureddit. I happened to see this link which was getting a lot of upvotes. But I can tell you one thing. A 12 years old looking at advice animals is much better than a grown up being judgmental, insulting and generalizing. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26724638174.0" user="Qzone" delta="False">
    <text>It was very uncalled for. Hope you are happy with your kind and my kind and your kind stay away from each other. Insulting random people on the internet is something I hope not to be infected with.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
