<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="845238197.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dz8dyt/cmv_the_mlb_should_simply_allow_pitchers_to/">
    <title>CMV: The MLB should simply allow pitchers to communicate with their catchers via technology.</title>
    <original_poster>rawdigga</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand the history of the game and how important tradition is, but this imo is one of those situations where the sport simply needs to evolve with the times.

In the NFL, coaches can communicate with their quarterbacks via radios in the helmet. Is anyone complaining? We've already got instant replay in all major sports, is this not breaking from tradition? It's not exactly difficult to fixate a telescope lens on a catcher (home base does not move). This can be done from a high rise across the street from center field. With a little effort, the center field vantage point is undetectable in most ballparks.

As for tradition, what's worse? 3 years of .... "I wonder what could have been"... or allowing pitchers and catchers a more surefire option to communicate with one another.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33145673776.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Stealing signs is legal. However, using technology to steal signs is already illegal. 

From Wikipedia:

Stealing signs is not a violation of [Major League Baseball](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Major_League_Baseball)'s (MLB) rulebook, depending on how the signs were stolen.[\[2\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-2)[\[3\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-3) According to the [unwritten rules of baseball](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Unwritten_rules_of_baseball), stealing signs as they are given by the third base coach, or by a [baserunner](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Baserunner) on [second base](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_base)  watching the catcher's signals is acceptable, but a batter peeking in  to see the signs is a violation; it is up to the defensive team to  protect their signs so they are not stolen.[\[4\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-4)[\[5\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-5)  The signs the catcher sends to the pitcher to relay the next pitch are  considered more "sacred" than the signs a third base coach relays to the  batter.[\[6\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-hidden_art-6) 

At the December 1961 [Winter Meetings](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winter_Meetings), the [National League](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_League) banned the use of a "mechanical device" to steal signs.[\[7\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-7) The use of electronic equipment is not specifically forbidden by MLB rules, though in 2001, [Sandy Alderson](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sandy_Alderson)  while serving as executive vice president for baseball operations of  MLB, issued a memorandum stating that teams cannot use electronic  equipment to communicate with each other during games, especially for  the purpose of stealing signs.[\[8\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-8) Before the 2019 season, [Rob Manfred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rob_Manfred), the [commissioner of baseball](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commissioner_of_baseball), instituted specific prohibitions on where teams could position cameras and how [instant replay](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instant_replay) officials can communicate with managers in an effort to reduce illicit sign stealing.[\[9\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-9)[\[10\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-10)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147128770.0" user="three_trapeze" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;According to the [unwritten rules of baseball]

unwritten rules of baseball.
So, irrelevant. Got it. 


&amp;gt;At the December 1961 [Winter Meetings](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Winter_Meetings), the [National League](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_League) banned the use of a "mechanical device" to steal signs.[\[7\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-7) 

Baseball was a much different sport in 1961. Some rules remain relevant, most not. 

&amp;gt;The use of electronic equipment is not specifically forbidden by MLB rules, though in 2001, [Sandy Alderson](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sandy_Alderson)  while serving as executive vice president for baseball operations of  MLB, issued a memorandum stating that teams cannot use electronic  equipment to communicate with each other during games, especially for  the purpose of stealing signs.

Yeah great. OP isn't suggesting that teams steal signs with technology, he's suggesting teams communicate with technology just like most other sports because it's 2019. 

&amp;gt;[\[8\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-8) Before the 2019 season, [Rob Manfred](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rob_Manfred), the [commissioner of baseball](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Commissioner_of_baseball), instituted specific prohibitions on where teams could position cameras and how [instant replay](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Instant_replay) officials can communicate with managers in an effort to reduce illicit sign stealing.[\[9\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-9)[\[10\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sign_stealing#cite_note-10)

Again, OP isn't talking about stealing signs with technology.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
