<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="845238197.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dz8dyt/cmv_the_mlb_should_simply_allow_pitchers_to/">
    <title>CMV: The MLB should simply allow pitchers to communicate with their catchers via technology.</title>
    <original_poster>rawdigga</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand the history of the game and how important tradition is, but this imo is one of those situations where the sport simply needs to evolve with the times.

In the NFL, coaches can communicate with their quarterbacks via radios in the helmet. Is anyone complaining? We've already got instant replay in all major sports, is this not breaking from tradition? It's not exactly difficult to fixate a telescope lens on a catcher (home base does not move). This can be done from a high rise across the street from center field. With a little effort, the center field vantage point is undetectable in most ballparks.

As for tradition, what's worse? 3 years of .... "I wonder what could have been"... or allowing pitchers and catchers a more surefire option to communicate with one another.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33145507136.0" user="A35J" delta="False">
    <text>I am personally against instant replay in certain situations (I.e. a player barely lifting his foot off the base) as I believe it removes a human element of the game. This would do the same thing. Stealing signs is a part of the game, it’s a thinking-man’s sport. You need to not only outplay the other team but you must out manage and think them as well. Allowing technological communication removes the chance for gaining an edge by stealing signs. However, stealing signs cannot be done with technology. That is taking away from the integrity of the game. Have a base coach or baserunner let the batter know, not the dugout after watching a camera show the signs. 

Additionally, if technology were to be allowed, catchers would not be able to directly communicate with pitchers as the batter would hear them speaking too. This means the sign would have to be given from the dugout. What happens if a pitcher wants to shake off and throw a different pitch? The catcher and the pitcher have no way of communicating.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33145571179.0" user="rawdigga" delta="False">
    <text>Signs can be relayed via pulses that only the catcher can feel, i.e 2 buzzes on the left wristband = curveball. I think the actual management of calling the pitch is not a problem with tech.

You’ve pointed out the historical argument. I agree, but technology is already being used.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33145830162.0" user="powerupmushroom" delta="False">
    <text>I'd rather remove parts of the human element that are prone to making mistakes.  Tennis already uses technology to see if serves are in or out.  Why not do the same with something like strike zones?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33146391213.0" user="castor281" delta="False">
    <text>They are testing electronic strike zones in college right now to see how it works out. Personally I'm skeptical about it. Aaron Judge is 6' 7" and Jose Altuve is 5' 6" so their strike zones are gonna be vastly different. Somebody that bats [like Bagwell](https://media.golfdigest.com/photos/59ee19d9c9513a02a799e403/master/w_3570,h_2008,c_limit/GettyImages-535543.jpg) will have a different strike zone than someone who bats standing straight up. An umpire can distinguish between those things where a computer can't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147080886.0" user="three_trapeze" delta="False">
    <text>Artificial intelligence and machine learning can autopilot a car for tens of thousands of hours on our roads without causing a single accident. You think AI can't differentiate the strike zones of different players? You think it can't attenuate for a player bending his or her knee, or a last-microsecond trajectory change because of some crazy knuckle?

Spoiler alert: AI can and will call balls and strikes with more specificity and sensitivity than umpires.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147630204.0" user="castor281" delta="False">
    <text>Artificial intelligence and machine learning have been taught through countless hours of work and preparation from scientists and engineers to be able to deliver payloads or passengers to a specified point at a cost of 10's of billions of dollars. I don't think the MLB nor the scientists and engineers will put that kind of effort into the strike zone.

Todays AI isn't anything even resembling actual AI, so take your negative, condescending, shithead comments elsewhere. There isn't anything even approaching actual AI in todays marketplace. AI as it exists today is computer algorithms trained by humans that have an admittedly lack of knowledge on the subject. Current AI is, at best, an imitation of human instinct as perceived by humans. AI isn't a real thing yet so take your comment and fuck off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33148865780.0" user="three_trapeze" delta="False">
    <text>Oof someone's salty.

I know how machine learning models are trained. A model can be given the literally billions of data points the MLB has on balls and strikes, train it to frame strike zones, and then have it learn which calls were correct or incorrect. 

You're wrong. It's not cost-prohibitive either, the MLB just doesn't want to take away the umpire. 

I hope you one day become happy enough to not get so triggered by a Reddit comment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33146335065.0" user="castor281" delta="False">
    <text>To add to your first point, that applies to both sides. If there is a runner on second or the third base coach is relaying signals sometimes the catcher will give fake calls or signals to trip the batter up. For example, they might give a fake pitch location or shake off the previous call but still go with that pitch. With a runner on second the typically give multiple calls or overly complicated signals with the pitcher knowing which parts to ignore. In this way a catcher and pitcher can use sign stealing to their advantage to misdirect the batter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33148905928.0" user="rawdigga" delta="False">
    <text>good point, didn't really think of this.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
