<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="845238197.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/dz8dyt/cmv_the_mlb_should_simply_allow_pitchers_to/">
    <title>CMV: The MLB should simply allow pitchers to communicate with their catchers via technology.</title>
    <original_poster>rawdigga</original_poster>
    <original_post>I understand the history of the game and how important tradition is, but this imo is one of those situations where the sport simply needs to evolve with the times.

In the NFL, coaches can communicate with their quarterbacks via radios in the helmet. Is anyone complaining? We've already got instant replay in all major sports, is this not breaking from tradition? It's not exactly difficult to fixate a telescope lens on a catcher (home base does not move). This can be done from a high rise across the street from center field. With a little effort, the center field vantage point is undetectable in most ballparks.

As for tradition, what's worse? 3 years of .... "I wonder what could have been"... or allowing pitchers and catchers a more surefire option to communicate with one another.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33147113341.0" user="set_the_destroyer" delta="False">
    <text>I'll take you a step in the other direction, rather than allow communication from a pitcher, we should replace pitchers with machines controlled by the catcher a la what Hunter S. Thompson proposed.

&amp;gt; ALL "PITCHING", by the way, will be done by a fine-tuned PITCHING MACHINE that pops up out of the mound, delivers a remote-controlled "pitch" at the batter, and then drops back out of sight, to free up the whole infield for running. ... If a batter hits a home run with the bases loaded, for instance, his team will score 16 total bases (or 16 points). But, if it's 3 up and 3 down in an inning, that team will score Zero points. 

 [https://proxy.espn.com/espn/page2/story?id=860846](https://proxy.espn.com/espn/page2/story?id=860846) 

Baseball is a dying sport, and one of the main reasons is that it's boring for many to watch.  There's too little action.  Removing the pitcher and replacing them with a machine will eliminate the downtime and level the playing field (literally and figuratively).  Then we can focus on offense and not have to watch a guy bend over, grab his crotch and spit 100 times between each pitch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147157173.0" user="three_trapeze" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Baseball is a dying sport, and one of the main reasons is that it's boring for many to watch.  

Lol not according to revenue. 

https://www.statista.com/statistics/193466/total-league-revenue-of-the-mlb-since-2005/

I like your idea though. Let's have pitching machines, catching machines, batting machines, fielding machines, and coaching machines for the games. Bring human capital to 0. And while we're at it, let's have fan machines and announcer machines. And even vending machines. 

Oh wait.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147201853.0" user="set_the_destroyer" delta="False">
    <text>I can't see your link unless I pay 59$ a month, does the MLB make money off that?

According to attendance:

[https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/29/sports/baseball/mlb-attendance.html](https://www.nytimes.com/2019/09/29/sports/baseball/mlb-attendance.html)

If there's no one watching, there's no money to be made.  Also, it's evident by all the changes the MLB is making, pitch timers, subscriptions, juiced balls.  Gotta try to stop the bleeding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33147437335.0" user="AmericanNinja02" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really care about the baseball or the MLB, but I would point out that the article you linked not only makes your point about attendance, but it also makes the previous commenter's point about revenue.

"At the same time, league revenue, which topped $10 billion in 2018, is up more than 70 percent from a decade ago, thanks in large part to increasing media rights fees, which reached an all-time high this year."

The article doesn't seem to indicate that the sport is dying so much at it is adapting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33148319074.0" user="FBIOPENUPORELSE" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think baseball is dying because it's a boring sport, I think baseball is dying because it's an expensive sport.

Football, for example, I can go to Walmart, get a ball and a couple friends and boom, a child has developed interest in football

Basketball is pretty similar, there are open courts everywhere in my town.

Base ball tho, u need a bat which is like $300 then a glove which a cheap one is like $75 and a helmet, balls, a diamond field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33148958243.0" user="set_the_destroyer" delta="False">
    <text>True, but ingenuity can and has always gotten around that.  Little kids in Cuba play stickball with a broomstick and a rock with tape around it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
