<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84703288.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1efhh4/there_is_no_good_alternative_to_a_democratic_form/">
    <title>There is no good alternative to a democratic form of government. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>HatePeopleLoveLife</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think all governments should be based on individual liberty and democracy. And statism, monarchy, autocracy, and dictatorships are ALWAYS bad.

I'm not going to elaborate on exactly why I think so, at least not here, I just want you to argue why I'm wrong.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26725555194.0" user="3_14159" delta="False">
    <text>This CMV seems like the perfect opportunity to test this hypothesis: http://www.reddit.com/r/AdviceAnimals/comments/1ea3h6/got_an_essay_due_im_sure_someones_done_this_before/


Governments based on democracy rely on keeping the voters informed (of the truth) and it depends on the integrity of the voters. One of the big drawbacks of democracy is that it can be too trusting of voters' knowledge and social media. If there is ubiquitous propaganda and/or a high illiteracy rate, voters may not have reliable information and may make a poor decision in choosing a leader.

An important factor in changing you view is also why you think dictatorships are always bad. Hypothetically (and almost always in practice), dictatorships are bad for the country as a whole since it has a lot of corruption. However, a dictator may (potentially) in fact make amendments that help the country, more so than a poorly-conducted democracy.

PS: Fun fact, George Washington had strong support to be a monarch for the colonies. He refused and opted for a democratic style of government. He only ran for President because people wanted him to be president, and he was reluctant to accept the job even when elected. I do not think his policies (either good or bad) would have changed if he was a monarch rather than president.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
