<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84974284.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1elaks/i_dont_believe_that_women_should_have_to/">
    <title>I don't believe that women should have to mandatory join the draft. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>InsertWittyThing</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that men are better suited for fighting in the armed forces than women are. If America was ever in a situation and they used the draft the men should go to war and the women need to stay home and support the troops in other ways. Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react. 
Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times. Plus, they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.
Women would obviously be able to still volunteer or enlist, but they should not be forced to join the draft.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26728320241.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that men are better suited for fighting in the armed forces than women are. 

For the sake of argument, lets say this is true.  I don't actually buy this, especially when winning a fight has a lot to do with weapons technology rather than physical strength, but again, let's just say.

For every soldier on the front line firing a weapon, there are usually between five and seven people in charge of logistical stuff, ranging from base security to driving the trucks to interpreting the intelligence.  There is a need for a lot of manpower, and yes, womenpower.  Drafting women will give us the people needed to fill these roles.

&amp;gt;Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react. 

It's not like men turn in to perfectly logical Vulcans in combat.  

&amp;gt; Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times.

What, and men don't make poor decisions?

&amp;gt;they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.

This has been said about blacks and gays as well.  "The unit will get distracted, the unit won't function as well."  Guess what:  The unit got over it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
