<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84974284.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1elaks/i_dont_believe_that_women_should_have_to/">
    <title>I don't believe that women should have to mandatory join the draft. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>InsertWittyThing</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that men are better suited for fighting in the armed forces than women are. If America was ever in a situation and they used the draft the men should go to war and the women need to stay home and support the troops in other ways. Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react. 
Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times. Plus, they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.
Women would obviously be able to still volunteer or enlist, but they should not be forced to join the draft.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26728283411.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Think of it this way: that the US military opened up frontline combat positions to women shows that they clearly have the ability to perform satisfactorily in said positions - the US military knows far more about this than you or I.

So assuming this is true, why should women not have to join the draft when men do? If they can fight just as well, which the US military has implied, then the only possible reason for allowing them the luxury of not joining is a belief that the lives of women are worth more than those of men. This is an unfair, misandric belief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728304237.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>I like your point the best. You're right it is unfair. As I said in another comment I think there should really be no draft however I don't see that happening. Women could certainly join but I think we need a strong system at home to work and support our troops. So while the men who are in the draft anyway fight we have women helping in other ways at home. Wars aren't just about fighting and everybody needs to be in a place that best suits them. I understand that that statement isn't fair and that there are some men who would be better fighting and some women who would be great fighters but other than volunteering it would be very hard to determine what would be best for each person. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728313417.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but like you said there is no way of knowing which men or women would be better suited to support roles and which would be better suited to frontline combat.

Maybe we do need a strong support system, but don't you think a better way to decide who went to war and who performed support roles would be a lottery of some kind? That way, we would avoid making sexist judgments to determine who performed each role, and the risk of dying at war would be shared equally between every individual rather than just among men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728319190.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>So how would this lottery work? Just everyone throw there names in there? What about if there was something like when men and women joined the draft they were given a physical and some were put at more of a priority than others? I still think that if that was the case it would still be a majority of women at home and men in the war but it would at least put more people in the right place. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728324121.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>'So how would this lottery work?'

Say men and women both have to sign up for the draft. Now suppose a war broke out and 2,000,000 troops needed to be mobilised, 1,000,000 of them in frontline roles and 1,000,000 in support roles. Every drafted military member, regardless of their gender, would be given a number from 1 to 4. Everyone with the number 1 or 2 would fight in a frontline position and everyone with 3 or 4 would be used in a support role.

You're right though, the lottery isn't really a good idea. Your idea:

'What about if there was something like when men and women joined the draft they were given a physical and some were put at more of a priority than others?'

Does actually sound better to me. The thing is, I wouldn't mind if a majority of men were selected for frontline roles with this method (which they would be) because it's actually based on their skills rather than just their sex. This way, everyone who gets selected for frontline combat, be they male or female, has been selected because they are better for the role than those who weren't selected. 

So basically, I'm against drafting just men for frontline roles because you're selecting purely based on sex. Therefore, you have to believe that either all men are better than all women for combat, or that men's lives are worth less than women's. Both are obviously untrue.

I hope I answered your original question well, sorry if this post doesn't make sene because I'm quite tired.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728329427.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>It does help a lot! And I realize what I said was sexist and I do think that the other system would fit better. It's just the logistics that would have to be worked out and people screwing the system. I was just trying to think of a cookie-cutter simple system that would mostly work. Thank you for the answer!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728704833.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Please give them delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728885709.0" user="matthewrozon" delta="False">
    <text>It seems no one give deltas anymore or 30 people per thread do.. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728964086.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>How do you over mobile?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728327992.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>There are certainly a tiny minority of women who are suited for being combat soldiers, but if you forced *all* women into the army, the differences between men and women would be very clear ... women are, in general, physically weaker than men</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
