<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84974284.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1elaks/i_dont_believe_that_women_should_have_to/">
    <title>I don't believe that women should have to mandatory join the draft. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>InsertWittyThing</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that men are better suited for fighting in the armed forces than women are. If America was ever in a situation and they used the draft the men should go to war and the women need to stay home and support the troops in other ways. Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react. 
Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times. Plus, they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.
Women would obviously be able to still volunteer or enlist, but they should not be forced to join the draft.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26728274728.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, men are more suited for fighting than women due to their greater strength (on average of course). The other reasons you listed though are both sexist and false.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728275600.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain please? I'm just curious. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728279927.0" user="whiteraven4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react.

If this isn't sexist then give scientific proof. Why do you say women are too emotional? Define 'too emotional'. Should men have to take an emotional test to prove they aren't 'too emotional'?

&amp;gt; Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times.

What? Yes, the hormones on women's bodies change very often but that doesn't impact their ability to think rationally. How is saying women make poor decisions not sexist?

&amp;gt;Plus, they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.

So can other men. And since men are the ones who can't focus, why not train them better? This statement is sexist to both men and women. Saying men are going to be distracted by women and can't control themselves and women by blaming them because of the actions of men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728296102.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>http://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2013/03/130326101616.htm

Part of this says that men make decisions more based on rules and regulations while women rock the boat more. In my opinion it is more important to make decisions like a man would because everything needs to go according to plan. I suppose this isn't exactly emotional but it was what I was going for. Just the mentality of men v. women. 

I get very hormonal and make awful decisions when I'm on my period. Along with any other woman I know. Plus this brings up things like cramps and other sicknesses. A lot of women throw up when their on their period and have immobilizing cramps. Are they supposed to work through this or what? Read the The Loewenstein-Lerner classification under Immediate Emotions http://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emotions_in_decision-making
I'm not saying all men would be distracted or saying there are no other  distracting things but 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728297493.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>It's just another huge distraction. You can't train a man not to look or think about women! 

But these are all further reasons. The main one is that men are simply better suited for that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728359491.0" user="DrinksBathWater" delta="False">
    <text>Should we not allow gay men into the draft as well? You wouldn't want them to be distracted by the other guys.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728424238.0" user="whiteraven4" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really know anything about the army. Is it realistically possible to just make sure you send women on shorter missions when they aren't due? And just give all women in the army birth control to regulate their periods and help with symptoms. There can be some way to deal with people who are against it for religious reasons.

Assuming you are right, what about women who have more of a 'men mentality'? What about men who have more of a 'women mentality'? The problem with saying 'on average' and generalizing is that everyone is different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26729730110.0" user="EricTheHalibut" delta="False">
    <text>I would assume that women who are disabled by their periods would get assigned to some other duty, but there are huge numbers of cooks, clerks, drivers, and so on, and if a draft were necessary, there'd probably be industrial conscription as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728415904.0" user="herrokan" delta="False">
    <text>i agree with you on this

&amp;gt;So can other men. And since men are the ones who can't focus, why not train them better? This statement is sexist to both men and women. Saying men are going to be distracted by women and can't control themselves and women by blaming them because of the actions of men.

but i disagree with 

&amp;gt;

    &amp;gt;Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react.

If this isn't sexist then give scientific proof. Why do you say women are too emotional? Define 'too emotional'. Should men have to take an emotional test to prove they aren't 'too emotional'?

    &amp;gt;Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times.

What? Yes, the hormones on women's bodies change very often but that doesn't impact their ability to think rationally. How is saying women make poor decisions not sexist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728418974.0" user="whiteraven4" delta="False">
    <text>Are you going to elaborate? We can't continue a discussion if you don't give me anything to discuss.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728434805.0" user="herrokan" delta="False">
    <text>I won't be able to tell you anything meaningful since all my "evidence" is anecdotal, as i am not a scientist. But basically in my opinion it's clear that women are far more emotional and weak minded than men (OF COURSE not all women are like that, and OF COURSE some women are emotionally strong, and some men are not, but I am talking about my personal experiences and the majority of women I have encountered here) 

Even women that I would consider intelligent or even very intelligent sometimes let their emotions take controll over their rational thinking and this is a very negative trait in my personal opinion.

If you want to discuss further, alright. But I would understand if you wouldn't want to argue with someone that has no scientific proof at hand right now. (the only "proof" i have right now is that I know that women are much more likely to develope some mental illness at some point in their lives)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728438867.0" user="whiteraven4" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's more that society allows women to be emotional. I have no evidence either, but how do you know men aren't more emotional when no one can judge them? And why is it bad to let emotions rule sometimes? Letting emotion always rule is just as bad as letting logic always rule, imo.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728444556.0" user="herrokan" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but how do you know men aren't more emotional when no one can judge them? 

I don't know about all other men, however I know about myself, and I am fairly certain that my male friends are not as emotional as any females i know.

&amp;gt;And why is it bad to let emotions rule sometimes?

Because emotions are volatile and not following any logical rules.

&amp;gt;Letting emotion always rule is just as bad as letting logic always rule, imo.

why do you think that letting logic rule 100% of the time is bad?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
