<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="84974284.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1elaks/i_dont_believe_that_women_should_have_to/">
    <title>I don't believe that women should have to mandatory join the draft. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>InsertWittyThing</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that men are better suited for fighting in the armed forces than women are. If America was ever in a situation and they used the draft the men should go to war and the women need to stay home and support the troops in other ways. Most women are too emotional for that sort of this and would think too much rather than react. 
Plus women get hormonal and might make poor decisions during certain times. Plus, they could potentially be a big distraction to the men on duty.
Women would obviously be able to still volunteer or enlist, but they should not be forced to join the draft.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26728306469.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not good to base selection of anything in society on gender because the differences within genders are bigger than differences between them. There are some women who are more suitable for battle than some men, both physically and mentally. As an example, it would be much better to draft a large female police officer than a skinny male cartoonist. 

About that hormone thing. Some (not all) women are noticeably affected by monthly hormonal cycles. Only in rare cases does this affect their ability to function normally. I've never even heard before that it would affect their ability to make decisions. Is this something you just made up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728315037.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>I posted an earlier comment explaining the first part. I know things get lost in translation over text but can you read it please? It's just because my hand hurts from typing (I have a torn ligament I'm getting surgery on soon). 

And here is an article about the hormone thing! 
http://www.dailymail.co.uk/health/article-1286817/Women-prone-emotional-stress-men-sensitivity-hormone.html
 
Thanks for replying!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728332285.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is an animal study carried out on rats and we cannot say that the biological mechanism is the same in people.

So uhm, you want to exclude women based on a guess? Female rats will eat their offspring if they feel threatened after delivery so clearly they react quite differently to stress than humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728347182.0" user="InsertWittyThing" delta="False">
    <text>"But researchers already know that CRF regulation is disrupted in stress-related psychiatric disorders, so this research may be relevant to the underlying human biology." It still very likely (btw I think we've got this whole thing figured out in another comment)

And I realize it's sexist, but I also feel it holds true a lot of times. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26728435089.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But the article doesn't even mention decision making. It just seems like you are grasping at straws to defend prejudice. We know that men are more prone to take risks. I could leap from that and say women are more suitable for combat because they are less likely to make rash and risky decisions. The reason I don't make that leap is that I realize that individuals are more different than genders.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
