<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740055131.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with this stance is that it permits suspension of moral standards based on the perceptions of the person making the decision.  In other words, *society* has dictated rules for the "means" -- killing is wrong, rape is wrong, treat people equally, don't steal or threaten, etc. -- but the "ends" are decided *by an individual*.  

By saying the ends justify the means, you are saying that a person may ignore what society has decided is right based *solely on what they perceive to be right*.  You are, in effect, saying that each person is welcome to define morality however suits them, since the "ends" are valued according to them.

Even if you (somehow) construct a situation where society at large has equal participation in both means and ends, there is still a temporal argument to be made; i.e. valuation of "means" evolve with a society and are frequently tested and refined, whereas "ends" are by definition a single data point -- a single decision.

Saying ends over means is equivalent to saying personal gain over social morals, which is a rejection of the social contract.  You have the right to reject the social contract; society then has the right to reject you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740078820.0" user="CatsAndSwords" delta="False">
    <text>This seems a good argument against the first point (the trolley problem), but I don't think it adresses the other two examples. A restriction of rights, or a policy such as China's one-child policy, is decided by the government, so is ultimately the result of the people's will, and not of an individual (still, something could be said about the diverging interests of a people and its government).

Your argument that :

&amp;gt; Even if you (somehow) construct a situation where society at large has equal participation in both means and ends, there is still a temporal argument to be made; i.e. valuation of "means" evolve with a society and are frequently tested and refined, whereas "ends" are by definition a single data point -- a single decision.

does not make much sense. An "end" is not necessarily a single data point (problems akin to the trolley problem occur frequently), and the valuation of "means" and of "ends" both change. And even if an "end" would be a fixed decision and the valuation of "means" would change, I don't see how it is an argument against the idea that the ends justify the means.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740103568.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>An "end" must be a goal, correct?  It must be a fixed condition you wish to reach, or it is not an "end."  When similar ends have happened before, society expresses its intent on those ends through its valuation of means.  Put another way, a "means" was likely an "end" once, and one that society didn't like the outcome of -- and here you may say "person" instead of "society" to the same result.  Experience is more valuable than theory, because theory is by necessity on a lack of information; "ends" is theory whereas "means" is experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740081144.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Of course. Morality is created by society but altered by each individual. Every person is going to have a different definition of "acceptable" means and ends. I don't mean to say that what I define as justifiable is objectively accurate. I mean to say that, based on each individual's goals for society and themselves, for every person's actions can be justified by the effects they cause *for every other individual*. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740094467.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, I agree.  But the problem is it's impossible to know with certainty what effects *will have been* for an action; decisions are made on incomplete information.  

Think of it this way.  "Means" are things that society has *already judged the effects of*.  "Ends" are things that we, as a society, *don't yet know the full effects of*.  If I try to sell you on an investment with a 1000%/year return rate, you will likely write it off as a scam, because you know that investments typically don't deliver like that.  Even if you were wrong, you made a good decision based on the information available to you, and on average you'll come out ahead.  The information society has available is encoded in its valuation of "means"; our stance as a society on e.g. murder reflects our valuations of people's rights; a willingness to sacrifice those for *one* thing implies, by necessity, a willingness to sacrifice them for *any* thing considered so valuable, and therefore it is not a right at all.

To provide one more perspective:  rights *must* be inalienable, or they are not rights.  Everything else is utility functions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740097864.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Well, yes. I mean this more for hypothetical situation where we know the effects of various actions but some people object to taking the one with "better" effects on moral grounds, like the Trolley Problem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740117444.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>Problems like the Trolley Problem don't actually happen, because of uncertainty.  In reality, the problem would be something more to the effect of "act, and 49% **+/- 10%** die, or don't act, and 51% **+/- 10%** die."  The question then becomes "let some people die, or kill some people."  The advantage is not clear.

You may argue that you *do* know, with certainty, but you are asking society to trust you enough to let you murder people; we place an impossibly high standard on that because we know that murder is an ultimate violation of rights.  You have the right to risk your life on a trolley; you also have the right to not have your life deliberately taken.   When I ride a trolley, I know I might die, and I accept that risk; I have *not* accepted the risk that someone *may decide to kill me*.  In other words, I accept the risk because I know it is *uncertain* and therefore *impartial*.  I have never known a person to be impartial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740120911.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I know that things like this are always probabilistic, which is why I'm not talking about the real world. I'm talking about a hypothetical perfect world with no fluff like "uncertainty" .  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740136402.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>I submit that in an easily computable deterministic world (i.e. one with no uncertainty) the valuations of "means" would differ, as well, for the reasons above; as a result you would find that the means don't *need* justification, since social "rules of thumb" would not be relevant.  In that world, therefore, ends do not justify means, since "means" as a concept of categories of actions (with corresponding social judgement) are not necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740734100.0" user="Bobertus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but the "ends" are decided by an individual

What does "ends" mean to you? The meaning from wiktionary that, to me, fits best here, is "result". However, it does not make sense to say that I can decide the result of my actions. I can decide that drinking poison makes me immortal, but I will still die (obviously).

&amp;gt;  You are, in effect, saying that each person is welcome to define morality however suits them, since the "ends" are valued according to them

Society can very well define what results are good and what results are bad.

Could it be that you simply don't trust an individuals judgement of what effects their actions have? But in that case you you could apply "the end justifies the means" to actions by the society, without that problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740993730.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; However, it does not make sense to say that I can decide the result of my actions. I can decide that drinking poison makes me immortal, but I will still die (obviously).

Yes -- this is *exactly my point*.  You may decide that the "ends" (immortality) justify the "means" (drinking poison).  However, we know that the means are dangerous -- that's why the ends don't justify them; because the danger of poison is *known*, where the benefit of immortality is *hypothetical*.

It doesn't matter whether society or an individual defines the results -- the results are uncertain by nature of living in a pseudonondeterministic world.  The means are *known*, and the ends are *unknown*, so we as a society avoid ends that require dangerous (read: to a person or to society) means, since the benefit is not clear. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740997449.0" user="Bobertus" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, that is a strange way to look at it. The result of drinking poison is not "hypothetical", we *know* it doesn't lead to immortality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741008191.0" user="dokushin" delta="False">
    <text>Again, this speaks to the heart of my point.  "We" know -- i.e., society knows.  It's not inconceivable that *a person* wouldn't know.  If a person becomes convinced that ingesting poison will benefit them but is aware that society condemns ingesting poison, he is *exactly* comparing means (poison) to ends (benefit), and a belief in the latter will kill him.  In this way, "means" encodes social wisdom, and "ends" encodes personal theory.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
