<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740062297.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think your view still applies when you consider the measurement problem? For example, the Flynn effect, plus various critique, suggests that the concept and means of measuring IQ has some problems. If you select policies based on their effect on IQ then you'll be amplifying the effect of any discrepancy in the test or metric.

This is the main ethically-agnostic problem with Ends-Justify-Means: the justification always boils down to some kind of measurement. The Trolly Problem measures the number of warm bodies, not by, say, if the 49% you select to die are fertile and the 51% you save are sterile.

Ends-Justfy-Means assumes infinite predictive scope and accuracy, but it's the very fact that we cannot have such prescience that has lead to the development of moral and ethnical systems in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740075295.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't. Which is why I don't actively apply this view in the real world. I only hold this view *given* that we can measure the end result effectively. If for whatever reason we cannot, the entire system becomes rubbish. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740082849.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose then that you'd be forced to consign your belief to the mythical "perfect world"? In other words, have I Changed Your View to:

"in cases where perfect and complete information is available for judgement, unsavoury actions are justified"?

If I have, then now I can focus on the judge himself and say that you're claiming anyone in that position has the authority to set the value of other people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740085157.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Perfect situations where the results of actions are perfectly known ahead of time is what I am concerned with here. Whether the results are "good" or "bad" depends on the person making the observation, the the question is the same but may get different results from every individual. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740096960.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the question is the same but may get different results from every individual.

 Well suppose that the results from, say, our favorite whipping boy Adolf Hitler, are different that the results from an equally hypothetically perfectly informed Winston Churchill. How would we, as a society, solve the obvious problems that come from this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740109145.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone decides for themselves, as the currently do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740117817.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure you gave me enough exposition in your answer to figure out a good reply. I'll assume you mean that everyone gets to be a judge?

Even in a world where everyone has perfect information, would we not still find situations that essentially boil down to a battle-of-opinions? A perfectly informed Bugs Bunny puts up a "Duck Season" poster, and a perfectly informed Daffy puts up a "Rabbit Season" poster.

The stalemate would now have to be resolved by irrational means: the stronger agent uses their might to impose their judgement and carry-out the means that lead to the ends they value.

Therefore, isn't it better to say your view is actually "might makes right" in disguise?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740125912.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Might makes right, but only if you agree with the might. Closer to "might has the ability to act on what it believes to be right". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740130137.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Might makes right, but only if you agree with the might.

 Ah, so would the segment of the population that doesn't agree possibly develop defensive cultural norms such as "the ends do not justify the means", and have a valid reason to do so?

 Perhaps they recognize that strength is transient, that one day they'll be on top, and it'll be more important to pin the principle down now rather than suffer an unending cycle of domination and victimhood with no end in sight?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
