<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740091876.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>So your argument is that if we knew the effects of all our actions, then taking the actions that lead to the most positive effects would be the actions that we should take. But if everybody had this same ability, then there would be no need to limit freedoms or impose a one child policy because people would self-regulate. In this hypothetical scenario, the ends do justify the means, but most of the examples you give would no longer be relevant. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740095448.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I never said everyone gets the same ability. And, even if they did, what constitutes a "positive" or "negative" effect or action would be different for everyone. In this situation, *everyone's* actions are justified (to themselves at least), but the powerful would still need to limit freedoms to impose their will. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740098640.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>So your moral system depends on just what individual people think is positive and negative? That sounds like an awful idea. What about people with a skewed view of morality. You can't create a moral system that just relies on every individual deciding for themselves what is right. That's a recipe for disaster.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740112226.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>That is what we have now. The only difference is that people are more affected by the things we do than the things we create than I think they should be. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740118768.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>No, we have a moral system based on societal standards. Yes humans have certain deeply ingrained moral intuitions, but society creates a broader spectrum of ethical rules based on what it perceives will best satisfy those inherent moral judgments. I think you agree with that. 

You think that societal moral standards should be shifted to care more about ends then means given we live in a society where people grasp the effects of their actions to a greater degree. I argue that in terms of having society function best, there must be a mixture of ethical judgments that condemn actions in and of themselves and ethical judgments that condemn actions because of the results. Some actions, like theft and murder, need to have blanket bans because it just makes pragmatic sense. In most cases, whatever good they might cause is outweighed by the badness of the action itself. 

I feel like I'm rambling a bit, but I'm looking for the point of contradiction between our views. I think that society's ethical standards have a good balance between things that are inherently wrong and things that are consequentially wrong. Are you saying that nothing should be considered inherently wrong? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740131782.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; No, we have a moral system based on societal standards. Yes humans have certain deeply ingrained moral intuitions, but society creates a broader spectrum of ethical rules based on what it perceives will best satisfy those inherent moral judgments. I think you agree with that.

Yes, but each person alters what society gives them a little bit to create their own personal moral philosophy. The broader moral themes would still be present, but only if they are self-congratulating. "Freedom is good because freedom is good" would go extinct, but "freedom is good because freedom makes people happy" is perfectly capable of surviving, unless it actually didn't make people happy. 

&amp;gt; You think that societal moral standards should be shifted to care more about ends then means given we live in a society where people grasp the effects of their actions to a greater degree. I argue that in terms of having society function best, there must be a mixture of ethical judgments that condemn actions in and of themselves and ethical judgments that condemn actions because of the results. Some actions, like theft and murder, need to have blanket bans because it just makes pragmatic sense. In most cases, whatever good they might cause is outweighed by the badness of the action itself.

Yes, because we live in the real world. In the real world, actions such as murder or theft are *usually*, almost always, bad. I don't think that this philosophy should be applied in actuality. 

&amp;gt; Are you saying that nothing should be considered inherently wrong?

Only in such a world where we know the effects of all actions. In actuality, of course some actions need to be considered inherently wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740138839.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>So is that the only place where we disagree? You think morality should be abstract and not based on real world applications? I think that morality should be aspirational, but still practical. 

You're basically advocating for a form of moral skepticism in which the good is entirely unobtainable. I think that a moral system where the highest good is unobtainable, but individual actions can be judged as either good or bad is far better. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740155016.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I suppose so. In all honesty I dedicate very little though to real world moralities, because the answer is usually boring. Heuristics are essential to real world morality, I find them uninteresting. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740286259.0" user="Amarkov" delta="False">
    <text>You're making a huge assumption here, and I don't think you realize it. Why are you so sure that it's *meaningful* to talk about morality apart from the real world. 

I'd argue that it's more than a little bit like saying "yes, in the real world the Earth is made of rocks, but what if it *wasn't*?" The results you get might be self-consistent, but it's not clear that they'll be connected at all to what's normally thought of as morality. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
