<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740097905.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant.

Question:  Favorable to who?

Example: You are put to a choice: kill a loved one and save 20 random people, or kill 20 random people and save your loved one.  What are you advocating here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740099186.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I would advocate that you do the hard thing. That doesn't mean that I, personally, would, but I would be wrong. My actions would be morally unjustifiable. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740102867.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>So you're saying, favorable to the greatest amount of people?  

Saving a loved one would be pretty favorable to an individual...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740110675.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I am human, and make bad decisions, much to my dismay. The fact that my moral compass can be corrupted by emotion is not sufficient to change it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740116136.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, do you have a sort of "absolute" morality, where it is based on favorable outcomes for the majority?  This seems to be the case I'm just looking for confirmation here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740121850.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I have a set of moral guidelines that I believe are justified. That does not make me a moral person, even by my own definition. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740124113.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't answer the question.  I'm not looking for hypocrisy, that's been established already.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740135189.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>What constitutes a favourable outcome is subjective, so no. I do not believe in objective morality, if that is what you're asking. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740139746.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>Ok -- what I'm looking for is specifically this: your overarching premise is "the ends justify the means" specifically if the result is "favorable."  I'm trying to find out who it needs to be favorable to in order to be justified.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740148565.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Whoever is judging it, that is, everyone who is aware of it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740156175.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, so, something could be justified if say, Bob isn't aware of it, but then could be unjustified if he becomes aware of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740243725.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>If Bob is not aware of it, it is neither justified or unjustified in his eyes. What I meant was that everyone decides for themselves whether certain actions are justified. If you are not aware of something, you cannot form an opinion on it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
