<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740695414.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Here's another thought experiment, I'd be curious to know your answer to:

There are five patients in a hospital, that each need an organ transplant to continue their lives: one needs new lungs, another a new heart, the third a new liver, etc. Would you kill a healthy person to harvest their organs, so that these five patients could live? Lets say they're all 25 years old.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741133969.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. I mean, maybe I would not personally kill them, but that is because I'm weak like that. I do believe they should die. Such a problem is no different from the Trolley Problem except for the fact you have to actually make a decision rather than react in a split-second. 

It's like those deterministic problems every Philosophy 101 class gets. After having determinism explained to them, they are asked if Susan is truly morally responsible for her preferred ice cream flavor, vanilla. Most of the class will say no. The class is then asked if Bob, a father who kills his wife and child because he wants to elope with a mistress, is morally responsible. To this, most of the class answers yes. There is no actual objective difference between the two questions, but one preys on human emotion in hope of getting a different response. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741217180.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>So would kill one random person for each two people in need of an organ transplant worldwide? Would you willfully die, so that two other people could continue to live?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741244131.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; So would kill one random person for each two people in need of an organ transplant worldwide?

Definitely. 

&amp;gt; Would you willfully die, so that two other people could continue to live?

No, but that it hypocritical. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741810519.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>So you'll probably agree then, that a society, where any person could at any point be hauled away to be killed for their organs, would cause a lot of distress within a society?

Would you want to live in a society, where you and your family members and friends are constantly at risk of being killed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26742205036.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I agree. This is the thought that made me change my view a few days ago. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
