<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="86147245.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fafn1/the_ends_justify_the_means_cmv/">
    <title>The ends justify the means. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>294116002</original_poster>
    <original_post>This was inspired by the "kill two people to save one" thread that was started a few days ago.

 This ideology is very often associated with terrible dictators and death and genocide, but I think that far more people actually hold it than let on. I very honestly believe that, if a result is favourable, the method used to reach it is very often irrelevant. A small note must be made here about probability: an action I take has a 1% chance of success, and succeeds, is *less* justified than if I had taken an action 
which had a 60% chance of success but failed. So I suppose my view could be refined as "in cases where the only variable of a set of actions or methods is the effect of said actions, unsavoury actions are justified ", so this is more of a philosophical CMV than a practical one. 

A few examples would be pertinent. **I AM WELL AWARE THAT SUCH SCENARIOS ARE VIRTUALLY IMPOSSIBLE AND AM MERELY USING THEM AS THOUGHT EXPERIMENTS, THANK YOU.**


* I believe that the Trolley Problem, that is, killing one person to save more than one person given that you know nothing of any of the participants, is justified in all it's forms. If I have to make a choice to kill 49% of the Earth's population to save 51%, the answer is the same.  There are only two actions to take, each have a 100% success rate, and the only variable is the result. Whether I am a passive observer or an active participant makes no real difference. 

* Rights and freedoms should be abolished if they demonstrably shown to have some net negative effect on society. If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press on, say, the general happiness of the population, average IQ, life expectancy, and median household income, and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

* If it can be demonstrated beyond a reasonable doubt that China's one-child policy will have a net-positive effect on society (say we create a parallel universe where the only difference is parallel-China does not create this policy), than the policy is justified, so long as the only thing we can change is whether or not to enact the policy. All future legislative policies *must* remain the same between the two Chinas.   </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26740081855.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If we created a controlled experiment to test the effect of freedom of the press ... and find that a free press reduces every one of these things in the long run, than that particular freedom is unjustified and should be removed. 

I do not believe such an experiment could ever exist.

Furthermore, there are forms of good outside of happiness of the population and the other things you list - freedom of the press for example can be a check and balance for the people against the government. If we start limiting what people can say, we can censor dissent against he government and in the long run that would cause a greater negative effect. 

Many of our rights are for just such situations. Even if you measured that guns cause such-and-such pain and suffering, the ability to protect oneself from assailants or even the government helps protect us from other greater negative effects, like an oppressive government. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740083053.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>C'mon dude. I specifically mentioned everything you've just said in the topic explanation. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740087631.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>Your entire point relies on such an experiment existing and in having some ill-defined view of what positives and negatives are, you can't just hand wave that away. If we're talking about, for example, getting rid of freedom of speech, the method we used to determine if it's a good idea or not is vitally important.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740091582.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, the entire view rests on such an experiment existing, but only if I wish to apply it in the real world. I made a special aside for that. *GIVEN* that such an deterministic method exists, the removal of freedom of the press would be justified. Whether such a method actually exists really doesn't matter for this purpose. I'm not actually advocating that we get rid of various rights and freedoms, just that, **if it could be demonstrated that they are bad for society**, removing them is justified. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740097349.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Basically, what you are arguing is that in order to maximize utility, you might need to remove freedoms. There are plenty of good arguments against that claim:

a) Removing freedoms could never be a part of maximizing utility. Human beings value freedom to the point that what you gain will always be less than what you lose. You might not buy this one.

b) Freedom is a good in and of itself, not morally neutral. Thus even if people have more utility without freedom, freedom is more valuable. This still allows for freedoms to be reduced for the good of society, but the calculation is more skewed towards freedoms.

c) This is evidence that utilitarianism is flawed. If your moral intuitions tell you that freedom is good, but you have a moral system that can justify removing people's freedom, maybe what's flawed is the system, not the moral judgments. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740107003.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; a) Removing freedoms could never be a part of maximizing utility. Human beings value freedom to the point that what you gain will always be less than what you lose. You might not buy this one.

History begs to differ. In fact, people only value freedom once they already have it, for the most part. That's why employees that enjoy high wages and vacation time are more likely to strike than those that do not. 

&amp;gt; b) Freedom is a good in and of itself, not morally neutral. Thus even if people have more utility without freedom, freedom is more valuable. This still allows for freedoms to be reduced for the good of society, but the calculation is more skewed towards freedoms.

My entire point is that this is not true. What good is freedom if nobody lives past thirty? What good is freedom is 90% of the population is illiterate? What good is freedom if nearly every newborn and mother die in childbirth? Freedom is only good if it stops these things from happening. Otherwise, what is the point of it?

&amp;gt; c) This is evidence that utilitarianism is flawed. If your moral intuitions tell you that freedom is good, but you have a moral system that can justify removing people's freedom, maybe what's flawed is the system, not the moral judgements.

I'm not advocating utilitarianism. I'm advocating a weak form of consequentialism. And, for the record, I have no negative intuition about removing freedoms. The only reason I support most of them is because they provide a net gain to society, in my opinion. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740112323.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Utilitarianism is a form of consequentialism, and I assumed that it was the form you were arguing for, but I guess I'm wrong. So then what do you mean by positive for the rest of individuals in existence. The most individuals? And what metric are we using to measure how good the consequences are? Personal moral intuitions of the individuals? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740124063.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I don't presume to know what is objectively good for everyone. I can only define "positive" as what I consider to be positive effects for society, as everyone else can do for themselves. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740135603.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Well here is one problem I just realized with this line of argument. You are advocating for consequentialism, but your line of argument seems to be (correct me if I'm wrong) "See how great these consequences are. Don't you want to be a consequentialist?" I, on the other hand, reject consequentialism, and thus you have to convince me by showing that consequentialism, on a meta-ethical (Am I using this word right? Probably not) level, is a better form of morality. Your argument can't be, that Actual Consequentialism leads to the best actual consequences, thus it should be the basis of morality. That's a syllogism. By definition Actual Consequentialism leads to the best actual consequences. That's what it advocates doing

The issue is that you aren't addressing the meta-ethical (still using it wrong) concerns, such as that the system is unpractical. If it does not function in the real world, then why posit it as the best moral system? Also, you haven't given me a good reason to reject the idea that actions can be bad regardless of the consequences. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740146833.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>I'll give you a few scenarios than. 

* You must consent to one person's death or the entirety of the human race will die in agony. 

* Nobody in Nation X wants or ever will want to own a pair of aviator sunglasses. You have to option to make ownership of said sunglasses a constitutional right. 

* You can either case one person unbearable pain for one full day and save their life, or kill them ensuring they never feel pain again. 

What is the action you take, in each of these? I'll respond based on that. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26740384850.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>1. I would have to consent to that person's death. But does the person consent to being killed for the sake of humanity? I assume they do.

2. Sure, make it a constitutional right. 

3. Well what do they want? I would probably go for unbearable pain if they couldn't tell me which they preferred. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26741137825.0" user="294116002" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But does the person consent to being killed for the sake of humanity? I assume they do.

They have no knowledge of what is about to happen, and therefore do not consent. 

&amp;gt; Sure, make it a constitutional right.

Why? 

&amp;gt; Well what do they want? I would probably go for unbearable pain if they couldn't tell me which they preferred.

They cannot tell you what they want, but you can assume that, *during* the pain episode, they would want to die, but afterwards they would thank you for not killing them. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
