<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="869470252.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ednrjg/cmv_anna_sacoolas_should_return_to_the_uk/">
    <title>CMV: Anna Sacoolas should return to the UK voluntarily and face trial</title>
    <original_poster>VertigoOne</original_poster>
    <original_post>For those unfamiliar with this incident, Anna Sacoolas is the partner of an American consular official based in the UK. She was driving on the wrong side of the road and caused a traffic accident which killed a 19 year old on a motorcycle in Northamptonshire. Following this incident, she fled the country under what was believed at the time to be diplomatic immunity. This was back in October 2019. Since then, it has been determined that she did not in fact have diplomatic immunity because she was only the partner of a consular official, and she was based outside of London.  

Recently the UK's Crown Prosecution Service have determined that the evidence is sufficient that she could be charged with the offence of "Causing Death by Dangerous Driving". They have now begun extradition processes. The maximum penalty for an offence of this kind could be 14 years in prison.

Representatives of Ms Sacoolas have described the incident as "a terrible but unintentional accident" and argues that the charge and potential sentencing is "disproportionate".

The reason I think she should return to the UK is pretty simple.

She did it.

No one is disputing that she was driving on the wrong side of the road.

Failing to obey a road traffic law out of ignorance is bad enough, but you don't need to be married to a consular official to know that the UK drives on the other side of the road to the US. She can't have been ignorant. She can have been negligent.

The fourteen year jail sentence is the maximum. Not the expected result. Although refusing to face justice is likely to increase, rather than decrease, the sentence length. Also, it isn't the job of Americans to interpret what is and is not 'proportionate' in the British legal system.

Even if she had diplomatic immunity, it is not a literal "everything-proof shield". It's purpose is to prevent diplomats being taken advantage of by another nation's laws. It's not there to let diplomats get away with serious crimes.

If the situation were inverted, there's not really any way that the US would tolerate the UK holding a British diplomat who left the country under mistaken diplomatic immunity.

Why should she be able to perpetually take advantage of a mistake and not face justice? She committed a crime. No one is disputing that. It doesn't matter if the crime was done by accident or not.

Criminals should be tried and punished according to the legal system.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33348821400.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The reason I think she should return to the UK is pretty simple.

&amp;gt; She did it.

&amp;gt; Anna Sacoolas should return to the UK voluntarily and face trial

I totally agree that she should stand trial, and I'd like to see her stand trial.

But what reason would *she* have to go voluntarily? Obviously, if it looks like extradition may be successful, then it *may* help her case if she goes before being extradited. However, otherwise she has no reason to.

&amp;gt; The fourteen year jail sentence is the maximum. Not the expected result. Although refusing to face justice is likely to increase, rather than decrease, the sentence length. Also, it isn't the job of Americans to interpret what is and is not 'proportionate' in the British legal system.

Do you think that she can be sure that only the accident itself will be taken into account for sentencing? And not that the UK will overdo it on trying to show that they're giving special treatment to (presumed) diplomats?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348896956.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But what reason would she have to go voluntarily?

Because it's the right thing to do? Because it will reduce her sentence. Because the alternative is basically her saying "if you can escape the law, you can commit a crime!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348961461.0" user="tubkb" delta="False">
    <text>A part of me would want to hand myself in cus she will now live with this hanging over her, with every US regime change, each time the USA needs a favour or something from the UK she will be scared it’s finally the time they revoke the immunity and send her off to jail. Also the infant and I imagine constant hate mail and threats. For me the threat I may at any time be sent to face justice constantly looming for the rest of my life is worse than actually just facing the consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33349261608.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not think that the UK will try to make an example of her by giving her the maximum sentence, in order not to seem to be giving special treatment to someone with presumed diplomatic protection? 

With all the media attention this got, it seems unlikely that they'll only take the facts of the accident into account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33366572413.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you not think that the UK will try to make an example of her by giving her the maximum sentence

Not if she co-operated initially.

Due to her fleeing the country, she'll likely face a harsher sentence should she be extradited.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33367790701.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Then that will be a prejudiced trial, which under different conditions would be a mistrial. I'm not sure I would go, even though it would be more moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33367962334.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>No it wouldn't at all.

These circumstances are always taken into account when sentencing.

Sentencing guidelines give a minimum and maximum, and depending on the circumstances of the case, the judge decided what they want to do.

Fleeing the country and refusing to co-operate with the authorities would be grounds for the maximum sentence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33368888795.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Fleeing the country and refusing to co-operate with the authorities would be grounds for the maximum sentence.

That's exactly my point. A fair trail is less likely. Even though at the time, she was officially advised by the American Embassy, i.e. her own government, to leave the UK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33368995391.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>Why is a fair trial less likely? If she can prove that her government advised that, it'll be taken into account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33373166925.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't it more likely that the UK will try to make an example of her by giving her the maximum sentence, in order not to seem to be giving special treatment to someone with presumed diplomatic protection?

There has been a lot of press attention on the family who are not getting justice. And so many people have already publicly criticized the fact that she has managed to "escape justice" thus far, that it's unlikely they'll find an unprejudiced jury. The case is even used to call for a reduction in the power of diplomatic protections.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33373187556.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Isn't it more likely that the UK will try to make an example of her by giving her the maximum sentence

Yes, but that doesn't necessitate an unfair trial. She'll be given the maximum sentence within the guidelines for the crime she committed.

&amp;gt;The case is even used to call for a reduction in the power of diplomatic protections.

Because her husband wasn't a diplomat...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33373483623.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, but that doesn't necessitate an unfair trial.

I agree that it doesn't necessitate it. I just think that it's more likely. They can't be seen to be soft on her, because of the global outrage and everyone siding with the family.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33373501138.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>A harsher sentence within the sentencing guidelines isn't unfair though, so I'm still struggling to see how you believe it would be an unfair trial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33373517818.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>But whether they go for the harsher or the less harsh sentence is precisely what affects the fairness. 

You can't say across the board that the harshest sentence is fair by virtue of it falling within the sentence guidelines.

For it to be fair, I feel that it would be necessary that they purely decide this based on the facts of the accident, and not anything that happened afterwards. But that's precisely what I think is unlikely.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33350135582.0" user="ilikefatdolphintits" delta="False">
    <text>They will extradite her anyways. If the USA wants to be bff with UK after brexit, they would not refuse to extradite her. I know the British far too well, they are petty enough to make this a national scandal and destroy USA relationship over this. 

(No offense )</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33377693012.0" user="fakeplasticcheeses" delta="False">
    <text>Working within the confines of the law is not ‘petty’. Let’s not forget Trump isn’t exactly void of pettiness in his behaviour either. 

At the end of the day, a family is without a son and someone who caused death by careless driving, who doesn’t believe they are culpable, wakes up on Christmas Day with their family. 

Sacoola’s lack of empathy and compassion is a repugnant display of that of an entitled white woman. Hopefully, she can see beyond her own self involved behaviour and voluntarily return to the UK to stand trial.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33490256827.0" user="BrightonTownCrier" delta="False">
    <text>Lets set aside the sweeping generalisation because it's ill informed, pointless and frankly laughable.
 
Firstly you can't know the 'British' that well if you refer to the  people from Scotland, Wales, England and Northern Ireland with one term but you are actually just referring to the English.

Secondly if you think fighting for justice for a person that did what Anne Sacoolas has done (not just the negligent driving and manslaughter but fleeing and attempting to use their husband's professional position as a get out of jail free card) is "petty" then you have a frighteningly amoral attitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33492423880.0" user="ilikefatdolphintits" delta="False">
    <text>Are you Anne googling your own name or something?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33515263873.0" user="BrightonTownCrier" delta="False">
    <text>Doesnt even make sense. Why would I call her out? 

Also didnt realise you put "No Offense" at the end of your post which as all adults know means you can say whatever you want without consequence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33351321289.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, ethics. I’d feel pretty guilty if my actions lead to someone dying and I wouldn’t be able to sleep at night if I didn’t own up to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33351403432.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>But with all the media attention this got, do you think it likely that they'll only take the facts of the accident into account?

Isn't it likely that the UK will try to make an example of her by giving her the maximum sentence, in order not to seem to be giving special treatment to someone with presumed diplomatic protection?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33351434355.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It sucks but ultimately this is her own doing. Were I in the same situation I would not have fled in the first place. If she has an integrity she’ll do the right thing. Everyone makes mistakes and this was a big one. Mistakes have consequences. That’s life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33351479969.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not so sure of that. At the time, she was officially advised by the American Embassy, i.e. her own govnernment, to leave the UK.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33366571008.0" user="GregorF92" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But what reason would she have to go voluntarily?

If you're guilty of a crime, you can generally get a lower sentence by co-operating.

By fleeing the country and only returning under a successful extradiction request, the judge will see she has no intention of being co-operative, meaning the judge is less likely to be lenient.

Considering the United States has never denied a single extradition request from the UK under the treaty, it would be in her best interests to co-operate, in hopes of a lesser sentence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33367808624.0" user="ralph-j" delta="False">
    <text>At the time, she was officially advised by the American Embassy, i.e. her own government, to leave the UK. It doesn't seem fair if that's taken into account, which it likely will be. Under different conditions this would likely result in a prejudiced trial, and thus a mistrial. 

I'm not sure I would go, even though it would be more moral for the victim.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
