<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="869470252.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ednrjg/cmv_anna_sacoolas_should_return_to_the_uk/">
    <title>CMV: Anna Sacoolas should return to the UK voluntarily and face trial</title>
    <original_poster>VertigoOne</original_poster>
    <original_post>For those unfamiliar with this incident, Anna Sacoolas is the partner of an American consular official based in the UK. She was driving on the wrong side of the road and caused a traffic accident which killed a 19 year old on a motorcycle in Northamptonshire. Following this incident, she fled the country under what was believed at the time to be diplomatic immunity. This was back in October 2019. Since then, it has been determined that she did not in fact have diplomatic immunity because she was only the partner of a consular official, and she was based outside of London.  

Recently the UK's Crown Prosecution Service have determined that the evidence is sufficient that she could be charged with the offence of "Causing Death by Dangerous Driving". They have now begun extradition processes. The maximum penalty for an offence of this kind could be 14 years in prison.

Representatives of Ms Sacoolas have described the incident as "a terrible but unintentional accident" and argues that the charge and potential sentencing is "disproportionate".

The reason I think she should return to the UK is pretty simple.

She did it.

No one is disputing that she was driving on the wrong side of the road.

Failing to obey a road traffic law out of ignorance is bad enough, but you don't need to be married to a consular official to know that the UK drives on the other side of the road to the US. She can't have been ignorant. She can have been negligent.

The fourteen year jail sentence is the maximum. Not the expected result. Although refusing to face justice is likely to increase, rather than decrease, the sentence length. Also, it isn't the job of Americans to interpret what is and is not 'proportionate' in the British legal system.

Even if she had diplomatic immunity, it is not a literal "everything-proof shield". It's purpose is to prevent diplomats being taken advantage of by another nation's laws. It's not there to let diplomats get away with serious crimes.

If the situation were inverted, there's not really any way that the US would tolerate the UK holding a British diplomat who left the country under mistaken diplomatic immunity.

Why should she be able to perpetually take advantage of a mistake and not face justice? She committed a crime. No one is disputing that. It doesn't matter if the crime was done by accident or not.

Criminals should be tried and punished according to the legal system.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33349793070.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>She's de facto exiled from the country. The UK doesn't have to worry about her ever committing another crime in their jurisdiction, and British taxpayers don't have to shoulder the cost of imprisoning her. Part of the point of imprisonment is to separate dangerous people from the general public. For all practical purposes, as far as the British are concerned, she's essentially serving a life sentence in a much bigger cell. Unless you believe bad things need to happen to bad people because they just do, independent of any actual social benefit derived from punishment, this seems like a win for everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353447384.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>You're ignoring the underlying implication here. That you can commit a crime, if you can escape.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353601656.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>So if I understand you correctly, is your main concern the precedent set here? Are you worried that this opens the door to someone else coming to the UK and committing a crime intentionally under the protection of real or presumed diplomatic immunity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33387282059.0" user="bushcrapping" delta="False">
    <text>I highly doubt you would call that a win if it was your child.  Just like you stated part of the point of imprisonment is to protect society but another part is punitive and/or rehabilitation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33387572022.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>To me, a de facto lifelong exile is as good as imprisonment. I recognize rehabilitation as a valid goal of the justice system, but at the current moment, it's a goal, not a reality. Maybe the UK justice system is radically different in that regard. But punishment as an end in its own right is something I see no value in. What actual benefit does anyone derive from bad people suffering in and of itself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33388516787.0" user="bushcrapping" delta="False">
    <text>Although I would often agree with a lot of crimes that no one benefits to pure punishment based judicial systems but in this case Someone is dead.  So yes I think there is a benefit to punishment in the justice system. I think justice here is the key word, where is the justice in an exile for murder? A mother is without a child but not being able to see Big Ben is a worthy punishment? I’m sorry I just don’t believe that if you were family of a dead/raped/tortured party that you would see exile as a befitting punishment and be happy with that in place of incarceration.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33388606401.0" user="Glory2Hypnotoad" delta="False">
    <text>I'll admit I'm an abnormal case. I don't have most people's sense of what I would call negative altruism. I believe punishment has a number of practical benefits, but I don't have any primal urge to see bad things happen to bad people. You're probably right that justice is the key word, but to me the concept of justice comes off as a thought-terminating cliche. It's what people say when they just take it as axiomatic that people who do bad things need to suffer because they just do.

I also think that the distinction between murder and a negligent accident matters here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33389972708.0" user="bushcrapping" delta="False">
    <text>Well most human beings do feel that urge for primal revenge and I promise you if people lose faith in the justice system you would not like the consequences of the vigilantism that ensued. It’s not just suffering for suffering sake. 
&amp;gt;
Definitely important that it was an accident and I wouldn’t advocate for locking her up for decades but her actions caused the death of another human and she should serve some form of punitive punishment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
