<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="869470252.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ednrjg/cmv_anna_sacoolas_should_return_to_the_uk/">
    <title>CMV: Anna Sacoolas should return to the UK voluntarily and face trial</title>
    <original_poster>VertigoOne</original_poster>
    <original_post>For those unfamiliar with this incident, Anna Sacoolas is the partner of an American consular official based in the UK. She was driving on the wrong side of the road and caused a traffic accident which killed a 19 year old on a motorcycle in Northamptonshire. Following this incident, she fled the country under what was believed at the time to be diplomatic immunity. This was back in October 2019. Since then, it has been determined that she did not in fact have diplomatic immunity because she was only the partner of a consular official, and she was based outside of London.  

Recently the UK's Crown Prosecution Service have determined that the evidence is sufficient that she could be charged with the offence of "Causing Death by Dangerous Driving". They have now begun extradition processes. The maximum penalty for an offence of this kind could be 14 years in prison.

Representatives of Ms Sacoolas have described the incident as "a terrible but unintentional accident" and argues that the charge and potential sentencing is "disproportionate".

The reason I think she should return to the UK is pretty simple.

She did it.

No one is disputing that she was driving on the wrong side of the road.

Failing to obey a road traffic law out of ignorance is bad enough, but you don't need to be married to a consular official to know that the UK drives on the other side of the road to the US. She can't have been ignorant. She can have been negligent.

The fourteen year jail sentence is the maximum. Not the expected result. Although refusing to face justice is likely to increase, rather than decrease, the sentence length. Also, it isn't the job of Americans to interpret what is and is not 'proportionate' in the British legal system.

Even if she had diplomatic immunity, it is not a literal "everything-proof shield". It's purpose is to prevent diplomats being taken advantage of by another nation's laws. It's not there to let diplomats get away with serious crimes.

If the situation were inverted, there's not really any way that the US would tolerate the UK holding a British diplomat who left the country under mistaken diplomatic immunity.

Why should she be able to perpetually take advantage of a mistake and not face justice? She committed a crime. No one is disputing that. It doesn't matter if the crime was done by accident or not.

Criminals should be tried and punished according to the legal system.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33348773791.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; She did it.

That's terrible logic. If that's how we are doing things, we should do away with the legal system as well, and just let the criminals confess and get arrested voluntarily. Let's see how that goes, shall we?

&amp;gt; Why should she be able to perpetually take advantage of a mistake and not face justice?

&amp;gt; Criminals should be tried and punished according to the legal system.

That's how the legal system operates. At every step in the process between the crime and punishment, there are certain duties that have to be fulfilled, and failure to do so gives the incorrect outcome. No other part of the process has the burden of rectifying the others. The only way around that is to correct the point of failure, not some naive assumption that people bypass the point of failure completely. 

This is not an extraordinary situation either. For example, defense lawyers can try their best to protect the accused because they can expect the prosecutor to be competent enough to win if the collected evidence is sufficient, regardless of how good the defense is. The prosecutor doesn't need to concern about whether the criminal is guilty or not, because they can expect the relevant authorities to collect enough evidence for the right judgement, and for the defense to be competent enough to prevent the government from railroading the accused.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348784249.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's terrible logic. If that's how we are doing things, we should do away with the legal system as well, and just let the criminals confess and get arrested voluntarily. Let's see how that goes, shall we?

If a criminal admits to a crime, and their is substantive evidence that they committed the crime, then running from prosecution is wrong.

&amp;gt;That's how the legal system operates. At every step in the process between the crime and punishment, there are certain duties that have to be fulfilled, and failure to do so gives the incorrect outcome.

The purpose of the legal system is to determine if a law has been broken and who it has been broken by. Both facts are not in doubt. If you have evidence that a crime has been committed, and evidence that you know who the crime has been committed by, enough evidence to go to trial at least, then that person should be tried. Where is the break down in the logic here?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348843245.0" user="therudestpastor" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;If a criminal admits to a crime, and their is substantive evidence that they committed the crime, then running from prosecution is wrong.

This is always wrong. Her accusations that sentencing is exaggerated and whatnot is basic legalese for trying to weasel out of facing prosecution from the CPS by claiming the punishment is cruel.

&amp;gt; The purpose of the legal system is to determine if a law has been broken and who it has been broken by. Both facts are not in doubt. If you have evidence that a crime has been committed, and evidence that you know who the crime has been committed by, enough evidence to go to trial at least, then that person should be tried. Where is the break down in the logic here? 

I think you're now arguing for extradition here? A quick Google search tells me it might be in the works for the CPS to proceed with the request for it but there are other political matters at play here which may be putting a wrench in the gears.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348894003.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think you're now arguing for extradition here? A quick Google search tells me it might be in the works for the CPS to proceed with the request for it but there are other political matters at play here which may be putting a wrench in the gears.

I'm arguing that since she doesn't dispute the crimes, the only reason she has for being in the US is "I don't want to go to prison".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353085702.0" user="aintscurrdscars" delta="False">
    <text>you're confusing the normal civvie procedures with procedures involving multiple countries.

no due process is being avoided except by the suspect (who hasn't denied guilt)

totes extraditable and prosecutable with the evidence at hand, and then it's up to the country with beef to finish the judicials.

i feel like you're just arguing to argue here, not to change any minds</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33354318422.0" user="therudestpastor" delta="False">
    <text>How so?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33349038451.0" user="Arctus9819" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If a criminal admits to a crime, and their is substantive evidence that they committed the crime, then running from prosecution is wrong.

Confessions can't be forced? Evidence can't be fabricated? You're missing the whole point of having due process.

&amp;gt; The purpose of the legal system is to determine if a law has been broken and who it has been broken by. Both facts are not in doubt. 

No, that's only one subsection of the legal system. You're missing out on the entire evidence collection, arrest and charging process that occurs beforehand, and the sentencing/appeals that occurs afterwards. Failure at any part of that process breaks the whole process, no matter what the other parts of the process say. 

Just think of a scenario where the defense lawyer knows that his client is guilty because his client told him (and only him). A part of the legal system then knows whether a law was broken and who broke it (via a confession), but it means jack squat because revealing that is not his role in the legal system. 

Likewise, Anna Socoolas' role in the legal system is to want her freedom no matter what, and she has no duty to do anything else just because those who are supposed to stop her failed to do so.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
