<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="869470252.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ednrjg/cmv_anna_sacoolas_should_return_to_the_uk/">
    <title>CMV: Anna Sacoolas should return to the UK voluntarily and face trial</title>
    <original_poster>VertigoOne</original_poster>
    <original_post>For those unfamiliar with this incident, Anna Sacoolas is the partner of an American consular official based in the UK. She was driving on the wrong side of the road and caused a traffic accident which killed a 19 year old on a motorcycle in Northamptonshire. Following this incident, she fled the country under what was believed at the time to be diplomatic immunity. This was back in October 2019. Since then, it has been determined that she did not in fact have diplomatic immunity because she was only the partner of a consular official, and she was based outside of London.  

Recently the UK's Crown Prosecution Service have determined that the evidence is sufficient that she could be charged with the offence of "Causing Death by Dangerous Driving". They have now begun extradition processes. The maximum penalty for an offence of this kind could be 14 years in prison.

Representatives of Ms Sacoolas have described the incident as "a terrible but unintentional accident" and argues that the charge and potential sentencing is "disproportionate".

The reason I think she should return to the UK is pretty simple.

She did it.

No one is disputing that she was driving on the wrong side of the road.

Failing to obey a road traffic law out of ignorance is bad enough, but you don't need to be married to a consular official to know that the UK drives on the other side of the road to the US. She can't have been ignorant. She can have been negligent.

The fourteen year jail sentence is the maximum. Not the expected result. Although refusing to face justice is likely to increase, rather than decrease, the sentence length. Also, it isn't the job of Americans to interpret what is and is not 'proportionate' in the British legal system.

Even if she had diplomatic immunity, it is not a literal "everything-proof shield". It's purpose is to prevent diplomats being taken advantage of by another nation's laws. It's not there to let diplomats get away with serious crimes.

If the situation were inverted, there's not really any way that the US would tolerate the UK holding a British diplomat who left the country under mistaken diplomatic immunity.

Why should she be able to perpetually take advantage of a mistake and not face justice? She committed a crime. No one is disputing that. It doesn't matter if the crime was done by accident or not.

Criminals should be tried and punished according to the legal system.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33348749315.0" user="Trimestrial" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Even if she had diplomatic immunity, it is not a literal "everything-proof shield". It's purpose is to prevent diplomats being taken advantage of by another nation's laws. It's not there to let diplomats get away with serious crimes.

That's exactly what diplomatic immunity is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348774835.0" user="VertigoOne" delta="False">
    <text>This is a "technically correct" situation. The reality is very different.

Technically speaking, diplomats can get away with murder. However when there is substantive evidence, it is expected that the country sending the diplomat will relinquish diplomatic immunity. In a functional sense, this is only a marginal addition to the burden of proof logic when it comes to serious crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348822087.0" user="Trimestrial" delta="False">
    <text>The US could have waived her immunity. I think they should have. But they didn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353950181.0" user="Tenushi" delta="False">
    <text>Is it not true then that she didn't actually have diplomatic immunity then? If she didn't, then this point is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33348825346.0" user="therudestpastor" delta="False">
    <text>This has happened before so it's no longer technical speech. I believe Jamal Kashoggi was murdered in Turkey and his body was found chopped to pieces in the diplomat's home. The diplomat just fled back to his home country and he never faced justice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33349077472.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>He has been murdered in the Saudi embassy in Istanbul. So technically a Saudi was murdered on Saudi territory by Saudis. Now that's still murder and given that it was allegedly ordered by the crown prince himself that's a highly political topic. Though as Turkey is in NATO and Saudi Arabia is an "ally" in that region and given that Trump has already announced that he won't stop arms trafficking to Saudi Arabia nothing probably nothing will come from that, because none of the involved has a vested interest in justice.

However if idk a Turkish journalist would have been killed in the Saudi embassy like that or if a diplomat were to be killed on inside or outside their embassy, that can be a reason for sanctions, dropping of diplomatic contacts or even war. So idk if the U.S. had taken responsibility for Kashoggi as he lived in exile in the U.S. for some time, that would have been reason for sanctions and so on. 

So it kind of depends on how serious the crime and how willing to countries are to jeopardize their relations over such a crime. But I guess most would rather hand over their diplomats then to risk a war if it was a personal failure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353048329.0" user="aintscurrdscars" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds to me like she and her partner constitute "lower ranking officials" and that these crimes are definitely punishable and extraditable

&amp;gt;Lower-ranking officials have a weaker type of protection called “functional immunity.” These officials are covered only for crimes committed within the scope of their regular work responsibilities. **If, for example, a consular official** got into a fistfight during a meeting with a U.S. official, he would be protected from prosecution. **If the fight occurred at a bar over the weekend, he would not.** Service staff for an embassy or consulate, from the kitchen employees to the valets, have no immunity whatsoever. **And, contrary to popular belief, any diplomat can be issued a traffic citation. They just can’t be forced to pay it.** (See the State Department’s breakdown of immunity levels [here] (https://www.state.gov/privileges-and-immunities/) .)

https://slate.com/news-and-politics/2010/04/how-far-does-diplomatic-immunity-go.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353363173.0" user="Snowdmania" delta="False">
    <text>She’s not a diplomat, nor is her husband. So diplomatic immunity is irrelevant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353373707.0" user="Trimestrial" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have any source that states, she didn't have a diplomatic passport, or diplomatic immunity?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33353880775.0" user="Snowdmania" delta="False">
    <text>Its mainly just what I’ve gathered over following the news instead of one specific source. I’ve edited this post a bit and tried to add in at least a few news articles.

Her husband is not a known diplomat and [apparently](https://www.lbcnews.co.uk/uk-news/dominic-raab-urges-us-to-reconsider-immunity-for-d/) his name does not appear on the UKs official registers of diplomats. He works at a base where no diplomats work and the exact nature of what happens at the base is undisclosed. He’s suspected to be a spy. Where things get legally fuzzy is there’s apparently a secret agreement between the US and UK foreign office which grants special immunity to spies working at certain intelligence bases. Harry’s family are suing the UK foreign office. [They claim](https://www.standard.co.uk/news/uk/harry-dunns-parents-launch-legal-action-against-foreign-office-which-could-cost-family-upwards-of-a4298651.html) that foreign office had no legal power to make a secret agreement and that they were shown the the secret agreement but it makes no mention of immunity for family members. Freedom of information requests to reveal the secret agreement to the public have been rejected, the foreign office originally told local police to not tell the family she had been allowed to leave the country and imo it all just seems like one big cover up. The foreign offices current position is that it doesn’t really matter as now she has left so whatever immunity she had is no longer relevant and they have requested her extradition.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
