<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="87228342.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fxlti/true_privacy_has_always_been_imagined_our_only/">
    <title>True privacy has always been imagined. Our only concern should be right to due process; everyting else is a distraction. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>PomerGyle</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most of us aren't as sneaky as we think. So, our concept of "privacy" has always been more of a feigned ignorance by our peers, dependents, and authority figures. Restated, it is more likely than not, that in the chaos of our lives, we've let slip each of our dirty little secrets at one point or another. Therefore, perceived violations of privacy are a violation of our imagination.

The judiciary has been tasked with declaring what facts can be brought in support of our guilt or innocence. So, our primary concern should not be keeping secrets but rather, ensuring our right to a fair trial. Outrage over privacy violations feels good but it serves nothing.

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26750871132.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Violation of privacy IS violation of due process. Due process requires that you be served a warrant in order for evidence to be used in court. If a cop has to have a warrant to collect photos or your diary for use in court, why doesn't your wife have to in a divorce? It is a violation unless you have given permission for her to see AND use it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26750910266.0" user="PomerGyle" delta="False">
    <text>I think we actually agree. My point was that we are sloppy secret-keepers by nature and due process is the check on our shortcomings in this regard. Who cares what the government knows as long as they can't prosecute me for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26750939327.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Who cares what the government knows as long as they can't prosecute me for it.

In what sense? The court of public opinion is always accepting new cases, and can dole out just as much punishment, if not more, than its legal counterpart.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751087829.0" user="PomerGyle" delta="False">
    <text>Well said. Although, I would say the problem with the court of public opinion is more the lack of fair-mindedness rather than the lack of privacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751096734.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>Was speaking more toward the potential for the information to be used in a manner seperate from legal ramifications. In most cases it's easier to have the person ostracized than thrown in prison.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751108153.0" user="PomerGyle" delta="False">
    <text>Very true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751022822.0" user="Van_Devious" delta="False">
    <text>[this](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1fv4r6/i_believe_the_government_should_be_allowed_to/caeb3pl) comment made earlier by /u/161719 might be relevant</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751093250.0" user="PomerGyle" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, very. But, while I agree that his warning to us is relevant I find it difficult to prove that is definitely where we're headed. What evidence would you argue suggests that we are?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26752339975.0" user="Van_Devious" delta="False">
    <text>you ask the wrong man. /u/161719 had the insight. i merely noticed the relevance and timing. i could only guess to point to history. ideally history shows us mistakes we might one day learn to not repeat.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
