<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="87315525.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fzh39/i_for_one_would_rather_have_security_over_privacy/">
    <title>I for one would rather have security over privacy CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Gedalya</original_poster>
    <original_post>With all the controversy about the NSA spying on US citizens one quote that has been used very often was &amp;gt;People willing to trade their freedom for temporary security deserve neither and will lose both. -Benjamin Franklin.
Here's my issues with that statement. 
* Freedom is relative, as long as you live in a civilized society you are are never really free. 
*&amp;gt;* Lets say we truly trust the government, what will you propose we should do about the threats we are facing? 
 </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26751752577.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>Take a gander at this. (The post by /u/161719)

http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1fv4r6/i_believe_the_government_should_be_allowed_to/caeb3pl?context=3

This should sum it all up, Gedalya.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751771278.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>I've read it several times the past two days, It's been linked everywhere. It doesn't really answer my question. Lets say his illustration is accurate and it's as simple and plausible as he makes it sound, I still would rather live under an oppressed government then under the threat of getting killed any moment of the day. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751780206.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>So you'd rather go to prison and be tortured because you went to a protest than you would have the (extremely unlikely) possibility of being killed by a mentally unstable man? I really don't see the logic in this, if you want to be safe just move to Canada or something. You sound just like someone who helped DESIGN the whole PRISM catastrophe, you know?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751832683.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>How about this?
I'd rather go to prison for a day(extremely unlikely) while the gov makes sure I am no threat to the safety of the people than to have myself blown into tiny pieces of bloody flesh. 
Or maybe I sound like someone who didn't grow up with a huge "MURICA" sign above my bed and just doesn't get it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751856274.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>The only problem with that is that, ONE, you don't like privacy? Who the hell wants someone playing big brother to be watching you? TWO, it won't be like that. Maybe at first, but if it keeps happening eventually the US will become a Dystopian country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751927094.0" user="skyence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if it keeps happening

If what keeps happening?

&amp;gt; eventually

This could mean tomorrow or a hundred years from now. Any thoughts on a concrete time frame?

&amp;gt; the US will become a Dystopian country

Could you please clarify what you mean by "Dystopian country"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26752012188.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;if it keeps happening

If things like PRISM and what-not keep happening.

&amp;gt;This could mean tomorrow or a hundred years from now. Any thoughts on a concrete time frame?

It might not be now, but assuming the above keeps taking place (and progressively gets worse) it'll probably be 20-50 years.

&amp;gt;Could you please clarify what you mean by "Dystopian country"?

ಠ_ಠ Really? Call it what you like, America is trying to become a 'safe' place by becoming a police state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751815705.0" user="Nomaki" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I still would rather live under an oppressed government then under the threat of getting killed any moment of the day.

The chance of you being killed at any moment of the day by a terrorist are so astronomically small compared to say:

* Being killed by cancer
* Getting hit by a car
* Tripping over your own feet and breaking your neck

and thousands of over things.

Why should you, and every other person in the United States *(and soon us over here in the UK)* have to live under the scenario outlined by /u/161719 just because there is a phenomenally tiny chance that some equally tiny percentage of people might be killed by some mentally unstable bloke who has a grudge against a nation?

Even then, the Boston Bombings and other attacks show that even with these measures in place, attacks still happen, and always will no matter how much control the government attempt to exert.

It isn't the terrorists who are affected, they just use alternative methods to bypass the system. It's the millions of innocents who are terrorised by the government instead who suffer.

Why not, then, invest those billions spent on sifting through everyone's emails to stop the 0.0001% chance of an attack killing maybe 100, or awfully, 1000, on finding better ways to detect and treat cancer?

Are the lives of those hundreds of thousand of people who die from cancer worth less than the few who may be involved in a terror attack?

*(This probably has come out as a stream of rambling and probably hasn't had any impact on your view, but I felt the need to pour my mind out. Hopefully some of it sparks a debate of some sort!)*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751838995.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>Terrorism is not about how many killed or suffered. It's about living in a constant fear knowing you might get killed out of nowhere. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751856738.0" user="Nomaki" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly, but you're saying your fear of being part of one of those 0.0001% outweighs the fear of everyone else at being arrested at any time for whatever reason the government might glean from your emails, post and phone.

I feel worried when I see a police car whilst I'm driving, not because I know I'm breaking any laws, but I'm worried I *might* be breaking some small, buried law somewhere which I didn't even know *was* a law, but the chap in the police car might be having a slow day and needs to meet today's quota of "Bad Guys Got" and pull be over for having my headlights aimed too low in contravene of section 4.1.3.a (i) of the Highways Act 1987.

Exactly same for this. My fear of terrorism is far below my fear of being visited by the police because in one of my emails I sent last week to my friend, I expressed wanting to punch some guy who'd been a dick to me at the pub the other night, thus contraveneing section 4.1.2 of t the Malicious Electronic Communications clause of the Internet Communication 1994 bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751858193.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>If you're living in fear like you just described, you need help.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751893396.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>No, terrorism is about causing fear.  If you live in fear of dying form a terrorist attack, *the terrorists have already won.*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751823777.0" user="Pups_the_Jew" delta="False">
    <text>You compare the two as if they are equally likely, or maybe just two sides to the same coin.

An oppressive government curbs your behavior in ongoing aspects of your life, multiple times a day. This can affect travel, business transactions, behavior in relationships, recreational activities, political organizing, journalism, and countless other areas. 

Even if you believe that you can continue to act in the same way, or close enough to the same way, it is indisputable that you are living in a situation where that can change without any ability on your part to bring it back without considerable effort.

Add to this also, the immense costs associated with building and maintaining such an infrastructure. 

On the other side of the coin, there is the minute possibility that you or someone you know will be hurt in a terrorist attack. A possibility which will NEVER be brought to zero, regardless of how much of our freedoms we are willing to trade for increased safety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751773682.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>Besides. His biggest weakness is the fact that we have the Internet. We don't need mainstream newspapers to tell us what's going on in the world. Any whistleblower can voice his/her opinion on there and no one can really stop it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751804221.0" user="dazhealy" delta="False">
    <text>Except whistleblowers don't just tell the story and move on with their lives. Bradley Manning is on trial, Julian Assange has been living in a converted office in the Ecadorian Embassy in London for 354 days. There are hundreds of others (not just connected to wikileaks), who have lost their jobs, reputations and freedom because of whitleblowing. People do attempt to stop them and discredit them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751807366.0" user="Nomaki" delta="False">
    <text>There's whistleblowing and public information about atrocities and all manner of awful things almost all the time, and the same thing always happens:

* **Information is leaked**
* **People are outraged**, call for change
* **Whistleblower gets arrested**, and probably charged for all manner of things *(treason etc, think Bradley Manning being solitarily confined and treated in manners which contravene many human rights, another thing which is public yet no one cares)*
* After a couple of weeks, the **public consciousness moves on** to something else to be angry about *(corporate tax evasion, gay marriage, some other political scandal)*
* **Everyone forgets** about event 

Rinse and repeat.

Social media - whilst being an extremely valuable and important tool for exposing corruption, failures and such - isn't an ultimate weapon.
Information is freely available about lots of terrible things, but the problem is **no one cares** after the initial period of outrage.

* Bradley Manning exposed war crimes by America in Iraq / Afghanistan, shooting at civilians, then attempting to suppress the information. Everyone was horrified and angry, now? No one really remembers it or is doing anything about it.

* Guantanamo Bay is still open and being used, despite the massive torture controversy surrounding it. No one is really angry about it any more, because they're too busy being angry about this NSA business.

And many more.

Social media does not free us from corruption or police state.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
