<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="87315525.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1fzh39/i_for_one_would_rather_have_security_over_privacy/">
    <title>I for one would rather have security over privacy CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Gedalya</original_poster>
    <original_post>With all the controversy about the NSA spying on US citizens one quote that has been used very often was &amp;gt;People willing to trade their freedom for temporary security deserve neither and will lose both. -Benjamin Franklin.
Here's my issues with that statement. 
* Freedom is relative, as long as you live in a civilized society you are are never really free. 
*&amp;gt;* Lets say we truly trust the government, what will you propose we should do about the threats we are facing? 
 </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26751721437.0" user="Amarkov" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Lets say we truly trust the government, what will you propose we should do about the threats we are facing?

This is a silly question. Even if you trust the government *now*, it's just silly to believe that the government will never try to do something shitty. All historical evidence points against that. That's the problem with giving up privacy for security; eventually the government will try to abuse that lack of privacy, and it's a lot harder to go the other direction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751726002.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>Yes makes perfect sense. So now I am asking how would **you** act in such a situation, you were being elected by the people to protect them and there's this terrorist group trying again and again to hurt your constituents </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751727414.0" user="Amarkov" delta="False">
    <text>The same way as we do, except minus all the collecting data on random civilians part?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751741270.0" user="Gedalya" delta="False">
    <text>So where do we draw the line? what about spying on suspects?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751812067.0" user="322955469" delta="False">
    <text>We draw the line with a warrant, before the police (or any government agency) can spy on anyone the should be required to obtain a warrent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751831152.0" user="322955469" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;and there's this terrorist group trying again and again to hurt your constituents

I think you are significantly overestimating the risk that terrorism poses, the chance of dying in a terrorist attack in the USA is about [1 in 20,000,000](http://swampland.time.com/2013/05/06/chances-of-dying-in-a-terrorist-attack-number/).  To put that in perspective, the odds that you will some time in you life be struck by lighitning are about [1 in 10,000](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightning_strike#Epidemiology). No sane person would advocate installing an oppressive government to combat the risk of lightning strikes, thus peoples seeming willingness to sacrifice there freedom to reduce the insignificant risk of terror atacks is pure irrationality (specifically the [availability heuristic](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Availability_heuristic)).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26751857367.0" user="DmitryStrelnikov" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, this nailed it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
