<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="873579806.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/eg3uhq/cmv_skwovet_is_just_british_bidoof/">
    <title>CMV: Skwovet is just British Bidoof</title>
    <original_poster>ShaddowFox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I mean, just look at this damn thing. It's all poofy and useless. It's like Bidoof just stood on two feet and poofed it's tail. It's everywhere, like tree herpes. And all it does is get in the way and steal my berries. You know who else always showed up to ruin my good time? **Bidoof**, that's right! I bet you can also guess what gangster is rolling the same typing with a similar stat spread? ^Bidoof. Skwovet is terrible. You know who has the same dentist as Bidoof? I mean, it's Greedent... but it still counts!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33384399134.0" user="Azkorath" delta="False">
    <text>What makes Skwovet the British version of Bidoof?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33384838772.0" user="ShaddowFox" delta="False">
    <text>Well. In every generation there's kind of a Bidoof spot. Typically normal type. They're incredibly common toward the beginning of your journey. You see them frequently enough, they get annoying.

* Gen 1 = Rattata
* Gen 2 = Sentret
* Gen 3 = Zigzagoon
* Gen 4 = **Bidoof**
* Gen 5 = Patrat
* Gen 6 = Bunelby (I think. 🤔)
* Gen 7 = Yungoos
* Gen 8 = Skwovet

Galar is based on the UK, with the map focusing on the island of Great Britain when viewed from the north. 

Skwovet being from Galar, I jus used British because I'm a bit drunk and being silly.

edit: had to fix tha list formatting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33385413259.0" user="Morasain" delta="False">
    <text>You literally just listed why you're right, and everyone already knows about this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33386245478.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>Technically, that would make Skwovet British Rattata, not British Bidoof.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33390116628.0" user="pillbinge" delta="False">
    <text>That means Skwovet is the British Bidoof/Rattata, not the other way around.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
