<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="87538882.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1g49fm/i_dont_find_bo_burnham_to_be_funny_cmv/">
    <title>I don't find Bo Burnham to be funny. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>thisburritoisgoodbut</original_poster>
    <original_post>(sorry in advance for the lack of brevity) A lot of people seem to love Bill Burr and I've tried to get into his comedy but it's kind of painful (in truth, I've seen maybe like 3/4 of one special, can't remember which). He's just kind of ranting about various topics that most of the time could be interesting except he's not making any jokes, he just kind of says stuff with some profanities sprinkled in there for good measure (but it never shocks me like it's supposed to). There aren't any actual jokes, no real wit. I feel like I'm taking crazy pills when I watch with other people, because it's as if they're on auto pilot, laughing at nothing in particular when they feel like they're supposed to, rather than because Bo *made* them laugh.. Someone explain to me what it is that I'm missing (if anything)

I also see Lisa Lampanelli in the same vein.. I see what she's trying to do but she's not making me laugh!

I'm far from an expert but I watch a decent amount of stand-up comedians. I don't believe myself to be a particularly funny person, but I try to appreciate the art that goes into stand-up, and I get a kick out of watching a comedian develop their own style of jokes, their own "character". I find that my favorite comedy usually has some point to make. I don't care if it's about something political, religious, sexual, clean or dirty, etc. if the comedian makes their point well and makes me laugh, they'll win my favor.

For reference, some of my favorite comedians are (in no particular order): Louis C.K., Dave Chappelle, George Carlin, Mitch Hedburg, Brian Regan, Steven Wright, Mike Birbiglia, Kevin Hart, Demitri Martin, Frank Caliendo (before his impressions got played out), to name a few of the top of my head.

EDIT: just realized a ridiculous mistake on my part.. This whole time I've been using the name Bo Burnham, BUT I MEANT WAS BILL BURR!!!  &amp;gt;_&amp;lt;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26753977187.0" user="conceptalbum" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There aren't any actual jokes, no real wit.

This is saying "he isn't funny", which is something completely different from "He doesn't make ME laugh, therefore I don't find him funny." I personally don't find him to be funny either, but that's because of my taste in comedy. It is ridiculous to claim that a joke is not an 'actual' joke, simply because it doesn't make you laugh. Who are you to decide that something objectively isn't funny, because you don't find it funny?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
