<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764284832.0" user="JoCoLaRedux" delta="False">
    <text>Occupy failed because:

* It suffered from a delusional sense of self-worth and self-entitlement, which dictated that if they just showed up and yelled loud enough &amp;amp; long enough, then Mr. Wall Street would finally emerge from his penthouse, then pull a white, silk hankie from his Armani suit, wave it around in the air and surrender. I think this also drives the "OWS failed because of government crackdown" narrative. It makes the movement's shortcoming more excusable, more self-glorifying and romantic to think they were dangerous enough to have been destroyed by Big Brother. Did they receive resistance from authorities? Abusive treatment, even? Definitely, but we're not exactly talking about Tienanmen Square here. A lot of cities did their best to accommodate OWS, and for a long time at that.


* A hefty dose of radical chic. The 60's counter-culture has been so glorified by Baby Boomers that protesting has a trendy, vapid appeal, and OWS ended up being sleep-away camp for a lot of weekend radicals who were suffering from protest envy of The Arab Spring.


* Cognitive dissonance: The movement de-fanged itself from the get-go by placing a disproportionate amount of emphasis on the corporate half of the corporatism equation, which is sort of like protesting a PB&amp;amp;J while only yelling at the jelly. Why? Well, because they couldn't rightly go after government and overlook the present Corporatist in Chief, and if I remember correctly, according to one survey, something like 48% of Zuccoti Park OWS would vote for Obama again. If you want a better idea of the partisanship at hand, remember that the OWS protests occurred just a couple weeks after the al-Zahawi assassination. If those protests had occurred 4 years earlier and that had happened, you just know there would be an ocean of anti-Bush placards present. How many anti-Obama signs do you remember seeing at OWS?

So what else could they do? Where else would they focus their efforts, really? Protest each and every corporation, one at a time? The only option they left themselves was to stay put and let the whole thing get bogged down in the three P's: Protesters, Pepper spray and Parks. And all the while, fucking winter is coming and they have no contingency plan beyond expecting people to tough it out. Just hang tight and hold the parks forever, I guess. 

You can only do that for so long before the movement starts to look less like the lunch counter protests of the civil rights movement and starts to resemble the pouty toddler who refuses to leave Chuck E. Cheese's and has to be carried out baby-tantrum style.


* Kicking their own ass with their own distorted values: To quote Matt Taibbis 2007 column, *The Left's Silly Victim Complex:

"We all know where this stuff comes from. Anyone who’s ever been to a lefty political meeting knows the deal – the problem is the “spirit of inclusiveness” stretched to the limits of absurdity. The post-sixties dogma that everyone’s viewpoint is legitimate, everyone‘s choice about anything (lifestyle, gender, ethnicity, even class) is valid, that’s now so totally ingrained that at every single meeting, every time some yutz gets up and starts rambling about anything, no matter how ridiculous, no one ever tells him to shut the fuck up. Next thing you know, you’ve got guys on stilts wearing mime makeup and Cat-in-the-Hat striped top-hats leading a half-million people at an anti-war rally. Why is that guy there? Because no one told him that war is a matter of life and death and that he should leave his fucking stilts at home."

Now transfer that same mentality to OWS' General Assembly, where everybody gets a say in everything, because everyone is equal, and there's no leaders, maaaan...you end up waiting weeks for them to issue statements that are laundry lists of demands &amp;amp; grievances that mention everything from colonialism to free college, and just generally sound like they were drafted by dorm full of first year-liberal arts students in between bong hits. Without leaders, spokespeople and nobody to effectively respond to media, Joe Lunchpail is left completely in the dark. I have a pretty large, fairly well-educated and aware family. When the subject came up at Christmas, nobody could tell you what OWS was about.

I think we'll look back at OWS the same way we look back at Hands Across America: something that was well-intentioned at the time and might have done a little bit of good, but is thoroughly wince-inducing in retrospect.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764388217.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand what you mean when you say, "self entitlement" with regards to the protest. Example? I agree with you that Occupy's execution was awful. Their lofty ideals were impossible to meet, because they were fragmented and each would require its own protest to gain any traction in getting carried out. I get that. 

But again, I don't see immediate implementation of these solutions as the overarching success off Occupy: Coming together and raising grievances against a very broken system is, to me, meaningful and significant. Execution of the pie-in-the-sky solutions couldn't happen via Occupy, but by individuals taking steps outside of the protest. Want more unions rights? Sign up with that nonprofit you met fighting for that very cause. Want an alternative currency that's not controlled by the central banks? try bitcoin. Want affordable food options? Grow a community garden and shop at a farmer's market. I appreciate that Occupy served as an opportunity for people to cross-pollinate with these various movements and meet with like-minded people. Maybe this sounds flowery, but I think it would be unrealistic to expect anything else. 

I think part of the reason people view Occupy as a failure is because we expect INSTANT results. Movements and revolutions take decades. And that's okay. The fomentation of ideas is what defines Occupy as a success--even if these ideas are not novel, we haven't seen so many people from all over the world fighting for their implementation in quite some time. It's utterly inspiring to know that I'm not crazy for thinking the bailouts were little more than looting of our coffers, considering it wasn't like the mainstream media was telling me that. It's inspiring for the unemployed student to know that they're not lazy, but it's really damn hard to find jobs. Hell, even the simple act of people making a free meal for each other is uplifting. When every other source is telling the people, "relax, everything's okay," it's refreshing to see worldwide outbreaks indicating that the system's broken and needs reform. I don't expect solutions from these mass gatherings, only that we should seek to find them. That's what made Occupy significant for me. 

Occupy will, however, be meaningless for those who saw it as a beginning, end, and subsequent failure. I took away a lot of solutions: I've strengthened my resolve not to buy from big box stores. The Rolling Jubilee is an AMAZING project that seeks debt forgiveness by buying back bad loans traded for pennies on the dollar in shadow markets. I give grants for community garden projects. Occupy highlighted the real need to contribute to these things. Will Joe Lunchpail take away these lessons? Maybe not, but that's like not being able to see what he was supposed to learn from college because he didn't know which classes to take. Occupy had amazing ideas and some amazing minds at that protest. Not just the dude on stilts but professors, journalists, long-time activists.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764733769.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't understand what you mean when you say, "self entitlement" with regards to the protest. Example?

Well those horrifically embarrassing signs that people liked to take pictures of themselves holding would be one of the most obvious.  "I spent my life savings playing a carnival game, and all I got was this stuffed banana with dreadlocks.  **I am the 99%**."   God, if I ever do anything that publicly embarrassing I'll kill myself.  Their whole "message" was basically presented as "those people are rich, I'm not, therefore I'm no longer showering and will be standing in this park near the drum circle for a bit".  There was zero content, and a healthy serving of "I don't like that those people have a lot of money"...that's about it.

&amp;gt; I don't see immediate implementation of these solutions as the overarching success off Occupy

The real problem is that we are not dealing with a "movement" that fought for solutions and failed, but rather something which never really stood for any solutions to begin with.  They didn't *even* fail.  Failing would at least be respectable.  A movement has goals, and they were no movement.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
