<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764314475.0" user="suddenly_mozzarella" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy!

&amp;gt; 3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.

It's a stretch to presume any kind of meaningful causal connection between OWS and events in Turkey and Brazil. "Young people are protesting against the government" isn't exactly something that's never happened before OWS. Besides, if you *are* going to presume a causal connection between OWS and Turkey/Brazil, then there should also be a similar causal connection between the Arab Spring and OWS. All by itself, that fact nixes your claim of originality.

The difference is that the Arab Spring actually changed things (how *much* things changed and whether it has been for the better is up for debate), and so far, neither OWS nor the Turkish protests have done a damn thing to upset the established power structures in those countries. In the case of Turkey, it's probably only going to make things worse, because Erdoğan is quietly setting himself up as a neo-fascist dictator. Some Brazilian cities reverted their bus fare increases today, which is really all they needed to do to shut the whole thing down. Now anyone who keeps protesting can be painted as a malcontent.

&amp;gt; 4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.

This is kinda what protesters have been doing since forever. OWS didn't invent "hell no, we won't go".

&amp;gt; 5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement.

OWS didn't plant any those seeds either, and it didn't even *re*-plant them well, due to the total incoherence of the movement. Bartering has been around since the dawn of civilization, and it happens *en masse* at Burning Man every year with no political undertones at all. The ancient Greeks used direct democracy at some points in their history, and frankly, direct democracy is A) pretty much logistically impossible in a modern industrial nation of 375 million citizens and B) wouldn't actually change very much. "Buy local" has been a thing since at least the 1950s, and has been a fundamental component of pretty much every left-leaning grassroots ideology for as long as I can remember (and it's not even unique to the left, either: "buy American"). And 90% of the people who whine about the failure of the two-party system are just going to vote Democrat or Republican anyways, because that's how American politics works.

&amp;gt; 6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kent_State_shootings  
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jackson_State_killings  
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orangeburg_massacre  
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/COINTELPRO

And that's just the stuff I can remember off the top of my head right now. It's pure historical ignorance to claim that OWS is even *close* to the first time the government has used counterintelligence or violence to control a domestic activist movement, and even worse than ignorance to claim that such a thing would have been thought "absurd" before OWS.

I'm probably 15 years older than the average age of the Zucotti Park protesters, and COINTELPRO operations were leaked to the public six years before *I* was born. If you want to form a worthwhile opinion on the impact of popular protesting in the US, there's absolutely no excuse for knowing nothing about its history.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764350918.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>My reference to Brazil and Turkey isn't to say their issues mirror Occupy's. My point was that I've been reading a ton of Redditor comments and memes saying things like, "Why don't we protest for our rights like they do in Brazil or Turkey? Why are Americans so lazy?" I bring up Occupy to counter the belief that we're unable to create large-scale movements like those we see in other countries today. That's all. 

You seem to be interpreting my statements as Occupy being novel in refutation to points 4 and 5: I'm not saying Occupy invented these things, but brought them to the forefront of debate on a scale not seen since... well, a long time in America. Yes, these concepts existed amongst various demographics (left-leaning ideologues, as you said) but not amongst such a group of differing backgrounds seeking to implement this change in society. In this respect, it differs from Burning Man, as everyone knows this is a one-time, special occasion with no agenda to introduce it outside of said event. But I do like that you mention Burning Man--it's a beautiful example of people peacefully partaking in several of the concepts raised by Occupy. I do, however, disagree that direct democracy can't work: California's referendums have their problems, but they've introduced amazing legislation when people have more of say. Also, I see no reason for the electoral college when it's possible to tally all of the votes individually as opposed to sending someone on horse to speak for a group of people. But direct democracy's feasibility is a bit of a tangent from debating the efficacy of Occupy. 

Also on point 6, look, I'm well-aware of the things you've mentioned. I'm not saying Occupy was the first time such tactics have been used. But if you were to give a survey to the average American about the feasibility of the FBI or CIA doing this to a group before Occupy, many would say something stupid like, "no, that's absurd to think our government would violate privacy like that. They probably only do that to the real fringe groups like the ALF or ELF...and they had it coming, I say!" Do you know what a hard time I had mentioning COINTELPRO to people? Nobody in my circle knew what that meant, and when I explained it, I was very quickly labeled a conspiracy theorist despite the clear evidence. But post-Occupy? Now I bring up police infiltration and I'm met with a bitter cynicism as opposed to ignorance. Again, Occupy brought together a much more diverse group of people, or, cynically, a group of people very seldom targeted by the FBI and CIA before this (white, educated, middle class). G20 summits, perhaps, but Occupy was far greater in scope. Police brutality and police infiltration gave a clear message that their reach isn't just limited to fringe groups, minorities, and political parties, but ANYONE who stands up to the agenda. Though it shouldn't be, given the FBI's history, I think it served as a huge wakeup call to the public that such tactics are the norm and not the exception. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764436960.0" user="suddenly_mozzarella" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I bring up Occupy to counter the belief that we're unable to create large-scale movements like those we see in other countries today. That's all. 

That's not the argument you made in your OP. You were arguing that it was (and I quote) "meaningful and significant", not merely attempting to establish the basic fact of its existence. I agree that it existed, and even that it was large in scale.

&amp;gt; You seem to be interpreting my statements as Occupy being novel in refutation to points 4 and 5: I'm not saying Occupy invented these things, but brought them to the forefront of debate on a scale not seen since... well, a long time in America.

That's precisely what you said. That's what the word "innovative" means. It's a derivative of the word "novel". If that's not what you meant, then you've chosen your words too poorly to convey your thoughts effectively.

The meaning of the words you originally chose directly contradicts what you now claim to have meant. So either you're moving the goalposts, which suggests that you're dishonest, or you're just a sloppy writer, which suggests (per the experience of my many years in academia) that you're a sloppy thinker. Neither of those things leads to effective, worthwhile discussion.

&amp;gt; Yes, these concepts existed amongst various demographics (left-leaning ideologues, as you said) but not amongst such a group of differing backgrounds seeking to implement this change in society.

[OWS protesters](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupy_Wall_Street#Protester_demographics) were young (2/3 under 35), white (82%), college educated (75% with at least a bachelor's), employed (87%) but not *too* employed (only 13% claimed to have incomes greater than $75k/year), and left-leaning (over 80% self-identified as at least moderately liberal). It was a movement populated mostly by precisely the kinds of people — middle class white folks — that you'd expect to populate a liberal movement with no real concrete policy goals.

&amp;gt; Also, I see no reason for the electoral college when it's possible to tally all of the votes individually as opposed to sending someone on horse to speak for a group of people.

There are legitimate criticisms of the electoral college. This is not one of them. I'm not even totally sure what you think you're objecting to, here.

&amp;gt; Do you know what a hard time I had mentioning COINTELPRO to people? Nobody in my circle knew what that meant, and when I explained it, I was very quickly labeled a conspiracy theorist despite the clear evidence.

I think this says more about the people in your circle than it does about anything else. I learned about the Kent state shootings and COINTELPRO in *junior high school*, and not from my parents, or from some other kid, or from the crazy hippie down the street, but from a teacher as part of a scheduled class lesson. It's a pretty well-known facet of American history.

&amp;gt; Police brutality and police infiltration gave a clear message that their reach isn't just limited to fringe groups, minorities, and political parties, but ANYONE who stands up to the agenda.

It's funny how no one ever self-identifies with the word "fringe", isn't it? "They would never do that to *us* because we're just so different from (read: better than) all those crazy wackos they did it to before" is pure magical thinking. Personal exceptionalism at its most naïve.

If you ever find yourself surprised by the lengths an established power structure will go to to maintain its power, then you probably haven't been paying very close attention to A) history, B) your own government, or C) basic human behavior. Popular protest that is both politically effective and largely non-violent is *extremely* rare. Off the top of my head, I can only think of two examples in my lifetime, and both of them happened within a week or so of each other in late 1989: the fall of the Berlin wall (9 November) and the Velvet Revolution that ended in the overthrow of the Czechoslovak communist party (began 17 November).

Outrage is fine. Outrage can be politically effective if channeled properly (which OWS pretty much completely failed to do). Surprise, on the other hand, is pollyannaish, if not outright ignorant.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
