<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764670940.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I support their sentiment, but u feel the lack if a clear message was the doom I the movement. "Cooperations are bad" is not a good enough message. They were disorganized, unfocused and lacked a clear objective. 

Say what you will about the tea party (racist, ignorant, hateful... The list goes on) but atleast they had a message and stuck to it. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
