<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764223717.0" user="damnatu" delta="False">
    <text>When people refer to OWS as a failure they refer to it in regard to tangible results, change in policy etc. OWS was not meaningful because it did not really achieve anything. 

Arguments 2) and 3) boild down to it was meaningful because it was popular. I would not really use that as a useful metric. Moreover, it is a bit American centric of you to assume that you are the inspiration for every protest. I'm pretty sure people in Spain had their own issues to deal with, for instance

4) it seems like it solved a problem for future activists trying to hold future rallies. I fail to see how that is beneficial to the average Joe.

5) These ideas existed before OWS. Some were popular (the failed two party system, buying local) and some are not part of the public discourse becuase they are unfeasable (direct democracy - on a large scale) or because they are retarded (barter). 

6) You assumed the government wouldn't infiltrate a protest? That's rather naive of you.

Overall, I belive that OWS was a complete failure and, while I agree with the sentiment, it failed to produce any real tangible solutions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764250724.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>A movement of that size should have had some tangible results. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764403811.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>Amazing how an 11-word point is perhaps one of the most compelling. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764625513.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think this generation could have been written about in the history books is OWS accomplished something that resulted in a change of course for our society/country. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764311005.0" user="wvtarheel" delta="False">
    <text>The OP changed my view!  Before reading his post I thought Occupy was a pretty big deal, and was a significant political movement of the last few years.  Then after reading what he had to say, and reading some of the comments here, I realize that I am wrong and Occupy was just as big of a waste of time and effort as it seemed to many.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764394888.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like I'm repeating myself with answers, but the refutations seem awfully similar, too.

--If tangible results are your brightline of success, then yes, you would deem Occupy a failure.
--"Popular" in that it was a populist movement, yes. I think that bringing together large numbers of people from diverse backgrounds to raise grievances against society is a great thing.
--No, I don't think Occupy was the inspiration for other protests. What I'm saying is that Americans often whine that they're lazy because they don't protest like Brazil and Turkey: I use Occupy to counter this claim that Americans are too lazy or uninformed to protest.
--As I said to user suddenly_mozzerella, on point 6: "look, I'm well-aware of the things you've mentioned. I'm not saying Occupy was the first time such tactics have been used. But if you were to give a survey to the average American about the feasibility of the FBI or CIA doing this to a group before Occupy, many would say something stupid like, "no, that's absurd to think our government would violate privacy like that. They probably only do that to the real fringe groups like the ALF or ELF...and they had it coming, I say!" Do you know what a hard time I had mentioning COINTELPRO to people? Nobody in my circle knew what that meant, and when I explained it, I was very quickly labeled a conspiracy theorist despite the clear evidence. But post-Occupy? Now I bring up police infiltration and I'm met with a bitter cynicism as opposed to ignorance. Again, Occupy brought together a much more diverse group of people, or, cynically, a group of people very seldom targeted by the FBI and CIA before this (white, educated, middle class). G20 summits, perhaps, but Occupy was far greater in scope. Police brutality and police infiltration gave a clear message that their reach isn't just limited to fringe groups, minorities, and political parties, but ANYONE who stands up to the agenda. Though it shouldn't be, given the FBI's history, I think it served as a huge wakeup call to the public that such tactics are the norm and not the exception."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
