<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764121524.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>In what way was it meaningful and significant? How are you actually judging political movements? The power of the state changing its size/nature or only that it changes hands?

Politics is tricky to judge; for example what would have happened if the strongest anti-nazi party would have "succeeded" in Germany? The communists at the time weren't exactly anti-mass murder during ww2.

The tea party also showed "failed two party system", "alternative currencies"; I feel these ideas time had come, not that a bunch of poeple living in a park showed them to the world but only that it was ok to ignore these age old taboos and everyone was thinking the same thing for years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764144635.0" user="ForRealsies" delta="False">
    <text>The Tea Party movement seriously challenged a number of Republican Primaries, and some of congress is made up of "Tea Party" platform members today.     
    
There are no Democrats in office that hold any meaningful tie to the Occupy Movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764371861.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Give it time; the loudest chick gets fed eventually and idealism on faulty premises fades quickly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764719162.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; idealism on faulty premises fades quickly.

I guess OWS definitely did.  A few short months at best, whereas the tea party has several years under its belt now.  How does that fit in to this statement?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764736458.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>Idealism dieing out would be selling out not "failing" to run for office; from my standpoint as a anarcho-capitalist, both the teaparty going form classical-liberalism to neo-con and ows form sorta anarcho-mulalist to run of the mill socialism(don't tell me that's going anywhere else); are bad things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764953165.0" user="plasmacutter" delta="False">
    <text>"There are no Democrats in office that hold any meaningful tie to the Occupy Movement."

I suppose (**senator**) Elizabeth Warren does not exist? 

How about all the blue dogs that Occupy-related movements primaried out of office? How about occupy-related movements that put Alan Grayson back into office?  How about the occupy-related activists that dogged Romney and brought him down when everything was saying "carter 2.0" in obama's future?

Do you think florida would have gone blue without occupy?

Many people see what they want to see based on their own proclivities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764149317.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>I listed the ways in which I thought the movement was meaningful and significant. 

Like you, I don't think that the people at Occupy first introduced these ideas. They did, however, promote these ideas on a scale not witnessed before at any point in America during the last century or so. I don't think that statement's hyperbolic, either.

I judge the movement's efficacy based on how it's shaped discourse and consequently, perception. For example, the phrase "99 percent" has a wholly different meaning now than just a few years ago. We talk of "banksters," and even "occupy" itself has now entered our lexicon. Maybe this achievement sounds better suited for an ivory tower, but if you replaced "shaped discourse" and "perception" with "achieve brand recognition" and "product placement," then this effect is something multinational corporations are willing to spend billions to accomplish. 

I think Occupy was a good first step, as it forced us to confront that there's a very real problem with our government and it being hijacked by corporations. NOBODY was talking about this in 2008, except for the Tea Party (which was quickly cast off as a group of lunatics), and a few college campus groups. It's like the AA program: Acceptance is the beginning. Occupy, to me, was meaningful and significant in that it caused people to unite around the acknowledgment of a problem. It's especially profound when we take into account that educational institutions, the mainstream media, and our government were NOT the ones telling us this message. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764227993.0" user="damnatu" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody was talking about this in 2008 because the Supreme Court ruling of Citizens United (which sparked the whole backlash against corporations getting involved in goverment) was in 2010. By 2011 lots of people were paying attention, not just OWS</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764366229.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I listed the ways in which I thought the movement was meaningful and significant.

Yes but they were long winded, poorly formatted, and unclear in terms of how I see the world; 

Maybe I should have been more clear: if "Nazi Germany" would have been communist Germany and it ended in roughly the same number of deaths ( I would expect this to be the case but that's irrelevant) would the communist party had "succeeded" in a meaningful way?

&amp;gt;NOBODY was talking about this in 2008

These ideas are OLD; "maybe society would be better if we put the right people in power" was Plato's entire premise, "maybe we shouldn't have one all powerful leader" was even older. What matters is when the young havent been abused enough to accept lies or the lies become even more unbearable for some external reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764171354.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>Also, I'll point out the early revolutions in France for comparison. As highlighted in Les Mis, it didn't look like that rag tag group of kids did shit when they stood up to the army in 1832. At the end of it, they wondered what it accomplished and came away from it thinking it was a great failure. However, these early stand-offs were percolations of the sentiment that led to the ultimate French revolution... which came in 1848: sixteen years after the those initial uprisings. More stuff went down to justify larger-scale protests and attacks, but the reasons were consistent. 

It might seem like Occupy stood for nothing, but the very broad reason of "economic inequality" has basically been the reason for the revolutions throughout history. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
