<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88553786.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gq0je/i_believe_that_the_occupy_movement_was_meaningful/">
    <title>I believe that the Occupy movement was meaningful and significant: CMV</title>
    <original_poster>in_the_airoplane</original_poster>
    <original_post>I honestly don't understand why many point out what a "failure" Occupy was as a protest. I believe that:

1) The mainstream media was a huge driving force for convincing the public that it had no direction or purpose. I think this is intentional, as it's touted as a failure to dissuade the public from trying something like it again. Downplaying it is their attempt at quelling the masses. 

I believe that Occupy WAS significant because it 
2) created a global outpouring of support, galvanizing hundreds of thousands (perhaps millions?) of people all over the world onto the streets. Though we look with envy to Turkey and Brazil at their ability to stand up and cite how we Americans are lazy, we started Occupy! 
3) brought together people from all walks of life for a number of different, yet still related causes. While some claim that it was detrimental that there seemed to be no single cause of protest, the same thing is going on in Brazil--they're protesting not just bus fares, but so many other things from corruption to crony capitalism.
4) highlighted innovative solutions to problems, like the communications system of having entire groups relay messages in unison to overcome loudspeaker rules.
5) brought to light ideas and concepts not often discussed: the barter system, direct democracy, alternative currencies, buying local, the failed two party system... though these haven't yet sprouted, Occupy helped plant these seeds into our collective psyche as to their possibilities. I think the "solutions" aspect of the protest goes largely ignored, but was one of the most powerful parts of the movement. 
6) we better understand what we're up against: before, it was considered absurd to think that the police would attempt to co-opt and infiltrate peaceful protests, or that they'd use violence to such a degree. While this was a painful lesson, I think it helped us wise up to the nature of the government. While their tactics may cause some to believe protests are ineffective, others see it as all the more reason why we NEED to be protesting.

I like having my views changed and picked apart. So here you go. Now, why do you think Occupy was a failure? Are there any lessons to learn, or should it be tossed like an old carcass from our memories, not worthy of resuscitation? 

EDIT: It's midnight here so I'm going to bed. Apologies if statements of mine were unclear. I've somewhat changed my view in that 1) Occupy should have had more tangible results for a protest of its size, and 2) Yes, their over-ambition to implement lofty solutions got the best of them. I'm still really optimistic that the movement could lead to other protests that have learned from its mistakes. I still think the problems of society raised by Occupy are exceptionally valid and in dire need of reform. HOW this will be done on a large scale by the masses... well, not sure. If no such change is forthcoming, then I would view Occupy as an abysmal failure. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764147714.0" user="Warm_Bagels" delta="False">
    <text>I think you give the mainstream media more credit than it deserves. 

As with any political organization, you have to recognize the trade off between size and appeal. The Occupy movements gained traction and attention because it was spontaneous; Americans all over were congregating to protest and it wasn't being orchestrated by some group in the shadows. In fact, it was more of an idea than an organization, but that was its ultimate weakness.

Without major central leadership, the movement was bound to be hijacked by other groups intent on bringing attention to whatever issue they saw as important. You yourself listed a multitude of issues that you felt the Occupy movement stood for. But the idea of a protest is to gain the attention of the media in order to coherently bring an issue to the forefront of discussion. 

The Occupy movement unfolded like a child crying for attention, only to mumble once the parents were listening. People wanted to support the Occupy movement, but it became too frustrating.

I think the Occupy movement was a failure, and the nature of this discussion is fairly indicative; you didn't ask if the Occupy movement successfully achieved some specific milestone but if the Occupy movement did anything at all. That doesn't mean we can't learn from this. Future movements can definitely learn from this. 

**tl;dr The lack of strong leadership and a coherent message ultimately prevented the Occupy movement from translating its widespread appeal into substantive discussion or change. When you stand for everything, you stand for nothing.**</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764160977.0" user="in_the_airoplane" delta="False">
    <text>Then I have an honest question: do you feel that the protesters in Brazil are misguided for focusing on so many issues as well? 

And actually, I do think there was one cohesive message from the Occupy movement: Money is grossly misallocated between the 'haves' (1 percent) and the 'have nots' (99 percent). But yes, from this single focal point came several issues of protest such as escalating costs of education, lack of health care, disbanding unions, etc.

One thing I think is crucial to take away from the "Occupy" movement is that it's no longer realistic to expect the media to bring issues to the forefront of discussion. The mainstream media has been co-opted by corporate interests. It amazes me how many people judge the value of an idea, protest, or sit-in based on whether or not it's covered by major news outlets. I think if we wait for this type of validation, we'll forever be disappointed and we'll continue relinquishing our personal power to the institutions we're seeking to change. 

I don't think Occupy was at the stage where it could expect specific milestones. As I mentioned in another post, we're still at the point where just getting the people to realize there's a problem is HUGE. For people to even be discussing how our democracy has been hijacked is incredible, especially when this message wasn't conveyed by the outlets that normally shape public perception (media, schools, govt).  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764302600.0" user="Warm_Bagels" delta="False">
    <text>I'll try to address some of the points you mentioned:

----------------------

1. In all honesty, I'm not very well read on the protests happening in Brazil. I'm not going to pretend I understand the situation as well as I would like. But it is noteworthy that the initial protest over bus fare motivated the government to reverse the bus and subway hikes. It was a specific issue with a solution suggested by the protesters, and the government listened. But at this point, I also believe that the protesters have devolved into making too many sweeping demands without clear solutions or a plan of action. But it's still too early to make any conclusions.

2. I completely agree that there was a theme to the Occupy movement. But protesting that money is grossly misallocated becomes way too broad and involves too many complex issues. Assume that the media faithfully and accurately covered the Occupy movement to the degree that you desired. The existence of labor unions and the state of the US healthcare system are incredibly divisive issues within the public sphere. So it shouldn't be surprising that support for the movement fizzled once it came down to the specifics. Again, when you stand for everything, you stand for nothing. 

3. I think you see the mainstream media as something more sinister than it actually is in reality. It's unlikely that the CEOs of Fox News and MSNBC held a meeting to confirm how the Occupy movement would be portrayed as. Sure, it's undeniable that they're in the business for the money. But I'm not sure that the coverage of the Occupy movement strayed too far from the truth. If anything, people have short attention spans, so mainstream media is unlikely to cover the intricacies of the movement. Occupy should have realized this and boiled down their protest to an important but specific issue. That's where you're going to see the most change and discussion happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764413888.0" user="gingerkid1234" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;And actually, I do think there was one cohesive message from the Occupy movement: Money is grossly misallocated between the 'haves' (1 percent) and the 'have nots' (99 percent).

But that's not a thing to protest.  That's a talking point.  The actual thing a protest can show support of are things like...

&amp;gt;But yes, from this single focal point came several issues of protest such as escalating costs of education, lack of health care, disbanding unions, etc.

About which the occupy movement was incredibly unfocused, as you admit.  If the protests got people to listen to "wealth is very unequally distributed", it didn't have a coherent follow-up.  The only possible result was getting people to accept a value judgement about a fact, rather than *do* anything in particular about it.  And a successful protest gets people to do something about it.  The Occupy movement, even if it had been as successful as it could've been, simply couldn't have done that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764714654.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  If the protests got people to listen to "wealth is very unequally distributed"

It's so very true that this was the entirety of their "message", and the dumbest part is that it's not exactly like no one was aware that the rich people have lots of money before a giant unwashed meetup group decided to point it out.  It's like saying that a group holding up signs saying "the sun is warm" is a "movement".  I don't really understand how people got so excited about the most inane talking points anyone could have ever thought of.  A movement has demands and goals...can people really not tell the difference?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764640822.0" user="Dhanvantari" delta="False">
    <text>The same can be reasoned for the view that being a leaderless movement ultimately prevented it from being hijacked by a single group intent on bringing attention to whatever issue they saw as important. The supporters of the movement were very diverse and held some conflicting views, if one leader with were to rise up his ideology might be perceived as receiving more support than it actually did while at the same time marginalising other ideologies also supporting the movement that may have even conflicted with the leader's message.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764709896.0" user="ThePantsParty" delta="False">
    <text>The big point though is that without some kind of actual message, it's not even a "movement" to begin with.  What you've described is very accurate, but what you've described is a meetup group, not a movement.  And that's exactly what we saw in implementation:  a bunch of people sitting around talking about vague notions and feelings over milk and cookies, and then eventually going home.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764938323.0" user="plasmacutter" delta="False">
    <text>But the Occupy movement ALWAYS had one, coherent message:

**There is too much corruption in our politics, the wealthy have too much of a say and nothing to lose by disenfranchising the majority of us, and it needs to stop.**

Occupy has branched out into 4 very distinctive sub-movements:

* A movement to end citizens united and corporate personhood

* A movement to reduce dependence upon (and thereby the power of) large multinational organizations through local sourcing of (you name your good here)

* A movement to watch-dog and push out any politicians who acted against "main street"

* A movement to leverage social networks to bail out and support the hardest-hit among us against centralized corporate greed. (Examples: a group that collects money and pays off medical debt, A group that shuts down corporate bidding on private residences)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
