<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88618188.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gre8c/i_believe_young_people_cant_get_jobs_because_the/">
    <title>I believe young people can't get jobs because the present workforce is dominated by the older generation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>iy_xy_OoO</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe this because over the past few weeks I've been surveying this idea, and I've noticed some things. If you ever get on the road, anytime before 6, 7, or 8 p.m., etc. (quitting time), you'll notice that most everyone in their cars are older people. Rarely do you see teenagers in them, and if you do, they have friends in there, so you'd have to assume that they're going out to have fun, and not to work. 

Whenever I've had a job, I'm always surrounded by people in their 30's, 40's, and sometimes even older than that. 

So the question I would have after all this, is: Do teens have any business looking for employment at their age? Even after they leave college, you still hear about them having a tough time finding work. So where does the problem lie? How can we fix this?

The newer, younger generation is growing up, and soon we'll take over. How soon? Not soon enough...

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764757740.0" user="InertiaofLanguage" delta="False">
    <text>I think the reason is more likely lies in the overall lack of jobs. With fewer jobs, the market shifts in favor of employers, meaning they can be more picky about who they hire. Older people simply tend to have more working experience, as they've been alive longer. They also are having to work longer, as NOAHA202 said. 

This is also industry dependent, however. In the tech industry, from what I've read, many older people have trouble finding work because they don't have an as up to date education. 

Additionally, many blue collar and entry level jobs are more easily outsourced that jobs that require experience.

So your competing with people with more experience, or more education, or people willing/able to work for less money. Or any combination of those. 

Fix it by destroying capitalism :)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
