<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="88618188.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1gre8c/i_believe_young_people_cant_get_jobs_because_the/">
    <title>I believe young people can't get jobs because the present workforce is dominated by the older generation. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>iy_xy_OoO</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe this because over the past few weeks I've been surveying this idea, and I've noticed some things. If you ever get on the road, anytime before 6, 7, or 8 p.m., etc. (quitting time), you'll notice that most everyone in their cars are older people. Rarely do you see teenagers in them, and if you do, they have friends in there, so you'd have to assume that they're going out to have fun, and not to work. 

Whenever I've had a job, I'm always surrounded by people in their 30's, 40's, and sometimes even older than that. 

So the question I would have after all this, is: Do teens have any business looking for employment at their age? Even after they leave college, you still hear about them having a tough time finding work. So where does the problem lie? How can we fix this?

The newer, younger generation is growing up, and soon we'll take over. How soon? Not soon enough...

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26764763179.0" user="asrealaspossible2" delta="False">
    <text>The jobs that USA teens used to have were taken over by the 30 million or greater illegal immigrant hispanics/mestizos/latinos.

It is not the fault of the "older generation", but the felony invaders and ultimately their enablers who bring them here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764801819.0" user="channelactive" delta="False">
    <text>1) You know a lot of middle-aged Americans that spent their teens picking lettuce, Sewing Nikes, and nannying rich white kids? This is obtuse at best. 

2) Young professionals and college graduates are looking for jobs that have 401(k)'s and healthcare, not black lung and back problems

3) The only people "enabling" illegal immigration are the people paying undocumented workers. The next time you go bargain-hunting for anything from shoes to kitchen remodeling, remember what you're paying for.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764815142.0" user="asrealaspossible2" delta="False">
    <text>1.  Without 30 million felons illegally in the country and illegally working in the USA, the natural state of the economy would work itself out.  The less intelligent (blacks) would take over the manual labor entry level jobs.  The white teens would take over the white collar entry level jobs.

2.  That has nothing to do with college graduates or "young professionals"(whatever that is), but "teens".

3.  China makes the most of our consumable junk, not Hispanics/latinos/mestizos.  Illegal immigrants steal jobs from the low class US citizen.  Once again, with no illegal immigration, the people on the left side of the bell curve(blacks and low class whites) would be doing the work.

Blacks should be 100% against illegal immigration and Hispanics/mestizos/latinos in general but with their genetically lower IQ, their quest to destroy white people blinds them to something that would help them.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26764823190.0" user="channelactive" delta="False">
    <text>Oh. You're racist. I thought you were just a regular idiot. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
