<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="903350017.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/extxc1/cmv_israel_is_not_the_primary_cause_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Israel is not the primary cause of the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, nor can they do much to stop it.</title>
    <original_poster>thosewhowait</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been seeing a lot of people and politicians argue that we need to put pressure on the Israeli government to end the humanitarian crisis in Gaza. There absolutely is a humanitarian crisis going on there; the nearly two million Palestinians living there don't have clean water, building materials, or infrastructure. However, it seems to me that this is largely due to the fact that Hamas is the de-facto ruler of the strip. As I understand it, when Israel decided to pull out of Gaza, they established considerable infrastructure like greenhouses to give the Palestinians a head start, but as soon as they pulled out, Hamas organized parties to destroy the Israeli infrastructure that they left. Also, rather than using building material like concrete to actually build up high quality infrastructure, they use it to build tunnels under Israel so they can conduct terrorist attacks on civilians. Hamas has also been increasingly authoritarian and preventing rival parties to hold any public events, so the people's ability to put a more effective and people-oriented government into power is greatly diminished. Putting aside Hamas's corruption, they are also in a conflict with Isis (which has established strongholds in the Sinai, bordering Gaza) which is further distracting them from increasing the standard of living of their people.

I want to make it clear that I do not at all support Israel's expansion of settlements into Palestinian territory, and I genuinely do believe that some form of two state solution involving Israel and at least the West Bank will be possible, but with Gaza specifically, I'm not really sure what can realistically be done by Israel that would not put their citizens in danger. As I understand it, Israel limits import of construction materials because Hamas continues to use them to build tunnels under Israel, screens shipments to Gaza because of continuous rocket attacks on civilian areas by Hamas, and prevents free movement from Gaza to the West Bank because suicide bombings / stabbings are a serious issue there. It's a lot less infrequent for buses to blow up now, so it seems pretty effective. 

I really do feel that the Gazans are the true victims here, but I think Hamas is currently the main cause of their suffering, not Israel. Regardless, I'm not sure what a concrete, feasible action would be for Israel to help the Gazans that wouldn't open them up to further terrorism.

Also, I just want to clarify that this is about the *current situation*. I think it's another conversation about the events that led up to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict as a whole, but I'm more interested in discussing what Israel could realistically do *right now* that would not compromise their security.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33641400635.0" user="edwardlleandre" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As I understand it, when Israel decided to pull out of Gaza, they established considerable infrastructure like greenhouses to give the Palestinians a head start, but as soon as they pulled out, Hamas organized parties to destroy the Israeli infrastructure that they left.  

Your understanding is [wrong](https://www.nytimes.com/2005/07/15/world/middleeast/israeli-settlers-demolish-greenhouses-and-gaza-jobs.html). Which I don't blame you for, incidentally, it was a pretty common bit of propaganda, one even spewed out by Hillary Clinton.

The fact is that Israeli settlers trashed roughly half the greenhouse on their way out the door. When the handover was complete, there was looting (which isn't shocking, given how destitute the area is and was at the time) but enough of the facilities were left over that they rebuilt with investment from the Palestine Economic Development Company and were ready to [sell](https://www.nytimes.com/2005/11/28/world/middleeast/gaza-gets-ready-for-a-harvest-of-produce-and-promise.html) by november of that year.

Even with the effort that palestinian groups went through to fix the greenhouses that had been damaged, it ultimately didn't matter. Israel violated a signed international agreement to keep the Karni crossing open 24/7, leaving it closed over 1/3rd of the time. Because of this, Palestinian farmers were literally [throwing away](http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/business/4818478.stm) their crops to be eaten by animals rather than having them simply rot entirely. There was no [security reason](https://www.haaretz.com/1.4895067) for the closure, according to the IDF commander in the area.

By april of 2006, the project had been shut down. They simply couldn't afford to pay workers when they were not allowed to sell their crops. A number of the greenhouses were eventually sold to farmers in Sinai who could actually sell their crops. Others were destroyed during [Cast Lead](https://www2.ohchr.org/english/bodies/hrcouncil/docs/12session/A-HRC-12-48.pdf) where they were deliberately targeted with both weapons and, in a few cases, bulldozed alongside farms, coops etc.

So the short version, is no, no they didn't. Even your opening statement: 'They established infrastructure like greenhouses to give the palestinians a head start' is wrong. The Israelis built greenhouses while they were occupying their land, and then the settlers were ultimately paid to leave them behind rather than razing them to the ground as they'd done with the houses and other infrastructure they'd built.

I could go on and on with the errors in your OP, but I'm hoping that a thorough breakdown of this one specific issue will cause you to rethink the baseline of your argument. You are being lied to in order to make Palestinians seem like violent savages who tear down any hope of civilization, when the reality is that they do their best, only to be fucked over by Israel any time they attempt to make progress.

They are not blameless, no one in that conflict is, but accepting Israeli propaganda will not help you see the situation in any sort of realistic context.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
