<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="903350017.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/extxc1/cmv_israel_is_not_the_primary_cause_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Israel is not the primary cause of the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, nor can they do much to stop it.</title>
    <original_poster>thosewhowait</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been seeing a lot of people and politicians argue that we need to put pressure on the Israeli government to end the humanitarian crisis in Gaza. There absolutely is a humanitarian crisis going on there; the nearly two million Palestinians living there don't have clean water, building materials, or infrastructure. However, it seems to me that this is largely due to the fact that Hamas is the de-facto ruler of the strip. As I understand it, when Israel decided to pull out of Gaza, they established considerable infrastructure like greenhouses to give the Palestinians a head start, but as soon as they pulled out, Hamas organized parties to destroy the Israeli infrastructure that they left. Also, rather than using building material like concrete to actually build up high quality infrastructure, they use it to build tunnels under Israel so they can conduct terrorist attacks on civilians. Hamas has also been increasingly authoritarian and preventing rival parties to hold any public events, so the people's ability to put a more effective and people-oriented government into power is greatly diminished. Putting aside Hamas's corruption, they are also in a conflict with Isis (which has established strongholds in the Sinai, bordering Gaza) which is further distracting them from increasing the standard of living of their people.

I want to make it clear that I do not at all support Israel's expansion of settlements into Palestinian territory, and I genuinely do believe that some form of two state solution involving Israel and at least the West Bank will be possible, but with Gaza specifically, I'm not really sure what can realistically be done by Israel that would not put their citizens in danger. As I understand it, Israel limits import of construction materials because Hamas continues to use them to build tunnels under Israel, screens shipments to Gaza because of continuous rocket attacks on civilian areas by Hamas, and prevents free movement from Gaza to the West Bank because suicide bombings / stabbings are a serious issue there. It's a lot less infrequent for buses to blow up now, so it seems pretty effective. 

I really do feel that the Gazans are the true victims here, but I think Hamas is currently the main cause of their suffering, not Israel. Regardless, I'm not sure what a concrete, feasible action would be for Israel to help the Gazans that wouldn't open them up to further terrorism.

Also, I just want to clarify that this is about the *current situation*. I think it's another conversation about the events that led up to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict as a whole, but I'm more interested in discussing what Israel could realistically do *right now* that would not compromise their security.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33640667519.0" user="twig_and_berries_" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think Israel giving up land to return to the 1947 border wouldn't solve the problem or do you think that's just too unreasonable? Because from my perspective you can argue Israel or Palatine/Hamas is to blame more but it seems like it's hard to not fault both.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641270320.0" user="Positron311" delta="False">
    <text>I think you mean 1967.

Israel wasn't a country until 1948.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641560304.0" user="thosewhowait" delta="False">
    <text>Nah I think he was correct. There was a 1947 partition plan that would have granted 45% of the land to a Palestinian state.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641734237.0" user="twig_and_berries_" delta="False">
    <text>That was my understanding but if that's up for debate I'm fine using the lines from 49-67.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33644252251.0" user="Pancakes_Plz" delta="False">
    <text>Bear in mind, you would probably be furious if another country carved your home up and gave (about half) of it to the ancestors of people that had been gone for 900+ years, then those same people proceeded to try to take every bit of it.  


Having said that, the only way I can see is Jerusalem being a 100% neutral area governed by a third party. /shrug Make the entire city a world heritage site or such.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33645844827.0" user="peekabookpenguin" delta="False">
    <text>palestinians never had a distinct country to begin with, so it makes no sense to say another country carved up their home. 

jews were welcomed to live in there and they bought land there legitimately. what right did the Arab Palestinians, either morally or legally, have to prevent them from doing so?

The Arab Palestinians were given multiple chances to live in peace with the Jews, and every time they chose to reject it and launch genocidal wars against the Jews with the neighboring Arab states. And now they claim to be victims.  That's rich.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33646111785.0" user="Pancakes_Plz" delta="False">
    <text>Sure thing, have nice day there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33645952199.0" user="Old-Boysenberry" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but that was just a plan, not actual borders. So "going back to 1947 borders" means not existing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641553919.0" user="thosewhowait" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you think Israel giving up land to return to the 1947 border wouldn't solve the problem or do you think that's just too unreasonable?

Both. The Palestinians already rejected the 1947 borders. I do think it's a possibility that some good negotiation could end up with the PA accepting that kind of deal, but I don't think Hamas would compromise on their desire to take over 100% of the land. And going back to the '47 borders would result in around a 1/4 loss in land for Israel (from a bit of research, looks like the '47 partition plan would have granted Palestinians 45% of the land, while they now control around 20%), including Jerusalem, which I'm not sure is so realistic at this point</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641894033.0" user="twig_and_berries_" delta="False">
    <text>So you don't think with even going back to the 67 borders Hamas will still have enough control and won't be satisfied such that nothing will be solved? I respect that position. I personally think Hamas has such control because they give people a little bit and they're destitute. More land, less destitution and I think Palestinian people would need Hamas less and thus more willing for a peaceful compromise. But it is hypothetical so it's perfectly reasonable for you to disagree, I'm just basing my theory on how Hamas got power to begin with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33645932428.0" user="Old-Boysenberry" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you think Israel giving up land to return to the 1947 border

So you mean going out of existence? Israel was founded in 1948.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33646016781.0" user="twig_and_berries_" delta="False">
    <text>Am I missing something or did you comment just to pedantically point out that it was a *proposed* border, not an actually implemented border? Not trying to be sarcastic, I genuinely think I'm missing something.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33646038109.0" user="Old-Boysenberry" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think that's pedantic at all. Those borders never actually existed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33646063800.0" user="Kman17" delta="False">
    <text>The 1947 border is no longer feasible.  The international community has primarily called for the ‘67 borders.

The larger issue has been the so called right to return, which is super unreasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
