<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91570869.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iioj9/cmv_why_isnt_wonder_woman_sexist/">
    <title>CMV: Why isn't Wonder Woman sexist?</title>
    <original_poster>BottomOfTheNinth</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most of what I hear and see about Wonder Woman leads me to believe she's sexist. In the depictions I've seen of her she comes from a society that banished men, she seems to be surprised when men are good (and on the opposite side of things, surprised when women are evil) and generally can't go five minutes without calling men dicks because her dad was an asshole.

To clarify, this isn't some men's rights post. I don't care on some kind of personal level if she is or isn't sexist, I just kind of want it clarified for me because a lot of people say she isn't sexist - yet in the examples I've seen of her (the Justice League cartoon, the animated Wonder Woman film, the Flashpoint comic book series...) she pretty much just hates men in general. A lot of people have also told me that while Wonder Woman herself isn't sexist, the Amazons are, so I could kind of do with that being explained too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26795787293.0" user="presidenttrex" delta="False">
    <text>Aw man, I can talk about comic book history stuff all day. Problem is, from many perspectives, she totally is sexist. And it's *completely intentional*. 

**First, some history:**

When comic book superheroes first arrived (Superman in Action Comics #1, 1938) they were invented as a mashup of classic SciFi and the pulp adventures of the time. But the early creators, gentlemen like Seigel and Schuster, Bill Finger, Bob Kane, Jack Kirby, etc. were mostly young, Jewish, and from outside the mainstream pop culture of the time. So they created these worlds as a response to being outcasts, and in a way, created an exclusionary group themselves. In a period when parents were worried about youths falling in with "bad crowds" and scares about communist and anarchist underground groups politically agitating at the tail end of the Great Depression (and with the Nazis and Communist revolutions abroad), popular comics aimed at kids written by outsider Jewish groups creeped some people out.

So in 1940, in an interview with Family Circle magazine (1940's equivalent to a "mommy blogger") psychologist William Moulton Marston famously argued "Don't Laugh at the Comics." His take (and I absolutely agree with his on this) is the comics carry an ENORMOUS potential to capture imaginations and mold young minds. (In a good way) He talked about their "great educational potential". It was so popular, he did a followup article in 1942. 

So DC Comics hired him (kind of sort of to head off some of the criticism about the violence in comics) to write a new kind of superhero, as Marston hoped for, who would triumph over people with love instead of fists or excessive violence. His wife agreed, as long as he "made her a woman." Marston's arguement for this was... 

&amp;gt;"Not even girls want to be girls so long as our feminine archetype lacks force, strength, and power. Not wanting to be girls, they don't want to be tender, submissive, peace-loving as good women are. Women's strong qualities have become despised because of their weakness. The obvious remedy is to create a feminine character with all the strength of Superman plus all the allure of a good and beautiful woman."

Also here's some things about Marston:

- A contemporary of psychologist Alfred Kinsey, who at the time, was researching human sexuality and gender... a radical idea back in this period.

- Invented the systolic blood pressure test and contributed to the invention of the polygraph ("lie detector test") by including blood pressure data into the test. (Remind anyone of the "Lasso of Truth"?)

- Based the looks, personality, and overall design of Wonder Woman off his wife (and fellow academic) Elizabeth Holloway Marston, and their polyamorous girlfriend Olive Byrne. 

So they made Wonder Woman to try to appeal to girls by giving them a powerful role model (and open up a previously untapped market to sell more comic books) AND to help change boys minds that women can powerful in their own right and didn't need a man to save them. As a matter of fact, OP said...

&amp;gt;five minutes without calling men dicks because her dad was an asshole.

Thing is, Marston intentionally wrote Wonder Woman's origin to be as "man" free as possible. She's molded by clay and blessed by the gods, with no parents (because superheroes aren't supposed to have parents) and raised by Hippolyta on an island of all women. Heck, even her "mother" tries to hold her back. Her creation is free from anyone's influence and demonstrates the agency of a completely self-empowered women... decades before second wave feminism. Marston was mind-bogglingly ahead of his time in this instance. But Diana calls all men dicks, because the character was raised in such a overwhelmingly powerful female environment, so when she's actually introduced to (hu)men, they don't possess the power of gods like her and haven't trained all their lives to be relentless warriors. The world of "men" is so far out of her understanding, her frame of reference is all out of whack. 

It's only when she meets Steve Trevor (*opinion- who's reboot in the New 52 is one of the best reboots DC has ever done*) that she meets men for the first time... and she sees them as weak and in need of her protecting them. This stands the traditional gender roles on their heads and is essentially crazy talk back in 1940. 

So, over the years, she's handled mostly by male writers (to mostly poor to mediocre results), gets rebooted A LOT, even morphed into some weird 70's spy thriller thing for a while. And it was only when Gloria Steinem had Wonder Woman placed on the cover of "Ms." magazine did she become a huge symbol for feminism. Before, she existed in the male-created and mostly male consumed comic book world as an counter example of a powerful woman to characters such as Lois Lane who always needed saving somehow.

But my biggest argument against Wonder Woman being a "sexist character" is the fact she was created by men, and over the years mostly written by men. (Gail Simone's run being one of my favorites, though) The current run, by Brian Azzerello (who coincidentally, lives a couple blocks south of my house), is a fantastic reboot and frames her as just a person trying her best to keep her crazy family from hurting anyone. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
