<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91670667.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iktjf/mod_post_new_readers_from_bestof_welcome_and/">
    <title>[Mod Post] New readers from bestof, welcome! And regarding controversial opinion threads...</title>
    <original_poster>IAmAN00bie</original_poster>
    <original_post>**This is Mod post 33. You can read the previous Mod Post by clicking [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1ib8mf/meta_how_to_make_a_good_argument/) (visit the wiki page we compiled based off of it [here](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/argumentation)), or by visiting the [Mod Post Archive](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modpostarchive) in our wiki.**  

---

Hello everyone coming in from /r/bestof! [Thanks to this post](http://www.reddit.com/r/bestof/comments/1ikcbj/fedworkerthrowaway_describes_how_crushing_working/) we're getting a huge spike in activity.

Since there are a lot of new members coming in, I would also like to remind people to please **read the sidebar!** Also, [check out our Wiki!](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/index) We've put **a lot** of work into it, and there is a lot of information about this subreddit that can be found there!

As some of you will notice, the submissions have been temporarily restricted. This is done so all newcomers will have time to read the rules before submitting. We will lift the restriction soon, but please stay tuned.  

**DeltaBot may crash from having to award so many.** If your delta does NOT get counted, please wait before messaging us because we know there may be problems!

---  

While I have your attention, I also want to clarify one thing that has bothered a few users for awhile. To a few who come in, this subreddit may not seem very welcoming. Why? The various controversial opinion threads (you know the ones!) that are posted usually get a ton of comments plus a lot of upvotes, so to some it might make it seem like this subreddit's users all believe that.  

There are a few things I want to mention:  

1) **OP's view does not represent that of the community.** Controversial threads simply get more attention because people are passionate about their views towards them. About half the comments will support OP (especially if OP's views fall in line with mainstream Reddit), but you can be assured that the other half represent the minority view (we WILL enforce comment rule 1). There are no circlejerks to be found here! Don't take the thread title at its face value! Try and challenge OP's view. We enforce rule 1 to ensure that the minority view has a fighting chance! 

2) **Is OP really being open-minded? Is this some kind of brigade?** We used to have an old rule called rule VIII that disallowed people to use this subreddit as a soapbox. Well, we got rid of that rule because we felt that **it should be implicit in the ethos of this sub and will be enforced as such**. If you believe someone is here NOT in good faith, either through their comments or history, then **message the moderators.** Getting into needless slapfights only wastes your own time.  

3) **Why do we allow controversial opinions like XXXX?** You either allow them and take them on a case-by-case basis, or ban them. While it's true that on really heated topics people are less likely to have their view changed, *it does happen.* I've personally seen deltas awarded in many of these threads, even if they're not from OP. These threads are also the most popular by far (whether or not the activity is legitimate, ie. could be due to brigading, is up to debate but I believe it's legitimate) so taking away these discussions would hurt the subreddit. *I'm sorry if seeing these discussions puts you off!* Really, I'm not a big fan of them myself either. If you want to see posts that interest you, *try making one yourself!* Also, upvote and participate in threads that interest you! [Yesterday's Disney villian thread](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1ihnzp/i_believe_maleficent_from_sleeping_beauty_is_the/) was an unexpected success, for example.

4) **So what kind of threads do we remove?** Obvious troll posts like "I think the Holocaust was bad CMV." which, due to rule 1, would force users to argue that the Holocaust was *good*. See where I'm going? We also will remove threads when it becomes clear that OP is not appearing open-minded, or if OP is consistently rude to users in their own thread.  

5) **Think about what the alternative would be!** Controversial opinions that you might see on /r/askreddit's ~~weekly~~ daily thread may get posted here, but **because of rule 1, at least the comments challenge that opinion!** What *if* the opposite view were posted? Ex. "I don't think the Roma are as bad as Reddit makes them out to be, CMV." You can imagine what the responses would be like, right?  

I hope the above clarifies our position on these kinds of threads. I also hope people can point others to this thread when they are confused or frustrated by this sub's content. 

---  

Regards, the mods of /r/changemyview.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796259647.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, if you could lift the submission ban, that'd be great.

*Pleaseeeeeee* :DD
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
