<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796431494.0" user="SLO_Chemist" delta="False">
    <text>I have a few thoughts on your post, OP. 


* throughout, all of your claims are merely anecdotal ("it seems..." "my guy friends..." "women in my life") So to apply your own experiences to 50% of the worlds population would be fallacious (I.e. inductive fallacy).
* You feel this way. As such, you have a biased opinion before any interaction with a women happens. I would guess that you are prone to noticing "dumb" women more than men, and noticing "smart" more than women (I.e. confirmation bias).


&amp;gt;research agrees with both (not as smart, not as fit) of these points.


* Please provide a source that says men are more intelligent than women. Until then, I don't need to address this point further.
* In your experience, how have the women demonstrated their relative lack of intelligence? If you mean they are not problem solvers, they do not step up to an intellectual challenge for the joy of it, they are not as rational, they can't give logical directions as clearly or correctly as a man can, they do not debate well, etc. then consider why this is the case. Women face things growing up that you do not think about. While you were building Legos, they were playing with an ez bake. When you graduated up to science kits, or robotics kits, they graduated up to a whole fake kitchen, or a more expensive doll than they previously had. From birth men are trained to be analytical, problem solvers, while women are trained to be in the kitchen. If you doubt this, I will not argue it, but you can visit the gendered aisles of a toys r us and decide for yourself. I did this and it was eye opening. Toys are just a small part. Women are statistically ignored by teachers. They are encouraged by guidance counselors to seek arts degrees over sciences etc. women are depicted in the media a certain way, compared to men. The result is: growing up, a woman's childhood toys, the characters she looked up to, teachers, authority figures, and everything that was marketed to her, have shaped her into something that's much different than what men become due to our own social pressures. To look at this current difference between genders and say "women are inferior" is EXTRAORDINARILY intellectually lazy, and ignorant.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
