<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796348867.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>How do you feel about the thousands of girls smarter than you at college?  Why does it matter if there are more intelligent men (not that I'm agreeing with this premise that ignores all context and history)? Do you find pride in being in the "better gender"? How does such a thing impact how you interact with individual women? 

You find what you seek. Tons of people interact with women more than you do, yet they don't hold the same sexist notions as you do. Why? Because they don't hold distorted, condescending views of women. A woman shopping doesn't reinforce or suggest any ideas of gender supremacy, your personal bias and false assumption does.  

Also, if you are arguing that women are of lower intelligence, you should at least spell basic words correctly to support your argument. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796351481.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a dumb fuck. There's plenty of men and women smarter than me around the world. Sometimes it makes me feel sad and insignificant, but the rest of the time I try to focus on being the best person I can be.

The point about spelling errors is completely valid. Feel free to correct all my grammer mistakes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796366580.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Right and there's plenty of dumb men and women in the world, so why would you assume the worst about women (she's dumb and helpless) and best about the men (he bought all the privileges for the woman)? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796368401.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Most wealthy women did not build their fortune. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796369491.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>How many women do you interact with? Do you see many women who inherited millions from their rich husbands or fathers? Most young wealthy people in general didn't build their own fortune. 

Or do you interact with average women who don't have a fortune lying around? That your bias would carry on to judge the most mundane tasks that every person does such as drive a car or go shopping is ridiculous. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796371569.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>In what period of time? Like a day? Probably anywhere from 3-10 depending. What is many? I know a few. I do as well interact with "average" women, most of whom(did I do that right?) are driving cars their husbands bought or supplemented income for. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796376081.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>So you're assuming the woman makes less money than her husband and thus she is inferior. If the reverse held true, would you claim the woman is superior to the husband based on income? 

And if she doesn't have a career, if she chose to be a homemaker, is she also automatically inferior due to her role? How do you know these individuals aren't more intelligent or better human beings or whatever it is used to determine someone's worth.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796449583.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>I have a lot of Indian coworkers.  The female ones are absolutely brilliant.  We actually had one change jobs because the employer tried to push her into a senior management role.... They feel they're more successful and effective working predictable hours and then going home to raise the family that their husband is not competent to do.

At least two of them at one point made more than their husband.

I work with a female QA expert who used to be a Programmer...she quit because she wants the weekends home with her kid so her husband can work them.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796488797.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>His statement of most wealthy women not building their fortune is 100% correct, if you are looking at the most wealthy people in the world. There was a thing recently (ish) which showed the inheritance vs self made for men and women. Most women did not make their own fortune. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796401766.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to enter the argument that the patriarchal society of the last hundreds of years has dictated that women can't/shouldn't/don't need to work. Men are the caretakers, men are the providers. Women are merely the cooks, maids, teachers, nannies, planners, secretaries, etc in their homes. Women haven't made fortunes yet because society is only beginning to realize that they can. Men have had years of encouragement in the workplace, whereas women have had years of adversity and doubt. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796428469.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you're referring to that list that made the front page the other day that pointed out that 19/20 inherited their wealth....

That's pretty easily pinned on historical factors. 

Not to mention that a huge portion of wealth is, if not directly inherited, the product of seed money (used to start/expand a business) from a previous generation. Family dynasties are a big part of affluence, and if you look at a top 100 list of rich men, you'll find that very few of them did not come from wealth already.

It's more accurate to say that wealthy people tend to inherit fortune, even if they manage to expand upon it later, and that daughter/wife inheritors are a culturally newer phenomenon.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796447970.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be assuming that success in Capitalism (a system that isn't even absolutely accepted) is a primary factor of success and overall worth.

Sorry, but the way in which women can get wealthy more easily than men (through manipulating the system) seems stronger evidence of women being superior than the way men earn the money in this system..

...That is, if you don't have money and you want it, you're more capable of getting it if you're a woman.  There's more marriage-made women than self-made men.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796643075.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You are living proof that men can be dumber and inferior to women and you still believe that women are inferior. You're a lost cause.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796664845.0" user="devonclaire" delta="False">
    <text>It's spelled grammar. With an "a", not an e.

Sincerely,

A woman</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798006121.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Rule 2. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
