<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796306861.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>Until i can pass a living human being through my penis then do it again two more times because "what the hell you wanted kids didnt you" i will always believe my wife is the more emotionally strong and stable person.

Men are physically stronger. Intelligence wise its hard to correct for educational and privilege biases. Emotionally? Women may look like train wrecks but its us guys who are inferior. Masculinity precludes the possibility of displaying and thus resolving emotion and conflict, causing anger, violence, depression and suicide. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796313619.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Men can't give birth so women are more emotionally stable and strong? I don't see how that logic works. If men had the option of giving birth and passed on it fair enough. It should also be noted that a vast majority of women end up having children and anything the vast majority of people can do isn't that impressive.

Men tend to be on the left and right side of the bell curve while women are in the middle. It's not too hard to control for education level and priveledge in studies.

I believe women are emotionally superior but I think that is a result of the patriarchy. Also do you mind telling me how you think the system we live in now came to be if women are equal to men?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796316150.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>Birth does not equal emotionally stronger, youre reading to fast. Birth equals physically capable of handling a lot of pain.

And men are in a dominant role out of physical strength and not having to give birth,  things that were actually important ten thousand years ago but have little bearing in modern society, especially ones that have paternity leave making the genders even more equal.

You cant chalk intelligence up to men being better then immediately turn around and say emotions arent women being better, its just the patriarchy. Either both are or neither is, as the existence of a patriarchy means men have greater advantages in attaining education and high level employment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796321591.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I'll start with your last point first. I do not know at what time men became physically superior to women, same way I don't know when women became emotionally superior to men. I would argue that the brain is much more malleable than the body however. I also don't believe I ever said the intelligence wasn't a result of the patriarchy. The issue is however, if the patriarchy has been around since the beginning of time, does it really matter if something is the result of it or natural?

As for your first point, you literally said, until I can give birth I know my wife is x and y. You're never going to be able to give birth so I fail to see the relavancy. 

I should also note that physical strength has lost it's importance because (most) men choose to not be violent with women. If they choose otherwise, or chose not to give them paternity leave, these issues could become more relavant. Men simply choose not to beat women they could with ease, not the other way around.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796323849.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>Physical strength lost its importance with the invention of tnt a century and a half ago. Gun&amp;gt;muscle.

And male apes are always stronger than female apes, look at our entire order.

And you said that intelligence was innate and not based on the greater opportunities afforded to men the past millennia. The first is what you are trying to say in that women are inferior. The second is correct in that women are currently being held to be inferior because they have been forcibly prevented from being better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796330614.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>It's lost some of its importance for sure, but all? How and from where are women getting these guns in your scenario?

Male apes do a lot of shit humans don't. Pun intended.

And I think this is a bit of semantics argument. I believe women are inferior today, not particularly bothered about whether it started 10000 years ago or 15000. I also believe that the oppression is voluntarily removed by the males.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796333712.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>If you ignore all of human history the blacks, natives, hispanics, etc are all also inferior. Would you argue that as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796343047.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know about natives but there were times that blacks were on top of the world(Timbuktu), and times when Hispanics were on top of the world. Whites being in power is actually a fairly recent event if you look at the whole scale of human history. Men and women however...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796345372.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>You are ignoring history, remember? That means you dont remember the Zulu, or Aztec. They are poorer and more violent now. Therefore they must be inferior because they are inferior, as there are no historical implications. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796347419.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Can you please point me to where in my posts I've said I'm ignoring history? I think you're being hyperbolic in your interpretation because history is a big part of this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796350667.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>"I dont care whether this started 1000 years ago or 15000 years ago". As to the point of men oppressing women. The persistent theme of physical violence, upon reading the whole thread, has me concerned for your mental well being.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796360469.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>So once again... Where did I say I didn't care about history? You're twisting my words.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796411063.0" user="shades344" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like what you need is a value for standard deviation of IQ values for men and women to prove/disprove your claim that women are more "average."

Unfortunately, I'm at work and can't provide that, but if anyone else could, that'd be awesome. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
