<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796353282.0" user="mafoiking" delta="False">
    <text>While physical strength was certainly important once a point of time, it's becoming increasingly irrelevant. In this day and age, physical strength seems to generally play no role in how successful you are. In fact, you will find that a lot of the physically weak individuals to be more successful (think of people who excel in their studies but are terrible at sport). So it doesn't really matter if men are physically stronger than women anymore. Even in ware fare, it's technology that wins wars today.

As for your point about intelligence,  you argue that women are inferior because the smartest people tend to be men. However, if the studies are right, and show that women are on average more intelligent, then couldn't one argue that those extremely intelligent men are merely outliers and not representative of the general male population?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796362676.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>It's losing importance because men are giving it up. They could take it back. Some do. One could argue anything really so yes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796366573.0" user="mafoiking" delta="False">
    <text>How would physical strength ever become that important again. What is the point of being stronger than someone when they have a gun? It's losing importance because it doesn't provide the advantage it used to.
About my other point. If those really smart men are not representative of men in general, then how does that having a few smart men (but a lot of stupid ones) suggest that women are inferior to men. If women are smarter than men on average, then wouldn't that suggest that men are actually inferior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796368949.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I'm a little confused, do you think men have it better off than women today?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796416916.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Question wasn't directed towards me, but yes.

That I, as a woman, have to fight for equality and respect in any situation that a man wouldn't have to is disheartening.

That my academic advisor (a man) looked me in the eyes when I told him I wanted to be a biochemist and laid out the 4-year plan I had set up for myself and told me I might want to reconsider, because women rarely succeed in the lab and he was "worried about my emotional health", is a huge fucking slap in the face.

That my primary value is, according to much of society, based on my physical appearance and my body (and I don't say this as an unattractive female) sucks. Though, to be fair, a man's is often based on how much money he makes, and that'd make me just as frustrated, were I a man.

That I will make less money, on average, than a man of the same ability, same knowledge, same background, same qualifications, same everything, in most fields is unfair no matter how you cut it.

That I have to constantly be more aware of my surroundings than most men will ever understand is exhausting. I'm sick of gripping my keys between my knuckles, having to wear my hair down so as not to provide an easy point of restraint to an attacker, and walking the long way around a block because the alleyway which bisects it could be, at any given moment, dangerous to my life.

Yes, I think men have it better off. Many of my statements are generalizations, but I don't think they're far off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796423697.0" user="MynameisIsis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That I will make less money, on average, than a man of the same ability, same knowledge, same background, same qualifications, same everything, in most fields is unfair no matter how you cut it.

I agree with all your points save for this. Accounting for career choice, equivalent education, credentials, background, and such, women make 97% of what men do, a value that can be attributed to statistical noise. The problem is not that women make less given equal certs, experience, and qualification, it's that women are usually denied the opportunity to gain those things in the first place. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796429825.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting reframe of the statistic. I've never heard it put like that, but that makes perfect sense. The point still stands, then, except in the way you put it. Thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796444878.0" user="tisbutme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That my academic advisor (a man) looked me in the eyes when I told him I wanted to be a biochemist and laid out the 4-year plan I had set up for myself and told me I might want to reconsider, because women rarely succeed in the lab and he was "worried about my emotional health", is a huge fucking slap in the face.

Where is this taking place ? As a guy who worked in biology, where I am &amp;gt;50% of lab people are female. In some labs, it gets to 70%. I wouldn't even imagine anyone saying anything like this...

&amp;gt;That I have to constantly be more aware of my surroundings than most men will ever understand is exhausting. I'm sick of gripping my keys between my knuckles, having to wear my hair down so as not to provide an easy point of restraint to an attacker, and walking the long way around a block because the alleyway which bisects it could be, at any given moment, dangerous to my life.

Again, where are you from ? Granted, I'm not a female, but not one of my female friends lives this way. Sure, there are places/parties/... where I wouldn't let them go alone, but in day-to-day life ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796450272.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>That was Iowa State University. I don't even remember the guy's name anymore. I've since changed my major and transferred schools (neither of which had anything to do with him), but that conversation will forever piss me off. It's part of the reason I'm going into education policy and leadership, actually.

I live in Milwaukee, WI. Certainly not the most safe city in the nation, I know. It's not that I live every day terrified for my life, sure someone in a mask is going to jump out of a bush and hack me to pieces, but there's a level of awareness myself and my female friends use that my boyfriend and other male friends don't get. Party etiquette, places I will and won't walk, having to ignore the endless catcalls and come-ons. I really do carry my keys like that, avoid alleys, and usually take my hair out of a ponytail or bun, especially when I'm walking alone or at night. I've never had issues, but I know too many people who have that I'm willing to take the extra precautions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796759045.0" user="tisbutme" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;but that conversation will forever piss me off

Please believe that this kind of behaviour isn't representative of the biology field as a whole, but of one dickish individual.

&amp;gt;I really do carry my keys like that, avoid alleys, and usually take my hair out of a ponytail or bun, especially when I'm walking alone or at night. 

None of my (20 to 25yo) female friends do any of these things. I hope I don't have to live in a place where this would be a reasonable behaviour. Good luck with everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796819781.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Oh absolutely. I have plenty of female friends who are going into various sciences and love the fields and the people they've met. I know that guy was abnormally rude and not everyone is like that, but I also know he's not the only one.

And thanks. My school's in a rough part of town; I certainly don't ever plan on permanently living in a community like I do now. It's not all bad, and I'm sure lots of the sketchy-looking people are very nice and completely innocent, but I don't want to wait until it's too late to realize I'm wrong on that either. :)

Edit: sorry, accidentally triple-clicked 'save' somehow...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796374976.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>It's losing importance because its becoming less and less relevant in society. Do tell us how that is the result of men giving up or how they can take it back. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796386999.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>Because science, so intelligence, has become more important the physical strength, even in war. Why the hell should we go back to the dark age when this would make us as a society weaker?

I'm starting to get the impression that sexism is just one layer of your problem. You're uncontent with your place in society. Intelligence, which you think you don't have, has become more important then strength, which I guess you have. That much weaker guys can have a better position in society and look down on you makes you sad. But that even women have a better place in society and are more prestigious makes you angry. That's why you're thinking about why you tolerate to be ruled by people who don't stand a chance in a fistfight with you. Am I right?

But it's not the fault of women that society had changed, it's kind of evolution. Women only take the chance to break out of the oppression they were put in. So don't hate them because nobody deserves to life oppressed by stronger people, and it doesn't matter if they are physically stronger or just clever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796451202.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>How could they take physical strength back?  Armwrestling instead of gunfights?  There's no way to take physical strength back as important because it's genuinely *not* important anymore.

The truth is, any absolute survival value still given to physical strength is entirely artificial.  If a bodybuilder tries to murder a gun-holding paraplegic, the bodybuilder loses.

The same is (obviously) true with women.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
