<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796320078.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly.

To the extent that this might be true, or might have been true in the past, it is because women have been systemically oppressed for generations.  Women who might have excelled in the sciences 50+ years ago did not have the opportunity to do so because their roles in society were restricted to childbearing and housekeeping.  To this day, women have a hard time breaking into scientific fields because it's still considered a "boy's club".  Women of the past (and still today to an extent) were reduced to essentially property to be protected, while men held the position of control.  With control comes the ability to either excel greatly or fail miserably.

As far as men being smarter, though, that's not at all demonstrable.  The only methods we have of measuring intelligence put women (barely) on top, but those methods are unreliable at best. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796324296.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Systematically oppressed by men, who are now choosing not to oppress them. If tommorow we wanted to go back to women being property there certainly isn't anything the women could do to stop it. I agree that it is hard for women to break into certain fields for a lot of reasons but I think that is a seperate discussion. I agree that control is crucial, but how did men get this control? 

As far as your opinion on the credibility of experts in their field, I find people tend to reject information when it doesn't fit their world view. There is a lot of data on this subject and not really debatable in the academic fields.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796343437.0" user="Nallenbot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I find people tend to reject information when it doesn't fit their world view.

You tend to find that huh?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796346346.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Well I never even said men were smarter so I'm not sure where this is going. I said the smartest men are smarter than the smartest women. It's not the same.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796349186.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I said this in my other comment, but I'll repeat it here.  You cannot form generalizations based on outliers.  Your conclusions are guaranteed to be skewed, due to the nature of outliers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796352740.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>How are we defining outliers? Grubbs? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796356113.0" user="Nallenbot" delta="False">
    <text>Do you need the meaning of outliers defined?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796364342.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Yes? But can we stay away from the snark and sarcasm? It really doesn't help the discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796377837.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>Because there is no discussion when you don't want to discuss. Look at the facts and then come to an conclusion, not the other way around. To say men are more intelligent because of some outliers who also mostly lived in a time where women were not allowed in science, is (sorry) not very logical. Sorry but I know women who are smarter then you, and I know women who are stupid like me. We're individuals and therefore mostly stupid. If you want to you can stop beginning your thought process with a conclusion and afterwards only insert to facts who reinforce this conclusion, that's how you stop being sexist. These outliers you brought up as "proof" are the best example for this kind of thought process.

P.S.: When you and your friends only hang out with stupid women it says a lot about you and your friends, but not about women generally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796409413.0" user="wintercast" delta="False">
    <text>thank you for your post script.  that really meant something.  

one thing i have learned, if "you" (meaning anyone) are the smartest person in the room, you need to find another room.  Otherwise you will not learn anything or grow.

I am a female that at this point makes more money and is more educated than my spouse.  But i dont care.  I dont think of him as stupid.  I also work in a male dominated field (although that is changing).  I am also attractive, but i buy my own drinks :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796414745.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>That's the way it should be. I mean we also respect surgeons more then bankers because to earn less doesn't mean you're worth less.

Clarification: I didn't mean to imply you haven't the same worth as your son or that you're in anyway comparable to a banker. ;-) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796515854.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>The argument isn't about mean level differences, but about the variance of the distribution. Different numbers of outliers is relevant when considering the variance of distributions.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796398389.0" user="motioncuty" delta="False">
    <text>How do you quantify smart. Is there a smartest man in the world? Who is he, what is he doing with his life? I am not sure brains and brawns determine greatness. The older I've gotten, I come to realize determination and willpower unlock the power that brain and brawn support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796444013.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>Statistically, this is wrong.  It doesn't evidence average intelligence, it doesn't evidence the maximum intelligence, and it doesn't evidence the outlier rate.

The truth is, if the strongest person alive was a woman for a couple years, that wouldn't mean anything about the gender as a whole.

I think this argument backed you into a corner.  One man does not a superior species make... and as there have been super-genius women, we're one outlier anecdote away from this argument being nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796550146.0" user="Rosetti" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well I never even said men were smarter

What? You said exactly that in the main post body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796879725.0" user="freedommerc" delta="False">
    <text>False. OP states that the smartest men are smarter than the smartest women. Read before making accusations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796348195.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Systematically oppressed by men, who are now choosing not to oppress them.

Do you think that just because feminism arose in the last ~century, it means that suddenly we're on equal social footing?  I assure you, that is not the case.  Thousands of years of oppression don't just disappear in the span of a generation.  

Have you considered that, being in a privileged position, you might be unaware or minimizing the affects of social conditioning?  Young boys are encouraged from birth to be the dominant gender, especially in their professional lives. Young girls are still taught that their position in society is to be childbearers and housekeepers.  Those social memes have a large impact on how men and women behave in society.  *Not only* do they have an impact on behavior, they also have an impact on performance. 

That isn't to imply that men are actually better in academics--other posters have already linked to sources to the contrary--but minimizing the impact of the current social structure is a mistake on your part. 

&amp;gt;If tommorow we wanted to go back to women being property there certainly isn't anything the women could do to stop it.

I don't believe that to be the case.  While there may be disparities in physical strength between the genders on average, that in no way means that women are incapable of defending themselves physically. And, putting physical strength aside, we now have much more political and socioeconomic influence.  That isn't something that can be reversed in a day, any more than the generations of female oppression can be erased in a day. 

&amp;gt;I agree that it is hard for women to break into certain fields for a lot of reasons but I think that is a seperate discussion.

It is absolutely not.  Your argument is that men perform better that women in their academic and professional lives.  How, then, can you separate that from women being pushed away from certain professional fields?  If your argument is that there are more examples of brilliant male physicists, then you have to examine why that is.  In part, it is because women are discouraged from entering scientific fields.

&amp;gt;As far as your opinion on the credibility of experts in their field, I find people tend to reject information when it doesn't fit their world view. There is a lot of data on this subject and not really debatable in the academic fields.

Do you have a source for that?  Because others have already pointed out studies that show that women test better than men.  Your argument against that seems to rely on outliers, but you say elsewhere that you rely on those outliers to generalize.  Generalizing based on outliers is... patently silly.  First, generalizing at all is wrong when dealing with individuals.  But if you do feel the need to generalize for whatever reasons, it should be based on medians or averages, or else your conclusions are bound to be severely skewed. That is the nature of outliers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796350658.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Just out of curiosity, what are you assuming I am? A straight white cis male?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796351334.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm assuming you're male, but that is kind of beside the point, regardless.  Even if you're a woman, you are simply wrong in your view. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796355314.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>excellent argument, "you are simply wrong". What you mean is "I do not agree with you". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796365538.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I wish more people could make this distinction. Would make life so much easier for all parties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796365692.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Even sexy parties?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796365765.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Especially sexy parties.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796400191.0" user="abzka" delta="False">
    <text>You forgot to change your account.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796728392.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Oh wow...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796372966.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>He/She did give an excellent argument. Many people did. 

It's not so ridiculous to claim his assertions are simply wrong. 

It's not his fault that OP would rather [talk to himself](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/cb5v3z6) and share his 12 year old sense of humor rather than address the points brought up. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796378196.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No he/she did not, he/she gave an extremely biased argument and reacted with sarcasm when asked to substantiate claims. Then he/she asserted their opinion as "you are simply wrong" in a CMV post.

OP's methods of entertaining himself do not validate whether or not someone else' argument is legitimate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796406791.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>As a woman who agrees wholeheartedly with your arguments, please keep it civil. The subtle shots make us all sound the like catty bitches Hollywood so badly wants us to be. Don't make it true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796409576.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>The comment I responded to had the same snide tone. But why does mine reflect women or contribute to a negative stereotype because you perceived me to be a woman and he a man? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796411649.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>You're right about their tone being rude as well, but since you're coming into this discussion on the opposite side of OP (assuming you're a woman based on your username), your sarcasm is especially undermining to your point. They already think we're idiots, apparently. No need to give them extra ammo.

Didn't mean to offend, really.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796415914.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>how exactly was what I said in any way snide? You seem to be reading everything you disagree with as threatening. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796826396.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>idk, maybe the sarcasm that started with, "excellent argument?"

you seem to be just derailing people in this thread because you have nothing worth to say. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797135533.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>and what are you doing right now?

Sarcasm isn't even remotely the same as snide. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796496463.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>By you are wrong, I assume you mean 'I disagree'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796355792.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source for any of your claims? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796374480.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Which part? That we can't suddenly turn women into property again? That sexism didn't just disappear magically in the past few decades? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796380025.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  I assure you, that is not the case.

&amp;gt; Young boys are encouraged from birth to be the dominant gender, especially in their professional lives. 

&amp;gt; Young girls are still taught that their position in society is to be childbearers and housekeepers.

&amp;gt; Not only do they have an impact on behavior, they also have an impact on performance.

&amp;gt; While there may be disparities in physical strength between the genders on average, that in no way means that women are incapable of defending themselves physically.

Women are literally incapable as being as strong as a man. I think you've also missed the point of what he was saying about there being nothing they could do about it, as you've narrowed it down to physical restraint.

&amp;gt; women being pushed away from certain professional fields?

Such as? I think you will find women are getting extra bursaries for STEM subjects that men do not qualify for. 

&amp;gt; If your argument is that there are more examples of brilliant male physicists, then you have to examine why that is.

Well one conclusion could be drawn that men are better logical thinkers, but you seem to think it's because women are oppressed. 

&amp;gt; In part, it is because women are discouraged from entering scientific fields.

Again, I think you will find it's actually the opposite in quite a few western countries. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796390726.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe because most of those are common knowledge? 

Clearly no one's saying you can't do anything about it. There are tons of women out there that prove those stereotypes wrong. That doesn't mean those restraints and obstacles are nonexistent. 

Many women themselves feel that they were discouraged from STEM throughout their lives. "The survey showed significant numbers of minority women (40 percent) chemists and chemical engineers said they were discouraged from pursuing a STEM (science, technology, engineering or mathematical) career. [source](http://www.bayerus.com/News/NewsDetail.aspx?ID=862593F0-F489-B4D0-283DB12C656EA899)

But I'm sure you are more knowledgeable on the matter than the actual women scientists and engineers speaking from their own experience. 

Throughout history women weren't even allowed to achieve higher education, let alone be encouraged to. They were deemed unworthy and incapable to study them. How about the stories of famous scientists who were snubbed of their accomplishments. Jocelyn Bell Burnell who found the radio pulsar was snubbed of a nobel prize, [because at that time, only the "senior men" would receive credit"] (http://news.nationalgeographic.com/news/2013/13/130519-women-scientists-overlooked-dna-history-science/)

Clearly it's because men are better logical thinkers and women are never oppressed or disadvantaged right? What about all the young girls today who don't have the sheer magnitude of the number of all those role models that their male counterparts have? How about the environment where men dominate? You don't think that maybe there's a chance that women are pushed away and discouraged from these fields, or is it simply because women = le not smart and good at science as much as the men. 

&amp;gt; Young boys are encouraged from birth to be the dominant gender, especially in their professional lives. Young girls are still taught that their position in society is to be childbearers and housekeepers.

Do you think this is false? He didn't claim every young boy and girl are taught this way, but this still holds true in many places. Do you think older gender roles and norms suddenly just disappeared in the last few decades? Young boys are given tools and trucks to play with and girls are given dolls and tea sets. Do you think everyone suddenly started ignoring these kind of old stereotypes and biases? 

You do realize the programs and initiatives to promote more women in STEM fields is because they're so few and underrepresented? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796401400.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>"Common knowledge" is not backing up a source. 

&amp;gt; Do you think this is false?

I asked for a source. Nothing more. Again, you haven't provided a source, just started some other rhetoric with no back up. 

&amp;gt; You do realize the programs and initiatives to promote more women in STEM fields is because they're so few and underrepresented?

Which is not actively discouraging them is it, which was my point. 

Again, I didn't ask for you to spew forth a load more rhetoric, I asked for sources to substantiate everything you've said. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796404901.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>bla bla bla dismiss all other points I've made and all sources I already brought up.

But here's some more sources if it pleases you. 

[Kids' books are almost twice as likely to feature a male hero than a female heroine](http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/books/8494392/Childrens-books-are-sexist-and-enforce-gender-inequality.html)

[The study’s lead author, Janice McCabe, a professor of sociology at Florida State University, examined nearly 6,000 children’s books published from 1900 to 2000. Of those, 57 percent had a central male character compared with only 31 percent with female protagonists.](http://artsbeat.blogs.nytimes.com/2011/05/05/new-study-finds-gender-bias-in-childrens-books/)

[Gifts of trucks or dolls are given to toddlers depending on the child's sex. 
Stories about princesses are read to little girls, while stories of dragons and swords are 
read to little boys.]
(http://digitalcommons.liberty.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1205&amp;amp;context=honors)

From the sources above
&amp;gt; It was found that only 
29% of the boys helped with cleaning the house while 72% of the girls were required to 
perform this task 

&amp;gt;For example, boys are more likely to be encouraged to play sports, 
while girls are encouraged to participate in housekeeping activities 

&amp;gt; Television teaches children messages pertaining to what behaviors are gender 
appropriate. One study found that only 17.7 % of major characters in prime time 
television were women. The women usually filled less serious and less significant roles. The male actors were more likely to dominate the show and were usually the focus of 
attention.

&amp;gt; Not only were the cartoon programs stereotyped, but the commercials shown 
during children's television programming are also guilty of portraying gender role 
stereotypes. Females were commonly shown in passive roles rather than being actively 
involved with the activities depicted in the commercials. More males than females were 
shown in the workplace, and more females than males were shown in the home. Men 
were commonly shown in independent, high activity positions, whereas women were 
shown in passive, group oriented roles</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796411153.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's utterly hilarious that you've got your knickers in a twist because I asked for a source, which is exactly what you did to the guy. 

Why didn't you just link up sources to begin with instead of going off on one? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796414062.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a point? Or are you just trolling at this point. I've given you sources since my first post, you on the other hand have no actual discussion to contribute to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796425371.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Asking you to substantiate claims is not trolling. You're the one who treated it as a threat. Heaven forbid you should actually have to back up any claims you ever make.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796446004.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not a mod, but please follow rules 2 and 3.  The meat of this CMV is extremely awesome to behold, and both sides have a lot of interesting points.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796495491.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>As you have been told, common knowledge is not a source. You need to source all your claims if asked to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796397890.0" user="Discoamazing" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I find people tend to reject information when it doesn't fit their world view.

You realize that this is exactly what you're doing, right? By your own admission, when you say that you immediately class any person you meet that doesn't fit your preconceptions as an "exception."

If you don't mind, could you explain how you first came to hold these views?  Was it how you were raised?  Have you ever been emotionally close to a woman? (In other words, have you ever had a long term significant other?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796415954.0" user="BenLW" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If tommorow we wanted to go back to women being property there certainly isn't anything the women could do to stop it

Could you expand on this more? Do you think that men could simply use their physical force to enslave women?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796442388.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; there certainly isn't anything the women could do to stop it

Women outnumber us.  They know how to use guns.  They often have a history of being the "power behind the throne" for men.  

It's not their finest hour looking back, but remember that women were the driving force behind prohibition.  And at the time, they didn't even have political power.

I don't see much of a situation where men have been so effective while so "oppressed".  (Prohibition was much more well organized than a lot of the slave revolts/organizations... and even critical ones of those were organized by women)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796497254.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>While I clearly have no source, I think it is pretty clear that men would dominate a war of the sexes, they are simply better soldiers physically. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796503961.0" user="novagenesis" delta="False">
    <text>Isn't that just a red herring, though?

There won't be a violent war of the sexes; it would destroy our species.  I'm only referencing that they could do something to stop it...even a quasi-successful armed defense would end such an attempt.  Enough women would be militarily superior to enough men that only  a complete annihilation would lead us to beat them (I am a guy).

I think you're putting too much weight on to my "women outnumber us" part.  I wasn't suggesting that we could not slaughter all the women in the world.  I was suggesting that they are not such a minority that we can reliable oppress them without consent.  

Additionally, there is no precedent of success conquering and oppressing a full-revolution population of their population percentage.

On the contrary, any oppression would have to happen more socially and politically (even if there was some amount physical violence)...and I'm suggesting that it's not bloody likely that we could beat them down in that arena.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798000120.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Oh I did not think it was relevant, I was simply disputing the fact that women might win said war. I really do think that if necessary, men could very easily oppress women purely due to being physically better. However this is clearly off topic for the CMV. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796523193.0" user="ultra_violence" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If tommorow we wanted to go back to women being property there certainly isn't anything the women could do to stop it.

What's your point? 

If I threw you in a lions den you'd get mauled to death. Doesn't make the lion BETTER than you. It only means it had better weapons to hurt you with.

Women have been hideously subjugated by men for thousands upon thousands of years, simply because of the fact that when push comes to shove, men win due to physical strength. *That doesn't make it acceptable or right though*. 

As a result of these millenia of oppression, men have created what is called a patriarchal society -- in other words, it's a man's world. Built by men, for men. This happened because men forcefully TOOK power and used that power to build a society that suits MEN more than it suits WOMEN. 

Additionally, from birth, women are guided down particular life paths due to their sex. There are very entrenched ideas about what is acceptable for a woman and what is acceptable for a man. Of course there are exceptions to the rule but in general, many women are psychologically manipulated from birth by a society that favours men's interests over women's.

For example, women are told by advertising, societal norms, memes, the attitudes of men and other women, that physical appearance and sex appeal is of the utmost importance, that all women must bear children, that women aren't good at maths, that pink is for girls and blue is for boys, that women must like "thing X" but not "thing Y", that men are breadwinners and women stay at home, that a man can sleep with many women and keep his honour but a woman cannot do the same without having some nasty label attached...

It is only in the past ~150 years that standards of personal liberty have risen for women. Before that, a woman could be raped by her husband and have no legal recourse. She belonged to him the same way his horse did. You may think 150 years is a long time, but in terms of societal change, it's not. It takes much longer than that for society to change to become completely equal and fair. We haven't made it all the way yet but luckily we're generally heading in the right direction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796637399.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I find people tend to reject information when it doesn't fit their world view.

People also too commonly accept dubious or biased information because it exactly fits their world view. It's the nature of all research that it has to be taken with a grain of salt because they are inherently biased to prove one thing. For every study you find to prove something, I bet I can find another that disproves it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796380725.0" user="n0t1337" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; &amp;gt; It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly.

&amp;gt; To the extent that this might be true, or might have been true in the past, it is because women have been systemically oppressed for generations.

That is adorable. Thanks for making me giggle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796492867.0" user="Eh_Priori" delta="False">
    <text>Have you ever opened a history book?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796719272.0" user="avantvernacular" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. There's quite a bit of war and conscription in there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796732848.0" user="n0t1337" delta="False">
    <text>Right yes, the fact that men are more likely to succeed for fail spectacularly has more to do with the historical oppression of women than their biology, and the reproductive strategies that said biology encourages.

Unless of course men's flatter bell curve has been the case through all of history, in which case that argument would be silly. And it's not like most other male mammals in sexually dimorphous species have flatter bell curves for reproductive success than their female counterparts, because then that argument would be really silly.

Listen if we're going to say that women have been oppressed throughout history (Which isn't wrong, per se, but it is a tad reductionist, as the marxist mold of class based categorical oppression is one that simply doesn't apply to gender roles.) then this oppression is a symptom of having a taller bell curve, not the cause.

TL;DR: Men win hard and fail hard because sperm are cheap and eggs are expensive. Men have flatter bell curves for reproductive and financial success (And even things like IQ, or height.) than women do. This has held constant in pretty much every single human culture, past and present, and holds true even outside our species. Saying that the bell curves for men are flatter due to sociological reasons is putting the cart before the horse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796388544.0" user="siamthailand" delta="False">
    <text>Women got oppressed because they were less smart. Simple as that. The fact that it happened in pretty much all socieites and cultures pretty much proves it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796397612.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That conclusion doesn't follow. You could just as well say women were oppressed because men are physically stronger.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796404966.0" user="siamthailand" delta="False">
    <text>Thousands of animals are physically stronger than humans. Guess who have the upper hand?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796521410.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>If women were somewhat smarter than men on average, they could still have been subdued physically. People are _much_ smarter than many animals. If men and women are equal or only slightly different, other differences can play a larger role (such as physical strength). 

Alternatively, we can consider the cultural example of not very intelligent bullies subduing much smarter classmates in the playground.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796407319.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Source me, bro. How do you know this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796418621.0" user="BenLW" delta="False">
    <text>I've posted this elsewhere in the thread, but it is again relevant

Well, they're [IQ scores] not rising any faster than any time in history. They've been rising quite consistently over about the last 150 years, and they've maintained the same rate. But the thing that's happened over the last 50 years is that women have fully entered modernity, and that means that they've finally had equal opportunities with men for education and jobs. And in all the countries where we have good data, on a very excellent intelligence test, Raven's, they now either equal men or are slightly ahead of them. But, you know, we're missing the point when we focus too much on IQ. The other thing that psychologists talk about is executive functions, and that's the ability to use your mind and not be distracted by temptation or immediate emotion. And that's where the women are beating the men. If you take a 17-year-old boy in school and you take a 17-year-old girl in school of the same IQ, in America at least, only the upper third of boys would match the upper half of women on reading, and only the upper quarter of boys would match the upper half of women on written composition. And that's why the girls are getting better marks and flooding universities and flooding professions like law and journalism. So the real news is that women, when exposed to modernity, do equal men for IQ. But in the formal educational setting where they apply their intelligence, they're outperforming men all hollow.

So what this is suggesting here is that your social environment affects your IQ (the closest measure we have of intelligence). So, if women were assigned different roles than men (which they were), then they adapt (not in terms of evolution, within a person's lifetime) to their surrounding - so if women are excluded from business/academia, they will have lesser skills than men. So, women's oppression can contribute to the "lack of smarts". As society moves away from oppression, these gaps eventually evaporate, and we will see far more women in leading positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798916449.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>How well this reasoning would be thought of if the shoe was on the other foot? Larry Summers can answer that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797624288.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As far as men being smarter, though, that's not at all demonstrable.

It is easily falsifiable, men are so dumb that you can get away with saying that "women have been systemically oppressed for generations" and not that women got everything that makes them human from men. Men are so dumb that they give it away for free, and then pay for it. So fricking dumb that they then get blamed for not giving it away as soon as possible.

&amp;gt;women have a hard time breaking into scientific fields because it's still considered a "boy's club".

shouldn't they at least be grateful that there is something like this in the first place?

http://endofwomen.blogspot.in/2012/10/male-dominated-history-and-definition.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798005483.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Really? Was this actually a seirous post?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797950435.0" user="rds4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To the extent that this might be true, or might have been true in the past, it is because women have been systemically oppressed for generations.

At least that's the narrative that you want everyone to believe, whether it's true or not.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
