<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796351672.0" user="Nallenbot" delta="False">
    <text>When you grow up you'll meet plenty of women that will change your mind. Formidable women who destroy you in the work place, earn serious money, drive better cars than you own, are more attractive than you, think faster, make better decisions. Then you'll realise this incredibly narrow view that *somewhere* out there is a man that might be able to do *some* of these things better is absolutely meaningless. Because if you search high and low and find this man someone can just high and low and find the woman that trumps him.

These 'ultimate people' that you think show that men are better than women do not exist. They are something you have dreamed up from aggregated statistics.

Lastly this view you have that essentially women have only made progress because men have physically allowed it and we could slap those bitches to the curb any time we like is borderline dangerous. If you carry this view forward in your life and actually think it has validity one day you will betray yourself. Maybe you'll feel amazing, maybe you'll have showed this pathetic *woman* that she'll only do exactly as much as you allow her to. Maybe you'll end up like [this guy](http://news.bbc.co.uk/1/hi/world/south_asia/7676341.stm).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796362127.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>What if I told you I am grown up, and ad hominem fallacies are a bad way to change my view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796368315.0" user="Nallenbot" delta="False">
    <text>You're doing this a lot. You're taking entire swaths of argument and dismissing it wholesale on a single point tangential to the content. Address everything else I said.

You said yourself that you find people tend to ignore things they don't agree with, and you're ignoring or dismissing everything you don't agree with. You will probably walk away from this thread thinking "Well, none of them could change my mind, I guess this is even more evidence that I'm right."

The ad hominem fallacy is attacking a personal trait unrealated to the point of discussion, like if I said "you only think this way because you have blonde hair" or "you would say that, you don't even put your change in the charity jar."

I think your lack of maturity, painted up and down in this thread in almost every answer you give is absolutely central to the view that you ostensibly came here to have changed, but personally I believe you are simply reinforcing through the cursory dismissal of every point made.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
