<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796392524.0" user="LordKahra" delta="False">
    <text>[This study from the University of Toronto displays that all differences between male and female spatial ability are erased after 10 hours of video games.](http://www.gamefront.com/study-shows-playing-video-games-improves-womens-spatial-skills/) Even further, the differences were maintained without further practice after the subjects were retested five months later.

Men and women are different in some ways. We're the same in some ways, too--a lot more than most people think. The human mind is a pretty insane organ, and it's one we're barely beginning to understand. Fretting about some minor, statistically insignificant average when you're dealing with a real human being is just going to get in the way of having good relationships (of all sorts) with other human beings.

Stop thinking of people as groups. Stop thinking of them as boxes, and ideas, and caricatures that have been repeated ad nauseum in vain attempts to look witty.

We are people. Treat us like it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796530177.0" user="_Search_" delta="False">
    <text>So now how do we get women to play video games?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796541342.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>Stop the entitled sexist teenage boys who are horrible to women playing games from being such dicks. Seriously. I never talk or reveal my gender if I can help it, especially if I can tell that the people I'm playing with are teenagers, because of how many times I've either got creepy and misogynistic messages or just killed by the rest of the team. It's a massive problem in shooters and some MMORPGs, so much more so than in real life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796542980.0" user="_Search_" delta="False">
    <text>Which games do you play?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796553012.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>The ones I've encountered this kind of thing in are CoD, Halo, Black Ops, Counterstrike and LoL. I suppose they're mostly populated by teenage boys, so also there'll be more of the kind I'm talking about. Games with a wider spread of ages and demographics are much better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796667976.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Stop the entitled sexist teenage boys who are horrible to women playing games from being such dicks.

On the flipside, many (but certainly not all) of the female gamers I've encountered in all manner of games from FPS to MMO don't view it as a meritocracy.  Plenty of female gamers use their gender and not their skill to garner attention, favorable treatment, or straight up donated perks.  

As much as I only care about your individual skill and not what's between your legs, there are plenty of guys out there that will be misogynistic/crude/spiteful.  As much as you probably just want to enjoy the game and not worry about getting scrutinized for what's between your legs, there are plenty of women out there that will milk their gender for all its worth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796702159.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>It annoys me that those same women would throw a fit if a guy did that. Or at least, tried to. I think they're kind of like the gamer version of feminazis.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796739382.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I don't think there's going to be a good solution unfortunately, there's a lot of immaturity on both sides.  Hopefully that won't stop you from enjoying games.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796751641.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, it won't. I will enjoy my games if it fucking kills me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796753549.0" user="hooj" delta="False">
    <text>[Yessss](http://cdn.memegenerator.net/instances/250x250/37194948.jpg)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827191043.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, I'll get right on that. How about a plausible response please. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827275301.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>Because I was speaking directly to you; you are the Chosen One, /u/h76CH36.

And also because it was clearly not a rant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827394263.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Still waiting for a plausible response. Do 4 lines constitute a rant, anyway?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827540396.0" user="noodledoodledoo" delta="False">
    <text>Well I said it and a rant is what it felt like, does that constitute a rant?

Plausible answer? There is none. There is no plausible way one person could change the mind-sets and actions of millions of others. It will take a long time and a lot of people (or a few well-known and influential people) to change how women playing games is viewed, and to make people feel like women playing video games is a normal, even positive thing. Stop asking for things you know don't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796565954.0" user="LordKahra" delta="False">
    <text>Women make up about 40% of the gaming population, but it's not particularly socially acceptable for women to spend a lot of time gaming, so it tends to be swept under the rug. I personally had a hard time getting  access to a lot of classic games as a kid, because my mother wanted me to grow up "normal."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796566948.0" user="_Search_" delta="False">
    <text>I know, I was joking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796732418.0" user="superapplekid" delta="False">
    <text>I've heard some people claim that the 40% statistic comes from research that counted (along with traditional video games) facebook games, board games, and smartphone games. Not that they aren't games, but the number misleadingly implies things that may not be true.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796957119.0" user="_Search_" delta="False">
    <text>It's true, there aren't as many females in the hardcore crowd.

I have aunts that would spend hours playing computer solitaire or pinball.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797008977.0" user="LordKahra" delta="False">
    <text>[Here's an article with a link to the PDF at the bottom](http://arstechnica.com/gaming/2008/07/esa-study-40-percent-of-us-gamers-are-women/). I don't have time to review it but if you do happen to glance through it and reply with what you find... &amp;lt;3? Otherwise I'll probably reply back tonight. Responsibilities call.

Also, I'd link to the PDF directly, but a younger me has been gotten by that sort of thing before. &amp;gt;.&amp;lt; Just a PSA.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797054955.0" user="superapplekid" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the link. The PDF only mentions the ratio in regards to 'game-playing', but repeatedly calls games either computer or video games everywhere else (no mention of the survey method being used). I googled for some more info, and couldn't really find much. The one tidbit I found was that woman are something like 40% likely to buy games, which includes mothers, some of which may play with the games with their children.

I can feel comfortable removing board games from the list, but I think things like Wiifit, Angry Birds, and Words with Friends still count. Not that these aren't 'games' or that computer/video games are somehow superior, I just get the feeling this stat is meant to give the impression that video game culture isn't as much of a boys club as it may be. This suspicion is doubled by how hard it is to find the specifics of the surveys over the mountains of opinion pieces it creates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797948321.0" user="rds4" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Women make up about 40% of the gaming population,

yes farmville</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796816717.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>A bunch of my female friends and I all play video games. We just refuse to wear headsets and speak, because we have guys proposition us or try to friend us immediately after hearing our voices. There's more women than you'd think that play video games, we just tend to be quieter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
