<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="19" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796398708.0" user="MrTastix" delta="False">
    <text>Consider that men, for a longest time, excelled primarily because woman were not allowed to do anything. The stereotype that woman should stand in a kitchen and cook was quite the norm up until at least the 20th century.

It wasn't until the 1800's that woman started getting more and more legal rights, and even then many of them were related to *marriage*, not job status or education.

Men have been given every oppurtunity to suceed. The greatest inventors and craftsmen are not men by design, they are men due to their times lack of equality. Woman were never given a chance to succeed whilst men were given all the chances, and that is why the greatest feats among human history seem to be done by a majority of men.

Arguments of physicality and intelligence quota are also relatively poor examples of male superiority. There are plenty of men who are physically weak, more-so than the average woman. Genetics does a lot to affect this. On average men may be stronger but in today's day and age that is no longer everything.

Intelligence quotas (or IQ) are also just plain wrong. They test the user in how they use reason and logic, rather than common knowledge or knowledge of a specific subject. There are many people with a an average IQ who are extremely proficient in one particular area; Men such as Einstein and Hawkins might have large IQ's but that is because they were and are knowledgeable in an IQ tests average areas.

To say one is smart because they have an IQ in the top 1% is ignorant. They are smart about certain things and ignorant of others. They can actually be gamed with the right knowledge at the right time. Ever seen an IQ test that teaches cooking? I haven't, so must we now presume Gordon Ramsey is stupid?

Woman simply need the chance to prove themselves, and in the 21st century they shall. But like men, only if they want to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
