<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796347132.0" user="TheNopx" delta="False">
    <text>Saying that they are inferior means you think they are worth less and you measure it by physical strength and intelligence. If we just assume you are right about them being not as intelligent and weaker, then I can still argue that those two things aren´t what makes somebody superior.

I could also say being superior is measured by height, by how loud your voice is, how good you can dance, how good you can feed yourself or how pretty your feathers look. So what I´ll say is, there are no values wich make something superior to something else in a non subjective way.

What matters in this discussion (in my opinion) is, do we need women. The obvious answer is yes and the obvious reason is because they give birth to children. I am sure there are more reasons why women are helpful for society, but they don´t matter right now.

So even if you say something like "men provide the food" and even if it were true, it wouldn´t matter, because food isn´t the only thing that matters. I am pretty sure that women are essential for psychological stability in a society and we need that just as much.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796349617.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Replace inferior with whatever word you want. Don't worry too much about the title the OP more clearly reflects my views. I do agree the title was badly worded.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796352536.0" user="TheNopx" delta="False">
    <text>So you are just saying that women are less intelligent and weaker? But why does that matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796360937.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>It taints my interactions with women and I don't like being sexist. Other than that, it doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796386756.0" user="Alpine93" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like I'm more rational in my thinking than 80% of women. This makes dating hard for me since I don't want to come home to that every day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796475858.0" user="Homericus" delta="False">
    <text>Then don't date one? Do you also feel like you are more rational than 80% of men, but you just don't have to date them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796941160.0" user="Alpine93" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not physically attracted to men in the least. I like women that think for themselves, and not use their friends as one hive-mind brain of stupidity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
