<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796330787.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>As I see it you make two claims. The rest is your own thoughts and experiences and I don’t think I’ll be able to do much to change those.

&amp;gt; The strongest people are men

What do you mean by strongest? Physical strength? Yes, men are on average 1/3 stronger than women. That how our biology works and if less strength = inferiority period then this discussion is pretty much over because that’s just how it is. If you have another definition of strength, like mental or emotional strength the matter becomes a bit more confounded. Women tend to do better in studies (I’ll come back to this) and on job interviews. [This]( http://www.theglobeandmail.com/life/health-and-fitness/health/men-more-affected-than-women-by-job-interview-anxiety/article12071389/) article refers to a study that claims that men are more affected than women by job interview anxiety. I would say that the ability to handle stressful situations such as important interviews and college studies is testament to mental strength. Why do you think men are stronger mentally than women, where does this take expression? Also, women tend to be more resistant to various diseases because they have twice as many X chromosomes and also fight off diseases [better](http://news.bbc.co.uk/2/hi/health/8047321.stm). If we were in a pre-industrial society then sure, I’d like to be able to life heavier weights than others, but today? I rather had a strength that is actually helpful, like tolerance to stress and not getting a cold.

&amp;gt; The smartest people are men

Again, what type of intelligence? Women have begun to score higher than men on [IQ- tests](http://www.telegraph.co.uk/education/educationnews/9401241/IQ-tests-women-score-higher-than-men.html), do better than boys in [school](http://psychcentral.com/news/2013/01/05/why-girls-do-better-in-school/50050.html), and in [college](http://chronicle.com/article/Young-Women-Are-More-Likely/133980/). 

What matters most today?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796339361.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I think women get less nervous before job interviews for the same reason women get more nervous before other activities.(unless research shows that women get less nervous for activities across the board, in which case this statement is null and void) Men get so worked up because in our society the measure of a man is how he provides. Men just don't care about their potential mates occupations as much as women do, the same way women just don't care about appearance as much as men do.

I don't really think either sex is stronger mentally to be quite honest.

But as I'm reading your post I'm finding that I have an answer to all of your claims so perhaps your second sentence was accurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796347742.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Men get so worked up because in our society the measure of a man is how he provides.

You are admitting that men’s behavior at socially constructed at least to some extent. The same thing must then be said about women. Have you considered that the things that you believe makes women inferior are a consequence of discourses and themes in a society that has been created by men for men and, while we have come a long way since, is still very much shaped by that patriarchal heritage? Or is everything that makes men inferior a social construct and everything that makes women inferior biology?  

And if it is socially constructed, are women really to blame? Can we really speak of women being inferior when our society creates [glass ceilings](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glass_ceiling) and continue to reproduce attitudes that limits women from living up to their potential and rewards them for conforming to a behavior that we then describes as inferior (like a focus on beauty and materialism)? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796348855.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Is it a social construct if its always been there? Not a loaded questions genuinely curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796354130.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>It can be. Also, biology = natural but natural ≠ right. We can argue that men are biologically disinclined to commit to monogamous relationship because our natural instinct is to copulate with as many females as possible in order to "spread our seed" But since we're creative, intelligent creatures we can step away from our biology and commit to another behavior based on an input other than evolution, for example morality. 

If we base our perception on what makes women inferior in a pre-agricultural understanding of society that dictated that women shouldn't work because work was heavy and men was stronger, yea women are inferior in that aspect of life at least. But what was natural at one point can be considered as artificially constructed today because the circumstances from which that behavior came has been altered. Maybe the subordination of women were a natural order 10.000 years ago but it doesn't mean that it is natural today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796366521.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>But it also doesn't mean that it isn't? Am I interpreting this correctly? Sorry for the double negative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796414822.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>It doesn’t mean that it isn’t natural today? Let’s say that:

Women were naturally subordinated to men in a natural state and;
Therefore women are inferior to men today.

If the circumstances that led to a certain order has changed, is that order still relevant?  

Imagine a society where people had to complete hard labor everyday in order to survive. Sure, women could help out occasionally but they were frequently unable to provide for the society since they were tied up in a continuous circle of reproduction and had to give birth and care for off-spring. It would be men that sustained the population and for the most part it would be men who made the decisions. Women wouldn’t participate, economically, or political, in the society.

Now imagine that this society found a wealth of resources that allowed it to sustain itself without the input of hard labor. It became an economy of services rather than production. Women were subordinated to men in the first society because the burden to preserve society fell harder on them than on women. Do you think this order is valid even after the circumstances changed and the preservation of society relied on the performance of tasks where women were better or equally good as men, even if the first society more properly reflected the natural order of things?

Women are projected to be the breadwinner in a majority of American households by 2025, today it’s 40 % and growing. Of the fifteen job categories that will grow the most in the next decade, all but two are primarily occupied by women. We’re developing into a society in which qualities traditionally attributed to women are the ones that are most important: people skills, listening skills, being quiet and listening in early school-years. 

Natural selection isn't the survival of the fittest. It is the survival of those most adapted to the environment. In the post-industrial rich West, this seems to be women. 
 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
