<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796405595.0" user="WantingHuskies" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind.

Equality doesn't mean the same, or just as good as, it means balanced. The fact you're basing your judgment on fitness and intelligence is very narrow, especially as you're using anecdotal evidence and no statistics.

&amp;gt; Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

and women are better suited at certain other difficult tasks. so, I don't see what the relevance of this point is just because an intelligent man made it. 

&amp;gt;I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these privileges.

so do women not earn their own money? do men not have things bought for them by parents or spouses?

&amp;gt; The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points

 In your original point you said "I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized". I'm assuming you don't know everyone in the world on a personal level, so you're basing a whole world view on a less than a percentage of people in the world.

&amp;gt;I want to get over this belief because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day.

so are you looking down on women because you don't think they're as good as men? I'm a woman and I corrected 3 spelling mistakes in your OP when quoting you, does that make me smarter than you in every way?

After doing karate for 8 years, I've learned many things about equality, 
1. Physically, there is no absolute for anyone based on their gender, some people are stronger, some are more flexible and some are more agile.
2. Mentally, I've seen men break down into tears at gradings as much as women.
3. nobody gets it any easier than the other, its as true for life as it is in the dojo.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
