<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796339709.0" user="ANAL_RAPIST_MD" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that woman are not an inferior gender but more of a ying to our yang. Similarly how one arm is more dominant then the other, but you would have a difficult time in life without the weak arm.

On physical strength men are obviously superior but in today's society it means very little. In the past labor was much more intense and required physically fit men to build the foundation of our country. In today's modern era machine's have replaced the need for intense labor in most fields and as technology improves the need will be even less. In a construction site it really doesn't matter how strong you are to work a crane or drive a bob cat. 

The intellectual point is a very difficult one, you can't really gauge on a scale how intelligent or smart someone is. I think the main issue behind women not being regarded as intellectually equal to men is we as a society systematically suppressed women for hundreds of years. This is the main reason you only hear about great things men did, because women never had a chance or were brushed under the rug for their accomplishments. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796344670.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree that the oppression isn't helping. What I'm saying is, if the oppression is permanent, at what point does is stop being a social construct and start being natural?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796357549.0" user="ANAL_RAPIST_MD" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What I'm saying is, if the oppression is permanent, at what point does is stop being a social construct and start being natural?

Clarify? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796366795.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Really don't know how else to put it. Apologies</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796371155.0" user="ANAL_RAPIST_MD" delta="False">
    <text>Well i don't believe the oppression is permanent, but is a slow process to have women more accepted as equals in a society that has been dominated by men. It's human nature to want to keep power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796385174.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>Is our society less real then our nature? How do you define what is natural, our first societies? And why is this better then our "unnatural" ways we live today, like driving a car, taking medicine or using birth control?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796399295.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe he means a self-fulfilling prophecy situation: Since women have been told they're inferior to men for so long, at what point do they actually become, in whatever ways, inferior?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796654295.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not natural. It is a social construct. 

That would be like saying: White people seem to score higher on test in America than Blacks. At what point does it stop being social construct, and start being natural that Whites are smarter than Blacks. 

See how stupid that sounds? Based on your logic and reasoning, you can say that White people and smarter than Black people, but that is not true. Statistically that may appear true, but the capabilities of both are in fact equal, but the social construct of society has kept them repressed for many years. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796717567.0" user="polyhooly" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by "natural?" That women have been oppressed because they are "naturally" inferior? Well the very fact that as soon as your begin allowing women equal opportunities, educating them equally, and respecting them as equals, you begin to see any gender discrepancies in intelligence virtually disappear demonstrates that women's performances in intellectual tasks is proportional to how they are treated in society, and the fact that the level of oppression women face in different societies varies, suggests that the oppression of women is a social construct. 

Human beings are good at treating other human beings like shit. I would say oppressing others is "natural" to human beings, but who is on the receiving end of that oppression varies based on social constructs. I disagree, but many would argue that in the western world the pendulum is swinging toward men being the more oppressed gender.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
