<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796380136.0" user="n0t1337" delta="False">
    <text>So, I mean you're problem is that when you think about the superior gender, you're thinking about the best of the best. The strongest people, the fastest people, the smartest people, the most successful people; they're all men. If however, you looked for the dumbest and least successful, they'd also be men.

If you look at median intelligence instead of maximum intelligence, men and women come out about the same. (Though perhaps women have a slight lead at the moment, I haven't really been keeping close tabs.)

If you're argument is that women are dumb because there are almost certainly men that are smarter than her, you must also recognize that she's smart because there are almost certainly men dumber than her. That's just the nature of a flatter bell curve.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
