<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796330755.0" user="joker_of_the_deck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women

I used to hold such a belief in my teens. Since then, I have come to view things differently.

No person is the average statistic. Every person, a cliche as this may be, is unique. Physical factors like gender is simply coincidental.

So when I am interacting with a woman, I know now that I am actually dealing with a person, primarily. The person might belong to any subset of classification we have - but is still a person in her own right. As a result, she has as much of my respect and benefit of doubt as any other person has.

Nothing else matters. Nothing else has mattered.

Edit: Correction of formatting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796336592.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>This is basically the view I wish I held. But your post has made me realize that I don't just generalize with women. I do it with rich people, poor people, smart people, tall people. If I see an attractive man, I assume he is swimming in it, if if see an attractive girl, I assume she never buys her own drinks. I've learned to be pretty good at constantly evaluating people so their first or second impressions don't stick as much, but even after I find out that pretty girl actually always buys her own drinks I tell myself she's the exception or assume there is something off about her that isn't apparent that is causing the situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796383293.0" user="LordKahra" delta="False">
    <text>This is an oversimplification, but:

1. Evidence contrary to viewpoint encountered.
2. Cognitive dissonance experienced.
3. In order to reduce discomfort, beliefs must be aligned with reality. Possible choices: Change beliefs or change reality.
4. Choice made: Devalue evidence, "changing" reality rather than beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796424537.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>*thumbs up for a basic psych education*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796462620.0" user="Nausved" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you don't need to be told how you're mistaken; you need to learn how to overcome your impulsive habit of assuming you know more about a given stranger than you actually do. It sounds like you understand, intellectually, what you're doing wrong, but for whatever reason your brain is stuck in this pattern of fallacious reasoning. (Out of personal curiosity, do you find yourself frequently forming beliefs on limited evidence in other areas, such as supernatural or spiritual concerns—especially beliefs that you are ashamed of or actively try to resist?)

Unfortunately, I don't think a forum like this is going to be of enormous help. It sounds more like you should should seek therapy from a professional who is specifically trained in kicking bad mental habits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796503351.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>But it sounds like you know your own opinion is bullshit here.  Maybe you don't really hold this view anymore?

In any event, at least you are trying to change it, if you haven't already.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796512679.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>In addition to what LordKahra said, there is a well-known problem in eliminating stereotypes that are wrong. Imagine you held a view of a group that was really far off the mark. When you encounter someone who happens to conform to that view, you use it as evidence you're right. However, you'll often be encountering _really_ counterstereotypic individuals. When this happens, people tend to create subgroups, saying that this happens to be a special case, instead of changing their overall view of the stereotype. 

Unfortunately, this makes it very hard to change stereotypes that are highly inaccurate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796655468.0" user="Drew_cifer" delta="False">
    <text>Men generally are obviously are superior physically and in dominance. Blame testosterone...that's just how we evolved. I think other than that females are pretty equal. I do, however, very much believe that the STEREOTYPE of females is far inferior to men. I think culturally, at least in America, younger adults want to fit in and socialize a lot. This makes a lot of women start behaving more like the stereotype to fit in, therefore making the stereotype more prominent. When I see a girl that I'm about to interact with, I make a judgement of them being a "typical" female, then interact with the person trying to disprove the judgement I made. If they disprove the parts I dislike about the stereotype, then they are probably a person who I would be happy to continue interacting with. I think that a women has the potential to be just as intellectual as a man, but cultural influences and other things make men use their potential more.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827187750.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Excellent point. Any individual can be described by maybe a thousand variables. If we measure by groups of individuals divided by some uniting attribute (sex, for instance), then you will simply get 1000 overlapping normal distributions. Each distribution can be fit to a curve and you can calculate fun attributes like lambda max and standard deviation. That's it folks.

Now, what are the implications of this? Let's examine some of the common variables which obviously separate men/women, say... height and strength. Yes, the lambda max of the men's curve is greater. The stddev is probably about the same. And the fun fact is that you WILL find many many many men weaker and shorter than many many many women. 

Let's talk about intelligence now. I almost agree that men seem to be more polarized. I like to think, from my experience that the lambda max form women is greater but the stdev for men is MUCH larger. This may partially explain the greater participation of men in STEM, nobel prizes, etc. etc. It may also explain the glass floor, which demonstrates that men are far more likely to be homeless. It may be partially explained BY the greater prevalence of mental health issues suffered by men...

But really, the take home, and this addresses /u/TyKillsTyGoT directly, is that any individual you meet is likely to fall into some position on those normal distributions which may be quite far from the mean. Judge people on an individual basis and not by their group. Math demands it! </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
