<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796487004.0" user="iamacarboncarbonbond" delta="False">
    <text>Did you ever consider that maybe you don't know a whole lot of smart women because smart women are intelligent enough to stay away from your sexist ass?

And yeah, the strongest man in the world is probably stronger than the strongest woman, but who gives a shit? It's not like humanity has to slay woolly mammoths for survival anymore.

Even if a woman is "just" a wife and mother, being a wife and mother is fucking important to society. Have you seen a baby? They're worthless. They can't walk or feed themselves or anything. You're judging women based on criteria *you* think of as worthwhile, not on things that are objectively worthwhile. Having babies and then making sure they're fed and don't drown or something? Pretty damn important to the human race.

Or how about other traditionally "female" roles, like nursing and teaching? Also pretty damn important.

A fish is going to suck a flying. A bird is going to suck at swimming. Neither is inherently superior.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
