<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796422573.0" user="rocqua" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that men are physically stronger than women. Other than that though, almost all perceived differences are not inherent to women, but to our society. It wasn't long ago that women were thought unfit for a huge amount of tasks. These days the situation has improved, but there is still some residual assumption of incompetence. Sadly this is almost a self-fulfilling prophecy. Since it prevents women from moving up, not to mention confirmation bias.

As for men being smarter, i'm going to assume this is because of the sciences. Let me tell you that, as a mathematics student, some of the most impressive students I know are women, and proportionally, there are just as many women struggling as there are men. Furthermore, for mathematics at my university, there is roughly a 50/50 split of M/F. Where we don't see this is subjects like physics or computing science, whilst these subjects are hugely similar. At the same time, these subjects are traditionally male. For computing science, this is obvious, no-one in society expects a female IT-student. For physics, as compared to mathematics, it is a bit less obvious. Look at it like this though: in physics you think of an idea, and then you build something to test it, going to physical extremes. In maths you think of an idea, and then you think about it some more. Which of the above do you think is stereotypically more male? Personally it's definitely the first, building something and physical extremes are a lot more 'male' in our society.

All of this disregards the fact that the prospect of being one of the very few women in a predominantly male organization can be hugely intimidating/off-putting.

My point, women's lower status is not a sign of their inferiority, but of them being discriminated.

Sincerely,
A man</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
