<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796471696.0" user="bluegreatasswhale" delta="False">
    <text>There are many women who live off the money of other people, and there are many women who are smart, but not as smart as man, or who are fit but not as fit as men. 

What I take issue with is that you deem women inferior, and don't seem to acknowledge that women have many roles where most men have one. *Not all men, most men* have one job: to work and provide. They are not tasked with taking care of kids, or doing housework. Many men are not equipped by their families or society to do those jobs, so by default it falls to women. 

The end result  of women performing multiple tasks, and take on multiple jobs, is they don't develop the aspect of smartness or fitness to the degree that men develop them. Women are generalists, while men are specialists. It doesn't make women inferior to men, it just makes them different. 

I'm not going to argue that  women are physically stronger or smarter, because all your evidence is anecdotal. I have anecdotes about how this girl I played rugby with is now the fittest individual (when compared to both men and women) in her army unit. I am smarter and have out scored men in my field of study plenty of times. I think both your "research" and anecdotes are not valid because they are ecological fallacies: you're taking aggregate level data, and applying it to individuals. You've tested your hypothesis among your friends/acquaintances and have generalized those results to all females. Likewise, researchers take many individual level data and aggregate them. That means you can't take those findings and apply it to an individual or group. Just because you know some ditzy women, or because on average women score worse on IQ test and aren't as strong  as men does not men all women are inferior to all men. 

I'll leave you with this thought: while men on average may test better, or be stronger, it is women who can truly affect change in a society. You want to increase the upward mobility of a society: educate women. You want the overall community health of your society to increase: target women. 

Women might not be the "genetically" or "physically" superior sex, but we often are the ones who are best able to bring about change and perform a multitude of tasks. We can take care of a family, and have a full time career. I don't think you could argue that lots of men have that ability. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
