<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796779744.0" user="avantvernacular" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to offer an alternative perspective, OP. (apologies, this is super long.)

Let us imagine we rank all the people in the world on an arbitrary scale of "superiority" from 1 to 5 (5 being most superior, 1 being most inferior). Then let us take your assumption that:

&amp;gt;  It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. 

And assume it's true - what could account for that? You may argue that it's by nature of the gender, but here is an alternative cause: 

Men (and boys) make up about 80% of suicides, 93% of workplace deaths, roughly 70% of violent crime victims, 60% longer prison sentences for the same crimes, and nearly 15 times the incarceration rate for the same crimes. These means that the overwhelming majority of people being killed, imprisoned, or otherwise "removed" from society are men. This can be argued to fit your definition of *"fail spectacularly,"* as I'm sure you'll agree.

Now let us make a reasonable assumption that this "removal" disproportionally affects those on the lower end of the "superiority scale" previously mentioned. That is to say for examples, that of people who commit suicide, they will be mostly 1s, 2s, and maybe some 3s, but very few 4s, and 5s, and is most likely similar for both genders. (My apologies if this seems callous, it feels that way as I type it but I think it's necessary to convey the point.) Effective the bottom of the scale is being "culled," be it either through death or imprisonment.

With so much of this "culling" occurring for men, and so little occurring for women, it is only natural to assume that it would skew the average.
For example, image we have a hypothetical 25 men born and a hypothetical 25 women born, each group have 5 1s, 2s, 3s, 4s, and 5s.
The average "superiority" value of both groups at birth is 2.5

Now let's account for how much has been removed by suicide after say, a quarter century. Since it affects men 4 times as often as women, let's say we lose 2 women and 8 men, both concentrated on the lower end of the scale (as explained above). Let's say the women lose a 1 and a 2; the men lose three 1s, three 2s, a 3 and a 4. The women's numbers are now 1^(x4) , 2^(x4) , 3^(x5), 4^(x5) , 5^(x5), while the men's are 1^(x2) , 2^(x2) , 3^(x4) , 4^(x4) and 5^(x5).

While both starting born at the same average of 2.5, the women's average of their remaining 23 is now **3.13** and the men's average of their remaining 17 is now **3.47.**

*Keep in mind that I exaggerate the number to make the example more clear, I know that %32 of men don't kill themselves by 25.*

Combine suicide with murder victims, incarceration, imprisonment at the rates I mentioned above, and the gap widens further. So the perception occurs that men are more "superior," but that only because so many more men than women have been "removed" from the sampling.

Now I know you're thinking *but wait, wouldn't there be far more women then men on the planet if this was true?* Yes it would, until you consider that more boys are born than girls - 1.048 to 1 in the [US](http://www.nationmaster.com/graph/peo_sex_rat_at_bir-people-sex-ratio-at-birth) - and yet in spite of this, in the general population there only 97 males to every 100 females. 

**tl;dr Men appear on average "superior" because a much larger portion of "inferior" men than women are no longer with us, skewing the average.**</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
