<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796351160.0" user="aeauriga" delta="False">
    <text>It seems like to get an answer you'll believe, I won't have to just confront your view on women in current society, but across time.

It is likely that men gained more power than women in the earlier days due to their strength and violence. Much of this could be attributed to testosterone and wanting to dominate other men in battle or women at home. This would likely give men the upper hand in tribal cultures that propagates society until a time where strength-based fighting no longer exists. 

Throughout time we have developed weapons that no longer require pure strength to have the upper hand. While men still have more overall strength, women have better manual dexterity and fine motor skills. Neither of these is outright "better," although I'd argue it is much more important in today's world to have fine motor skills than brute strength. All you can really do with brute strength is lift heavy things, or punch things, which isn't nearly as good as modern self defense tools/weapons.

So even though strength *was* a factor in the start of civilization, enough modern technology exists that it isn't better outright (guns beat punches). So what about other differences?

Having two X chromosomes makes up for a lot of diseases/deficiencies that males are plagued with. Living much longer on average regardless of country you live in seems clearly better. I'm going to say the cancers of each gender in their gender-specific parts are equal overall since breast/cervix and testicle/colon are all horrible and quite prevalent. 

Also, while on the matter of bodies, being larger is not better any more. Being male generally means eating more (due to larger bodies and usually faster metabolisms), which really just means spending more money.

Now for the matter of intelligence, as you've pointed out yourself in other comments here, women on average have higher IQ but there are more men on either side of the bell curve. Think about this using statistics. Outliers exist in any data set. In data sets with larger numbers of entries, there will be a larger overall number of outliers, with those outliers generally having a larger spread (in this case there will be more stupid/smart men and they will be smarter/stupider than their female counterparts). Why am I saying that there is a larger number of men than women in this pool of people you measure? Basically because of what others here have said, women have not had nearly as much opportunity to get into science/math/engineering as men have. Not only is it an issue of women not being allowed into math/engineering/science programs in the past, it's the continuing stigma that is hopefully now being destroyed that "women can't/shouldn't do math." 

Look up the story of https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emmy_Noether to see just how bad it was for women mathematicians in history. This is why you rarely see talk of women in science up until more recently.

At the very least you could see how if your viewpoint was held by other people in powerful positions it would be hard for women to ever break into any fields. If anyone hiring people for a job believes as you do, clearly there would be less women in that field. This would lead to people believing that women are worse at that field (after all, why aren't any of them in it if they are equals?). Your viewpoint itself would stop further progress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796363417.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really disagree with any of this. Just an unfortunate situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796367868.0" user="aeauriga" delta="False">
    <text>If you don't disagree with any of it then what else makes you think that men are superior?

The only thing that got men ahead, as I explain, is they were initially stronger and prone to violence. Unless you think that strength + violence is still superior, which in any modern society, it isn't.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
