<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="30" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796624957.0" user="someenglishrose" delta="False">
    <text>I am a lecturer in the biological sciences at an elite university. The data set I am going to use to refute your argument that women are the weaker sex, intellectually, is the final scores of my undergraduates (of course, this can't speak to physical strength, where other people have made good arguments). 



Before I begin, I should say that of course I appreciate that my students are not representative of people in general: they have already been selected for their intellectual capabilities. Nevertheless, I believe that this is an illustrative data set. I should also defend my use of undergraduate exam scores as a measure of intelligence as opposed to, say, IQ scores. Firstly, I think that exam scores are more representative of "real world" intelligence as they encompass both innate ability and the effort expended in learning and improving. Secondly, many IQ tests administered in Western populations actually have the same distribution as the exam scores I am going to talk about.



Obviously I can't share the raw data with strangers on the internet. Sorry! A description of the distributions (which, by the way, are normal) will have to suffice.



Among my students, we find that the mean score is higher in females, but the standard deviation is higher in males. That discounts your argument that women are "on average" less intelligent than men: among my students, the women are "on average" (mean) more intelligent than the men. If you take into account that we have already selected students in the top 5 or 10% of school leavers and that, as we have already noted (and this is well documented with IQ, too) the variance of scores is higher in males, that's surprising to begin with.



Examining now the question of whether the "top" males score better than the "top" females. In a pair of distributions like the ones I have described, that will actually depend on the magnitude of the differences, both in mean and in standard deviation. For my students, it works out that if you look at the top 5% of scores, the number of males and females is roughly equal, so the two factors balance out and the proportion of "elite" females is the same as the proportion of "elite" males. Within my data set, at least, the best males and no better than the best females. Even if you look at the very top student, it's a women as often as you would expect by chance.



That being the case, you may say, why wasn't Richard Feynman (say) a women? (Why wasn't Marie Curie a man? But we'll let that one go by...) I'll be honest: I can't rule out the possibility that when we are looking at the global population, the increased variance in male intelligence outweighs any difference there might be in average intelligence, so if we look at the very cleverest person in every generation, it's likely to be a man. *However* I think it's important to stress that by the time we are looking at once-in-a-generation individuals, it's not really fair to compare the representation of women to that of men, because women have so recently (even in Western populations) started to compete on a level playing field with men in terms of their education. In fact, the first generation for which we can sensibly do this is probably just beginning its career.



Even now, women suffer a significant career burden because of child-rearing: in my field I actually see *more* women than men getting the required grades in their undergraduate degrees to undertake a PhD. Similarly more women than men complete their PhD and continue in research. These women progress up the career ladder at the same rate as men, until they decide to have families, at which point they start to become underrepresented, and I firmly believe that this could be corrected with more gender-balanced family leave policies.



To speak to your personal problem: the distributions of male v. female intelligence, strength or whatever are actually irrelevant. You may judge the person in front of you as "inferior" to you (if you are that way minded) based on their actual intelligence, strength or whatever compared to you. Their gender is irrelevant since I would wager there are plenty of women who could outclass you in many measures.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
