<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796357655.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Inferiority or superiority only makes sense with relation to a goal, because judgements of value literally mean suitability for a purpose, good means "good for". And nobody can do everything.

Generally speaking women are inferior than men when trying to do manly stuff and superior to men when trying to womanly stuff.  For example they make better kindergarten teachers - more patience.

So generally speaking women deserve as much respect as much they re willing to fill mostly womanly, not manly roles in life, because this also roughly predicts how good they are at them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796362991.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>You're getting lost in the jargon, the OP conveys my feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
