<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="21" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796419409.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Ohh wow, there's lots of ways I can approach this.... let me think for a minute...

Hmm...

Well, maybe rather than trying to refute the study of superlatives (biggest X, fastest X, smartest X), I can address the implications of matching sets and your assertions.

So, when you say things like "X is superior to Y", then you are saying that "for every X, such that X does a thing, X does that thing better than any Y".

At least, that's how it comes across.

I don't think you're so anti-intellectual to recognize that there are many, many men who are inferior in many, many activities to many, many women. Your statements seem to support the idea that *any* man should inherit the status of 'superior' over *any* woman. So if you're thinking of superiority in ability, we can know for certain that it doesn't follow that if a member of X is better at something than any member of Y, that all members of X are also better than any member of Y.

So if we're making an inventory of skills and ranking all of the people on the planet by their ability, we might get a distribution that looks something like this:

Tallest: top 5% are members of X exclusively, the next 5% are about 80% X, the next 5% are split about 60x/40y etc

Smartest: probably going to have a lot more variance here, particularly since if you know anything at all about the science of *being smart* you'll know that it's actually very difficult to quantify, and hence rank. Intellectual ability varies dramatically within an individual, relative to age, health and levels of alertness - hence we are all entitled to moments of stupidity.

The distribution for "Smartest" is likely going to be much closer to 50/50 all of the way through, even if a slight edge goes to group X. 

Anyways, when dealing with superlatives and sets, for every high-ranking individual, we'll find that every member of both sets who scores below them is inferior.

For instance, I would be willing to bet substantial money that you, as you are right now, could **Never** beat any female olympian in their sport of choice. Not even one of the bottom tier olympians.

I would also be willing to wager that you are intellectually inferior to: female doctors, lawyers, physicists etc.

Not to mention qualifications about emotional intelligence when that is viewed as an adaptable behavior.

So that's that. Qualities such as ability aren't inherited by members of the same set here, and if you overlap the sets you'll find that many men are quite inferior to many women in a great many ways.

Now lets move on to being human beings again.

You like sports, right?

Sure, we all love the hero. The guy who scores a bagillion points a night. But what about the grinders? Don't they also play a role? Aren't they also to be honored for their contribution? Even if it's not as large, it's still a contribution. 

You know what I value in a person? I value their effort. I value a person who gives all that they can, every time that they can. I like the grinder who has a lot of heart. 

I value the 120ib girl who carries half her weight while camping without complaint, more than I value the 210 pound fat fuck of a guy who whines about his 60ib pack the whole fucking time. I value the girl who steps up to a challenge more than a guy who shies away from it.

I value heart and effort more than I value people who feel imposed upon, even if the little, weak, dumb person contributes less over all.

So here's how it plays out in real life. When we go camping, I carry the lion's share of the gear. I have 60ibs of weight over my girlfriend, and I'm a roofer, so I'm in excellent shape. But goddamned if that girl doesn't work, and work and work. I'll go to get wood, and she'll have set up the whole goddamned camp site and cooked us both some steak by the time I come back with firewood, and all while my guy friends sit around drinking beer and rolling joints. You know. Not contributing.

If you're the kind of person who will come back and think "Yeah... but I did more, so she owes me"

Then I'm sorry friend... but I know one thing for sure that most women are better at.

Not being a dick.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796485999.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be basically saying that certain women are better than certain men. This is true. However the point is that (besides horse back riding) men are better at everything that can be considered a sport, and everything which can be considered intellectual. This is both true if you take the best at both genders, and if you take the average (maybe not intellectual average, that one im not sure on). 

It is like saying, yes there are midgets who cna beat me in a fight. However the average normal guy woule destory the average midget, same goes for top tier. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
