<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796314549.0" user="knook" delta="False">
    <text>1) Who cares if we are stronger physically in the sense that I can lift more weight, I dont conceal a little human factory in me.

2) Women are now outscoring men in IQ :
http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/beautiful-minds/201207/men-women-and-iq-setting-the-record-straight

Boom</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796316509.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>I think physical strength is very important. In fact, if someone argued that the reason men control the world is because they are stronger than women I don't think I would object. The fact that women only get to have agency because men physically restrain themselves is not trivial. If tommorow the police disappeared, women would be a lot worse off than men.

I know women do better on average, because men are on the other sides of the bell curve. My point is that the smartest men are smarter than the smartest women. There will always be some women who are smarter than some men however.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796337906.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>This is an odd argument. 

Lets say there's a relay race and team A have two ridiculously fast sprinters but the rest is below average and two are not fast at all. Team B have none who can compete with team A's super sprinters but everyone is above average in terms of speed.

Who do you think finish first?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796340687.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on how fast or slow the super sprinters are of course. And the length of the race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796538988.0" user="Chuckabear" delta="False">
    <text>So, we should take an average right?

Also, the length of the race is irrelevant if each runner is running the same distance.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796398246.0" user="See-9" delta="False">
    <text>I think your argument is a bit silly as well. Innovation in society isn't determined by the lowest common denominator, it's decided by societal greats. The intellectual elite.

The human race isn't a literal one. If men make up 90% of the driving force behind the progressive force that moves society forward, it doesn't really matter if also make up a large portion of the weak links. I would say, in your analogy, team A's super fast runners will be recruited by an elite team to create an all-star team. The weak links of Team A and Team B will fall into mediocrity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796410006.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>It's important to consider that one of the big reasons men make up so much of this "driving force" you mention (and I don't necessarily disagree there) is because they made it so. Women were not given opportunities to help progress. If they were, society would undoubtedly have progressed differently (I'm not going to argue for better or worse; it's just an interesting thought experiment to consider). I don't know why or how men initially began commandeering nearly everything, but the point remains that women have not had as equal an opportunity to participate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796421482.0" user="jafarialaddin" delta="False">
    <text>/u/tmwy already brought it up but I'll reply as well. You can't really count innovation that already took place because women weren't allowed to participate on the same terms. 

To continue the analogy it's like saying that Team A had already run several laps while Team B waited to be let into the arena. And then claiming that A should be allowed to count those laps towards victory. And remember that Team B is still waiting for most its members to line up. Some haven't even been allowed to look at the arena. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797628958.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You can't really count innovation that already took place because women weren't allowed to participate on the same terms.

which would be? That women have equal opportunity? But didn't they do that already and came up short? Why is equal opportunity giving away what men did? 

*"Thus, thereason for the emergence of genderinequality may have little to do with men pushing women down in somedubious patriarchal conspiracy. Rather, it camefrom the fact that wealth, knowledge, and power were created in the men’ssphere. This is what pushed the men’s sphere ahead. Not oppression." - Baumeister (Is there anything good about men) *

&amp;gt;To continue the analogy it's like saying that

"Every man-made or rather human-made institution fell from space, and men being men, ran into the more prestigious ones and then locked the doors after them. Women being poor runners and with the additional handicap of being pregnant and with babies stuck to their udders were then not let in."

http://endofwomen.blogspot.in/2012/10/male-dominated-history-and-definition.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796675081.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think your argument is a bit silly as well. Innovation in society isn't determined by the lowest common denominator, it's decided by societal greats. The intellectual elite.

OPs argument is that on the whole women are inferior to men.  Which means you need to take the population *on the whole*.  I don't think this IQ idea has been properly supported with evidence, but even if we take it as fact.  How can you justify taking the men who skew smarter as an advantage but ignore the men who skew stupider as an obvious disadvantage?  At best its a wash.

To reverse his argument, what if I said, "women are smarter than men, look at all those idiots on the bottom end of the scale!"  Makes about as much sense as the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796352667.0" user="surreptitiouswalk" delta="False">
    <text>We don't live in a world where physical strength is important to progress society. Battles are often fought emotionally (diplomacy, politics, workplace relations, personal relationships and social and professional networks) or intellectually (science, political policy etc). Physical strength is only ever a last resort measure and its never welcome (revolutions, wars, domestic violence).

I don't know where you got the idea that the smartest men is smarter than the smartest women from.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796509306.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>I think the idea is that, while the means in IQs may be very similar, the spread or variation in IQ is larger for men. This would mean that there are many more men on the extreme low end of the spectrum, but also many more men at the extreme high end of the spectrum. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796536406.0" user="Chuckabear" delta="False">
    <text>Great. What is the basis, then, for focusing on only the smartest men and ignoring the dumbest? This should be addressed, by the way, after this:

&amp;gt;This would mean that there are many more men on the extreme low end of the spectrum, but also many more men at the extreme high end of the spectrum. 

is evidenced.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796550642.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>I should note that I'm not arguing for the OPs side, but was clarifying the argument. I think elsewhere in this thread, the claim has been made that in our society, we learn and benefit from others, even when we wouldn't be able to discover, create or think of the new ideas or technology on our own... so that a lot of progress comes from the people at the upper end.  

Equal means, but greater variation means that there are more people in the upper and lower tails of the distribution.

There is some evidence that men might have greater variation in IQ (some are referenced in the [wikipedia article](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sex_differences_in_human_psychology#IQ)), though this doesn't demonstrate that there's some sort of genetic (vs environmental) reason, if the effect is real.

Even if there are more men at the tails, why that would mean men are better than women on average isn't really clear - that portion of the argument seems more to do with what the OP thinks are the common behaviours in men and women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796639285.0" user="Chuckabear" delta="False">
    <text>I understand distributions with fat tails (upper level stats in college), but it doesn't change the average makeup of the group unless you decide to throw out a certain subset of the distribution. In order to do so, you'd have to provide some justification and, even if you did that, you'd have to couch any conclusion with the caveat that you were only looking at a subset of the population. I think we agree on this, but obviously it goes against the case OP is making here.

And I know you weren't necessarily defending the OP, but I was pointing out that even before you need to justify looking at segments of the population you need to actually demonstrate that your (his) assertions align with reality with evidence.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796706241.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>My apologies for explaining something you're already familiar with!  

Yes, I agree - even if it were true that the variance of IQ in men is larger, so that there are more very intelligent men, that would need to also be accompanied by the observation that there also are many more very unintelligent men, which doesn't really suggest that "women are the inferior gender" like the OP was suggesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796371828.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The fact that women only get to have agency because men physically restrain themselves is not trivial.

Welcome to society. We founded it to escape the rule of the wilderness: "The strong kills the weak". How is this argument important for you being sexist? Do you see physical weaker persons inferior to you? Why then being sexist and despite all weaker persons? Are you uncomfortable with modern society?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796395171.0" user="Discoamazing" delta="False">
    <text>Physical strength stopped counting for much at about the same time we invented handguns.

On a related note, do you judge everyone in your life based on their physical strength?  If someone can do more squats than you, does that make you inferior to them?

What do you really mean by "inferior"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796408576.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The fact that women only get to have agency because men physically restrain themselves is not trivial.

This makes it sound as if you're implying that it is every man's nature to own, dominate, control, rule women. Is that what you meant?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796423941.0" user="Victorhcj" delta="False">
    <text>I think ingenuity is way more important than physical strength. Imagine I was a small woman and I shot you with a gun, your dead body would be inferior to my alive body.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796474807.0" user="RdmGuy64824" delta="False">
    <text>If strength were the most important attribute, black people would rule the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796490579.0" user="sw_anon" delta="False">
    <text>Let's talk about physical strength for a minute.

Men have a lot of *upper body* strength and women have a lot of *lower body*. This is a fact and when women take self defense classes they are taught to get in a position where they can use their legs vs their arms.

While the average male may be able to bench more than the average woman, the average woman will squat more than the average man.

PS: physical strength has nothing to do with modern society.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796537050.0" user="benalg" delta="False">
    <text>Average woman can't squat more. It's just that womens legs are proportionally stronger then their arms when compared to men. Men's legs are stronger than womens but their upper body strength as a ratio of their lower body strength is higher.

[This study](http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/8477683) suggests that on average women have 52% of an average males upper body strength and 66% of their lower body strength.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798004642.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the average woman will squat more than the average man.

Thats just moronic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796534809.0" user="Chuckabear" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think physical strength is very important.

By that standard, do you also concede that lions, tigers, chimpanzees, gorillas, elephants, whales, sharks, etc, etc, etc are superior to humans?

What evidence do you have that the smartest men are smarter than the smartest women (I'll point out that you're moving the goal posts here)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796379193.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I dont conceal a little human factory in me.

Ooh... that's going to upset the women who can't have kids, Cotton.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796428036.0" user="maybe_I_am_a_bot" delta="False">
    <text>Biology dont real, only feels are real.

Most of the objective differences between men and women can be brought back to the fact that women need to be able to give birth to children. A woman that can't have kids will still have the hips, breasts and genitals of a woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796429271.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>The only facts that are true are facts that don't hurt my feels.  Everyone knows that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796383550.0" user="PointingOutIrony" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Women are now outscoring men in IQ

[This is the first time this has happened in a century, and it's only happened once.](http://abcnews.go.com/blogs/health/2012/07/16/women-beat-men-on-iq-tests-for-first-time/)

If anything, western society's pro-women anti-man stance in the last 30 or 40 years is the culprit.

You can also blame teachers' gender bias in educating children (80% of teachers are female).

You can even blame all the women-only scholarships tipping the college enrolement to 60% female 40% male.

The game is rigged.  This has nothing to do with genes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796388383.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If you're going to account for that you'll also have to account for the fact that the "game has been rigged" in favor of men for centuries. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796450301.0" user="WorldsEndGirlfriend" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly he doesn't care about history of oppression for women, but 80% of teachers are female? That's the evidence for the rigged game. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796498360.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Right?  20% of the Senate members are women, and 18% of the house members.  Jesus.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797619580.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>Men are the creators of the game, a terrible sin that they then allowed women in for free. See Baumeister's "Is there anything good about men?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827183251.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Men are the creators of the game

I'll fix that for you. In the past a tiny number of men created it. Now, a tiny number of men and a growing number of women perpetuate and modify it. The VAST majority of people, men and women, have suffered and continue to suffer from it. 

You're mistake is assuming that sexes are teams and homogeneously benefit/suffer. It's a very simplified worldview. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827508221.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You're mistake is assuming that sexes are teams and homogeneously benefit/suffer. 

I won't fix that for you.

&amp;gt;It's a very simplified worldview.

You haven't got a clue, do you? Neither do I on what you're going on about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827182571.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing needs accounting for. PointingOutIrony is claiming that recent trends are responsible for recent outcomes. This is an entirely reasonable position. It's a ridiculous position however to claim that boys educated in the 80s/90s who have suffered from a very real rigged game are mysteriously benefiting a great deal from the centuries that came before. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796393355.0" user="BenLW" delta="False">
    <text>Do you any sources for this? Here is an eminent psychologist on the issue (Jim is the Professor, Greg the interviewer)

Greg: So given that, is there any reason to think at all that that gap isn't just going to keep widening over the next, say, 50, 100 years?

Jim: I don't think it will keep widening because I think women are fairly fully exposed to modernity in many countries. Now, there are exceptions that prove the rule. For example, in Israel, about 20% of women are highly orthodox and cloistered from the modern world, and their IQs are about 10 points below men. So that's, of course, an exception. And throughout the developing world, you have a situation that has to be remedied. One of the most interesting things is the South African data where white women equal men, but whereas in the coloured and the Asian and the black communities, the women still lag. And they're areas where women, of course, have not achieved full entry into the modern world.

Greg: So on the nature/nurture side of things, this is clearly about nurture being the winner in these numbers.

Jim: Very clearly. At one time, it was suggested that women had some genetic deficiency, a mild one, that prevented them from matching men for mental ability, and that's now been disproved.

http://tvnz.co.nz/q-and-a-news/interview-prof-jim-flynn-5085910</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796531390.0" user="_Search_" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you for providing a contrary source while asking for a citation. WAY too many people just post "Source?" without any justification or explanation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797231582.0" user="PenguinEatsBabies" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, [the study in question wasn't as noteworthy as people here claim.](http://www.amnation.com/vfr/archives/022834.html)  (Ignore the "informal" analogy at the beginning.)

Moreover, [the preponderance of evidence](http://www.independent.co.uk/news/education/higher/dr-paul-irwing-there-are-twice-as-many-men-as-women-with-an-iq-of-120plus-426321.html) indicates a) that the male mean is slightly higher than the female mean and b) that the male standard deviation is much larger -- hence, there are twice as many men as women with IQ's above 120 and 30 times as many with IQ's above 170.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798924066.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;this is clearly about nurture being the winner in these numbers.

not yet.

http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1inr08/i_believe_that_men_and_women_are_different/cb6j9hh

&amp;gt;and that's now been disproved

And that's why I rather had not quoted Flynn himself, the dyed-in-the-wool progressive who is careful to strike all the right progressive notes lest he come across as another Bell Curver.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799053998.0" user="BenLW" delta="False">
    <text>"And that's why I rather had not quoted Flynn himself, the dyed-in-the-wool progressive who is careful to strike all the right progressive notes"

Rubbish. Yes is a lefty, no he does not change what he says to avoid criticism. Try attacking his actual arguments rather than making up criticisms about him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799083908.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Rubbish. Yes is a lefty

&amp;gt;no he does not change what he says to avoid criticism

you are not exactly impressing me.

&amp;gt;Try attacking his actual arguments 

if you read what I linked to, I did. Despite overwhelming advantages of nurture for girls in the developed world, they still lag behind boys on maths. Regarding the executive functions explanation, if the shoe was on the other foot, he would have been chastened like Larry Summers was, and the study I wrote about would have been touting how girls are so distracted by the societal influences that they are unable to devote same amount of time to their studies.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799202085.0" user="BenLW" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; you are not exactly impressing me.
You are not exactly impressing me. You implied he manipulates his conclusions to suit his left-wing views. I don't see any proof of this. 

&amp;gt;Despite overwhelming advantages of nurture for girls in the developed world

That wasn't proved anywhere. Flynn himself believes there is a genetic component to intelligence - so even if there is completely cultural equality, there would still remain some differences in IQ - the evidence you sights support this. But his contention is that societal influences are greater than genetic ones.

"he would have been chastened like Larry Summers was"

Perhaps he would have. He does also argue that African-American culture is holding people back from having higher IQs, which is far from a controversy free left-wing position.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796403833.0" user="shades344" delta="False">
    <text>I think the fact that social factors can tip the scales in favor of women disproves the OP's point that men are smarter genetically. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796434842.0" user="isaacarsenal" delta="False">
    <text>Yet the number of male scientists and professors outnumbers the number of females, except in the biology and nursing probably.

There might be "glass ceiling" in the academics before, but I don't think there is a sexist system which hold back the women developed countries to get academic positions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796665163.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think the glass ceiling exists anymore?  I'm going to recount to you some tales from my moms career (one of the highest ranked women in Canadian banking).

- When applying for her first job, employers asked her what kind of birth control she was using and how frequently.  It was common practice at the time.

-  She was fired for being pregnant.  They actually said this in her exit interview.  Unsurprisingly, she sued.

- When she opened her first credit card she applied with my father.  They had the same credit (no credit) exactly the same job and education credentials.  She was given a $500 limit and had to have her father be a cosigner.  My father was given $10,000 and no cosigner

- Much of the networking for her business is conducted at bars and stripclubs.  She can possibly go if its a large group but if its only a couple (or god forbid, one man) she can't.  Because they like their boys club and the wives aren't happy about attractive coworkers hanging out at a bar.

-  She has been told "if you were a man, you would have gotten that promotion".  By her boss about 10 years after the fact.

-  She repeatedly runs across phrases like "I just can't trust a man till I've gotten drunk with him".  For the reasons listed above, she never falls into that category.

I have no doubt that academia has its own versions of these.  Sexism isn't dead, not yet at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796954751.0" user="isaacarsenal" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for the insight. I didn't expect any of these in a country like Canada.

Nevertheless, the business/banking culture is much different than academic culture. I have been a Master student studying computer engineering in Iran and I can say I haven't encountered any incident of sexism during these 7 years. Hell, if there were any sexism it was in favor of the females. A few professors grade females better. Some professor prefer to have a female PhD student since female student are less "troublesome".

I am not sure female PhD students have equal chance to become faculty or not. Anyhow, who is holding back female researchers to become scientists? They have the same access to resources (books, labs, papes, etc.) as males; at least in Electrical and Computer Engineering.

I am not sexism and believe but this is what I have observed. I guess the situation in developed countries is even better than Iran. So, my question still holds: 

Why we don't have females scientists/researchers as much as males that publish theories and papers? Why the most scientists we have know and already know are males? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796994396.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;They have the same access to resources (books, labs, papes, etc.) as males; at least in Electrical and Computer Engineering.

Well, this would be the same argument made for the banking industry.  They have the same access to books, the can apply for the same jobs, but that really doesn't tell the whole story.  The way sexism takes effect is as much by individual bias as institutional rules.  Unfortunately, hard work and talent only speak for themselves as much as others are prepared to listen.  Men like OP here are still around in abundance, actually Reddit is a great place to look for sexism if you care to.  If what I've seen from my mother's career generalizes there is significant personal bias that comes into play.  Despite working 12 hour days her whole career and being very competent she didn't advance or get paid the way a man in her position would have (and in some cases did).  There was no institutional policy that got in her way, it was everything else that makes up people's decision-making.

I can't comment more specifically on academia beyond pointing to the large percentage and success women have in undergrad compared to the suspicious dearth in academic establishment.  Also the ample evidence that women are just as intelligent as men, including in STEM fields.

I would also point out that statistically the number of women who could even get higher education wasn't significant until a few decades ago.  Its difficult to expect people to shake off the influence of centuries old institutions and ideas after a decade or two or progress.  Plus its pretty misleading to compare the opportunities and achievements of those decades to centuries of opportunities and accomplishments for men.

I'm not really sure how Iran plays into this conversation?  Things in Iran are so much worse, so be happy with what you have?  I don't think the horrific conditions women in Iran live under are much of a reason to stop pushing for equality in the developed world.  Its a pretty good argument for the need for equality everywhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798003264.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When applying for her first job, employers asked her what kind of birth control she was using and how frequently. It was common practice at the time.

While I can understand this isnt on, you can clearly see the point. Its a real fucking hassle if an employee gets knocked up and has to take maternity leave. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799142961.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic we should never hire women for jobs because they happen to be the gender that carries the babies.  The babies made by *both* genders.  Its bad policy and discriminatory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799386630.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Well no. If a person is going to have to take a large chunk of time off, then its a hassle. Thats pretty clear. They may be good enoguh to make up for that though. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799606127.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Well no.

Well, yes.  Look up the statutes.  Its illegal to discriminate on the basis of gender and refusing to hire women because they will likely one day be pregnant is discrimination.  Women are carrying the children for *both* genders, its discriminatory to penalize them for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799638442.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>Sure its illegal. That is not relevant though. This isnt a discussion about whether its legal, its a discussion about whether its right. 

Statistically most women will have children. They will have to take time off from work. Can you seriously not see how this might be viewed as a downside? (Thats a yes or no)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26799745531.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;its a discussion about whether its right. 

And its not right since its, say it with me now "discrimination based on gender".  Since we've recently decided women should be treated equally to men I think a rather basic aspect of that is the ability to work.

Is childbirth inconvenient for companies?  Sure.  So is illness, minimum wage, safe working conditions, overtime, parenthood in general and the rather human need for occasional vacations.  But you know, what?  I don't give a fuck, and here is why.

The downside would be excluding a full half of the talent pool because once or twice in their lives they're going to take time off from work.  The downside would be forcing women to stay with abusive husbands because they can't get a job and escape.  It would be children living in poverty because their father left.   

The downside would be making women a breeder class, indentured servants since they can't get a job and support themselves financially.  

Companies serve society, not the other way around.  Its in the interests of society to have women work, but also have babies (to y'know, continue society).  I care rather more about human rights than industries' convenience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800152837.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; And its not right since its, say it with me now "discrimination based on gender"

I dont think that this is wrong as long as there is a logical reason that the certain gender may not be as well suited for the job (including the long run possibilities).

&amp;gt; The downside would be excluding a full half of the talent pool 

Who said exclude? It may simply put them at a slight disadvantage. A better candidate will still almost always get the job. 

&amp;gt; The downside would be making women a breeder class, indentured servants since they can't get a job and support themselves financially.

If there was a similar effect for men, e.g. chance of conscription, I would also support making decisions of that. Its nothing to do with the fact that they are female, its the fact that there is a trait which may be detrimental to their work. Its a purely logical decision. 

Also do you seriously think that if there was a slight disadvantage no women could get jobs? You really think lowly of women. 

&amp;gt; Companies serve society

Companies serve their shareholders. Their aim is to make profit. Im not sure where you get Companies serve society from. 
 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26801166101.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Also do you seriously think that if there was a slight disadvantage no women could get jobs? You really think lowly of women. 

I think that if women were considered poor candidates for jobs because they bear children then few will be able to get jobs.  Its no reflection on the women or their capabilities.  Its a reflection on the bigotry of the system.

&amp;gt;Companies serve their shareholders. Their aim is to make profit. Im not sure where you get Companies serve society from. 

Those shareholders are people in society.  The point of industry is to generate revenue to participate in the market - the theory behind the market is that it serves to raise everyone's standard of living.  Otherwise why have it?  If companies serve society in no way and actively work against its interests, why would we allow it to exist?  We wouldn't.

The profits are to serve the people, not the other way around.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26801219278.0" user="neutrinogambit" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Those shareholders are people in society.

A very small part of it. Companies have no reason to care about anyone else. You make it sound like every company should care about me or you. 

&amp;gt; I think that if women were considered poor candidates for jobs because they bear children then few will be able to get jobs.

Wow. just wow. So if there was even the smallest disfavour for women, boom, not many getting jobs. The fuck dude. 

Also you call it bigotry. Treating different people differently is not bigotry. The word implies some emotional issue. That has fuck all to do with emotions. It is a logical profit maximising reason.  

&amp;gt; The profits are to serve the people, not the other way around.

A company is there to make money (yes expand and shit but its all part of the money game plan). That is the point. You really think companies 'care' about the people? Seriously? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796426959.0" user="x4u" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 2) Women are now outscoring men in IQ 

Which only indicates that the IQ test that was used for this result is either outdated and needs to be readjusted or that there was a bias in the selection of participants.

IQ tests are specifically constructed so that male and female participants come out with very similar scores on average and have been readjusted many times over the dacades to keep it this way. There are significant gender differences in many IQ test aspects and the questions get selected and weightened carefully to make these differences level out on average. I.e. females tend to score better on word related tests whereas males are better at tests that require spatial thinking. But there are also aspects like memorization that are used to adjust gender bias: Females do better than males if the test is based on memorizing names or colors while males come out better if the test requires them to memorize foreign countries or cities or numbers of different magnitude.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797618658.0" user="namae_nanka" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"Who cares if we are stronger physically in the sense that I can lift more weight"

the feminists do. Mary Wollstonecraft, the grandmomma of feminism argued that barring the physical differences, there was no difference between men and women. The physical inferiority of women has been complemented by a moral superiority which continues to this day. And is the reason why feminism is so intent on making sure that it gets to equality where mental powers are concerned.

And as the good ole' boy Aristotle said, inferiors revolt in order to be equal, equals in order that they be superior.
So women are as good as men and sometimes better. Equal at maths, but even better at reading, don't you love them gender-equality.

http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1inr08/i_believe_that_men_and_women_are_different/cb6j9hh

That women are physically inferior is a great driver of feminist desire to make it up for mentally. And if you look up "The Frailty Myth" sometime, some would not even agree to the physical inferiority thing.

http://endofwomen.blogspot.in/2012/10/womens-brains-and-upper-body-strength.html

&amp;gt;Women are now outscoring men in IQ 

*Terman made efforts to correct item bias in the Stanford Binet so that as many girls as boys would be identified, and he went so far as to obscure the drop in girls' IQ scores between 11 and 17 by collapsing their means scores with the boys, yielding a nonsignificant decline in IQ for the entire group. *

http://www.davidsongifted.org/db/Articles_id_10165.aspx

gender equality has been with you for far longer.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
