<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="36" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26827180614.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

Are you sure he believes this? As I recall, he merely suggested that it's possible that there are innate differences between men and women which may contribute to the understanding of the traditional sex divide in STEM fields. I believe that he was fired unjustifiably as this belief is entirely plausible but it made enough people *feel* bad to dismiss him. Still, I think you are going a bit overboard with your claim. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
