<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91738787.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ima3n/women_are_the_inferior_gender_cmv/">
    <title>Women are the inferior gender. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>TyKillsTyGoT</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is an issue I have really struggled with since adolescence and would love to have my views changed. I'm sexist. No bones about it. I know that I should think women are equal and holding these views makes me less civilized, but I haven't been able to find any evidence that would change my mind. 

The smartest people are men. The strongest people are men. It seems like women are average while men can excel or fail spectacularly. Harvard president Larry Summers agrees that men are better suited for certain difficult tasks.

I really want to be able to look at women as people but whenever I see a pretty woman in a nice car, I automatically assume someone bought it for her. When I see a woman out shopping, I wonder what her spouse does to afford her these priveledges. 

The women in my life seem to support this hypothesis. I know some girls who are very smart, but they're not on the level of the smartest guys I know. I also know some girls who are very physically fit but once again they cant compare to the fit men I know and research agrees with both of these points. 

I want to get over this beleif because I feel like it is tainting all my interactions with women and as a result the view is being reinforced more and more each day. 

So please reddit, CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796321702.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>Men are genetically inferior to women.
Because of the Y chromosome which contains no genetical information men are more suceptible to detrimental genetic diseases and conditions.

Also men are structurally not as long-lived as women. The life expectancy of a man always lies about 5-10 years beneath the life expectancy of a woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796331633.0" user="TyKillsTyGoT" delta="False">
    <text>That makes sense to me because a man can simultaneously create an unlimited number of offspring while a woman can only give birth once every 9 months. In other words, and island with 50 women and 10 men would fare a lot better than an island with 50 men and 10 women in terms of growth.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796382772.0" user="angryeconomist" delta="False">
    <text>How do you define superior, the way men are superior? Is crating more offspring superior to living longer? Again you only count the arguments who reinforce your point. This is not a discussion, you also use this CMV to reinforce your already made point and not to discuss a idea open minded, that's by the way the only way to change your point of view, generally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796393557.0" user="Discoamazing" delta="False">
    <text>So wait, how does the fact that your hypothetical society would be better off with more women than men support your view? Sounds to me like it does the opposite.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796431187.0" user="x4u" delta="False">
    <text>I think he was referring to the life expectancy which should better be quantified as survival rate. It's not a big deal for the human society to loose a few men early because the other men could biologically easily make up for the loss while lost young females would result in less potential offsping on average.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796381170.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Also men are structurally not as long-lived as women. The life expectancy of a man always lies about 5-10 years beneath the life expectancy of a woman.

The life expectancy is lower for men for social reasons, not genetic:

* Men lead harder, more stressful lives

  - Men get harder, more dangerous jobs (95% of workplace deaths are men)

 - Men work longer hours than women.  Longer hours per year and longer hours per *day*.

* Boys go off and die in war, women don't.  98% of military casualties are men.

* It's expected of men to throw their lives away.  "Women and children first"

Edit:

*  Men also don't go to the doctor nearly as much as women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796388006.0" user="siamthailand" delta="False">
    <text>Actually testosterone is also responsible for shorter lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796388602.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796393093.0" user="siamthailand" delta="False">
    <text>Read around here, wish I had a source at hand. What it basically said was that male organs "wear out" a lot faster because of testosterone and how it was good for evolution. That's all I remember of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796397649.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>The reason for a lot of these things isn't because women aren't able to or won't, it's that (in what I would argue is the majority of cases) they've been told they shouldn't or can't. Historically, men have, in a way, done those things to themselves by saying women can or should not, so the responsibility automatically falls to the man. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796413978.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>However you want to justify there being almost no female coal miners, deep sea welders, or oil rig workers, my point remains- society is to blame for men dying before women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796417815.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's overzealous to assume that three, albeit very dangerous, job fields kill off enough men to lower the age expectancy of men below that of women. 

EDIT: The justification as to why there are few women in those career fields: they require immense physical strength. I'll never debate that women are as physically strong as men, because on a wide average, I'd be way wrong. Testosterone's a cool thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796419493.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>95% of workplace deaths are men.

That's not overzealous
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796428124.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>No, and neither is the military death statistic. Those don't help the age expectancy for men, but again, they certainly are not the sole cause that the male AE is lower than female.

The other factors you cited are all relevant and believable, but the origin of almost all of them can be traced back to men. Who decided "women and children first"? Read about it - it certainly wasn't a whiny female insisting that her uterus guaranteed her the right to life above a man.

Men leading harder lives is a small bit of bullshit, imo. Yes, they *often* work more dangerous jobs. This is likely due to their increased physical strength, and there's nothing that can be done about it. Those jobs must be done, and a woman can't do a lot of them. I don't like that and I'll admit it doesn't help my point. If the jobs could somehow be simplified or the tasks modified for a woman to do them too, I am sure that, given a not completely anti-female environment, women would do them.

Men working longer hours can likely be traced back to the fact (though I don't have sources - I don't think they exist) that women are the "caretakers" and men are the "breadwinners". The man goes to work, makes the money, and comes home to a clean house and dinner on the table. I would argue this system was set up, directly or indirectly, by men long ago. If men were historically the caretakers, women would work those same hours. Please don't try to say they aren't capable. But as it is, women are often tied down with children.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796430188.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The other factors you cited are all relevant and believable, but the origin of almost all of them can be traced back to men.

Whether you want to blame men for men dying sooner or not, my point remains valid.  The reasons for our lower life expectancy are mostly, if not entirely, social.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796432294.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I don't see what the ultimate goal of your point here was though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796434897.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>/u/Radijs said

&amp;gt; Also men are structurally not as long-lived as women. The life expectancy of a man always lies about 5-10 years beneath the life expectancy of a woman.

/u/Radijs is wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796437575.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Alright then. We might have to agree to disagree here. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796446244.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>You think men don't live as long for purely biological reasons?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796451257.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>I just think there's more to it than you said. Job stress with long hours, work- or military-related fatalities, and the "women and children first" "rule" aren't enough to lower the life expectancy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796455769.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>In World War 2, around 18% of the boys and men died in Russia.  These are soldiers, not civilians.

[There have been a LOT of soldiers dying, all (with a handful of exceptions) of them men.](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_wars_and_anthropogenic_disasters_by_death_toll)

Do you have an alternate theory?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796466703.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. A few, all taken from various articles.

[Source #1](http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=why-women-live-longer): This one speaks directly to your point about stress and suggests that there are biological forces at play which far outweigh your stress idea.

[Source #2](http://men.webmd.com/features/why-mens-lives-are-shorter-than-women): People have split opinions on WebMD, but some of their points here are valid. Men, on average, seem to be more reluctant to seek medical help. The fact that women are more eager to seek help doesn't mean they are weaker or overly dependent, but instead that they understand that there are people out there who know more than them and are therefore able to help with whatever the issue may be.

[Source #3](http://www.time.com/time/health/article/0,8599,1827162,00.html): This interview has a lot of suggestions as to why women may live longer, too many to summarize here.

I'm not proposing any one of these is the end-all-be-all answer, nor am I saying your suggestions are to be ignored either. Likely it's a combination of all factors to varying degrees in each person, which explains why some women die early and some men live into their hundreds. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796440011.0" user="tisbutme" delta="False">
    <text>I think the point is that women do not inherently live longer, which would make them "better" (in the context of this debate).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796442627.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Okay. I would still argue there are more factors going unaccounted for in /u/DashFerLev's argument, but I understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796414873.0" user="cacophonousdrunkard" delta="False">
    <text>while that is mostly true(gender is mostly social imo) , I don't think he was making a case for those things being the fault of women, he was just providing context to that statistic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796419215.0" user="tmwy" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough. I don't know if he was using it as such, but I don't think his statistics make a valid argument for men being superior to women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796497332.0" user="Eh_Priori" delta="False">
    <text>In addition, it has been shown that (highly developed) countries that rank higher in gender equality also have a smaller gap between male/female life expectancy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796504683.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Women also don't have heart failure as frequently until later in life because of our super estrogen powers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796505745.0" user="DashFerLev" delta="False">
    <text>Stress is a major cause of heart disease.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796464258.0" user="plentyofrabbits" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because of the Y chromosome which contains no genetical information

I'm not a geneticist but I'm not sure that's accurate. 

The way it was explained to me was as follows:

Men have XY where women have XX. Each X chromosome in a pair is going to have the same number of *genes* on it. In the case of a malformation on the X chromosome in one of the genes (which would cause a genetic disorder in many cases), in women, because they have double the genes, essentially, the "other" X chromosome is used for the expression of that gene.

I am not sure if it switches over to the "other" X chromosome entirely, or just for that individual gene. 

But for men, they don't have the extra X. They only have the one. In the case of a malformation on the X chromosome, there's nowhere else to look for "good" genes, so the malformed one is used for expression. 

This is the reason X-chromosomal abnormalities are most often seen in men and only very rarely (since they'd require a double-malformation) in women.

However, your point that:

&amp;gt;Men are genetically inferior to women

is still, technically, correct.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796504789.0" user="Zorander22" delta="False">
    <text>What does genetically inferior to women mean? The Y chromosome does contain genetic information - that's what chromosomes do. It is smaller than the X chromosome, and so there are parts of the X chromosome which aren't counterbalanced by another X chromosome. This means that men are more susceptible to recessive effects found on an X chromosome (both positive and negative).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827192896.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Men are genetically inferior to women. Because of the Y chromosome which contains no genetical information men are more suceptible to detrimental genetic diseases and conditions.

Your points have been refuted above but I'd just like to say, as I write this from the Genetics department of probably the top 1 or 2 school in the world, please please please don't use ridiculously oversimplified genetics arguments such as you've made above. It's embarrassing for all of us. Please listen to those who dispel your myths below.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827195147.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>So you're a fancy student at a fancy college. Are you posting this to stroke your own ego?

Cause if you are. You probably don't belong in that school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827206860.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Oooooh, an *ad hominem*. The refuge of those who are unable to navigate the seas of logic. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827210899.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>I wasn't trying to reason logically with you. I was being rude.
Why? Because I dislike the way you talked to me.

You never thought that I might have already seen some of the other awnsers. Even though my awnser was already weeks old and the replies to them would have arrived in my message center.

Instead you came at me with an attitude that "I'm learning with the best and because of that I should tell you what to do". Or that is what it looked like to me.

That display of arrogance ticked me off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827213697.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>You display of ignorance masquerading as fact ticked me off. Suppose we're even. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827215014.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, I just keyed your car. Now we're even. ;)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827219780.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Joke's on you! I don't have a car! =D (possibly more arrogance?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827220697.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>You're probably one of dem green hippies!

It's gonna be interesting finding out who's car I keyed...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827222222.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Nah, those greens hate [genes](http://www.hcs.harvard.edu/~policylab/2013/07/03/not-so-quiet-on-the-left-ern-front/). I'm not sure what they're worried about . Genes are DELICIOUS! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26827228549.0" user="Radijs" delta="False">
    <text>GMO-tastic!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
