<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91769249.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1imxlt/people_should_not_break_up_fights_unless_one_of/">
    <title>People should not break up fights unless one of the fighters explicitly states that they don't want to be fighting. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Taylor_Vontell</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has always been a major peeve of mine. I like watching random people fight, and I've been in a few myself. Every time there's a fight, some asshole decides to be a hero and try to break it up. Back in high school, these two kids pulled us apart even though we both explicitly stated that we wanted to fight. Now, I understand why a teacher, cop, or bouncer would do it, nothing against them, but if you're not an authority figure or at risk of injury or property damage yourself, you should let the people fight. For example, if you form a fight ring in high school around the two combatants, then no one is getting hurt, and nor is anyone not involved in the fight getting injured. In that case, no one should intervene unless an authority figure arrives. 

Now of course, there are exceptions. For example, if one person clearly does not want to be in the fight, then someone should break it up. For example, they may be asking for help or just being pummeled without throwing any punches themselves. Or if you witnessed the fight from the very beginning and one guy clearly just attacked the other without provocation. Then you should break up the fight. 

Otherwise, two adults should be allowed to fight and no one should intervene until one of them either states that he does not want to fight anymore, or is put into a state into which he cannot express this desire. Otherwise, people should just enjoy the show and mind their own fucking business. 

CMV
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796622607.0" user="A_Mirror" delta="False">
    <text>Every fight has a risk of death.  You never know when some punch is going to send you sprawling into the edge of a desk or traffic, etc. etc.  

If two people on the street are fighting then they are likely just mad about something and not really interested in fighting for fighting's sake, and bystanders trying to pull them apart are essentially trying to save them from grievously injuring each other without thinking their actions through.  Most of the time, when two people *want* to fight it's over something stupid and petty with no thought put into whether or not it's actually worth it.

If you want to fight someone there are times and places for it, out on the street is not one of them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796626755.0" user="Taylor_Vontell" delta="False">
    <text>I am willing to accept the risk of injury and death when I get into a fight. When I tell people to leave us alone and they decide to pull us apart anyway, then they are not respecting our wishes. I have had numerous hospital visits and months in the slammer. I know exactly what I'm getting into. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796646904.0" user="A_Mirror" delta="False">
    <text>Bystanders do not know that.

Consider the consequences of making fighting in public something that's okay.  It leads to a much more violent society, and there's that much more pressure on those that do not want to fight to fight.  It becomes very easy to break someone's nose and claim that they consented, or let someone attack you and say that you didn't actually consent.  You know what you're getting into, but there's plenty of teenagers and college kids with more guts than sense that could ruin their lives because they want to be a tough guy but they lack the experience you have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26796692942.0" user="Taylor_Vontell" delta="False">
    <text>People should learn from their mistakes. If they feel like an idiot, then they can refrain from fighting in the future. Bystanders are free to call the police or staff and I have nothing against that. However, bystanders themselves should mind their own business. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
