<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91769249.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1imxlt/people_should_not_break_up_fights_unless_one_of/">
    <title>People should not break up fights unless one of the fighters explicitly states that they don't want to be fighting. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>Taylor_Vontell</original_poster>
    <original_post>This has always been a major peeve of mine. I like watching random people fight, and I've been in a few myself. Every time there's a fight, some asshole decides to be a hero and try to break it up. Back in high school, these two kids pulled us apart even though we both explicitly stated that we wanted to fight. Now, I understand why a teacher, cop, or bouncer would do it, nothing against them, but if you're not an authority figure or at risk of injury or property damage yourself, you should let the people fight. For example, if you form a fight ring in high school around the two combatants, then no one is getting hurt, and nor is anyone not involved in the fight getting injured. In that case, no one should intervene unless an authority figure arrives. 

Now of course, there are exceptions. For example, if one person clearly does not want to be in the fight, then someone should break it up. For example, they may be asking for help or just being pummeled without throwing any punches themselves. Or if you witnessed the fight from the very beginning and one guy clearly just attacked the other without provocation. Then you should break up the fight. 

Otherwise, two adults should be allowed to fight and no one should intervene until one of them either states that he does not want to fight anymore, or is put into a state into which he cannot express this desire. Otherwise, people should just enjoy the show and mind their own fucking business. 

CMV
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26796823098.0" user="Missing_Link" delta="False">
    <text>Many people have a very different view to fighting. To many it is *never* appropriate in a civilised society and low class. Fighting is an animalistic action and doesn't rationally settle any dispute. Winning a fight, doesn't mean you were right.

But it goes deeper than that. Fighting is assault - a violent crime. When people go into fight mode they are essentially saying "screw the rules of society. My self-centred rage justifies me disregarding them." To simply condone that is allowing a community that you're a part of be thrown into chaos. It is allowing those people to degrade the class of your community. People don't want their community to be that kind of place.

Ultimately it is an extremely selfish and disrespectful act. Just like throwing your trash in the street, vandalism, public drunkenness or any other crime that makes our surroundings a less desirable place to be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
