<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797710689.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>My wife is 2 years younger than i am. As a percentage of my age that is less than 3.

If people are willing to put up with each others shit and are both mature enough (as determined by law) to consent to a relationship then let em have at it. Perhaps they find joy, companionship and connection with each other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797715277.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>Where I love the age of consent is 16.

A 15 year old sleeping with an 18 year old is illegal. What happens then? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797716897.0" user="shiav" delta="False">
    <text>Law is the law. Its 15 where i am, though i highly doubt youll get a prosecution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797731598.0" user="Lawtonfogle" delta="False">
    <text>What happens if they are just dating and not having sex, waiting til the younger turns 16?  Would you still consider such a relationship wrong?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797811798.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>I'd still find it a bit odd, and question the older partners motives; what's wrong with people their age? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797888288.0" user="zardeh" delta="False">
    <text>Nothing.  An 18 year old dating a 15 year old doesn't mean the 18 year old dislikes 18 year olds, or that they are attracted to 15 year olds, it means the 18 year old is attracted to *this* 15 year old more than people closer to their own age.  Maybe that's because the 15 year old is mature and shares interests with the 18 year old, maybe they have known each other a long time and are friends, who knows.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798244274.0" user="Lawtonfogle" delta="False">
    <text>Love is not rational.  When you fall in love with someone, you fall in love with someone.  This the difference between an 18 year old who only tries to date 14 year olds vs. an 18 year old who wanted to date a certain 14 year old.

Now, that doesn't mean you should just ignore the possibility of ulterior motives.  But you add in safe guards to the relationship.  Willing to eat supper once a week with the other's parents... willing to not have sex til the legal age of consent... that isn't something someone only looking for sex will do.

Also, consider this.  Would you rather you 14 year old be having sex with a 14 year old who is in the relationship just for sex or with a 16 year old who is wanting a serious relationship?  Due to how children can mature at completely different rates, it is definitely possible for one kid to be taking sexual advantage of another kid the same age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797878049.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>Many concessions are made in statutory rape charges if the offend</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
