<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797887134.0" user="sleepyj910" delta="False">
    <text>I think perhaps teenage years are difficult because people change so much.  There's not much difference between a 32 and 26 year old, but subtract 12 years and scandal!

So the main argument in your favor is that the younger party is much less mature, as maturity is somewhat logarithmic.  So one could more easily take advantage of a younger person.

That said, if both parties are happy, it's hard to really fault them.  Personally, I think dating a younger girl is annoying because they are so immature, and very likely to leave you as their personality changes as they grow, but girls mature faster than boys, and perhaps that 16 year old is on the same level as your 18 year old friend.

So while I'm not saying what they are doing is right or wrong, I think you should allow for the possibility that the younger person is more mature than they seem until you see otherwise.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
