<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797877177.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Today I learned my three year relationship with my boyfriend is shallow, slutty, and desperate because we started dating when I was 16 and he was 19.

Anyway. You realize your insecurity probably fuels this view, and that's the first step to changing it. And if you think about it, three years really isn't that much. As long as both parties are consenting and knowing what they're getting into, then it's not up to you to judge. You think it's disgusting? Cool, don't date a 15 year old then. But calling your ex girlfriend names because of a personal decision you have made for yourself is so uncalled for.

The "what's wrong with people their age" question is valid when it's larger age gaps. Like I had a 17 year old friend dating a 32 year old man. That is when you (nicely) approach them and talk to them about it if you think that their safety might be at stake.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
