<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797730921.0" user="Lawtonfogle" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are focusing on sex/hooking up, not dating it self.  What happens if you met a 12 year old dating a 16 year old for two years with very little sexual interaction?  Where would 'slut' come into play in such a relationship?

Lets go even more extreme.  Lets say you have a 14 year old dating a 20 year old, and they date for years with no sexual interaction until the younger party is old enough to legally consent?

Also, could you explain more on why you say it is wrong.  It seems like you are calling a younger party a 'slut' for being in such a sexual relationship, when most people who consider sexual relationships like this wrong think of the younger party as a victim, not a 'slut'.  I'm wondering why you don't see the younger party a victim and yet still see it as wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797814459.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>I do think of the younger partner as the victim, and I place more blame on the "scumbag" older party. I didn't make that very apparent in the opening post. 

I would still question an age gap even with no sex attached. What are the motifs? I find it hard to believe a 14 year old is emotionally mature enough to want to pursue a relationship just for companionship sakes. And I think that older partys only prey on the young for easy, naive sex. If they want a partner with no sex, wouldn't someone closer to their age that they have more in common with make sense? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798240735.0" user="Lawtonfogle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I do think of the younger partner as the victim, and I place more blame on the "scumbag" older party. I didn't make that very apparent in the opening post. 

Even the language here, the use of 'more blame' indicates some blame put on the younger party.

&amp;gt;I find it hard to believe a 14 year old is emotionally mature enough to want to pursue a relationship just for companionship sakes.

Is every relationship a teenager in only about sex?  I highly doubt that.

&amp;gt;And I think that older partys only prey on the young for easy, naive sex.

This completely ignores the aspect of love, of falling heads over heels for someone who may be your age, somewhat younger, or somewhat older (2-3 years is not a major difference).  While there is definitely a sexual desire aspect to such feelings, that is only a portion of the desire, and sexual desire can be held back for years.  Many teenager couples date without sexual interaction even when the law does not require them to.
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
