<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797788201.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>I don't mean to be blunt but it sounds like you're honest enough to admit the likely reasons for your view in your initial post, and it seems like you recognize at least on some level that they're not particularly compelling reasons.
I'm not gonna argue with you that someone sleeping with a child who's under the legal age of consent while they're over it is messed up, even if only from a "legal risk" perspective. So if that was your only issue, I could identify with you.

But what is it specifically about the idea of a girl choosing to be with someone older that gets under your skin? Is it because you can't help but assume that they *must* be being taken advantage of?

Do you feel exactly the same way regardless of which gender is in which role, older and younger?

Have you tried stepping back and approaching it from the perspective of, "if they make each other happy, then that's the most important thing because I want my friends to be happy"? Sometimes it's easy to lose sight of how we might want ourselves to be judged if we were in the position of those we're judging. I know you aren't in the same exact situation because you say you and your girlfriend are close in age. But, if somebody else didn't like some aspect of your relationship, thought the two of you weren't good for each other, would you want them to judge you? Or would you want them to trust in your judgment and be happy for you instead?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797805983.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>I just don't think I believe that someone who is 14 is *capable* of making an 18 year old happy. And vice versa. 

They're at different stages of their lives, what could they possibly have in common? One might be just starting to grasp basic calculus concepts while one is at uni studying math! They're so far apart! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797848315.0" user="Hayleyk" delta="False">
    <text>Some people like to be with someone less powerful that they can manipulate. They seek out naivety. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797850072.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>Yes and I hate it! That's disgusting! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797858130.0" user="Hayleyk" delta="False">
    <text>It really is. It's the cycle of abuse. Look for someone you can control, and convince her that she was pure, but now she's damaged and can't leave.  That why we can't blame people for being in that situation. That's what abusers already do.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797943710.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>That's true, but that's not exclusive to these types of young relationships with notable age differences. There's not cause to assume that *every* one of the relationships the OP described fits this description.

In general, I am inclined to agree that these relationships aren't the healthiest or stablest and usually not built to last. And I assume most people learn from their mistakes in time. But just statistically speaking, there are at least some people out there whose relationships started this way, and who went on to lead long, happy lives committed to each other forever. And it's not as though their relationships are or were invalid or "wrong" because people judged them for it in the beginning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797958148.0" user="Hayleyk" delta="False">
    <text>That's true, but in either case people shouldn't accuse the younger person of being a slut. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797966212.0" user="aleafonthewind2" delta="False">
    <text>While I see the point of much you have said, I think this is a little much. Since we're all using anecdotal evidence here, I'll throw in the fact that at 14, I was much more mature than many 18 year olds I knew. I was interested in politics, philosophy, religion (or lack thereof), etc., as well as sports, books, shows, whatever. I certainly didn't have the most sophisticated views on those subjects, but there is no reason I wouldn't have a ton in common with those older than me, nor is it acceptable to say I couldn't make them happy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
