<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="91873099.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1ip5qj/large_dating_age_gaps_between_teenagers_for/">
    <title>"Large" dating age gaps between teenagers (for example, 3 years) is shallow, "slutty" and desperate, and I can't help looking down on people who take part in them. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>CheekyLittleCunt</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm 18, I'm still part of the teenage dating world. 

My ex girlfriend met her ex boyfriend when she was 14, she started dating him when she turned 15. He was 18 years old. There was a constant weight on our relationship because of it. I thought the 3 year age gap was too much. When we argued I would call her horrible things like "slut" and "desperate". 

I have a friend who is 18, she's dating a 23 year old. I secretly think "slut" in my head too when I talk to her. 

Some of my friends who are 18 are dating 15 year olds. I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old.  I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc 

I know people can like or date whoever they want, and I shouldn't judge them for it. Age gaps when we get older mean nothing. But in our teenage years, 3+ year age gaps strike me as disgusting, immoral and just... "Wrong". I actually get visibly angry when I hear a friend I've known for years is sleeping with a 14 year old girl. 

If a 15 year old tried to sleep with me, I would laugh at them and tell them to beat it. I am not sexually attracted to anyone much younger than me. 

I know my view is sexist and fucked up.  I know that maybe it's because I'm just jealous because I never experienced these romances while growing up, or maybe I'm actually just an ephebophile and jealous of people getting what I want . I know it's possible I only have these thoughts because I'm a misogynist and have been (unsuccessfully) suppressing it. But please, try and explain it in a way that's respectful and not insulting. I'm trying to change my view for the better here and I don't think I handle hostility very well (I shut down) 

Thanks.  Oh and by the way I have a girlfriend and she 's close to my age. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26797746007.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Okay firstly I hate the word "slut", but I'm going to have to use it from here on out.

What is slutty about it? It wouldn't be slutty if it was with someone of the same age? Slutty means promiscuous, the age of your partners doesn't make you promiscuous, the number of them does.  

&amp;gt; I have a 20 year old friend who's sleeping with a 16 year old. I can't help of thinking of them as dirty, greasy, liars, users etc

This is where I may slightly agree with you. You seem to be blaming the younger parties in most of your post. Why are they the ones to blame, surely the older party is? Take a 14 year old girl and an 18 year old guy having sex. I would argue the 14 year old is being taken advantage of, is not old enough/mature enough to make that decision and the 18 year old is morally wrong. Same applies if the genders were reversed (obviously).

I find it really odd that you think of your girlfriend as slutty and desperate, surely you should be thinking her ex is a scumbag? 

I had an 18 year old boyfriend when I was 15. At the time I didn't see anything wrong with that, I loved him and couldn't even understand why it was wrong. Now looking back I can see that he completely manipulated me, that I was young and naive and fell for a lot of the bullshit he spewed, if I met someone like that now I would realise they were full of shit (well probably). Your girlfriend probably needs time to see why that relationship was wrong, maybe she won't ever feel like that, but you shaming her for it won't help anything. 

So basically while big age gaps in younger years can be and are in my opinion wrong, why are you blaming the younger party? They are the ones that most laws say are incapable of making that decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797809904.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>I guess in my previous posts It comes across as if I'm blaming the younger party more. I DO think her ex was a scumbag, I do think my friends who are dating your girls are disgusting. They hold more blame then the girls. What I don't understand is, if they're ALL so young and naive, why aren't their "frigid" friends being swindled by these abusers? 

Also I hate calling her a slut too, thats why i feel so bad. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797817828.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; if they're ALL so young and naive, why aren't their "frigid" friends being swindled by these abusers?

Firstly because people are different.They develop differently. Some people don't feel sexual feelings or strong sexual feelings until a lot older than others. Also it's not like young girls will be taken in by every older man who attempts it, it's an older man who they are attracted to who they click with/have a connection with, or at least feel they do, so perhaps the "frigid" ones haven't been approached by an older guy that they like or by any older guys, sometimes it's easy to gauge who is the type to pursue. 

If you hate calling her a slut, don't call her one, whether you think so or not it's hurtful and furthers the idea that women shouldn't be sexual and those who are should be shamed for it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797824340.0" user="CheekyLittleCunt" delta="False">
    <text>At the time she was not a woman, she was a girl! 14 years old! I don't think she should have been sexual. I know I have no right to say what she did with her body, but she didn't even know what her clitoris was at the time! She was just a child! :( </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26797827081.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I agree, completely. I lost my virginity at 14 too and it creeps me out or even disgusts me to think that. But I don't think it's her fault. She was taken advantage of. Think about a child (pre pubescent, say 9) who is molested, is it their fault? are they slutty? No they were taken advantage of, they are often times "groomed" by their abuser to think it is okay. I know that 9 is worse than 14 but it is still wrong.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26798402119.0" user="cyanoacrylate" delta="False">
    <text>If she's so naive and young, is it totally fair to blame her for being manipulated into acting on the hormones pumping through her body and urging her to copulate? When you are young like that, your brain really isn't very developed where decision making is concerned, and it's much harder to really form an idea about what your actions mean in the big picture. 

Also, even if she didn't know the anatomical names for her body parts, what's so bad about it as long as she knew enough to be safe having sex? I mean, I know how to eat healthfully without knowing *precisely* why some things are healthy for me, and this is considered a totally okay thing. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
