<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92103986.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iu3w2/i_believe_the_courting_process_should_be/">
    <title>I believe the courting process should be eliminated entirely from sex, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>allydelaann</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don’t think that pursuing someone solely for the purpose of having sex with them, even if you don’t know them intimately, should be cause for judgment. Proposing sex to a friend, acquaintance, or stranger with no intentions of furthering an emotional connection or relationship should be acceptable. I believe our society has a strange and harmful dichotomy of attitudes towards sex - it saturates so much of our culture but is somewhat taboo on an interpersonal basis. I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall. 

tl;dr Casual sex should be acceptable and encouraged.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26800049058.0" user="obfuscate_this" delta="False">
    <text>This is actually a very common view among sociopaths and people with certain manifestations of autism. Hangon, hear me out, this is not said in judgement. Empathy is something these groups lack- they can understand the emotions, and ethically respond to them, but they have trouble *feeling* them in the way most people do. This difference has many implications. I submit that one implication is a tendency to experience sex as a more purely physical act, relatively removed from the emotional realm of life. Two people with feelings of friendship for one another, who then decide to have sex, will likely feel an emotional shift in the relationship. This is *less* likely to occur in individuals any empathic obstacles (conditions above, traumas, inebriation, etc). 

Basically, in most people, sex tends to be an emotional *experience*. Not an emotional contract, not an emotional idea, but an emotional experience. There's insecurity, animalism, judgement- all around huge amounts of empathy. Perhaps most important- orgasms flood the brain with a massive chemical cocktail of pleasure and bonding and trust, if you empathize with your partner these moments can have large emotional impacts. What may sound like a decent idea when removed from it (e.g. yeah I could have sex with Sarah, that would be fun and logical) becomes a potentially dangerous idea in practice. You/Sarah develop asymmetrical feelings, expectation divide amplifies the emotional impact of the disappointed party. Courting allows both parties to get on the same page, therefore courting should be preserved. The illogical weirdness around sex is not *all* due to cultural/religious judgement, it's deeply rooted in our biology and psychology; there are limits to how far we can shift sexual standards by removing judgements. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800090439.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>Good argument. I'm not too well-versed in the chemicals released during sex and the consequences of that release. 

&amp;gt;Courting allows both parties to get on the same page, therefore courting should be preserved. 

In the situation I described, though, both parties would also be on the same page from the beginning. Would you say that part of the emotional attitudes you described surrounding sex can be attributed to the societal perspective that sex belongs in marriage or other long-term, committed relationships and therefore should be a deeply emotional act? If so, wouldn't a shift in sexual standards work to discredit that point of view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800315504.0" user="A_Soporific" delta="False">
    <text>In an especially casual situation how are you certain that they are on the same page from the beginning? What if one party has been crushing on the other for a while and take this a backdoor invitation to a relationship as opposed to something with no strings attached.

Courtship forces a conversation. Like when your computer asks you "Are you sure?" before deleting a thing. It's annoying, unnecessary, and stressful 99% of the time, but can totally save your ass the 1% of the time that you went through the motions without actually meaning the thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800154091.0" user="Malcolmthrowaway" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that this is a very good argument, but I would ask one question central to your thesis: is the emotional experience caused by social factors related to what we are brought up to think about sex, or is it inherent?

My point is a nature vs. nurture argument; if in OP's hypothetical we lived in a society that actively encouraged casual sex without expectation of emotional effect, then would the emotional experience as you call it occur at all? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
