<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92103986.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iu3w2/i_believe_the_courting_process_should_be/">
    <title>I believe the courting process should be eliminated entirely from sex, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>allydelaann</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don’t think that pursuing someone solely for the purpose of having sex with them, even if you don’t know them intimately, should be cause for judgment. Proposing sex to a friend, acquaintance, or stranger with no intentions of furthering an emotional connection or relationship should be acceptable. I believe our society has a strange and harmful dichotomy of attitudes towards sex - it saturates so much of our culture but is somewhat taboo on an interpersonal basis. I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall. 

tl;dr Casual sex should be acceptable and encouraged.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26800027071.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree. I think if you put a taboo on people's ability to judge others during sex that would cause far more stress. A great deal of the stress in our society is because people have poor choice in partners. If you stigmatize judgement people will make poor choices in partners even more, more unwanted children will be born, and there will be poor matches between very different people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800043833.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>I don't mean to stigmatize judgment or imply that anyone should be pressured into sexual encounters. Everyone would obviously retain the right to decline any proposition. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800130352.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>You aren't saying that people should be forced into sexual encounters but you are saying that the taboo (i.e. people viewing others negatively and avoiding them) should end.

A lot of people don't like casual sex, and find it unpleasant. If they are not allowed to have that taboo that means they are forced to associate with those who do like casual sex and not shun them if they are pressured for sex. The courtship process means taking things slowly, which means getting better consent, and many prefer that.

If you take steps to reduce the courting stage of a relationship and the romance that means that those who want courting and romance will be much more pressured to accept sex if they want romance. You would be reducing a pleasurable activity for people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800215523.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>I realize that, but I would argue that that taboo originates largely from the societal attitudes that I am arguing should be removed.

I'm not talking about relationships or romance, I'm talking only about sex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800260244.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>http://uk.answers.yahoo.com/question/index?qid=20100929151930AA04aau

Top answer says stds, weaker relationships, and cheating.

I'm sure one could find statistical evidence to support that perspective. That's not a 'societal attitude' it's a response to evidence in the world. You might disagree with the evidence, but there are many reasons other than socialization to oppose casual sex.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
