<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92103986.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iu3w2/i_believe_the_courting_process_should_be/">
    <title>I believe the courting process should be eliminated entirely from sex, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>allydelaann</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don’t think that pursuing someone solely for the purpose of having sex with them, even if you don’t know them intimately, should be cause for judgment. Proposing sex to a friend, acquaintance, or stranger with no intentions of furthering an emotional connection or relationship should be acceptable. I believe our society has a strange and harmful dichotomy of attitudes towards sex - it saturates so much of our culture but is somewhat taboo on an interpersonal basis. I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall. 

tl;dr Casual sex should be acceptable and encouraged.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26800300201.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;"I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall."

many people enjoy courtship, they have limitations because of their own preferences etc, and as such it is not stressful for them at all. The argument that these things relate to stress needs to be supported anyhow. Causing stress to you does not = causing stress to everyone.

Even if we did accept this description, it does not alone provide reason to believe that there would be less stress or that people would benefit from the alternative. Many people might become more stressed by the casual attitude toward sex than they were from the other form, for example, if it lead to more of a feeling of emotional isolation from people who previously benefited from the warmth of loving sexual relationships. Or some other thing, it does not really matter except to suggest that it is not entirely convincing that society at large would benefit from your personal preferences. 

lastly, even if we accept that your description is accurate and that there would be a benefit in the form of less stress, you have to then move to a reason that people ought to behave in the way you suggest. Causing less stress might fit with a utilitarian argument, but not everyone agrees that the best course of action in every circumstance is the one that causes the greatest pleasure or least stress. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
