<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92103986.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iu3w2/i_believe_the_courting_process_should_be/">
    <title>I believe the courting process should be eliminated entirely from sex, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>allydelaann</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don’t think that pursuing someone solely for the purpose of having sex with them, even if you don’t know them intimately, should be cause for judgment. Proposing sex to a friend, acquaintance, or stranger with no intentions of furthering an emotional connection or relationship should be acceptable. I believe our society has a strange and harmful dichotomy of attitudes towards sex - it saturates so much of our culture but is somewhat taboo on an interpersonal basis. I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall. 

tl;dr Casual sex should be acceptable and encouraged.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26800101331.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>What this effectively asks for is that people not take sex seriously and view it primarily as a form of recreation.  You are free to do that, but there are those who would argue (myself included) that your choice to place yourself wherever you are on the promiscuity scale incurs consequences that are your responsibility.  If I disapprove of what you do, that relates directly to my views on the importance of sex.

Anyone who views sex as having intrinsic meaning is going to disapprove of casual sex to some degree. I would say that if I acquiesced to your demand that I accept what you do as normal, I would have to abandon my own views and the benefits of those views.  I believe there are benefits to exclusivity; namely a greater sense of intimacy, trust, self-control and maturity when in an actual relationship.  I think it's unreasonable to demand that everyone abstain entirely from casual sex, but if we accepted it as the norm, I think I'd lose much more in my own loss of values than you would gain in my lack of judgment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800144717.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>Even if my ideal situation became the norm, you would still be entitled to your values and opinion. I just disagree fundamentally with those values.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800152551.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that, but it seems like you are disagreeing with the fact that I have and act on the values I do and that many others do the same.

Is this incorrect in some way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800190965.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that, but I personally believe that such values can be harmful and I don't think that they should constitute the norm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800199415.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, but if people like me are determining the norm by weight of numbers, aren't you arguing that we should change our views?  Isn't changing my mind (and those who think similarly) the only thing that is going to alter that norm?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
