<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92103986.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1iu3w2/i_believe_the_courting_process_should_be/">
    <title>I believe the courting process should be eliminated entirely from sex, CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>allydelaann</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don’t think that pursuing someone solely for the purpose of having sex with them, even if you don’t know them intimately, should be cause for judgment. Proposing sex to a friend, acquaintance, or stranger with no intentions of furthering an emotional connection or relationship should be acceptable. I believe our society has a strange and harmful dichotomy of attitudes towards sex - it saturates so much of our culture but is somewhat taboo on an interpersonal basis. I think that any limitations on sexual expression and release among consenting adults are harmful and cause unnecessary stress, and our society would benefit from fostering a more relaxed attitude towards sexual intimacy overall. 

tl;dr Casual sex should be acceptable and encouraged.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26800036707.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>But you can do this. You can go to a bar and try and find men or women there who are looking for casual sex. There are even apps for smartphones where the explicit purpose when signing up is that you're looking for nothing but quick casual sex with whoever is in your immediate area.

What limitations on casual sex do you think exist beyond the very fundamental, "You might want to have casual sex but that doesn't mean that everyone else will feel comfortable with it"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800057634.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>I would say that those things exist in their own niche, rather than being widespread throughout society and reflecting overarching values. I'd also argue that they are viewed in a negative light by many people. 

Exactly. A good percentage of people (based on my own personal experience) would be uncomfortable as a result, in my opinion, of societal attitudes seeing sex and particularly casual sex as taboo or inappropriate. I'm basically arguing for the removal of those attitudes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800065710.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>The app thing I'll give you to a certain extent, but only because it's such a recent development. But bars? I don't know how you can call that a niche, bars as a place where people meet, socialize, and pursue sex is kind of a staple of mainstream western culture.

And you seem to be making pretty big assumptions without being able to actually see inside others' heads. Have you ever considered that lots of people aren't necessarily "constrained by society"--that they might just be *genuinely* uncomfortable with the idea of casual sex?

In what specific way do you think sexual expression is currently being harmed or limited? Can't two people interested in casual sex do it as freely as they want? What prevents that from happening?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800125662.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>What else besides socialization, in your opinion, would cause someone to be uncomfortable with the idea of casual sex? 

I'm not suggesting that sexual expression is currently being limited in any excessively strict or formal way - by law, for instance. As a result of my own personal experience, conversations with others, and observation, though, I do believe that many people view casual sex with multiple partners unfavorably for no logical reason. In many circles, it just isn't "the done thing," for lack of a better phrase. Prevention of an act doesn't have to be at gunpoint; internalized norms and values and societal disapproval can work effectively as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800141710.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What else besides socialization, in your opinion, would cause someone to be uncomfortable with the idea of casual sex? 

STDs, unwanted and abused children, rape and false rape charges, people being pressured into sex for attention, feeling worthless after, drug use during casual sex, a lack of intimacy during casual sex, a desire for a monogomous relationship...

People do have a lot of valid and logical reasons to be opposed to it, personally or socially.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800154891.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>I mean...is personal preference not a valid reason to you? Why does it seem strange or negative to you that someone might not enjoy casual sex and instead only enjoy it in the context of an intimate or serious relationship?

To me, this is like saying, "Nobody should be uncomfortable with having anal sex even if it does not seem appealing to them in any way; everyone should be willing and eager to do it no matter what." Do you see how wacky that is? Would you hold people to that standard?

Casual sex isn't something that should be either encouraged *or* discouraged. It should just be something you do if you want to, and you don't if you're uncomfortable with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800154432.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>It might help if you ask yourself why does it make you uncomfortable if other people don't want to live a lifestyle of promiscuous and casual sexual encounters ... you say they judge that behaviour to be negative, but are *you* not judging *their* preference to be negative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800187576.0" user="allydelaann" delta="False">
    <text>I don't mean to imply that anyone should be forced to live a certain lifestyle. If someone wants no part in casual sexual encounters, then that's their prerogative. All I'm saying is that it should be entirely acceptable for those who wish to do so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800195039.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>But are these people really trying to stop you from living that lifestyle, or are you misinterpreting their own distaste for it in their own life? You know how people tend to express distaste for anything they don't like, whether it's food or music or movies, but they are not usually trying to stop others from enjoying it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26800193913.0" user="Blizzaldo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know where you are, but fuck buddies are not viewed in a negative light usually. You can easily find a relationship for casual sex, the trick is to always be upfront.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
