<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92502748.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1j2nks/i_believe_using_an_individuals_race_to_determine/">
    <title>I believe using an individual's race to determine anything about them is not only immoral, but is not beneficial in any way. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>seeellayewhy</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Preface:** my mother and I have been in this argument for a long time and any time a racially charged court case or anything of tbe sort occurs it gets brought up. I want someone to articulate it to me in a way I can understand because at this point I see no validity in her side whatsoever.

I keep hearing this argument that "one day when I'm put in a situation i'll understand" - still waiting for that day. Here are some examples of the kind of profiling I'm talking about:

* Being from the good old south, I hear family, friends and acquaintances say "oh this is a rough part of town" when they pull up to a stoplight and see a few black people hanging around outside.

* Another is just seeing people get uneasy when a black male walks into a gas station, bank, or some other place.

* And the last major one is like NYC's stop-and-frisk policy. They basically had a quota from commanding officers to stop young black males walking down the street, question, and frisk them.

Now, in the first two situations, my counter-argument is simply to ask how does this help? Do you feel like you have avoided dangerous situations by assuming black neighborhoods are dangerous? Have you ever prevented a robbery at a gas station by being on high-alert?

As for the last situation, I think this policy has a *negative* outcome. By being blatantly racist, these individuals who are stopped lose faith in the law. They assume police have ulterior motive to put away black men which can lead to them reacting in a negative way, which puts the police and the individuals in danger, amd perpetuates the idea that black men are violent and dangerous. It also leads to a lack of trust in law enforcement and can result in vigilantism.

**I believe that racial profiling, while it may prevent crimes, creates a bigger problem in perpetuating racial tensions and creating a lack of trust in the legal system.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26804914911.0" user="typesoshee" delta="False">
    <text>There is a huge, real-life example that is as relevant as it gets to your view!  And that real-life example is a major country called France.  

From [Wikipedia:](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/France#Demographics) "... it is illegal for the French state to collect data on ethnicity and ancestry, a law with its origins in the 1789 revolution and reaffirmed in the constitution of 1958..."

An article from Time magazine, ["Should France Count Its Minority Population?":](http://www.time.com/time/world/article/0,8599,1887106,00.html) "every time someone proposes including ethnic data within national statistics all hell breaks lose. The accepted wisdom in France, it seems, is that acknowledging difference, and naming it, is bigotry itself."

I would recommend reading the whole Time article (it's not that long) as well as just Googling around for more stuff.  If you Google in English, unfortunately probably 99% of the articles you'll find will be in favor of doing racial statistics because they're going to be either from a more liberal or an American or British point of view.  The Time article calls the traditional race-blind French view "conservative," so I'd say you can expect less of that view being distributed across the internet by English-language writers.  

This is what I would say: racial statistics is a tool.  It can be used for good, and it can be used for bad.  "Racial profiling" is the bad kind.  A controversial but "good" kind of using racial statistics is affirmative action.  We should utilize racial statistics in our policy because it allows us to do the good kinds of things.  But we need to battle the bad kinds of things.  From the Time article: 

"Tapped by Sarkozy in November to suggest ways of mending the nation's race relations, Sabeg has proposed compiling and analyzing racial statistics as one of several ways of making the nation's anti-discrimination initiatives and laws stronger and more easily applied."

The fact is, being race-blind does not erase race problems - in fact, it allows race problems to exist under your artificial radar.  How can you solve race problems if you can't even see where they are in the first place?  At the same time, we should work to stop the bad kind of racial statistics use, which are the examples you provided.  These are great examples of the perils of racial statistics.  

But racial statistics is a tool.  Every tool allows good and bad.  The internet allows more efficient productivity, but also allows new kinds of criminal activity.  So should we throw away the internet?  No, we use the good internet, and work to prevent and mitigate the bad internet.  It's the same thing with racial statistics.  We should use them to better tackle issues that exist in certain races, and work to prevent their abuse in discriminatory profiling.  

Here's an illustration.  Let's say the US goes race-blind.  Officially, or statistically, there are now 0 bad arrests that were motivated by racial profiling.  Maybe because police departments are now very strictly legally bound not to do racial profiling, arrests driven solely by racial profiling do actually go down.  *But there is not way to actually tell, because there wouldn't be any statistics on it in the first place.*  Maybe the number of bad arrests motivated by racial profiling have stayed the same or actually gone up, but now there is no way to tell from the official records.  The other issue is, now we can't tell if this neighborhood, which is clearly poor and has high crime (because say we still have income and crime statistics) has more blacks or more whites.  But if we know that this poor neighborhood has more blacks and is situated next to a rich white neighborhood, what does that mean?  **VS.** what if the poor black neighborhood is situated next to a rich *black* neighborhood, then what does *that* mean?  Knowing these things can help you get to the bottom of the situation and help you create better-targeted policy, but without any cultural data, you can't even tell what's going on.  

EDIT: Minor parts.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
