<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92502748.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1j2nks/i_believe_using_an_individuals_race_to_determine/">
    <title>I believe using an individual's race to determine anything about them is not only immoral, but is not beneficial in any way. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>seeellayewhy</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Preface:** my mother and I have been in this argument for a long time and any time a racially charged court case or anything of tbe sort occurs it gets brought up. I want someone to articulate it to me in a way I can understand because at this point I see no validity in her side whatsoever.

I keep hearing this argument that "one day when I'm put in a situation i'll understand" - still waiting for that day. Here are some examples of the kind of profiling I'm talking about:

* Being from the good old south, I hear family, friends and acquaintances say "oh this is a rough part of town" when they pull up to a stoplight and see a few black people hanging around outside.

* Another is just seeing people get uneasy when a black male walks into a gas station, bank, or some other place.

* And the last major one is like NYC's stop-and-frisk policy. They basically had a quota from commanding officers to stop young black males walking down the street, question, and frisk them.

Now, in the first two situations, my counter-argument is simply to ask how does this help? Do you feel like you have avoided dangerous situations by assuming black neighborhoods are dangerous? Have you ever prevented a robbery at a gas station by being on high-alert?

As for the last situation, I think this policy has a *negative* outcome. By being blatantly racist, these individuals who are stopped lose faith in the law. They assume police have ulterior motive to put away black men which can lead to them reacting in a negative way, which puts the police and the individuals in danger, amd perpetuates the idea that black men are violent and dangerous. It also leads to a lack of trust in law enforcement and can result in vigilantism.

**I believe that racial profiling, while it may prevent crimes, creates a bigger problem in perpetuating racial tensions and creating a lack of trust in the legal system.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26804137868.0" user="nopromisingoldman" delta="False">
    <text>So I agree with you entirely when you're talking about racial profiling and in the manner you said. But I came to this when I read the title, so let me say what I was going to.

Sometimes I'm very cognizant of the race of the person I'm talking to and it helps me to keep that in mind because there are a certain set of near-universal experiences shared between people of color, and that can tinge a conversation in a way that it becomes much more valuable for me. For instance, [for what it's worth I'm Indian] the conversation I'd have with another brown person on the topic of marriage is very different from that I'd have with a friend who is white. There is a shared experience that constitutes the societal boundaries of a South Asian household (for instance), or the absence of that shared experience is also interesting to me. And so my interpersonal interactions are sometimes much more meaningful if I keep this baggage in mind. 

Is this immoral? I'm not sure I would ascribe morality to it. Is it beneficial? Certainly.

However, bringing it into anything but conversations about cultural experiences or experiences that involve being of color is immoral, in my view. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804168573.0" user="TubbyandthePoo-Bah" delta="False">
    <text>Citing cultural differences?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804174956.0" user="nopromisingoldman" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what your question is - but as a topic of discussion, I do think differences are just as interesting as similarities and just as interesting to talk about.

Feel free to tell me if I misunderstood your question.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804169661.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting, and I would agree that for the cultural discussion part it is nice. My onlt goal in the title was to refrain from using racial profiling but I do agree with you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804176416.0" user="nopromisingoldman" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah haha I got that when I read the body of your post. I thought from the title that this would be about seeing the world color-blind, which is something I disagree with as a concept.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804185414.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>Might I ask why? Cultural differences and race history are interesting to study and understand our world, but like I said in my post, I see no benefit in profiling. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804196320.0" user="nopromisingoldman" delta="False">
    <text>Sure thing!.

There are fairly large differences in the treatment society affords people of different skin color, still. [I recognize this could be contentious, but profiling is in itself one of these discrepancies.] The law should be constructed to be cognizant of these and to compensate for them, not be unaware of them. If teacher perception of black students drives low motivation and thus high drop out rates (just an example, don't take this at face value) then in my opinion the correct action that the law should take should not be ignoring this in a 'color-blind' philosophy, but in providing paths for those affected to avoid this. Basically, if the problem is somewhat racially motivated, the solution (in my mind) has to be somewhat driven along the lines of race until the problem has been fixed completely. Thus, racial sensitivity is necessary in the construction of public policy.

There are other aspects I think of this in, but this is the base of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804222508.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>So essentially, you are a proponent of the basic idea of affirmative action like programs.

Now I'd like to ask, at what point does negative racial profiling and tension fade away? I would argue that the recognition of racial discrepancies creates a false notion that people are not equal. Example, if we take action to ensure black students are not punished by their racist teachers, people who may not understand the intention amd function of this program could just think black students are genetically dumber and overall poor students simply because they are black. How do we prevent that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804687754.0" user="nopromisingoldman" delta="False">
    <text>It's important to note a couple of things, in this case.

1. The primary concern for communities this underprivileged by societal dynamics is not the perception of racial equality, which is a symptom, but is the underlying problem of not being provided opportunities. Thus the primary concern of programs is providing opportunities, not smoothing over racial tensions. If that is the aim of programs, it's a secondary aim. If that's the primary aim, then the program is ineffective and fairly selfish in its approach.

2. Racial tensions will be resolved when it is broadly agreed upon that opportunities afforded to all people are equal, regardless of who they were born to, where they were born,and what their skin color is. In the US and UK especially this also has an international component - you cannot expect a happy Pakistani-American population if drones continue to strike Pakistan. When you can look at a Trayvon Martin being shot and the topic of conversation is not 'he was followed and killed because he is black,' regardless of whether it's true or not, then there will be no racial tensions. In short, racial tensions will be solved when it is possible to perceive equality in treatment from figures of authority, regardless of skin color. Now how does this interact with the idea of perceived biases from these figured of authority? The responsibility should, I think, lie with them to provide an environment that is free of this sort of tension. As a responsible authority figure. Through training and sensitivity. It requires a paradigm shift in thinking but in my mind this is what will solve the issue.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
