<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92502748.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1j2nks/i_believe_using_an_individuals_race_to_determine/">
    <title>I believe using an individual's race to determine anything about them is not only immoral, but is not beneficial in any way. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>seeellayewhy</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Preface:** my mother and I have been in this argument for a long time and any time a racially charged court case or anything of tbe sort occurs it gets brought up. I want someone to articulate it to me in a way I can understand because at this point I see no validity in her side whatsoever.

I keep hearing this argument that "one day when I'm put in a situation i'll understand" - still waiting for that day. Here are some examples of the kind of profiling I'm talking about:

* Being from the good old south, I hear family, friends and acquaintances say "oh this is a rough part of town" when they pull up to a stoplight and see a few black people hanging around outside.

* Another is just seeing people get uneasy when a black male walks into a gas station, bank, or some other place.

* And the last major one is like NYC's stop-and-frisk policy. They basically had a quota from commanding officers to stop young black males walking down the street, question, and frisk them.

Now, in the first two situations, my counter-argument is simply to ask how does this help? Do you feel like you have avoided dangerous situations by assuming black neighborhoods are dangerous? Have you ever prevented a robbery at a gas station by being on high-alert?

As for the last situation, I think this policy has a *negative* outcome. By being blatantly racist, these individuals who are stopped lose faith in the law. They assume police have ulterior motive to put away black men which can lead to them reacting in a negative way, which puts the police and the individuals in danger, amd perpetuates the idea that black men are violent and dangerous. It also leads to a lack of trust in law enforcement and can result in vigilantism.

**I believe that racial profiling, while it may prevent crimes, creates a bigger problem in perpetuating racial tensions and creating a lack of trust in the legal system.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26804146496.0" user="disciple_of_iron" delta="False">
    <text>Your title and ending statement are contradictory. In the title you say 

&amp;gt;is not beneficial in any way

but in the ending statement you say

&amp;gt;it may prevent crimes

There is a big difference between "there are no positives" and "the negatives outweigh the positives"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804170407.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I meant to say "is not beneficial in the long run".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804429551.0" user="30thaim" delta="False">
    <text>I would point out that it isn't beneficial in the short run either. It doesn't prevent crimes because you're only catching the black/hispanic/Muslim-looking criminals (and inventing reasons to arrest some innocent people) and letting all the white criminals have the benefit of the doubt. And the time you spend harassing innocent people of colour is time that could be spent looking for actual crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804460762.0" user="epursimuove" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  It doesn't prevent crimes because you're only catching the black/hispanic/Muslim-looking criminals (and inventing reasons to arrest some innocent people) and letting all the white criminals have the benefit of the doubt.

You're assuming that if you're profiling group X, you're spending no time whatsoever looking for non-X criminals. This is obviously not the case - focusing on one sector does not mean ignoring all others.



</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
