<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92502748.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1j2nks/i_believe_using_an_individuals_race_to_determine/">
    <title>I believe using an individual's race to determine anything about them is not only immoral, but is not beneficial in any way. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>seeellayewhy</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Preface:** my mother and I have been in this argument for a long time and any time a racially charged court case or anything of tbe sort occurs it gets brought up. I want someone to articulate it to me in a way I can understand because at this point I see no validity in her side whatsoever.

I keep hearing this argument that "one day when I'm put in a situation i'll understand" - still waiting for that day. Here are some examples of the kind of profiling I'm talking about:

* Being from the good old south, I hear family, friends and acquaintances say "oh this is a rough part of town" when they pull up to a stoplight and see a few black people hanging around outside.

* Another is just seeing people get uneasy when a black male walks into a gas station, bank, or some other place.

* And the last major one is like NYC's stop-and-frisk policy. They basically had a quota from commanding officers to stop young black males walking down the street, question, and frisk them.

Now, in the first two situations, my counter-argument is simply to ask how does this help? Do you feel like you have avoided dangerous situations by assuming black neighborhoods are dangerous? Have you ever prevented a robbery at a gas station by being on high-alert?

As for the last situation, I think this policy has a *negative* outcome. By being blatantly racist, these individuals who are stopped lose faith in the law. They assume police have ulterior motive to put away black men which can lead to them reacting in a negative way, which puts the police and the individuals in danger, amd perpetuates the idea that black men are violent and dangerous. It also leads to a lack of trust in law enforcement and can result in vigilantism.

**I believe that racial profiling, while it may prevent crimes, creates a bigger problem in perpetuating racial tensions and creating a lack of trust in the legal system.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26804147366.0" user="alecbenzer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Now, in the first two situations, my counter-argument is simply to ask how does this help? Do you feel like you have avoided dangerous situations by assuming black neighborhoods are dangerous? Have you ever prevented a robbery at a gas station by being on high-alert?

Are you suggesting that people shouldn't try and be alert about potential robbers, and that doing so would confer no benefit to not being robbed? If it's indeed true that a particular kind of person is more likely to rob a store, being more alert when such a person walks in seems like an effective step to take if your goal is to cut down on robberies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804173249.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>Right, but does particularly being on your toes when blacks come in help? Obviously a store owner should be prepared to do whatever they can to prevent a robbery, but how is one specifically benefitted by heighteed alertness around blacks?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804237116.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>Well "black" is just another category that you can put people in and collect data about. It would be reasonable to be more prepared when someone "wearing a hoodie and carrying a gun" walked into your store because they probably (sorry I don't have a source) are more likely to rob your store. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804550921.0" user="alecbenzer" delta="False">
    <text>If they try and shop-lift something, you're more likely to notice it, for instance. Just like store-owners might be more alert if a large group of teenagers walk into a store.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26804565470.0" user="seeellayewhy" delta="False">
    <text>So if black people are more likely to shoplift (that could in fact be a viable statistic IF it exists), do store owners prevent these by heightened awareness with blacks in the store, and how many white shoplifters do they miss by assuming security?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26805781970.0" user="alecbenzer" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; do store owners prevent these by heightened awareness with blacks in the store

_Assuming_ the blacks are more likely to steal/shoplift, I think that's perfectly plausible. Or at least, I'd be very skeptical of the suggestion that this did nothing for security. If someone's going to try and swipe something and they see an owner or employee watching them, they might decide not to. Even if they still try and take something, you've got a good chance of seeing them do it and catching them.

&amp;gt; and how many white shoplifters do they miss by assuming security?

That doesn't really have to do with your claim that watching black people more closely doesn't help prevent shoplifting (although it may be hypocritical).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
