<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92871272.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jajxk/i_dont_think_the_nsa_spying_on_us_is_such_a_big/">
    <title>I don't think the NSA spying on us is such a big deal. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jstavy</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here is my reasoning: growing up parallel to the development of the internet my parents always warned me that anything you put into a computer someone out there can see. It is permanent. So I have always assumed there is always someone watching. That assumption at the end of the day hasn't really changed what I put on the internet because everything is strictly my opinion and I don't care what others think of it.

As far as the recording of phone conversations and storing of email, that is just a case of national security. these things need to be saved in case someone is planning a terrorist attack on our nation IMO.	

I am just a normal citizen like many of you, but my opinion differs on this subject matter and I want to understand what the big fuss about it is. It has always just been a common knowledge and understanding for me that I am being watched.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26807944138.0" user="AaronEricaSpencerMit" delta="False">
    <text>It's wrong because it is already so very very easy to collect data and information about you from the internet, bring it together and get a very clear picture who you are. This makes you susceptible to blackmail. The government can control you.
Let me prove this with my quick google research about you:

* Your gender (not so exciting I know but it gets better)
* Your full name
* Your current occupation
* How old you are (exact birthay)
* Which country you live in
* Which state you live in
* Which city you live in
* What you look like
* What your hobbies are
* Who your mom, dad, sister and brothers are and what they look like
* Where you were born
* A lot of your friends
* A lot of other stuff not worth mentioning here

I stopped when I had to watch you smashing guitars.
Now imagine that this is not another bored redditor but the goverment collecting data about you. Also, for whatever reason (your political opinion or because you sat on santas lap last christmas), they don't like you and want you to do something. I don't care what. They can blackmail the shit out of you with all that information. So why should you care about the NSA and PRISM? The internet is already very permanent and what you once posted can't be taken back, but PRISM makes it even a little easier for the government to control you without even having to google your name.

If you want I can send you all I know about you to get you a little scared and tell you how I did it.

PS: Throwaway because I don't want you to do the same with me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807956263.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>oooo oooo ooo me me next, me next, me next.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807964637.0" user="AaronEricaSpencerMit" delta="False">
    <text>Only if I can post the information about you in here, else it isn't fun but work for nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807977205.0" user="ezarcs" delta="False">
    <text>Danger, danger! You cannot! From the [reddiquette](http://www.reddit.com/wiki/reddiquette#wiki_please__don.27t):

&amp;gt; Users posting personal info are subject to an immediate account deletion. If you see a user posting personal info, please contact the admins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807981282.0" user="AaronEricaSpencerMit" delta="False">
    <text>Alright I wouldn't have posted name and address anyway even if I found them. Just a little bit about him and what his hobbies are^^</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808017627.0" user="ezarcs" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it's a little sad that it doesn't describe exceptions - it would be nice if there would be an explicit exclusion for cases where permission is given, for example, or even just regarding one's own personal information, even though that is a tricky point. At the very least, you should be able to PM monkyyy with your findings, and monkyyy should be able to post your findings in here anyway..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808261601.0" user="seanarturo" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think those things constitute "personal data." If it did, I'd be very surprised since sharing any relevant anecdote from your personal life would technically be the same thing.

On a side note: I am willing to post your findings on me (I think I'm too easy to find stuff about since I'm way too open, but I do want to know if there's anything alarming out there) if you inbox them to me (or hell, if you find my email, email it to me hah)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807984486.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>sure
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808167095.0" user="Ptylerdactyl" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sort of curious, because I'm typically pretty careful. You have my express written permission to try to dox me; you can PM me if you're worried about the mods shutting you down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808507833.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Found out what town you live in, master's degree (but not where from). Basic interests are really pretty easy to figure out just by looking at where people post in Reddit.

Not able to validate your full name, and without that you're pretty limited. Relatively easy to figure out OPs full name, and go from there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808824461.0" user="Ptylerdactyl" delta="False">
    <text>This based on Reddit activity, mostly? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809007423.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Exclusively on reddit activity. You're not the only person who uses the handle ptylerdactyl, found associations with more than one full name with it on other sites.

The images you post don't have much personal information, although one screenshot says what town you live in.

Honestly, images can be a big gold-mine for information. Potential links to social media accounts like google+. Can sometimes do an image search to tie it to a name. Hell, sometimes images have EXIF data that has lat/long of where the picture was taken, valuable if taken at home or work.

You're pretty consistent about using imgur though, which strips out any EXIF data.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809071479.0" user="Ptylerdactyl" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You're not the only person who uses the handle ptylerdactyl, found associations with more than one full name with it on other sites.

This is actually something I kind of count on. There are at least four other people I've found, which is a nice buffer.

&amp;gt;The images you post don't have much personal information, although one screenshot says what town you live in.

After combing through a ton of old posts, I found the one that mentions this. It's not the place I live, but it's *pretty* close. I think my ISP routes through there, so MSN.com thinks that's where I am.

Not totally accurate, but still kind of close to home.

&amp;gt;You're pretty consistent about using imgur though, which strips out any EXIF data.

An added bonus of using reddit's favorite image host. Thanks for this, it's been really interesting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808506284.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Easier and harder for different people. OP leaves a pretty accessible digital footprint, with lax privacy settings on social media.

You, on the other hand, not as much information. While there's plenty about people with the usernames "monkyyy", it'd be too time consuming to verify whether it's the same person behind the name as you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808511356.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>???? 

I've posted my own name on reddit before, and I've never had a delusion of privacy and lower my security settings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808560768.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, most of the above information provided to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808509417.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to follow this up by also volunteering to send the above information to OP.

Btw OP, take down the damn pictures of you and your friends smoking pot on facebook. Employers look at that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808524193.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Lol. Not pot. Hookah. Tobacco. At a hookah bar. Good point though, if you can't tell the difference(can't tell unless you see the bowl) I guess others wouldn't either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808528687.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty much, and I think it's really a matter of tone. Lots of pictures of partying (the picture of 12 packs doesn't help) is usually enough to make employers pass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808535074.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>I wish I could just delete my Facebook altogether :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809308820.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Well, the government could have it at anytime even if you do delete it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808538057.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Btw this dude is right on the money with the info. Kudos to him! Now excuse me while I go try and hide from the internet! Lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808757441.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>Now imagine he had phone conversations and knew that you were, say, cheating on your wife. Would you be comfortable that some stranger had this info?

Now, imagine the people that have it have the resources to dig even deeper, and coerce you with the full backing of the law and government agencies behind them. It could be into "giving them information" about someone you work with. What would you do then? Would you tell the police, at risk of the news leaking to your wife? Or would you say "Hey, it's just info they want...it's to save us from terrorism, it's for national security!"

Or would you think "How did we let it get this far...?"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808597202.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Also, for whatever reason (your political opinion or because you sat on santas lap last christmas), they don't like you and want you to do something. I don't care what. They can blackmail the shit out of you with all that information.

This is simply alarmist nonsense. Where is the precedent for this being anything close to a likely outcome? There is none. The US does not arrest or blackmail political dissidents that are ordinary citizens, perhaps you're confusing the United States with North Korea. Furthermore, you think if the government wanted to know any of this stuff, they'd need to use Google to find it? Seriously, how naïve are you? If you have a drivers license, your state government already knows almost all of this information and all it takes is a warrant and the government can access it. Police can run your license plates and see all of the information associated with your car registration as well as your criminal record right from their cruiser. FBI agents likely have the same technology at their disposal. Your speculation is not valid evidence that something like PRISM is necessarily bad.

Just because something has the *potential* to be abused doesn't necessarily mean that it *will* be abused. Posting Doomsday rhetoric like this here is simply dishonest. In this case, acting like programs like PRISM will lead to the persecution of political dissidents is lunacy, it honestly makes you sound like a conspiracy theorist. Of course, if you have evidence that indeed the US is a special snowflake and that we're the only country with surveillance programs that will become a fascist dictatorship, please share it with me, because I'd like to know.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808622258.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>This is a harmfully inaccurate comment: "The US does not arrest or blackmail political dissidents that are ordinary citizens."

Uh, yes it does.  Pretty fucking frequently.

Source: actual U.S. history.

But, for anyone not interested in doing the research on the history, how about the present?  Here are three larger-scale arrests of protesters/dissidents on grounds that are at least questionable--from just this last week:

* http://www.huffingtonpost.com/2013/07/26/scott-walker-protests_n_3661022.html

* http://swampland.time.com/2013/07/26/another-day-in-washington-about-50-arrested-at-keystone-xl-protest/

* http://abclocal.go.com/wtvd/story?section=news/local&amp;amp;id=9180663

As you're reading these--if you're reading these--I'd ask you to keep in mind that the dissidents in all these examples are exercising free speech rights.  "But why can't they just do that quietly at home?", you ask.  Ah, yes: protesting quietly at home, the political action that changed the world.

I'm not even weighing in on the original question here: just had to address the blatant inaccuracy of the statement in deleigh's post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808740225.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>In what way(s) is it harmful? The last time the US government targeted political groups in such a way was during the Second Red Scare. Hardly a frequent occurrence. Saying that history shows you're correct and then providing absolutely no sources to substantiate that is not only lazy, but completely dishonest. If the proof were so readily available, and if you were truly interested in "addressing the inaccuracies" in my post, you'd actually cite your sources, not point your finger in the general direction of US history and claim that's enough.

Furthermore, were you at these protests? Do you have access to the police reports regarding these people's arrests? If not, what evidence do you have that these people were arrested for political reasons and not for simply being belligerent? None of the articles you link give credence to the theory that the arrests were suspect. That's entirely your own speculation and not something expressed in the linked articles. I'm surprised you didn't bring up Occupy, too, but I guess that doesn't fit into your narrative that the police are trying to quash uprisings in the name of politics and corporations. So much for addressing the blatant inaccuracies in my post with facts and evidence and not speculation, original research, and dishonesty. You're just as bad as the person I responded to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809616095.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Are you serious?  Why should I take my time to teach you shit you ought to know before you start running your mouth?  There's nothing dishonest about my indifference to educating *you* specifically, who are clearly too lazy to even bother googling after your claims are challenged.

I am pointing readers other than yourself to the historical record, which they can easily check out for themselves.  For instance, the fourth result in a google books search for "U.S. government blackmail activists" is the following, an academic text: http://books.google.com/books?id=un3V4GDAkQwC&amp;amp;pg=PA216&amp;amp;dq=U.S.+government+blackmail+activists&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ei=Mmn4UeTMHo3riQKY2IGADg&amp;amp;ved=0CEEQ6AEwAw#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=U.S.%20government%20blackmail%20activists&amp;amp;f=false.

Here, you'll find one (of thousands) of sources that describe something that is a matter of public record: "The founding director of the US FBI, J Edgar Hoover, used sexual blackmail to harass and control generations of American politicians and activists" (216-17).

When I say "source: history," this is a more polite way of saying "your statement is asinine, because it asserts pompously that which is demonstrably false and which every reasonably well-educated person knows to be false."  Typically, one does not bother providing sources for facts that are a matter of public record.

For instance, we also don't need sources to "prove" to one another that the U.S. government has consistently intervened *against* democratic political processes in Latin America and elsewhere, or that the U.S. government developed a consistent policy of illegal detainment and torture after 9/11.  These are well-known aspects of contemporary history.  So, too, are the arrests and blackmail of political activists.

It is disappointing to hear that you not only can't be bothered to look these things up and educate yourself, but that you are attacking me for suggesting that you do so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809646574.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, what an extremely rude comment. Take the fucking stick out of your ass and calm down. If you can't even be mature in an argument (as evidenced by the fact you feel the need to downvote my comments here just because they offend your oh-so-delicate sensibilities as well as talking down to me despite the fact I was nothing but civil towards you) perhaps this isn't the right subreddit for you to be posting in. I think you'd be better off in /r/politics with your attitude.

Second, it is not up to me to do research on your claims. If you want to make a claim, you provide evidence that supports it, plain and simple. That's how [the burden of proof](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philosophic_burden_of_proof) works. You assert the government frequently and systematically targets US political groups and US citizens for political reasons, you must provide evidence for that claim or I will rightfully assume it's false. You have still failed to provide an adequate source that proves your claim. Where in the link you provide does it explicitly state that the United States frequently targeted United States political groups and citizens for political reasons? Please give me specific page numbers and line numbers. I assume you read the source you're referencing, so you should have no problem doing this.

&amp;gt;When I say "source: history," this is a more polite way of saying "your statement is asinine, because it asserts pompously that which is demonstrably false and which every reasonably well-educated person knows to be false." Typically, one does not bother providing sources for facts that are a matter of public record.

No, it means you are too lazy to provide a source that supports your claim and expect me to do it for you, which I will not. If it's demonstrably false, why have you failed to prove it? If the proof is so readily available, show it to me. This shouldn't be a hard thing for you to do, but you insist on shifting the responsibility to me because you either cannot find a source and you're lying through your teeth or you don't understand how the burden of proof works, in which case I've provided a link to it further up and you now understand what responsibility you have to prove your side of the argument if you want me to believe you.

Watch how simple this is. The United States government does not prosecute political groups and citizens for political reasons and there is no proof that PRISM will lead to political dissidents being arrested. Source: history. Prove me wrong. Sources? I don't need to prove it, it's your job to do the research if you really want to know the answer. Look, I just did exactly what you did, I just proved what I said was right.

&amp;gt;For instance, we also don't need sources to "prove" to one another that the U.S. government has consistently intervened against democratic political processes in Latin America and elsewhere, or that the U.S. government developed a consistent policy of illegal detainment and torture after 9/11. These are well-known aspects of contemporary history. So, too, are the arrests and blackmail of political activists.

Number one, this is a strawman and completely irrelevant. Number two, you do need sources to "prove" these claims, but they're readily available with a quick Google search. Your claims, on the other hand, are not so readily available because they didn't happen.

It's disappointing that you can't even do something as simple as proving specific sources to prove your claim is correct. You had two chances, you struck twice. If you want, I'm willing to hear you out one more time, but if you can't provide any sources for the one specific claim that I wanted to see a source for, I'm not going to continue debating with you because it's obvious you just have an agenda to push and aren't really interested in listening to facts or being reasonable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809676815.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Wait, are you at all serious?  Go back and reread your own previous comment; I took my cue on tone from that, as it seemed your preference was for hostility and rudeness.

Are you familiar with how argument works in an academic arena?  As a general rule, we have a large collection of statements about the world that can be called "the public record" or "the historical record."  These statements are accepted as broadly accurate by all competent parties to a discussion.

Then, over and above these statements, there are innumerable other, debatable statements.  The ongoing process of debating these other, contentious statements, trying to get it right, is how we make history.

Now and then, in that process, we revisit certain statements everyone believes to be correct, statements that are part of the historical record.  People who revisit those statements and wish to argue that they are *not*, in fact, correct, are called "revisionist" historians.  They perform a great service, looking back on previously established knowledge in light of newly emergent facts or theories, helping us get the historical record itself more right than we had previously.

Obviously, because they are arguing against *what all competent parties assume to be the case*, revisionist historians have to meet a high standard of proof.  Accordingly, revisionist history tends to be very well-researched and argued.

But why am I telling you all this?  Here's why:

The historical record accepts that the U.S. government has a fairly long history of blackmailing and jailing ordinary citizens for political activities that one or another branch of the government finds objectionable.  *This is not a disputed fact.*  Whether you know this, or others on reddit know this, it is generally accepted and readily verified knowledge among historians.  Everyone who knows much at all about U.S. history understands and acknowledges this.

Accordingly, in your claim that there is no evidence to support concern for U.S. government misuse/abuse of personal information, you are acting as what we call a revisionist historian.  Now, if you can demonstrate that this claim is true, that the facts actually back up your assertion, you'll have done us all a great service--we'll acquire, thanks to your efforts, a new and deeper understanding of ourselves and our history.  We will, in short, change *what counts as historical fact*; we will change the historical record.

Because you are making statements that *do not* accord with what competent U.S. historians believe to be basic knowledge about history, the burden of proof is on you.  I did not bother "disproving" your initial claims *because those claims themselves were neither supported with evidence nor in accord with the generally accepted historical record*.

Do you understand better how this works now?

To recapitulate, because your position *challenges accepted history* (even if you, personally, may be ignorant of that history), it is incumbent on you to offer some support for it.  This you did not do.

By contrast, less for your benefit than for the ease of anyone else reading this exchange, I offered a few links that helped clarify what did not work about your claim.  You don't have to like or accept those links.  You should, however, actually read some historical scholarship at some point.  If you are struggling to understand the book I linked you to, I'm sorry, but I'm not interested in explaining it to you.

Like I said, I'm not especially concerned with helping you become more educated.  I glanced through your comment history, and arrived at the conclusion that you are a person who is fairly ignorant, unaware of his/her ignorance, and uninterested in amending that ignorance.  That is of course your prerogative.  But that's also why I have nothing more to say to you.

To anyone reading this exchange, I really do encourage you to check out the (rich) scholarship on U.S. governmental misuse/abuse of information.  An easy, and fascinating, place to start is with the FBI under J. Edgar Hoover.  In case you don't already do this, I encourage you also to seek out scholarly books and articles: books from publishers that do blind peer-review (which includes most, though not all, academic journals and university presses [X University Press], and also a small handful of non-university academic presses--such as Routledge, Blackwell, and Walter de Gruyter).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809750631.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>My tone was not confrontational, yours was. I simply called you lazy and dishonest for making a claim and failing to provide evidence for it. For claiming to "address the blatant inaccuracies" in my posts and then not doing so. I would expect the same kind of response if I did the same thing.

&amp;gt;Are you familiar with how argument works in an academic arena? As a general rule, we have a large collection of statements about the world that can be called "the public record" or "the historical record." These statements are accepted as broadly accurate by all competent parties to a discussion.

&amp;gt;Then, over and above these statements, there are innumerable other, debatable statements. The ongoing process of debating these other, contentious statements, trying to get it right, is how we make history.

None of this precludes you from being able to provide sources if requested. In fact, it should make it rather easy to do so since there should be an abundance of evidence that supports your claim. I'm not asking for much, I just want evidence that supports the claim that broad, systematic, and deliberate targeting of political groups and US citizens was carried out by the United States government for explicit political reasons. Not city police, the US government. Specifically, I'm more interested in the targeting of citizens, because that was the claim that was made in the original post that I addressed. I'd likewise prefer instances that are &amp;lt;50 years old, if possible, because they are the most relevant.

&amp;gt;Obviously, because they are arguing against what all competent parties assume to be the case, revisionist historians have to meet a high standard of proof. Accordingly, revisionist history tends to be very well-researched and argued.

&amp;gt;But why am I telling you all this? Here's why:

&amp;gt;The historical record accepts that the U.S. government has a fairly long history of blackmailing and jailing ordinary citizens for political activities that one or another branch of the government finds objectionable. This is not a disputed fact. Whether you know this, or others on reddit know this, it is generally accepted and readily verified knowledge among historians. Everyone who knows much at all about U.S. history understands and acknowledges this.

I acknowledge that the US has had a history of blackmailing people, but those instances are several decades if not centuries old. They are no longer relevant to or indicative of the tendencies of our current government. You say this happens frequently. How often did it happen under the last five presidents? The targeting of these groups was often motivated by moral panics such as the persecution of socialists, communists, and anarchists during the First Red Scare. That's a different set of circumstances and not what I'm referring to. What I'm referring to is the sort of persecution that happens in North Korea. That does not occur here. There is nothing that would lend credence to the idea that it's realistically going to happen.

&amp;gt;Accordingly, in your claim that there is no evidence to support concern for U.S. government misuse/abuse of personal information, you are acting as what we call a revisionist historian. Now, if you can demonstrate that this claim is true, that the facts actually back up your assertion, you'll have done us all a great service--we'll acquire, thanks to your efforts, a new and deeper understanding of ourselves and our history. We will, in short, change what counts as historical fact; we will change the historical record.

&amp;gt;Because you are making statements that do not accord with what competent U.S. historians believe to be basic knowledge about history, the burden of proof is on you. I did not bother "disproving" your initial claims because those claims themselves were neither supported with evidence nor in accord with the generally accepted historical record.

&amp;gt;Do you understand better how this works now?

It's my fault for not being specific. I should have stated that there were no recent examples of government targeting political groups and citizens for political reasons. I thought it was implied by my use of the present tense "does not" and not past tense "has not" or "has never", but I guess I was mistaken. Nevertheless, the burden of proof still lies on you for asserting that the government persecution of political groups and US citizens for political reasons happens frequently (you showed it happened, but you haven't proven that it has happened frequently). You gave three links to stories about protesters being arrested by police (city police aren't federal agents, by the way), none of which asserted that the circumstances of their arrest were suspect, none of which prove anything about the government. I take the stance that there is no probable reason to suspect the US government will use PRISM to target citizens for political blackmail, it's not my responsibility to prove that the government *won't* do something. It's up to anyone who thinks the government *will* do something to provide appropriate evidence that it's a likely outcome. Has Barack Obama targeted anyone in such a way during his presidency? If not, then it's not a likely outcome and a bit paranoid to assume the worst.

&amp;gt;Like I said, I'm not especially concerned with helping you become more educated. I glanced through your comment history, and arrived at the conclusion that you are a person who is fairly ignorant, unaware of his/her ignorance, and uninterested in amending that ignorance. That is of course your prerogative. But that's also why I have nothing more to say to you.

You're not even concerned with helping yourself become more educated, so that's to be expected. It's all right, though. You seem more interested in nitpicking my word choice instead of actually addressing my points, so I understand this argument is futile. All I can say is don't be so paranoid.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809825713.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Are you really so naive as to think that just because something hasn't happened for a few years, it's unlikely to ever happen again?

As I said, I have nothing more to say to you regarding specific historical facts; you are clearly a person who's not willing to own his/her own words and acknowledge when s/he is in error, and with such a person, discussion of concrete things is pointless.

But now, reading your most recent post, I'm intrigued on this new front.  How far back do you think you have to go, in the history of a state, before you say that patterns of behavior on the part of political actors no longer offer cautionary tales for the present and future?  Five years, twenty, two hundred, six hundred?

Is the broadly human tendency of individuals in positions of power to misuse or abuse their power really a thing of the distant past, no longer something to be concerned about?

Mind you, I'm not at all granting your claim that the Obama years, and the Bush years before them, and the Clinton years before those, and the Bush years before them, and so forth, have somehow been free of massive abuses of power--of just the sort that should make us concerned about blackmail, preemptive arrests, and other tactics designed to harass and control politically active citizens--but am asking here only about the motion of your thought.

In other words, I'm not interested in discussing the content of your beliefs, which I regard as hopelessly and bizarrely errant, but I'm fascinated by the way you move between them, by your particular variant of "logic."

It seems that you feel like anything that hasn't happened "recently" is unlikely ever to happen again.  In this particular case, based on what you've written, your stance seems to be as follows:

(1) There have been no recent abuses of power that would make us concerned about the way government officials (or private individuals working for security companies!) are likely to use massive amounts of information collected about private individuals.

(1a) Specifically, the worst and longest-running period of regular political blackmail by a U.S. government employee (i.e., Hoover, from a little ways into his 48-year tenure as director of the major domestic spy agency until his death in 1972) ended about fifty years ago.

(2) Things that haven't occurred for at least fifty years are unlikely to occur again now or in the future, at least in the domain of political repression/suppression of dissent.

(3) Therefore, no government official (or employee of a private security firm!) today is likely to abuse information in the way that Hoover did, by blackmailing people or framing political dissidents.

(4) Accordingly, we have no reason to be concerned about PRISM, etc.

Can you possibly really think this way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809872018.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Are you really so naive as to think that just because something hasn't happened for a few years, it's unlikely to ever happen again?

&amp;gt;As I said, I have nothing more to say to you regarding specific historical facts; you are clearly a person who's not willing to own his/her own words and acknowledge when s/he is in error, and with such a person, discussion of concrete things is pointless.

No, but by your reasoning, I should also be worried about slavery being legalized, blacks becoming segregated, and women losing the right to vote, but I'm not. Are you? They happened in the past, after all, they certainly can happen again, right?

As for your second paragraph, here is a direct quote from my original post:

&amp;gt;The US does not arrest or blackmail political dissidents that are ordinary citizens

I shouldn't have to explain this again, but it seems like it's necessary. Pay attention to the words "does not". That's what is known as the present tense in English. It refers to things which are happening in this current point in time. Things that are happening in the present, to put it more simply. It is completely irrespective of the past. I didn't say the US hasn't arrested or blackmailed political dissidents, simply that it is not occurring at this point in time. You seem to think that's incorrect, in fact, you even said it happened frequently, so I asked you for some evidence that perhaps would shed light on those injustices that somehow flew under the radar of all the news outlets. I think any reasonable person would have reacted the same way. You provided links to three articles detailing the arrests of protesters, none of which listed a motive for the arrest, none of which entertained the idea that the arrests were politically motivated. I said that wasn't evidence of the United States government arresting political groups or citizens for political reasons. You decided to cite historical instances from President Hoover (let me remind you Hoover was president eighty years ago), which doesn't exactly qualify as a recent event, at least not to me. I was even willing to go back as far as thirty years for a recent event, but that was not acceptable, apparently.

You then accused me, and still are accusing me, of saying the US has never arrested political groups and citizens for political reasons. Keep in mind I never once said that (nor implied it), it was entirely a notion you conjured up due to your misunderstanding of English grammar. I realize, in hindsight, I should have called you out for it right then and there, but I was too caught up trying to get just one source that substantiated your claim that I didn't do it. My mistake. Same thing goes for calling me a revisionary historian. I never once disputed historical facts, simply asked for evidence of supposed recent facts. As of this post, I have still yet to see a link to a news article that proves your claim that the United States is **currently** arresting political groups and US citizens for political reasons. At this point, I've given up. I'm just going to have to accept that I'm never going to see it because it simply doesn't exist.

&amp;gt;It seems that you feel like anything that hasn't happened "recently" is unlikely ever to happen again. In this particular case, based on what you've written, your stance seems to be as follows:

Before I start, keep in mind that my idea of recent is anywhere from thirty-forty years.

&amp;gt;There have been no recent abuses of power that would make us concerned about the way government officials (or private individuals working for security companies!) are likely to use massive amounts of information collected about private individuals.

Not in the way we're discussing, no.

&amp;gt;Specifically, the worst and longest-running period of regular political blackmail by a U.S. government employee (i.e., Hoover, from a little ways into his 48-year tenure as director of the major domestic spy agency until his death in 1972) ended about fifty years ago.

According to you, it was "sexual blackmail of politicians and activists", not exactly the groups I'm discussing. Furthermore, Hoover is one person. His actions are not indicative of the actions of anyone else except him.

&amp;gt;Things that haven't occurred for at least fifty years are unlikely to occur again now or in the future, at least in the domain of political repression/suppression of dissent.

Yes, generally when you go through five or more administrations without this type of thing happening, especially when you live in a world such as ours where information can be spread faster than ever, it's less and less likely to occur as time goes on because it's far more difficult to suppress the flow of information.

&amp;gt;Therefore, no government official (or employee of a private security firm!) today is likely to abuse information in the way that Hoover did, by blackmailing people or framing political dissidents.

By this logic, all prisoners should be locked up for life because there's a chance they will reoffend in the future and there's no point in letting them out if they're just going to come back in.

&amp;gt;Accordingly, we have no reason to be concerned about PRISM, etc.

There's no reason to suspect that it will be used as a tool for political blackmail of unfavorable political groups or US citizens. There are certainly concerns to be raised about blanket surveillance, violations of the first amendment and due process is, realistically, not one of them.

&amp;gt;Can you possibly really think this way?

Yes, I can, because I'm not paranoid. It's amazing what your mind is capable of thinking when you're not perpetually scared of a boogeyman that doesn't exist. I do not automatically assume the worst possible outcome in any given situation is the most likely outcome. Your entire argument boils down to speculation and hypothetical situations which have no modern historical information to substantiate them. You're just like the people who think if Snowden comes back to the USA, he'll be sent to Guantanamo Bay or killed when Bradley Manning, who committed far greater of an offense than Snowden and was charged under much harsher laws, faces a maximum of ~125 years and will likely only serve 20-30. 

This is an optional bonus question here, you don't have to answer it. Think realistically here. What about PRISM, based on the **facts**, leads you to believe it will be used in such a nefarious way? Before you type a single letter, keep in mind I don't want to see any speculation, I don't want to see any "what if"s, I want to see real evidence that shows that there is a very likely reason to believe that PRISM will be used to silence political opponents of the United States. Preferably, evidence from the Bush/Obama administration since they are the only two presidents so far that have been in office while PRISM has existed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809878581.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Holy shit!  You are *mind-numbingly* ignorant.  Not President *Herbert* Hoover, dummy: *J. Edgar* Hoover, long-time FBI director (and creator, after a fashion).

And, icing on the cake, in this long post of yours you have completely failed to engage with my question about the motion of your thought (or, apparently, to even notice that I don't at all grant your unargued, unevidenced assertion that there have been no abuses of power in the effort to silence political protest in the last thirty or forty years).

If it will make you feel competent to add another comment or two on here, knock yourself out.  For my money, you're a lost cause.  I have no further wish to communicate with you, on any front.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809883548.0" user="deleigh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Holy shit! You are mind-numbingly ignorant. Not President Herbert Hoover, dummy: J. Edgar Hoover, long-time FBI director (and creator, after a fashion).

I apologize. That was entirely my mistake for confusing the two.

&amp;gt;And, icing on the cake, in this long post of yours you have completely failed to engage with my question about the motion of your thought (or, apparently, to even notice that I don't at all grant your unargued, unevidenced assertion that there have been no abuses of power in the effort to silence political protest in the last thirty or forty years).

Just like you failed to address the fact you accused me of saying something I didn't say and failed to prove any of the claims you made? I don't think you have any room to talk about competency, honestly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808950742.0" user="immunofort" delta="False">
    <text>It is inaccurate I'll agree, but only on a technical level. I think his comment should be interpreted as "The US does not arrest or blackmail political dissidents that are ordinary citizens **for political reasons**."

Now, do you have any proof of the US government blackmailing or arrested people for political reasons?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809624968.0" user="beimpermissible" delta="False">
    <text>Yes.  It's a matter of public record.  Just look up "J. Edgar Hoover blackmail," for instance, and restrict yourself to scholarly sources (peer-reviewed journals and books), to weed out conspiracy garbage websites.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808676725.0" user="passeanonym" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with you that programs like PRISM is a significant threat. If the government, or branches within the police or military, is after you, they don't need PRISM to make your life very difficult. If you become a target, the data collected through PRISM is probably the LEAST of your concerns. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808758561.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>Well, they may not *need* it, but it makes it substantially easier. Why is it okay to let them build a structure around us designed to manipulate us as easily as possible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808773449.0" user="passeanonym" delta="False">
    <text>I am strongly against PRISM and similar programs as the level of political influence is discomforting and I fear for political abuse, not retaliation from agencies. Much of the information incorporated are already stored and available. As I see it, several concerns are a storm in a tea-kettle - but there a few real ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808947461.0" user="immunofort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  Why is it okay to let them build a structure around us designed to manipulate us as easily as possible?

Why is it OK for the terrorists to roam free when we could easily counter them with surveillance techniques? /s

If you're going to use extremely biased and loaded question, I can do that too. You should refrain from doing so because it just drives down the quality of comments. If you have to resort to such techniques, it just speaks to the weakness of your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810381629.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If you're going to use extremely biased and loaded question, I can do that too.

You could also explain why it is loaded, but that would be too difficult, way easier to be sarcastic I guess, eh? It is not biased, it is a structure designed to hone in on and identify anyone they want to.

How about this, I'll use an example here. Let's say the government says "We will install an agent in every home in America (forget logistics, let's just say they have the manpower). Would you be okay with being monitered 24/7 by someone you don't know? Would that be too far? I mean, hey, "Why is it OK for the terrorists to roam free when we could easily counter them with surveillance techniques?"

If that would be too far, then ask yourself, between PRISM and that, whre is the line drawn? Do you even know at what point it would be too much? When would **you** personally stand up and say "Alright, Government, that is enough!". Seriously, I would like to know, because at any point with stuff they can do, we could say "Whelp, its for our safety", so when does it become too much? 

I say at this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811113703.0" user="immunofort" delta="False">
    <text>If you can't see why it's not loaded, you're an idiot and it's not even worth arguing with you about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811361178.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>Classic. You should get an actual opinion sometime, instead of hiding behind some fake wall of self-righteousness. At least I can articulate mine. And since when were we arguing? I thought we were discussing. I guess people like you don't know the difference, and you think everyone with a different opinion is wrong and must either be pounded into submission and beaten or waved away. God forbid you say "this is why I disagree with you" without calling me an idiot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811398621.0" user="immunofort" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not pretending to be self-righteous. You are actually in fact an idiot because you cannot comprehend why your question was loaded. Go look up what a loaded question is. If you can come back to me with a response that actually acknowledges why your question was loaded then I'll be happy to have a discussion, but your loaded question just indicates that you're unable to have a neutral, unbiased discussion.

Why should I continue to discuss anything with you if you can't adhere to basic logic and etiquette when it comes to discussing matters? Why should I adhere to etiquette when you can't either? 

I could have explained why it's loaded, but it's so fucking painfully obvious why it's loaded. I literally googled "loaded question", I didn't even have to click on the first link, it's fully explained in just the preview.

&amp;gt;A loaded question or complex question fallacy is a question which contains a controversial or unjustified assumption</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808943391.0" user="immunofort" delta="False">
    <text>A few problems with that view.

It makes you susceptible to blackmail yes, but is blackmail even likely to occur in the first place? You have to establish that it is likely that they will at some point or will need to.  I suppose I can't prove that the government doesn't, but that probably isn't even required. Blackmail is illegal. If the government is willing to use personal information as leverage as part of an illegal action, they could get leverage on you without PRISM by other methods, eg threaten your family.

If I'm the government, and I want to control you, and I'm willing to do illegal things as a means to an end, then I have far more nefarious tools at my disposal rather than some phone calls and internet activity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26809244856.0" user="AaronEricaSpencerMit" delta="False">
    <text>Blackmailing is way easier than torturing, killing or similar.
Just take a look at history: DDR and the Stasi, if that means something to you. It has happened before but without the superior technology of today. I don't want it to happen again.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
