<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="92871272.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jajxk/i_dont_think_the_nsa_spying_on_us_is_such_a_big/">
    <title>I don't think the NSA spying on us is such a big deal. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jstavy</original_poster>
    <original_post>Here is my reasoning: growing up parallel to the development of the internet my parents always warned me that anything you put into a computer someone out there can see. It is permanent. So I have always assumed there is always someone watching. That assumption at the end of the day hasn't really changed what I put on the internet because everything is strictly my opinion and I don't care what others think of it.

As far as the recording of phone conversations and storing of email, that is just a case of national security. these things need to be saved in case someone is planning a terrorist attack on our nation IMO.	

I am just a normal citizen like many of you, but my opinion differs on this subject matter and I want to understand what the big fuss about it is. It has always just been a common knowledge and understanding for me that I am being watched.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26807897140.0" user="Amarkov" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;As far as the recording of phone conversations and storing of email, that is just a case of national security. these things need to be saved in case someone is planning a terrorist attack on our nation IMO.

Why? If someone is planning a terrorist attack on our nation, how will it help that the NSA has records of all the times that I've called my mom?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807902661.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Every conversation is a potential discussion of terrorist attacks... The ones where you call your mom I would assume the government would filter through and deem 0 risk and set aside. I don't know how that process works but I don't think they would be necessarily listening to those conversations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807906058.0" user="Amarkov" delta="False">
    <text>A decade ago, everyone assumed that the government would filter out those conversations *before* collecting data. So I'm not sure why you're so willing to trust that this is the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807913957.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Well I mean terrorists have to be smart if they want a successful attack especially in this age of espionage. Using code words and such. They have to gather sufficient evidence... Im not too educated on the topic, but I just don't see why it's a big deal if they store phone calls of me calling MY Mom. They can listen all they want about me talking to my mom about going to the movies, work, the girl I saw at the store or what not. Doesn't bother me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808235219.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>Would you approve of repealing the 4th amendment? Most people would be safer if the police could search whoever they wanted without needing a search warrant, and if you don't have anything to hide, it doesn't really matter, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807925772.0" user="grottohopper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't know how that process works but I don't think they would be necessarily listening to those conversations.

And so you just assume they're using this enormous power appropriately? Have you not realized the potential for abuse that his has, and that they have zero oversight?

You say now that you don't care if they know what you said to your mom, but what if they retroactively decide that something, anything you said was "suspicious," and target you for investigation, which *happens* to interfere with your plans to, say, run for office in your city on a particular political platform? 

What if you are involved in a protest effort in the future over a real issue that you care about, and suddenly someone has access to *highly* embarrassing recordings of your phone calls to a lover?

The point is that privacy matters, if not to you personally then to someone else. People have a right to communicate with one another without being recorded by an unrelated third party, and even if you don't care about having your information hoarded that is no reason to expect everyone else to roll over and let government monitor every aspect of our communications. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807938028.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Mission accomplished. You changed my view. I didn't think of it like that. I'm still not irate about the NSA like many are, but if there was a vote or something I would vote against it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807954727.0" user="grottohopper" delta="False">
    <text>from sidebar

&amp;gt; Award a delta if a comment has changed your view in any way. You must include an explanation for why you are awarding it. [More](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_4)

Thanks though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808020002.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>Don't change your view because of that.

The idea that something **has the potential** to be abused, therefore, should not be used, is completely ridiculous.

You can argue the cure for cancer has the potential to be abused by pharmaceutical companies, so lets stop that too.

You can argue that every single tool mankind ever invented has the potential to be abused by someone **intentionally** use it inappropriately.

There needs to be a debate on the privacy of digital space.  Technically, none of where this data is store is owned by you, physically.  Unlike a letter, which is physically your property.  Just like NSA doesn't have access to your laptop's storage, which is **your** property.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808760621.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>I think most people would say this system has the **high likelihood** to be abused, not just the potential.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808766584.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>Based on what?  Who are these people?  

"people" have very little information to make this ridiculous assessment.

There is no logic there to conclude a "high likelihood".   

For some strange reason, these people at NSA, these people who turn down six figure salaries at private firms to serve their country, people who passes the most thorough background check, people who are honorable and patriots by any standard of definition of the word.   These people, are the ones you deem has a "high likelihood" to abuse a program that is strictly monitored and enforced.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808786285.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Based on what? Who are these people? 

"People" being the ones who are against this system being in place. Everyone speaking out against it and how it is a violation of our rights, and is wrong, are the ones saying it will likely be abused.

&amp;gt; There is no logic there to conclude a "high likelihood". 

Of course there is. Are you saying that a government that has absolute and total control over its citizens is something that is not likely to be corrupted at some point in the future?

&amp;gt; For some strange reason, these people at NSA, these people who turn down six figure salaries at private firms to serve their country

Who are you even talking about? I don't see this conversation going very far if you think everyone that works at the NSA are doing so instead of 6 figure salaries because they feel patriotic.

&amp;gt; people who passes the most thorough background check

They do background checks, yes, but this has not stopped corruption before, unless you are saying that nobody has ever sold information for profit, for example.

&amp;gt; people who are honorable and patriots by any standard of definition of the word.

Again, who are you talking about? "Honorable" and "patriot" have absolutely no place in the system that earns people a Top Secret security clearance. As long as you have no serious criminal background, foreign ties, or financial/drug related issues, it isn't terribly hard to get one.

**However**, this is irrelevant to my point anyways, because I am not talking about the people at the NSA that handle the gathering of information at the ground level. I am talking about people in power that have access to it.

Take a few minutes and really ask yourself why you are so blindly okay with letting our government create a system around us where they have the power to coerce and manipulate nearly anyone they want by leaking personal information. And I don't mean in a month, or even a year from now.

Letting the government set up a system that can very easily be used to exploit and control the population, to such an extent that there is no return from it, and doing it in secret, is heinous. It's like just because this is the United States, people think nothing bad can happen, as if our country is too big to fail. 

&amp;gt; These people, are the ones you deem has a "high likelihood" to abuse a program that is strictly monitored and enforced.

Strictly monitored and enforced? How? By whom? Where did you get that from?

Absolute power corrupts absolutely. And having complete access to vast quantities of information about any particular person is absolute power, believe that. And for what? To stop "terrorism"? How many deaths have occured in the US because of "Terrorism" in the last 20 years? A few thousand? And a vast majority in one day, 9/11. Do you know how many people have died in the US due to drunk driving in the last 20 years? About 250,000. Just to give an example of how small a threat terrorism is. Yes, we had a horrible attack in 2001, and it was very shocking and public, and that is exactly the point, to get everyone horrified and panicking. Letting our government use (STILL!) the threat of terrorism to build an informational prison around us, while you call them patriots, is depressing. 

I say that the system in place is far more likely to be used for harm than good. I say that the pros are FAR outweighed by the cons. Even if everyone in the government and all the agencies have a good hold of this system now, that does not mean that whoever is running things in 10 or 15 or 20 years will, and by then, it will be far too late to do anything about it.

Am I saying this will definetely happen at some point? No. I am curious why you think it is far more likely that it will not happen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808800356.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>Because you obviously has no idea on what you are talking about.  This is the entire problem with this debate.  People who knows how stupid these arguments are can't speak up.  So all that is left is people on the outside, armed with **zero** knowledge, arguing about something they know nothing about.

Is it shocking that at every level of the government, those who knows supports it, those who doesn't oppose it.  Every member of the intel committee, President, Speaker of the H, everyone who gets to see behind the curtains speak about it in a rational manner and ask people not to over-react.  And then there is everyone else who spills non-sense based on fear of something they don't know.

Which, while it is a reasonable reaction when someone is faced with something they don't know or understand.  People need to educate themselves before they speak.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808822826.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>Eh, I guess we'll disagree. I tried to make several talking points for discussion, but all you want to do is say "you don't know what you're talking about". You don't know me, but you sure presume to, so believe whatever you want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808828129.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>It is just obvious that based on the points you make that you don't know how it works.  Which is not your fault.  I apologize for being annoyed.  I inappropriately took out my frustration on you.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808832079.0" user="Nrksbullet" delta="False">
    <text>Well I stated why I think what I do. You should do the same, it's dismissive to just say "you don't know how it works". And how what works? How governments can become oppressive and corrupt over time given enough power? It's happened so many times in the past. I just think it's silly that you are defending a government that I said could exist 20 years from now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808844210.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>You are right.   I have nothing to add.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808375625.0" user="anotherDocObVious" delta="False">
    <text>Another POV was touched upon in the movie Enemy of the state - pure chance that an innocent bystander was a witness to a political murder - and that fellow was targeted and killed because some very powerful people were connected. Similarly, in the movie Sniper, and of course the Jason Bourne movies. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808533198.0" user="jstavy" delta="False">
    <text>Δ This post changed my view. My it allowed me to look at the issue in a different perspective and even though it may not effect me much now it could hold me back from accomplishing certain goals I may/may not set for myself in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808533607.0" user="grottohopper" delta="False">
    <text>:) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807933105.0" user="DFP_" delta="False">
    <text>Oversight is hugely important when it comes to one's private data though, and pretty bad things can be done under the guise of promoting national security such as the [blackmailing](http://www.cnn.com/2008/US/03/31/mlk.fbi.conspiracy/) of Martin Luther King Jr. during the red scare.  The lack of oversight is what many of us are alarmed about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26808233508.0" user="sarcasmandsocialism" delta="False">
    <text>Given what we know about FBI activities over the last century, your assumption is very likely wrong.  It is also morally wrong that we have to make that assumption and that we don't know that there is a system in place that protects the privacy of citizens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26807926492.0" user="i_noticed_you" delta="False">
    <text>They don't, "listening" to your calls. "Listening" consist of a database that that picked up on key words. They don't have the time or manpower to listen to your phone calls. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
