<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26811342697.0" user="yiman" delta="False">
    <text>TBS:  The Total war series? Crusader Kings??????? Total ground breaking in genre.   

RTS:  Company of Heroes?  Dawn of War?  Cover based RTS?  Again, the Total War series.   

FPS:  Bioshock2?  Demonstrating that FPS can have a story that matters.  Borderlands?  Combining genre, basically creating a new hybrid FPS/RPS lootfest genre.

MMORPG:  Hello guildwars 2?????  No MMO will be the same after GW2.   Planetside 2?????? 

This is not evening accounting how indie gaming/mods is making PC gaming more revolutionary then ever.

What rock have you been living under?  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
