<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26811166637.0" user="MdxBhmt" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument sounds quite 'we didn't develop new genres of gamming, so we didn't evolve'

Think of literature. It's not developing new genres that is evolution, but How You Do It™

Frankly, if you put a modern game side by side a 2000 game, you'll fell the difference in polishing. They are, in most cases, more fluid, comfortable to play, streamlined. 

FPS got ridden of the health bar. This, hated by hardcore gamers, is an incredible tool for level designers. Designers are free to create multiple sequences of intensive combats. They don't have to worry about the player health management. It is also forgiving on the players mistakes. No more reset-the-level-because-I-lost-too-much-hp.

L4D has health, but has this concept for ammo. In case a player waste too many bullets in despair, the pistol has infinite ammo. The player is not a useless piece of digital meat if he does a mistake.

See, those tools (unlimited ammo, health regen) are not 'new', but we are now understanding better their implications in design. Designers can concentrate more on what they want the player to feel.

We also evolved on more informative UI's, how to teach new players, story telling mechanics.

Take the discovery of achievements for example. It's a wonderful guiding tool. If I got an achievement I must be doing something right, no? This help the player discover new things, or telling him that he is indeed progressing in the game, without being invasive (it's a meta tool)

One of the major problems is that not even half players reach the end of a game. [I'm serious.](http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/4171/staying_power_rethinking_feedback_.php) Game design is evolving around to fix this.

Maybe they get stuck, or demotivated,  and we are making tools to make you play that game.

Look at Braid master level design. The mixing of story telling by level design, game mechanics and graphics. The way it teaches you how to manipulate time, and how it hints puzzle solving.

Bastion, and a dynamic narrator and pleasant gameplay.

Amnesia, revamped survival horror with a combatless hero, giving you chills with terrific level+story design.

TF2, created an addicting formula for the old FPS team game. It's been 6 years and the player base never stopped increasing.

Metal gear, and how the mechanics evolved with the series.

Or take Cs 1.6 and compare to CS:GO. I bet you can quickly feel what a decade had brought to game design.

Darn I bet this can go forever if I search for more examples.

W3 and SC2 are two different beast. How it teaches the game metas (purpose of a unit, strategies), better interfaces, how the story telling is interwinded with game mechanics (you can see the difference on SC2  WOL against SC2 HOTS), SC2  is much more polished.

I can't talk about MMORPS, but MOBA games came from there. Dota2, HoN, LoL, they by themselves are evolving the genre in different ways. Better item/heroes balancing, game pacing...

__

Tl;Dr: We are evolving. Game designers are working on making games more entertaining, more involving, more polished, less stressful, less turn-down.

___

A very good series to learn about game design is [extra credit](http://www.penny-arcade.com/patv/show/extra-credits). I've not seen them all but they are very informative.

BTW, I Used We a lot, but by no means i'm a game designer.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
