<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810549820.0" user="James_dude" delta="False">
    <text>We had a milestone in gaming history in 2009 with Minecraft.

Minecraft was a revolution because it was completely the opposite to everything the game industry was driving towards at the time, but also extremely popular.

The direction of gaming before minecraft was studios increasing their staff and budgets and trying to pump out the next interactive film. Heavy graphics with linear objective based gameplay.

With minecraft people realised the real power of gameplay over graphics. It also gave the indie gaming industry a gigantic boost which lead to many exciting creative games, as well as a framework which made developing and selling indie games easier.

Minecraft's 'do what you like' approach was almost completely new. It had always been assumed that you had to push players to do stuff or they would get bored and quit. Now designers had evidence that given the right environment players would feel quite at ease without needing pressure.

So it's my belief that the innovation is happening, and I believe it will continue to happen for many years to come. Minecraft is just the most dramatic example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811508798.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>This.

Also Dwarf Fortress. No fancy graphics but very strong gameplay.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
