<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810606424.0" user="ZirunK6AUrg" delta="False">
    <text>There aren't as many ground-breaking games simply because much of the ground has been broken. You can't exactly re-break already-broken ground. The world can't have another System Shock 2 or Heroes 3 or Master of Orion because those have already been made.

In terms of your examples, H5 is a more fleshed-out H3. Units have more traits and abilities, heroes have more abilities, races have greater distinction. Obviously there won't be anything ground-breaking in a subsequent entry in a franchise essentially deemed perfect at H3.

Warcraft has heroes and items in standard play, for one. Neutral monsters and buildings, for two.

Can't comment on FPS, as I rarely play any of those.

I don't see why you bring up WoW. Are you expecting a game to innovate while it's both running and extremely successful? Are you expecting a genre-defining game to *not* have a billion clones of it pop up? What about The Secret World? Dungeons &amp;amp; Dragons Online? Defiance? Dungeon Fighter Online? Star Wars: The Old Republic? Whether or not they're good or successful, are they not at least significantly different from WoW, in some ways better?

I think the problem you're seeing is that you see the first airplane built and expect a space ship within the year. Logical extension, right? Being able to fly leads to being able to fly in space, doesn't it? But you wouldn't expect the Wright brothers to build a space ship. Perhaps they'd improve on their airplane iteratively, but a space ship is a completely different beast that requires much different things, and they'd never be able to build one out of their airplane.

And yes, as has been mentioned, looking to AAA developers for innovation is looking in the wrong place. Most modern AAA game budgets are too high to risk on a new thing when a new iteration of something known is guaranteed to sell well.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
