<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810723596.0" user="afranius" delta="False">
    <text>You're just getting older. People were saying the same thing 15 years ago. If you started playing video games when you were younger, everything seemed new and exciting, and now the familiar patterns are more obvious. There is still something new every few years (as others have pointed out), it just doesn't seem as new to you as Quake 3 did back in the day (which by the way was exceedingly derivative...).

The same thing applies to movies, literature, music, etc.

As for people pining for the "good old days" and complaining about how nothing good is made today, that's the textbook definition of survivor bias.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
