<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810802481.0" user="jimethn" delta="False">
    <text>Well, within your examples you're correct, but that's because you're picking specific genres. When you take that abstract a view everything is bound to look the same. The original Donkey Kong and Super Mario World 3 are both platformers, but the gameplay is completely different and the latter is certainly far more advanced than the former. The same goes for Mario 64 vs Mario Galaxy vs Mirror's Edge. But you're right, in all 3 cases you jump your guy around seeking objectives and avoiding obstacles. Similarly, it's no surprise that two adjacent generations of FPS or RTS don't show much differentiation.

Now if you compare the environmental destruction and squad based tactics of a game like BFBC2 with something like Counter Strike 1.6, you'll see they're pretty different. But they're both FPS with a physics engine, to be sure, if that's all you're looking at.

Games have always been a slow steady evolution and the reason things seemed so ground-breaking around the turn of the century is because that's when 3d games were first really coming into vogue. Everyone was exploring the new media and it was a very exciting time. Remember Quest 64? It was a terrible game by all metrics but personally I loved it because it was *an RPG in THREE DEE*! Now 3d has been around awhile and it's starting to settle down the same way 2d did, and I think that's what you're sensing.

That said, there's still plenty of exciting new games to play out there. When we were young we would always grab the latest exciting-looking game at Blockbuster or Game Stop, and we had our friends playing games to get us excited about things. We would never think things like "oh Pokemon Yellow is just like the first one" we were just exited to play the new games. Really I think it's the curse of the refined palate more than anything: Now that we have really gotten intimate with the exquisite vintage, we're just not that interested in the 5 buck chug.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
