<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810508129.0" user="thefalseidol" delta="False">
    <text>Your genre specifications are a bit odd, but I imagine we're talking about games that are likely not to port to console.

I'm not really sure why HOMM3 is the standard of excelence you're using, but fine, I accept it. I think Civ5, for one, is a vastly greater game, any number of Paradox games, and Crusader Kings specifically if you're looking for a game that innovates, even within Paradox. The new XCOM is a turn based strategy RPG, with turn based city building and research between turn based missions.

I'm not sure why you're surprised Warcraft and Starcraft are similar, but I think your premise is a bit skewed. Firstly, WC3 ABSOLUTELY changed the RTS world, while SC2 was specifically made to translate from SC as a way of maintaining its eSport base.  If you want to look at an RTS that has evolved, look at Rise of Nations, as an RTS with TBS elements, or Dawn of War.  

I think your abstraction of FPS is a bit unfair, how many games can be boiled down to just running and jumping? And those elements can create wildly different games, just look at how variable the games running on the Unreal engine are.

None of the games you're comparing are pinnacles of their genre, you're just comparing games to their predecessors and noting that they share core mechanics. Of course they do, otherwise, it wouldn't be called Heroes of Might and Magic 5, it would be the first game in a new series. I'm sorry you don't think they're different enough but that hardly diminishes the advances others have made.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
