<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810484151.0" user="1ibertyordeath" delta="False">
    <text>I think we have had some serious gameplay development in terms of stealth-based games, and big open ended non-linear rpg games due to the incredible developments in graphics and game engines. 

* Assassin's Creed was pretty groundbreaking at the time.
* Deus Ex Human Revolution was a new twist, in my opinion.
* Call of Duty 4 created a casual pick up and play FPS.
* League of Legends and other "MOBA" games are pretty fun.
* 3D has added another dimension to gaming, and will keep being built on.
* Skyrim, Oblivion, and Fallout have changed the game in terms of huge rpg games.
* The Division, which is coming out at the end of this year, appears to be a mix between a survival game, an mmorpg, and an FPS.
* Grand Theft Auto is a pretty awesome.
* Need for Speed and Midnight Club, pushed the racing games to a new level.
* Gran Turismo, on the PS3, pushed realism in racing to a new level.


There are a ton of other games also, that haven't been completely original, but have really pushed the envelope. There has been so much already developed that it can be hard to come up with something that has been completely original, but I definitely think gameplay is evolving. Graphics and better engines are enabling new and more advanced features in games that can totally evolve certain genres. 

I don't think there has been that many "groundbreaking games", but to say that it is not evolving is being a little harsh on developers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810494951.0" user="L34der" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for mentioning Assassin's Creed and the stealth genre. As i mentioned however ''if you played wc3 on Bnet''. Remember a custom map called DOTA? I don't care if i get showered with downvotes but LoL is imo a copy of DOTA with better graphics. Just goes to show how WC3's map editor is a bigger influence than most games on their own.

RPG's sure have pushed the envelope i'll grant you that but how have racing games changed significantly since NFS Underground? I'm genuinely curious.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810554918.0" user="HighPriestofShiloh" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Remember a custom map called DOTA? I don't care if i get showered with downvotes but LoL is imo a copy of DOTA with better graphics. 

LoL was meant to be a copy of DOTA.   DOTA was first released in 2005.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810604487.0" user="1ibertyordeath" delta="False">
    <text>Need for speed underground is in this decade, and DOTA, according to /u/HighPriestofShiloh was released in 05. 

Racing games haven't changed very much on the PC, mainly due to a lack of selection on PC, but they have changed on console. I recently played Gran Turismo 5 on PS3 and I found it to be stunningly awesome and superbly realistic, which is pretty groundbreaking when compared to NFS. 

The fact of the matter is, is that there are going to be fewer and fewer original ideas for games because a lot of that ground has already been broken. What we are doing now, is developing on these basic ideas and branching them off into other sub genres and adding new ideas to them.  Unreal Tournament and Call of Duty 4 are in the same genre, but they are almost entirely different games, just as Need For Speed is entirely different from Gran Turismo 5. 

The new groundbreakers are going to be games that can blend genres together and create a game that can appeal to a mass number of people. I'll bring up "The Division" again, in that it, from what I understand, is going to be an MMORPG, survival, and FPS combination. Games like this, and I think we will see more of them on these next gen consoles and PCs, will combine online play with multiple genres to deliver a new experience. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811834268.0" user="NeutralParty" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Remember a custom map called DOTA?

Valve certainly does considering they've made DOTA2 as a standalone game.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
