<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93120451.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jfw77/pc_gameplay_hasnt_really_evolved_in_any/">
    <title>PC gameplay hasn't really evolved in any significant way for a decade. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>L34der</original_poster>
    <original_post>Aside from graphics i can't think of a game that has broken as much ground as games did around the dawn of the millennia.

TBS: Heroes V may have had 3d graphics but the gameplay mechanics are the exact same as in H3 with only minor changes such as heroes taking a minor role on combat. If anything the graphics just slow down and distract.

RTS: Quick! Point out a fundamental difference between Warcraft 3 and Starcraft 2! They both have 3d graphics, same types of units and highly customized map editors. Difference is that there are 8 years between those games. If you were playing custom games in wc3 on Bnet you definately remember the crazy diversity the game offered.

1PS: Quake 3 had special items, multiplayer, different weapons, different missiles, armor and 3d. Physics engine? The characters jump up and fall down. If they fall down hard on the ground they take damage. If they fall in the water they don't. There's your physics engine. Portal is something of a challenger but it lacks multiplayer which imo makes it a bit of a novelty for people looking for a new PC gaming experience while only having one mission that you can't share with anyone.

MMORPG: World of Warcraft....has been going on now for 1 year short of a decade and there's no end in sight so i count it also.

So am i missing something or have they simply stopped making groundbreaking games?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26810484820.0" user="Overgoats" delta="False">
    <text>AAA studios are very risk-averse.  They don't create art, they create content as a commodity.  Think of them as a TV production house, making yet another episode of... *(slight pause while I look up current TV series)* Breaking Bad.  They're not trying to break ground here, they're trying to tell you the same story they've told you every week, 13 weeks out of the year, for decades.

They're not doing this because they're *uncreative*.  They're doing it because they like money, and lots of people will pay money for that commodity.

If you want to see actual gaming innovation, look at what independent developers like [The Chinese Room](http://thechineseroom.co.uk/) and [Capybara](http://www.capybaragames.com/) are doing.  These games aren't the polished, glitzy, lens-flare-a-riffic adrenaline-fests that Medal of Duty: Modern Ops tries so hard to be, but they explore genuinely new ideas in both narrative and interaction.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810509793.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly.

The AAA-industry is like hollywood. They make a giant investment in a game, hundreds of millions even and for that they will always be catering to the biggest target audience possible. As long as they have this *problem* , meaning that they'll keep producing this huge projects with a gigantic scope then the AAA-market won't see any real innovation in terms of creativity.

 If you really want groundbreakingly innovative games you can always go to the indie-scene. It might not be polished or high quality but you get really unique experiences and believe me, you will find something genuinly unique.

The argument that there were no breakthroughs in the gaming industry in the past 10 years on the pc is just wrong. Crowdfunding has been a huge influence and there are now more developer studios than ever. It's just that the indies don't have the budget to put a new trailer for their game on a cable tv channel during the prime time. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810647612.0" user="epursimuove" delta="False">
    <text>You're aware that Breaking Bad is often considered to be one of the greatest TV series of all time, right? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810650268.0" user="Overgoats" delta="False">
    <text>Medal of Duty gets excellent reviews and sells many copies.

But no.  I watch very little television, and only know of Breaking Bad because of the many references to it on Reddit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811068913.0" user="MalignantMouse" delta="False">
    <text>Well, unlike many 'production houses', the creators of Breaking Bad (Vince Gillian and AMC) had a specific arc in mind, and are concluding the show after this upcoming season, despite its continuing popularity. It'd easy get audiences for further seasons, but the creators are telling a specific story, not dragging it out to make a buck. Your point is well taken for shows in general (at least in the US; the UK is much better about this), but Breaking Bad is a pretty bad example of what you're looking to illustrate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26810764372.0" user="Mrgoodwil" delta="False">
    <text>I will never trust a statement like that unless it's subject has been around for about a decade. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26811832287.0" user="NeutralParty" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah. People were shitting their pants over Twin Peaks at the time, but now you'd have a hard time getting a majority to call it the best ever. (Not that it's hated by most people or anything.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26812196294.0" user="Mrgoodwil" delta="False">
    <text>Cult classic status is better than what I expect out of Bioshock: Infinite, but maybe it'll have it fans.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
