<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93665976.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jrl4o/street_smart_and_book_smart_are_two_different/">
    <title>Street Smart and Book Smart are two different types of intelligence. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>frog_dog_outlaw</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the term "smart" I am referring to the combination of *knowledge - knowing something with familiarity gained through experience* and *intelligence - the ability to apply why you have learned*. (my own interpretations of the definitions) To me book smart refers to academic achievements and success or how well you did in school etc. Street smart is almost instinctive; its more than just common sense, it is being able to adapt and change with your environment. I am not saying you can't have both, but they are two different measures of intellect. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26816111446.0" user="autobahnaroo" delta="False">
    <text>There is no such thing as common sense. I find it to be insulting to our ancestors who built up the knowledge and passed it down to the next generation, who confirmed its truth and value and continued its passage.

You are saying "smart" is the acquisition of knowledge. "Street smarts" is the acquisition of knowledge of the geographical area one lives in. Where to find this or that thing, how to get across the river, who to talk to for something, what's the fastest way to get somewhere... this is all knowledge built up by being outside, in the streets, and participating in society at large, and information from parents and siblings. It is exemplified in application (people generally won't talk about the fastest way to get somewhere if they aren't going there like they would historical facts or whatnot), but based on acquired information nonetheless.

Books are just a different medium for information that has been acquired by people before us. In order to access that medium, one must be taught how to read, how to disseminate written information, how to take notes, and ultimately how to use information that is largely mentally accumulated (instead of visually and actively) and act upon the world at large. 

Take chemistry for example - and maybe use Breaking Bad as an example. The 'street smarts' meth dealers gained their knowledge through trial and error and by stealing bits of information from others who also carried out trial and error. Book smarts was cleaner - they knew everything to do and how to do it, but they learned the process in books. But they are still doing the same things.

They're not different 'types' of intelligence, they're simply information acquired in different ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816354197.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Social intelligence and conventional intelligence. Conventional intelligence is your ability to acquire knowledge and skills, while social intelligence is your ability to understand and navigate complex social requirements. It's very clear that you can be very 'book smart', and not have the slightest clue how to ask a girl out on a date. This is also true in reverse.

Conventional intelligence is what we teach in the classroom, while social intelligence is what you learn from interacting with other people. These are both valuable skills in life, but they are completely different. For example, you generally aren't going to be very socially intelligent if have a poor capacity for empathy. It's the idea of social intelligence that people allude to when they talk about 'street smarts.'

Lastly, there's wisdom, and that's really closest to common sense. "Knowledge is knowing that a tomato is a fruit while Wisdom is not putting it in a fruit salad." The statement is trite, but there's a lot of truth to it. Knowledge without context of how to interpret and use it isn't very useful, and it's this idea that tends to be captured in wisdom.

Lastly, "common sense" is a phrasing used to describe a particular thing. Knowledge that's widely known, and easily logically consistent. Looking both ways before crossing the street is "common sense", because once you hear the rule, you go 'of course that makes sense!'</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816850696.0" user="Homericus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Conventional intelligence is your ability to acquire knowledge and skills, while social intelligence is your ability to understand and navigate complex social requirements. It's very clear that you can be very 'book smart', and not have the slightest clue how to ask a girl out on a date. 

This makes the assumption that you can't learn how to ask a girl out on a date from a book, which doesn't seem to be true. Certainly you need to go out and practice, but that is just as true about any practical skill (say, doing laboratory Chemistry) and so it still doesn't seem like "Social Intelligence" is a magic thing that cannot be gained from books.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817003967.0" user="Aoreias" delta="False">
    <text>Just because you can learn both skills from books (and for social intelligence this is a bit of a stretch) doesn't mean that they aren't different types of intelligence though.

If they were the same type of intelligence, it would stand to reason that the better someone is at picking up math skills, reading comprehension, etc. then the better they are at learning social skills and social communication. I think most people's personal experience shows that there isn't a strong correlation between aptitude at traditional school subjects, and sociability.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817013152.0" user="Homericus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think most people's personal experience shows that there isn't a strong correlation between aptitude at traditional school subjects, and sociability.

And I would say that for many people this is due to them not caring as much about sociability, and thinking that school subjects are more important. 

Another possibility is that they haven't considered that social skills can be learned much like traditional skills (since many people, like yourself, say so), and so they don't look into it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816384014.0" user="frog_dog_outlaw" delta="False">
    <text>How would you classify the information you acquire if not as 
&amp;gt;different 'types' of intelligence

**edit for formatting*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816411925.0" user="Credulous7" delta="False">
    <text>Pardon me, but I'm not even sure what you mean by "different types"? This could mean a lot of things, depending on how you classify intelligence. For example, if you classified "type" of intelligence as the method it is acquired, "book" smarts are acquired by reading books, and "street" smarts are acquired by talking to people, then yes, they would be different "types". So what is your definition of "type"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816414935.0" user="autobahnaroo" delta="False">
    <text>

I guess that would go against what I was saying, but I really don't think that the way we get information accounts for the differences in intelligence. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816465406.0" user="frog_dog_outlaw" delta="False">
    <text>*I kind of jumped around with my ideas for a bit so bear with me*

That link. That is something I agree with. I want to say that each of those types of intelligence are different because you learn them differently, they require different tools to learn and/or practice, they incorporate different parts of your brain, etc., but it seems to really boil down to ones ability to interpret information and apply it. 

However, some people have more of certain types of intelligence than others. Upon further reading I am seeing that "street smart" may not be clarified as a specific intelligence, but a skill-set derived from several types of intelligence. For example: you could have very poor people skills to the point of uncomfortable social anxiety due to a lack in Interpersonal Intelligence and Linguistic Intelligence vs. being able to play a variety of instruments at a high level would demonstrate a strong Musical Intelligence with a side of Bodily-Kinesthetic Intelligence. 

I believe the skill-set required for what I am referring to as "street smart" is a combination of several types of intelligence, as is "book smart." It is just using that intelligence with a different purpose. I would say "street smart" is a lot of Interpersonal Intelligence, Naturalist Intelligence, and Linguistic Intelligence but strongly adapted, based on what they've learned from their environment, to be utilized in their environment . I would say "book smart" is Logical-Mathematical Intelligence, but with a dash of Spatial Intelligence and Linguistic Intelligence. 

So... I guess this means you won</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816471005.0" user="autobahnaroo" delta="False">
    <text>A delta would be nice :) it's not winning or losing, it's just having your V a little bit C'd!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26816484847.0" user="frog_dog_outlaw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;amp;#8710; This guy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817538258.0" user="Jazz-Cigarettes" delta="False">
    <text>Confirmed: one delta awarded to /u/autobahnaroo.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
