<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93665976.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jrl4o/street_smart_and_book_smart_are_two_different/">
    <title>Street Smart and Book Smart are two different types of intelligence. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>frog_dog_outlaw</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the term "smart" I am referring to the combination of *knowledge - knowing something with familiarity gained through experience* and *intelligence - the ability to apply why you have learned*. (my own interpretations of the definitions) To me book smart refers to academic achievements and success or how well you did in school etc. Street smart is almost instinctive; its more than just common sense, it is being able to adapt and change with your environment. I am not saying you can't have both, but they are two different measures of intellect. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26816694531.0" user="jukaye" delta="False">
    <text>Street smarts is just as much as "knowing something with familiarity gained through experience and intelligence" as book smarts. Maybe for some people, dating is sort of an organic thing where you just dive into it and let it grow whereas studying for economics is something you go to the library, grab a book, and start reading.

But then you fail your econ test and failed your first date. you reread your economics homework and materials and try to study more. you reevaluate your last date and see what offends the girl. you figure out what you need to do in order to do better the next time. So the second exam comes around, the next date is later that night. This time you studied for the exam, you came prepared. you left feeling confident and you go home to get ready for your date. Time for that date, this time you go in well dressed, maybe bring a little gift like chocolates or something, you remind yourself not to ask conflict enticing questions like "what do you think of Israel and Palestina" and choose conversation topics like "what do you do" and "where did you grow up" U relax yourself, you dont sweat at the dinner. She enjoys your company. Date's over. But she wants to have a second one next weekend cuz u seem like a cool guy.

The weekend comes along, the econ test you did a couple days ago got an A cuz you came prepared. the girl you're seeing tonight ended up wanting the D, so you banged her.

At the end of the day, you did the same thing to tackle two different subjects: you identify the problem, implement actions to fix the problem, and get results. 

They're two different subjects, granted. but trying to distinguish book smart vs street smart is unfair because it's more like saying "hey chemistry smart is different than physics smart" or "maths smart is different than stats smart" they're just different subjects to study and people just have a difference of specialization. A high school jock that fails miserably in academics is good in social skills because subconciously he'd been practicing his social skills by learning how to talk to different kinds of people while the nerd in the computer lab neglects that aspect. 

And lastly "street smart is almost instinctive..." almost all disciplines of study has some level of instinct connected to it, but there are just as much written material you can read up to increase your 'street smart' knowledge. there's literally a subreddit for it called /r/socialskills so I believe that street smarts can be a learnt skill as much as any other branch of science.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
