<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93665976.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jrl4o/street_smart_and_book_smart_are_two_different/">
    <title>Street Smart and Book Smart are two different types of intelligence. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>frog_dog_outlaw</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the term "smart" I am referring to the combination of *knowledge - knowing something with familiarity gained through experience* and *intelligence - the ability to apply why you have learned*. (my own interpretations of the definitions) To me book smart refers to academic achievements and success or how well you did in school etc. Street smart is almost instinctive; its more than just common sense, it is being able to adapt and change with your environment. I am not saying you can't have both, but they are two different measures of intellect. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26816131407.0" user="muddled_thoughts" delta="False">
    <text>It's all about critical thinking, and acquiring a basic understanding of a subject matter. An experienced individual who is "street" smart may not necessarily understand a mathematical equation, and a person who is "book" smart may not necessarily know how to interact with a drug dealer, but when placed into a comfortable and familiar element, both individuals will proceed to remedy the issue in much the same fashion. They will analyze the situation for familiarity, draw upon precedent, and will ATTEMPT to solve the problem in the most familiar and simplest way possible.

The only real difference between "street" and "book" smart is knowledge of a base set of rules, i.e. experience. Even when you're talking about something like math, it's all the same. You learn the basics, and you build upon it through listening, watching, doing. At the higher levels, you look to solve seemingly impossible equations by applying what you know, what you've experienced, and you learn from your successes and failures.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
