<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93767103.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jtr5r/i_believe_humans_need_their_rights_limited_to/">
    <title>I believe humans need their rights limited to ensure survival of our species. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>The_Kennedy_Curse</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is something I've believed for a while. As a species, humans are self-destructive. We procreate too much and consume too many resources. I believe that something like China's one-child policy should be instituted in as many countries as possible to curb population growth. ~~I think currency should be done away with and governments should provide housing and necessities while the population works for the betterment and survival of humanity as a whole rather than for monetary compensation.~~

Am I crazy to think this is how the world should be? 

EDIT: Perhaps eliminating currency would be more problematic than keeping it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26817088543.0" user="phdre" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, it would be crazy to get rid of currency. Currency is a government backed medium of exchange. If you get rid of currency, people will go back to bartering with other things - cigarettes, gold and jewelry, anything that people value as a medium of exchange. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817092673.0" user="The_Kennedy_Curse" delta="False">
    <text>That's a good point, I hadn't considered that. What about the other aspects of the original post?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817100824.0" user="phdre" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, there are ways to provide people with incentives not to have more children. Increase taxes as individuals have more children. But a single child policy is also very bad for women. It is partly responsible for 'missing women' in Asia. [Source](http://www.econlib.org/library/Enc/bios/Sen.html). [Source 2](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Missing_women_of_Asia)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817202311.0" user="pirateneedsparrot" delta="False">
    <text>this is a myth that is very widespread. You may want to look at David [Graebers - Debt the first 5000 years](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Debt:_The_First_5000_Years). There never was a society that worked by changing goods. Its a totally made up myth and it is told to so many people. 

Tribal societys (for example nativ indians) lived very fine without money. And no, it was not i give you 2 buffalo for 10 bows or something. These society worked on mutual interest. Everybody would provide and everything would then be shared. That is how sane men do it. Backing up with currency is the **in**sane way to do. But we ware just so used to it.

Of course there are times where exchanging/trading is necessary, but this can not be the *basement* for a society. However, i cannot explain it properly, but do have a look at the book. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
