<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93767103.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jtr5r/i_believe_humans_need_their_rights_limited_to/">
    <title>I believe humans need their rights limited to ensure survival of our species. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>The_Kennedy_Curse</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is something I've believed for a while. As a species, humans are self-destructive. We procreate too much and consume too many resources. I believe that something like China's one-child policy should be instituted in as many countries as possible to curb population growth. ~~I think currency should be done away with and governments should provide housing and necessities while the population works for the betterment and survival of humanity as a whole rather than for monetary compensation.~~

Am I crazy to think this is how the world should be? 

EDIT: Perhaps eliminating currency would be more problematic than keeping it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26817110452.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;as a species humans are self-destructive.  

Some humans are, but if all of us actually were the world would be a very different place. Most people just try to live their lives and keep to themselves, tend their little patch of land, work their job, and take a vacation every once in a while. So we are not self-destructive as a species.  

&amp;gt;consume too many resources  

We also manufacture these resources, so would restricting birth rates really help if what we need is an educated work force and not just less of a work force?  

&amp;gt;humans need rights limited  

Absolutely not. What humans need is an environment to thrive in. We have to become mature from childhood on, and restricting access or freedoms does not help a person become mature; it helps them lose perspective.  
Everything people do, every idea and action, falls somewhere along the line between freedom and everything else. Safety is restricting, grace is restricting since we curtail movements to add more fluidity and thus we have to be more careful, and even engaging in freedom is restricting because there is no way for an single human being to experience something within the full weight of absolute freedom, since we have innate biases, wants, desires, needs, and capabilities.  
The last thing we need is a parent figure we don't understand as children, holding us back as we become older in ways we can't even fathom even after we've achieved enough self knowledge to recognize something restricting has happened.  
Look at China. Adults know they live in an oppressive state. There was a story lately, and I'm sorry but I don't have the link, where people were interviewing native Chinese people about Tiananmen square, and all the people interviewed said no they hadn't.  
Not because they hadn't though, they knew about resistance efforts in their own country.  
They just didn't want a visit from the government for saying they knew in public.  

&amp;gt;am I crazy  

You're not crazy. Since everything is a balance of freedom and something else, it's perfectly natural when facing an issue or scenario to fly to the opposite end of the spectrum involved, in this case freedom, and think of the biggest change you can think of to implement to disturb the surface of the waters and see if it helps.  
However, it doesn't. We need more educated, caring people. Not more restricted people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817418433.0" user="vierte_konto" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Some humans are, but if all of us actually were the world would be a very different place. Most people just try to live their lives and keep to themselves, tend their little patch of land, work their job, and take a vacation every once in a while. So we are not self-destructive as a species. 

The OP wasn't talking about a person being self-destructive as in suicide or what else. He was talking about the human species, which is undeniably self-destructive, but more importantly (from an ethical point of view) destructing most  ecosystems, species on this planet.

People just try to live their lives? By living in a huge house, heating it by burning hydrocarbons, driving SUVs tens of miles every day just to get to thier "job" (supossedly they are providing "value" to society). Not only that, but they change their car every 2 years, together with tons of electronics and other stuff, of course, being almost mind-controlled through advertising and similar propaganda. Wasted water is also unbelievable. The effect is tons of waste per capita, at a rate which is not sustainable, damaging the very environment which enables people to survive. The very rate of consumption and polution is thus leading to the destruction of the speicies, so yes, humans as a species are self destructing.

&amp;gt;We also manufacture these resources, so would restricting birth rates really help if what we need is an educated work force and not just less of a work force? 

No, we don't manufacture shit. We dig it out of the ground and in the process cutting rain-forests destroying ecosystems ...

&amp;gt; Absolutely not. What humans need is an environment to thrive in. We have to become mature from childhood on, and restricting access or freedoms does not help a person become mature; it helps them lose perspective.

I don't see how this is related. This very moment the rights of the vast majority of people on this planet are severely denied by a tiny majority leading major corporatocracies. Yet they don't even know that. A great environment for the development of a human being is much more likely to be available in the case of less consumption, being more aware of the world around them, with more contact from their parents and family. That's not what capitalism is encouraging. 

I realise I haven't been very clear, and besides extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence (my claims are not at all extraordinary, but they may seem so from certain limited points of view). Anyway I can only refer you to some works like Extreme Early Retirement (for a concise description of the modern society, although it takes a practical standpoint, not criticising the system, but rather finding workarounds through it).
And Noam Chomsky as well has some very bright observations in books like Understanding Power.

Most problems concerning this species are related to lack of rationality, which could only be solved through education, or teaching people about thinking. Sadly, I'm not aware of any real education on the face of this planet, that is not focused on memorating facts on narrow topics, rather than promoting thinking.

PS. Your solution with government housing and food is not really easy to implement, I think. But there are more beautiful solutions. Technology to automatically produce food for sustaing a local family is in existance. A robotised greenhouse, or similar things could work to effectively eliminate the need for people employed in this area.

PPS. You should read about basic income. It could be the biggest step forward since the Renaissance.

The bigger ethical problem is that a rather small portion of the population is causing the empoverishment of the rest, and causing the biggest distruction to the environment/other species. Now this statement requires some evidence, and I'm not in the position to provide it right now, but it exists in various scientifc papers. An example could be the fact that global warming will greatly affect (in 40-50 years) the availability of water in various places like Africa.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26817432293.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;undeniably self destructive  

Some people are, but not everyone is. Not everyone wants rainforest deforestation, but unless you serve in the Brazilian government there's little you can do today that isn't illegal.  

&amp;gt;try to live their lives?  

Again, not everyone wants to rely on fossil fuels, plenty of people would love to be able to heat their homes or drive their cars using renewable energy.  

&amp;gt;we don't manufacture  

Things aren't dug out of the ground fully formed. Every resource we have we have to process and then it becomes a manufactured good.  

&amp;gt;I don't see how this is related  

Freedom and giving people more restrictions are at opposite ends of the same spectrum. Acknowledging that we need educated members of the work force means admitting we need environments for maturing individuals to thrive.  

&amp;gt;I realize I haven't been very clear  

I don't think it's that, I just don't know why you're responding to me the way you have. I don't know what your goal is.  

&amp;gt;most problems solved by education  

Which was the point I made in my post.  

&amp;gt;can't think of any  

Critical thinking skills and leadership skills are valuable educational tools people could use, we just need to draft the legislation to implement the new curriculums we have to create for it. There are critical thinking classes in the UK, for instance.  

&amp;gt;Your solution with government housing and food  

I have to admit I have no idea what you're talking about here. Since I advocated not restricting people, or being more useful in our restrictions as per freedom vs everything else, I advocated education basically. I don't know how education 'isn't easy to implement regarding government housing and food.' I don't think this portion of your response was to me.  

&amp;gt;basic income, Noam Chomsky, extreme early retirement  

Again, how is that related to an exact excerpt or paraphrase of anything I said?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
