<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93803852.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jujik/judging_women_for_revealing_clothing_is_perfectly/">
    <title>Judging women for revealing clothing is perfectly acceptable, and should not be considered slut shaming. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>SparkleBear</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the most part, when people talk about slut shaming they are speaking of shaming a woman for having 'too many' sexual partners. While I side with the majority on that one, and think slut shaming in that context is wrong, that message is also often accompanied by the declaration that women should be able to dress and act however they want and not be shamed for that either. In my mind those are two completely separate things. 

Being promiscuous is often seen in feminists movements for women as being confident in their sexuality. However when I see women in revealing attire, especially posted on social media such as Facebook and Instagram, I don't think they are being sex positive at all. I think they are trying their hardest to get attention. 

In the same vein, my feelings towards SlutWalk are pretty negative. For those who have not heard of it, SlutWalk was a worldwide protest initiated when a Toronto cop told a group of students that to avoid rape they should avoid dressing like "sluts". The idea of it is that women should be able to wear whatever they want and not be considered slutty. In my opinion, as offensive as that cop's comment may have sounded, it really is good, practical advice. Common sense tells you that if you go into the street in a tight dress and fishnets you've put yourself in a more dangerous situation that if you go out in a hoodie and sweats. 

Moreover, the idea that anyone should be able to wear anything without being judged seems ridiculous. Your clothes and appearance are often the only information strangers know about who you are. They communicate basic preferences. The two above mentioned outfits say two different things about the people wearing them. Yes, it's true that wearing a revealing outfit doesn't mean you're sexually promiscuous, and may not fully warrant being called a slut. But in my mind it does mean you are trying to garner attention of sexual interest through your clothing which is more than enough for me to pass judgment. For reference, I am a young woman who is mostly liberal minded, and this is probably the most 'radical' view I hold. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26817464304.0" user="Nepene" delta="False">
    <text>http://scholarship.law.duke.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=1109&amp;amp;context=djglp#H1N3

Contrary to popular belief, rapists don't tend to target women based on how sexy their clothes are. They target them based on how submissive they are.

&amp;gt;Instead, rapists look for signs of passiveness and submissiveness, which, studies suggest, are more likely to coincide with more body-concealing clothing. (140) In a study to test whether males could determine whether women were high or low in passiveness and submissiveness, Richards and her colleagues found that men, using only nonverbal appearance cues, could accurately assess which women were passive and submissive versus those who were dominant and assertive. (141) Clothing was one of the key cues: "Those females high in passivity and submissiveness (i.e., those at greatest risk for victimization) wore noticeably more body-concealing clothing (i.e., high necklines, long pants and sleeves, multiple layers)." (142) This suggests that men equate body-concealing clothing with passive and submissive qualities, which are qualities that rapists look for in victims. Thus, those who wore provocative clothes would not be viewed as passive or submissive, and would be less likely to be victims of assault.

They're looking for an easy mark. That person in a hoodie and sweats is more at risk because they look defensive. 

That woman wearing almost no clothing? Everyone's eyes are on her. She's probably quite loud and open. People would notice if she went missing.

Common sense is often wrong. 

While I agree that we should be free to judge others on their clothing, the main problem comes when people tend to take that far beyond that idea.

The police have limited time. They can't follow up every crime. They have to decide which crimes to collect lots of evidence on. The courts have to decide which cases they can win. One of the things they look for in a rape case is whether the woman seems to have wanted it. If she walked into his house willingly the case will be a lot harder to prove, for example.

There are some notable court cases where people have argued that because a woman was wearing promiscuous clothing she was out on the prowl and wanted sex and so have tried to get a conviction. People are worried the police would do similar stuff, and refuse to prosecute if the woman was wearing skimpy clothing.

There's another issue. I go to some anime cons. I have on ocassion dressed up for these. People often believe that you wearing a skimpy outfit means that you want sexual interest, and so will slap your ass, pinch you, do sexual come ons to you. This is rather awkward for me- many anime characters do wear skimpy clothes, I can't change that, and I don't want to sleep with random women who come onto me.

I and many others would prefer if clothing weren't used to judge how into sex someone was anywhere near as much.

I think it would be rather sad to make certain types of clothing unwearable. If you want to avoid being sexually harassed in public, don't wear revealing clothes say. Revealing clothes are super comfy, especially in the summer. I'd prefer that we confront those who do sexual harassment and rape and make them stop.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
