<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93803852.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jujik/judging_women_for_revealing_clothing_is_perfectly/">
    <title>Judging women for revealing clothing is perfectly acceptable, and should not be considered slut shaming. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>SparkleBear</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the most part, when people talk about slut shaming they are speaking of shaming a woman for having 'too many' sexual partners. While I side with the majority on that one, and think slut shaming in that context is wrong, that message is also often accompanied by the declaration that women should be able to dress and act however they want and not be shamed for that either. In my mind those are two completely separate things. 

Being promiscuous is often seen in feminists movements for women as being confident in their sexuality. However when I see women in revealing attire, especially posted on social media such as Facebook and Instagram, I don't think they are being sex positive at all. I think they are trying their hardest to get attention. 

In the same vein, my feelings towards SlutWalk are pretty negative. For those who have not heard of it, SlutWalk was a worldwide protest initiated when a Toronto cop told a group of students that to avoid rape they should avoid dressing like "sluts". The idea of it is that women should be able to wear whatever they want and not be considered slutty. In my opinion, as offensive as that cop's comment may have sounded, it really is good, practical advice. Common sense tells you that if you go into the street in a tight dress and fishnets you've put yourself in a more dangerous situation that if you go out in a hoodie and sweats. 

Moreover, the idea that anyone should be able to wear anything without being judged seems ridiculous. Your clothes and appearance are often the only information strangers know about who you are. They communicate basic preferences. The two above mentioned outfits say two different things about the people wearing them. Yes, it's true that wearing a revealing outfit doesn't mean you're sexually promiscuous, and may not fully warrant being called a slut. But in my mind it does mean you are trying to garner attention of sexual interest through your clothing which is more than enough for me to pass judgment. For reference, I am a young woman who is mostly liberal minded, and this is probably the most 'radical' view I hold. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26818557270.0" user="ahatmadeofshoes12" delta="False">
    <text>I actually just wrote about slut walk and revealing clothing and its relation to rape (i.e. none).  I'll copy what I said here:

&amp;gt;I don't see how it is the victim's fault if they were raped, the rapist CHOOSE to do that to them, they are not at fault for another person's choices. This whole idea infuriates me as someone who knows a lot of survivors. What they wore was not remotely the issue, the reason they were raped was because someone choose to rape them.

&amp;gt;**TRIGGER WARNING: ANECDOTES ABOUT RAPE**

&amp;gt;My best friend was sexually abused by her first boyfriend, a man she thought she could trust, she was sober and never wears anything particularly revealing. Was it her fault that when he shoved his fingers into her vagina and she said no that he didn't stop?

&amp;gt;My friend's mother was raped at 13 by a 15 year old who pulled a knife on her at a party. He gave her two options, she could either have sex with him (i.e. rape) or he would stab her. Was it her fault that she didn't protest to avoid being stabbed and killed?

&amp;gt;My close friend was raped repeated as a child by her uncle and abused by her father. Was this little girl somehow dressed too scantily? Was it her fault that these men decided that it was okay to hurt her?

&amp;gt;I participated in an event called "Slut Walk" where thousands of men and women survivors came together to share their stories and protest the idea that what you wear puts you at fault for someone else's chooses to hurt you. Many people shared and there were quite a few people who wore the same clothes they had on the day they were raped. This could include everything from a basic pair of jeans and a t-shirt to pjammas.

&amp;gt;Many survivors spoke and several of their stories stuck with me, women who were raped as children, men who were abused by others, people who were drugged at parties, people abused by individuals who they loved and thought they could trust. One of the common themes was that they couldn't even be taken seriously by others when they told their stories because their peers and the justice system blamed them or said it was their fault.

&amp;gt;One story that stuck with me was from a gay man who spoke at the convention. At 16 he was pulled into a strange car while walking on the sidewalk. His attacker beat him and raped him and when he went to the police they laughed at him and told him that he must have liked it.

&amp;gt;When you blame the victims you are just perpetuating this system that does not take then seriously and allowing rapists to remain at large hurting others without consequences. It is NEVER the victim's fault, he or she never asked to get raped, NO ONE asked to get raped (I'm not talking about consensual "rape play" from the kink world which is basically consensual role play and therefore not rape). If someone is raped, it is because someone else made a conscious decision to violate that individual's autonomy.

Even if a woman is looking to get attention, then so what?  Its her choice and her body, how is it your right to be able to comment on that?  Its not your body therefore you don't get a say.  Besides even if she is dressed scantily that doesn't make it okay for someone to rape her.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
