<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93803852.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jujik/judging_women_for_revealing_clothing_is_perfectly/">
    <title>Judging women for revealing clothing is perfectly acceptable, and should not be considered slut shaming. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>SparkleBear</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the most part, when people talk about slut shaming they are speaking of shaming a woman for having 'too many' sexual partners. While I side with the majority on that one, and think slut shaming in that context is wrong, that message is also often accompanied by the declaration that women should be able to dress and act however they want and not be shamed for that either. In my mind those are two completely separate things. 

Being promiscuous is often seen in feminists movements for women as being confident in their sexuality. However when I see women in revealing attire, especially posted on social media such as Facebook and Instagram, I don't think they are being sex positive at all. I think they are trying their hardest to get attention. 

In the same vein, my feelings towards SlutWalk are pretty negative. For those who have not heard of it, SlutWalk was a worldwide protest initiated when a Toronto cop told a group of students that to avoid rape they should avoid dressing like "sluts". The idea of it is that women should be able to wear whatever they want and not be considered slutty. In my opinion, as offensive as that cop's comment may have sounded, it really is good, practical advice. Common sense tells you that if you go into the street in a tight dress and fishnets you've put yourself in a more dangerous situation that if you go out in a hoodie and sweats. 

Moreover, the idea that anyone should be able to wear anything without being judged seems ridiculous. Your clothes and appearance are often the only information strangers know about who you are. They communicate basic preferences. The two above mentioned outfits say two different things about the people wearing them. Yes, it's true that wearing a revealing outfit doesn't mean you're sexually promiscuous, and may not fully warrant being called a slut. But in my mind it does mean you are trying to garner attention of sexual interest through your clothing which is more than enough for me to pass judgment. For reference, I am a young woman who is mostly liberal minded, and this is probably the most 'radical' view I hold. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26817531374.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>Sometimes a person who wears scandalous clothing is immoral or needlessly promiscuous, or is self destructive, but sometimes they're not.  
So basing that judgment of their character on clothes alone will always guarantee you relying on appearance and other poor sources of reasoning for your judgment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
