<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="93803852.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1jujik/judging_women_for_revealing_clothing_is_perfectly/">
    <title>Judging women for revealing clothing is perfectly acceptable, and should not be considered slut shaming. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>SparkleBear</original_poster>
    <original_post>For the most part, when people talk about slut shaming they are speaking of shaming a woman for having 'too many' sexual partners. While I side with the majority on that one, and think slut shaming in that context is wrong, that message is also often accompanied by the declaration that women should be able to dress and act however they want and not be shamed for that either. In my mind those are two completely separate things. 

Being promiscuous is often seen in feminists movements for women as being confident in their sexuality. However when I see women in revealing attire, especially posted on social media such as Facebook and Instagram, I don't think they are being sex positive at all. I think they are trying their hardest to get attention. 

In the same vein, my feelings towards SlutWalk are pretty negative. For those who have not heard of it, SlutWalk was a worldwide protest initiated when a Toronto cop told a group of students that to avoid rape they should avoid dressing like "sluts". The idea of it is that women should be able to wear whatever they want and not be considered slutty. In my opinion, as offensive as that cop's comment may have sounded, it really is good, practical advice. Common sense tells you that if you go into the street in a tight dress and fishnets you've put yourself in a more dangerous situation that if you go out in a hoodie and sweats. 

Moreover, the idea that anyone should be able to wear anything without being judged seems ridiculous. Your clothes and appearance are often the only information strangers know about who you are. They communicate basic preferences. The two above mentioned outfits say two different things about the people wearing them. Yes, it's true that wearing a revealing outfit doesn't mean you're sexually promiscuous, and may not fully warrant being called a slut. But in my mind it does mean you are trying to garner attention of sexual interest through your clothing which is more than enough for me to pass judgment. For reference, I am a young woman who is mostly liberal minded, and this is probably the most 'radical' view I hold. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26817903928.0" user="TheTwitchyMaid" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Yes, it's true that wearing a revealing outfit doesn't mean you're sexually promiscuous, and may not fully warrant being called a slut. But in my mind it does mean you are trying to garner attention of sexual interest through your clothing which is more than enough for me to pass judgment.

I have to disagree. I am a female and while I don't mind showing a *little bit* of skin, sometimes I almost don't have a choice but to show more. For the record, I live in Florida and do not have a/c in my car. This week it will reach temps of 90 degrees Fahrenheit and the humidity will be over 60%. I really do not want to draw attention to my chunky white thighs or upper arms, but I am also not willing to go into my college classes or work drenched in sweat and smelling like old socks, so I end up wearing skimpy shorts and low cut tank tops. Really, not trying to be slutty, just really do not enjoy the heat at all. Also, I have been really sick and barely made it out of bed in my sweats and flip flops so that i could go to the store for medicine. So what you see on people does not always reflect what type of person that they are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26819254443.0" user="CrossPollinationProj" delta="False">
    <text>Regarding this train of thought (and following after Emmatini), there's an excellent study done by Duke that shows that the clothing that a women wears is not very indicative of whether or not she will gain the attention of a rapist. This is a link to it.
Here's a somewhat well-known quote, however.
"While people perceive dress to have an impact on who is assaulted, studies of rapists suggest that victim attire is not a significant factor. Instead, rapists look for signs of passiveness and submissiveness, which, studies suggest, are more likely to coincide with more body-concealing clothing. (140) In a study to test whether males could determine whether women were high or low in passiveness and submissiveness, Richards and her colleagues found that men, using only nonverbal appearance cues, could accurately assess which women were passive and submissive versus those who were dominant and assertive. (141) Clothing was one of the key cues: "Those females high in passivity and submissiveness (i.e., those at greatest risk for victimization) wore noticeably more body-concealing clothing (i.e., high necklines, long pants and sleeves, multiple layers)." (142) This suggests that men equate body-concealing clothing with passive and submissive qualities, which are qualities that rapists look for in victims. Thus, those who wore provocative clothes would not be viewed as passive or submissive, and would be less likely to be victims of assault."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
