<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="939703614.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fjh3y6/cmv_where_your_born_doesnt_matter_and_country/">
    <title>CMV: Where your born doesn't matter and country pride is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>Blank-VII</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I belong to a country and I think the concept is odd. I was born in the UK and have lived here all my life, but I fail to understand why people are so hard-core about being a 'proud brit' or anything. Where I was born isn't something I was able to decide for myself, and I want my life to be what I make out of it, not what it decides for me. I believe the only way to belong to a country is to find one whose culture is similar to your own tastes and opinions, and to move there. What's the point in being proud of a country I was born in if I feel no attachment to how it's run or anything else?

*you're

*View partially changed. Country pride is not pointless.

**Main view unchanged, it seems no-one can quite convince me. I've had some fantastic conversations and I'm really happy with how many of you engaged without being toxic. Stay safe y'all. Thanks so much!**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33899720030.0" user="Canada_Constitution" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe the only way to belong to a country is to find one whose culture is similar to your own tastes and opinions, and to move there.

Don't you mean ***try*** to move there? No offense, but entering another country as an immigrant is a privilege, not a right. The other country, in general, has to want you. You may not have an option to live in a country of your choice.

A sense of national pride/patriotism is necessary to bind a country together. You need common  symbols and a shared historical narrative to ensure unity. For example, here in Canada a lot of our historical narrative is about two nations, English and French, working together, at first to resist American invasion and domination, and afterwords to build a country founded on bi-lingualism, human rights, rule of law, and tolerance. These common civic values help keep the country (relatively) united to this day.

Without this common national narrative and culture, the government would fall apart, divided by regional and linguistic infighting. It likely would have been absorbed into the USA.

The UK, in particular right now, could use  a little bit of unity. It could help your country heal its wounds after Brexit, and perhaps rebuild of a sense of civic unity. Having some pride in your country could help heal what appears to be a bitterly divided society.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;***"We are a great country and shall become one of the greatest in the universe if we preserve it; we shall sink into insignificance and adversity if we suffer it to be broken."*** *- Sir John A Macdonald, Canada's First Prime Minister*</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899783540.0" user="Blank-VII" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Don't you mean try to move there?

Yes. Thank you for the correction. The world is not easy and is full of many cultures. It would be a shame if I was forced to label myself as someone sticking to one when I appreciate so many of them.

&amp;gt;A sense of national pride/patriotism is necessary to bind a country together.

and

&amp;gt;The UK, in particular right now, could use a little bit of unity.

On one hand, I totally agree. I wish the UK the best of luck in their struggles, but I don't feel like I'm part of it. I feel like I'm forced to sit here watching a country I live in yet never cared for die just because I was unlucky enough to be born here. Why should I be a Brit if I feel no attachment, and even worse - feel outright unnattachment due to the issues the country has brought on itself?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899872234.0" user="Canada_Constitution" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why should I be a Brit if I feel no attachment, and even worse - feel outright unnattachment due to the issues the country has brought on itself?

Because you will always be a Brit, and we don't get to choose everything in life. You're British. I'm Canadian. You are either a brit who likes your culture or does not.  Still a citizen of the United Kingdom though.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Citizenship is something that is inherently part of the luck of the draw of life, because you don't get to choose your parents. You have to find a place to immigrate to, get citizenship, -and renounce your original citizenship if you truly didn't want to be a brit anymore.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Why not work to help improve your national culture in some way into something you personally can be proud of?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899884559.0" user="Blank-VII" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because you will always be a Brit

I will always be called a Brit. That's cool, people can call me what they like. I disagree with them but I don't really care for labels.

&amp;gt;Still a citizen of the United Kingdom though.

​Yup, and officially that makes me British. But I disagree with the countries views and culture, which is why i'm not "typically" British, which is why I don't consider myself a 'Brit'.

&amp;gt;Citizenship is something that is inherently part of luck of the draw of life, because you don't get to choose your parents.

Exactly. Unfortunately. In an ideal world we get to choose whatever the hell we want and shape ourselves to be who we want - but this isn't that world. I won't let the fact that it's a dream stop me from wanting it, though. And I won't let the world I'm forced to be a part of define me more than I can define myself.

&amp;gt;Why not work to help improve your national culture in some way into something you personally can be proud of?

That's actually a fantastic point. But better than starting from the bottom and making something out of a country I don't care for - Why not make my own country and culture and let others who agree with me more there and consider themselves 'Blanks' or whatever? Why not move to Canada and try to improve what they've got going on, seeing as I agree with a lot of what they do? Why must I be forced to stay in Britain and contribute to something way behind places I actually agree with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899914897.0" user="Canada_Constitution" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why not move to Canada and try to improve what they've got going on, seeing as I agree with a lot of what they do?

Because Canada, or any other sovereign state, wants to know what you will contribute to the country. Immigration isn't about cultural self-actualization. It comes down to how is letting you live in the country going to contribute to  the new society you move to. In other words, immigration is about your worth as human capital to another government, and whether you meet its criteria</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899922430.0" user="Blank-VII" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because Canada, or any other sovereign state, wants to know what you will contribute to the country.

I'm aware. Perhaps I should have made it clear that I don't expect to ever move there, just as I don't expect my ideal world to ever come to fruition. I'm talking hypotheticals here. In the modern climate, I don't find pride in any country wholly, even Canada. I just like them the most.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33900261317.0" user="functious" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I will always be called a Brit. That's cool, people can call me what they like. I disagree with them but I don't really care for labels.   


It's a descriptive label. We need a way of describing where people come from and mixing that up with also having to mean that you 'agree with that country's culture' in some vague, abstract sense makes reality harder to explain, rather than easier. You're loading the term with a lot of unnecessary meaning.

I think you have an overly negative view of what you consider to be British culture since you were actually born, raised and live here. I suspect that you also have an overly romantic view of other countries' cultures in comparison and that if you were to actually live there then the aspects of that culture that don't appeal to you would become more salient.  


What is it specifically about Britain that you don't like? It seems as though you're simply generalizing about political views that you consider to make up part of the 'outgroup' (i.e. Conservatism and Brexit) and thinking that they're something that is peculiar to Britain when similar political tendencies are prevalent in practically every other country in the world.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33900068234.0" user="relativistictrain" delta="False">
    <text>Je pense que la moitié du Canada n’a pas eu le mémo sur la base de bilinguisme.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33900089660.0" user="Serial-Killer-Whale" delta="False">
    <text>As a Canadian, I dunno if where you got that form, but from what I've gotten, our national founding had more to do with being used as cannon fodder by the British, and earning our right as a nation in WWI. 

Canada entered the first World War automatically because the British did. Canadians were used as cannon fodder, only to prove themselves the best of the best. 

By the time the second world war came around, Canada elected _not_ to join the war with Britain, and waited a day first to prove a point. We were not _obligated_ to fight _for_ Britain. We _choose_ to fight _alongside_ it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33901684498.0" user="Canada_Constitution" delta="False">
    <text>I think you have to look farther back then that. The foundations of Canada go back to New France. The identity of two nations under one state go all the way to the Quebec act post plains of Abraham, and can be followed as more provinces created:


* Quebec act officially grants language and religious rights to the recently conquered colony of New France. Civil law is left intact, language and religious righs of the largely catholic population are left intact, a first for the British empire.

* American Revolution occurs. Atlantic English speaking colonies stay loyal to the Crown, french colony of Quebec decides to not join Americans during the revolutionary war, deciding the that yhr British are the best bet for retaining their rights and culture. First American invasion invasion of Canada fails.

* United empire loyalists, refugees from the thirteen Colonies who remained loyal, colonise what will become upper Canada. Quebec eventually is renamed lower Canada.

* War of 1812 repels the final attempt to conquer British North America

* Lord.Durhams report recommendsthe implementation of self-rule, also called responsible government to in British north american colonies.

* Sir John A MacDonald and George Etienne-Cartier come together with their.polticial rival George Brown to create a united Canada.at co federation.

* British Columbia joins Confederation and John a MacDonald gets a railroad built from coast to coast in 5 years to unite the country. 

* Massive immigration from eastern europe  occurs to the prairies, in order to ensure Canadians populate the future provinces of Alberta, Saskatchewan abd Manitoba, in order to prevent America taking what would otherwise be empty land.

* Louis Riel, and his execution, create tensions throughout.the nation

* Vimy ridge signifies one of the first major events which creates a sense of nationalism in Canada. 

* Statute of Westminister gives Canada near complete seperation as an independent commonwealth realm in the British empire. We declare war a day later in WW2 as you mentioned.

* Newfoundland and Labrador become the last province to join co federation

* Queit revolution in Quebec leads to huge changes  in Quebec culture. A huge focus is the rejection of a traditionally Catholic identity and embrace of secularism.

* FLQ crisis and Invocation of the war measures act increase Anglophone/francophone tensions. This leads to the first Quebec referendum, rise of the Parti Quebecois

* Repatriation of the Constitution severs last legal ties to the British monarchy. Canada is now a fully seperate monarchy. The Elizabeth II is now Queen of Canada and Queen of the United Kingdom legally, two legally distinct offices held at once

* Creation of the Charter of human rights and freedoms leads to increased judicial power in the supreme court. It also propels the government policy of multiculturalism forward, which is apticularly embraced in English speaking regions of Canada

* The failure of the Charlottown and Meech Lake accords, and the questions of Quebec  as a distinct society, lead to the second independence  referendum, in which Quebec was 50,000 votes away from leaving the country.

* 1993 signing of the NAFTA treaty and financial reforms of Paul Martin align Canada with a much more free market approach emphasizing exports and the close  relationship with the United States which and been growing , especially since the end of the second world war.

* Rebirth of a united conservative party in 2006 and subsequent victory of Stoeben Harper ends over 15 years of liberal government and unites Canada's broken right wing



* The victory of Justin Trudeau in 2015 brings us to the present day. The hold of the old federalist/seperatist dynamic in Quebec is broken François Legault and the CAQ, leading  to a rise in support for Soft Quebec nationalism, rather then outright seperation.

Current issues  include western alienation, conflicts over resource development, reconciliation and recognition of the place of indigenous peoples in Canadian history, and multicultural in English Canada vs interculturalism in Quebec

So as you can see, I think our history strenches and historical roots of our identity stretch far  beyond our actions during the early 20th centuries, although they are important.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
