<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="939703614.0" index="32" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fjh3y6/cmv_where_your_born_doesnt_matter_and_country/">
    <title>CMV: Where your born doesn't matter and country pride is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>Blank-VII</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I belong to a country and I think the concept is odd. I was born in the UK and have lived here all my life, but I fail to understand why people are so hard-core about being a 'proud brit' or anything. Where I was born isn't something I was able to decide for myself, and I want my life to be what I make out of it, not what it decides for me. I believe the only way to belong to a country is to find one whose culture is similar to your own tastes and opinions, and to move there. What's the point in being proud of a country I was born in if I feel no attachment to how it's run or anything else?

*you're

*View partially changed. Country pride is not pointless.

**Main view unchanged, it seems no-one can quite convince me. I've had some fantastic conversations and I'm really happy with how many of you engaged without being toxic. Stay safe y'all. Thanks so much!**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33908824441.0" user="nyetflix" delta="False">
    <text>Not your country exactly, but the culture and the specific place (your town, region, etc.) you grow up in definitely has a huge role in defining who you are. Sure, you didn't choose it, but you didn't choose who your family is, who the people you grow up around are, what you look like, what gender you prefer, etc. All that stuff still contributes to your development and your own understanding of who you are. I think being "proud" of it in the usual sense is often a bit naive (and nationalism is pretty bad), but part of liking and accepting yourself is acknowledging the circumstances you're placed in, including your culture.

Different groups of people do things differently. Whatever culture you're born in to might seem pretty default to you, and you might even find a lot of flaws in it and reject it, but the group still exists, and you usually can't change being a part of it. You still have to work to move that culture forward in the direction you want it to go in.  

As for being proud of places, I think that's part of actually engaging with nature and culture. Assuming there's something you like about being wherever home is for you (food, customs, pastimes, whatever), well, that's a reason to like that place and maybe share it with other people. And though it may not seem like it, every place is a little bit different. Part of enjoying and respecting nature and the world we live in is enjoying the specific places you're from.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
