<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="939703614.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fjh3y6/cmv_where_your_born_doesnt_matter_and_country/">
    <title>CMV: Where your born doesn't matter and country pride is pointless</title>
    <original_poster>Blank-VII</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't think I belong to a country and I think the concept is odd. I was born in the UK and have lived here all my life, but I fail to understand why people are so hard-core about being a 'proud brit' or anything. Where I was born isn't something I was able to decide for myself, and I want my life to be what I make out of it, not what it decides for me. I believe the only way to belong to a country is to find one whose culture is similar to your own tastes and opinions, and to move there. What's the point in being proud of a country I was born in if I feel no attachment to how it's run or anything else?

*you're

*View partially changed. Country pride is not pointless.

**Main view unchanged, it seems no-one can quite convince me. I've had some fantastic conversations and I'm really happy with how many of you engaged without being toxic. Stay safe y'all. Thanks so much!**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33899909986.0" user="Odda_" delta="False">
    <text>I would personally say that taking pride in ones country, as in the accomplishments of your countrymen before you, is a way of saying 'I recognise your legacy and the great actions you have taken. I respect the ideals of my forefathers and I promise to uphold them because that is the responsibility I must take for having pride in my country and its achievements.' I think that that's a pretty good attitude to have. An example of this since you are British could be the abolition of slavery and destruction of the trans Atlantic slave trade. Perhaps: 'Britain brought about the end of slavery out of a moral objection. I am proud of this and will continue this legacy onwards in my countries name by dismantling immoral structures, even if others refuse to take issue or take action with them just the same as my ancestors did'

Well that's my take on national pride at least, I guess at the end of the day people hold different ideas on what their nationality means to them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899919208.0" user="Blank-VII" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;An example of this since you are British could be the abolition of slavery and destruction of the trans Atlantic slave trade. Perhaps: 'Britain brought about the end of slavery out of a moral objection. I am proud of this and will continue this legacy onwards in my countries name by dismantling immoral structures, even if others refuse to take issue or take action with them just the same as my ancestors did'

I very much like this as an argument, targeting the good points of a country as a whole is a surefire way to make me appreciate said country. However, you could also give me positive history facts about other countries, and if you found one that *really* struck a chord with me, I'd want to then appreciate that country the most and appreciate it's culture. Unfortunately while history is a great factor in country pride, it ultimately doesn't have much impact on what a country is currently doing in the modern climate.

The modern climate is where I find faults and a struggle to agree with things, and therefore if I disagree with the way a country is run (e.g Britain), I won't be a proud Brit. I'll just be a guy stuck living in Britain.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33899988927.0" user="PieFlinger" delta="False">
    <text>seems pretty silly to be proud of something you had no part in accomplishing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33901969807.0" user="Odda_" delta="False">
    <text>What I'm saying is that by taking pride in something you didn't accomplish you take responsibility for the continuation of the legacy left by those who you are feeling proud because of.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33903676932.0" user="boyblueau" delta="False">
    <text>So does the inverse of this work as well? Britain was involved in the establishment of the slave trade in the first place. Not to mention many other atrocities committed globally. Do you take responsibility for those actions and therefore feel guilt for that legacy too?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
