<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33912812196.0" user="driver1676" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you.

&amp;gt; if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore. 

Being upset your partner is with someone else doesn't mean that you care about them. That means that you want something that you're not having, and while that's fine that's very much you caring about yourself, not them.

Jealousy is a complex feeling. It might represent insecurity, fear, anger, or any number of other emotions. It might help to delve into why you're jealous. Are you jealous because you're not having as much sex with them? Or are you jealous because she's having sex with someone else? Are you feeling jealous about her having sex with someone else, even if you're getting enough sex, love, and intimacy in your relationship for your own needs? Do you feel jealous because you need ownership of her body, and her being with someone else violates that need?

Take it as a sign that you're not having your own needs met. That doesn't mean it's someone else's responsibility to meet those, but it means you need to change something. Can you meet your needs in the relationship without taking ownership over your partner's body?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912901570.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>I changed my view thanks to one person that commented on this post but i still strongly dissagree with basically everything that you said there. I had this opinion in the first place because of people who think like you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912953882.0" user="driver1676" delta="False">
    <text>You disagree that jealousy is a sign you need to change something? You disagree that you shouldn't own someone else's body?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33913021331.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>"Being upset your partner is with someone else doesn't mean that you care about them. That means that you want something that you're not having, and while that's fine that's very much you caring about yourself, not them."

-Ok that is just stupid and simple minded, you should put more thinking into it. And to make things worse you start talking about how jealousy is a complex feeling right afterwards.

"Are you jealous because you're not having as much sex with them? Or are you jealous because she's having sex with someone else? Are you feeling jealous about her having sex with someone else, even if you're getting enough sex, love, and intimacy in your relationship for your own needs? Do you feel jealous because you need ownership of her body, and her being with someone else violates that need?"

- This is basically a sequel to your first statement. Alot of changing thesis in a very simple manner.
I understood how some people dont feel jealousy but from these questions you don't seem to understand even how basic human emotions work.
It is not all about sex and having enough of it, and what in the world is enough love and intimacy ? Ownership of body ? Really ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33939083634.0" user="driver1676" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Ok that is just stupid and simple minded, you should put more thinking into it. And to make things worse you start talking about how jealousy is a complex feeling right afterwards.

So do you have some justification for why it's "stupid and simpleminded?" You disagreeing it doesn't mean it's dumb or even wrong.

&amp;gt; even how basic human emotions work

How do "basic human emotions work?" Could you provide any peer-reviewed sources of how basic human emotions work?

&amp;gt; It is not all about sex and having enough of it, and what in the world is enough love and intimacy ? Ownership of body ? Really ?

I'm not literally asking you those questions. They were examples of ways to explore your jealousy, and the only wrong answer is the dishonest one. Be honest about why you're jealous that your partner is sleeping with someone else or put an honest effort in understanding where your feeling comes from. If you feel jealous because you don't want someone else touching your partner then doesn't that sound like you wanting ownership of their body?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
