<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33913361247.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>I am perfectly OK with being in a poly relationship but I've not met any women that I'm attracted to that are interested in that.  So I'm in a regular relationship. 

Ask yourself this.  If Black widow or [insert hot chic here] wanted to touch your weiner on a regular basis would you say no if you knew she was touching other weiners also?  You still need to be safe wash your hand and wear a condom of course but what would you do?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33913820604.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>Hahaha i wouldnt mind having sex with multiple woman but i don't believe in being in a relationship with multiple woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33913870228.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>What's the difference?  What if Black widow wanted to blo you every Tuesday and then you guys can go bowling afterwards?  

Are you going to say no to blo job bowling Tuesdays?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917227889.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Real relationships are about a lot more than getting blowies and going out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917246500.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>Are you also turning down Black widow Blojob bowling Tuesdays?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917299943.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes. Because I’m an adult in an adult relationship with adult responsibilities and adult problems. I have a wife and we both have to balance our careers and setting up the rest of our lives with raising two young children. Is black widow gonna be a part of all of that? If so for how long?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917311051.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>Probably a month.  2 at most until she's board of you and stops returning your calls.  

I guess for you it's better to have never loved at all.  Makes sense.  I get it though raising kids and making sure they don't grow up to be demons is more important than having your Weiner touched by a hot girl.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917334155.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It looks like you didn’t really comprehend my response. My point is that even if people tried that, it would fail. A three-way relationship is not capable of handling life’s challenges. Someone will bail.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917376868.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>A two way relationship and many one way relationships fail.  It's difficult and definitely harder but it is not impossible for it to succeed. 

Again....if black widow AKA Scarlett Johansen invited me into her harem of dudes I'm down.  She's worth at least 20....maybe 50 million dollars.  Pretty sure there's enough square footage in the house(es).  She could touch my weiner once a week or more and Incan spend my time mountain biking, building dhitr, fixing up classic cars and drinking beer with the homies.  Anyone talking shot about the Jost nailing my GF gets booted off the island.  What's not to love about this?

If you didn't have kids you would say no to this?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917466496.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What you’re describing is a fling, not an actual relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917388364.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>Note:. People who claim "I'm an adult" or say "just grow up" are hella boring ass people with mundane lives that suck.  But I'm sure this isn't you, you are super interesting have tons of friends and I'm sure you're an awesome dude to hang out with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917472879.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>No I’m very boring. And you will be too. That’s life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917603699.0" user="NervousRestaurant0" delta="False">
    <text>Noooooooooo........</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
