<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33912760996.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be arguing that because polyamory doesn’t work for you personally, that it can’t work for anyone. You can be in a polyamorous relationship and care for another person, while also appreciating that they receive a different kind of love from another person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912804224.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>It just seems absurd to me. I believe that you really have to totally let go of your ego to do that, and at that point it doesnt really even matter who fits you and who doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912822879.0" user="driver1676" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it doesnt really even matter who fits you and who doesn't.

The only thing "fits" really means is how happy you are in the relationship. Are you meeting your goals in life with this relationship you have? If so, it fits. If not, try to change that. Take ownership of your actions and feelings.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917238237.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What’s the longest polyamorous relationship you’ve ever heard of? Do those relationships survive a severe illness? Do they survive a deep depressive episode? Do they survive having a child? I’m not being facetious. I’m confident a non-monogamous relationship can’t survive any of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33918978305.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>They can indeed survive hardships if the relationships are strong. If someone falls ill, you might have me or more adults who can bear the emotional and financial burden. Same goes for having a child - sure it can be tough with another person coparenting but it can also be beneficial. A lot of this will vary between polyamorous relationships and their particular dynamics.

While YOUR non monogamous relationship might not survive, people who prefer the dynamic polyamory offers would be able to survive it. 

Sure, polyamorous relationships can fail, just like any other relationships. But they don’t fail because they are polyamorous, they fail because sometimes that happens in relationships. There are different challenges that present themselves in polyamory, but a lot of benefits too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33919206642.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If someone falls ill, you might have me or more adults who can bear the emotional and financial burden.

But does that actually happen? Why do we only ever see this kind of thing with young people who are all about sex, or fundamentalist religious zealots that have multiple wives who are only faithful to *them*?

&amp;gt; But they don’t fail because they are polyamorous, they fail because sometimes that happens in relationships.

The numbers would say you’re wrong. A Polyamorous relationship failing is exponentially more likely than a monogamous one that’s been going on for the same amount of time. That’s because emotionally healthy adults aren’t “immune from jealousy.”

Here’s the fundamental reason polyamorous relationships never work: 

* All relationships change as time goes on. When it’s between two people, they try to adapt with the change together. 

* **When there are more than two people, it’s next to impossible for all of them to adapt the same way and keep the relationship going.** Someone WILL drift away or two of them WILL be closer. That is unsubstainable and that’s why only young people think this is an option.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
