<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33912739148.0" user="WVildandWVonderful" delta="False">
    <text>I don't know what you mean about "will never work," as if polyamory were theoretical. It's not for me (or you), but it works for some. I have a friend who is polyamorous, and she and her partner and girlfriend are very happy. They've prob been together 2 or 3 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917221879.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Being together for 2 or 3 years doesn’t qualify as “working.” Not when we have monogamous relationships that last 70 years, where people build an entire life together, have kids, deal with career struggles, deal with sickness, and overcome. There’s just no way a trio (or more) is equipped to handle anything like that, let alone for any extended period.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917677108.0" user="WVildandWVonderful" delta="False">
    <text>Of course a 30-something isn't going to have the life experiences of someone who is 90 years old. But I don't think you've addressed how having an additional partner wouldn't support you in sickness or with your career or co-parenting or whatever. 

I'm monogamous and engaged. Polyamory is not the relationship style for me. Merely offering an observation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33917755512.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; But I don't think you've addressed how having an additional partner wouldn't support you in sickness or with your career or co-parenting or whatever.

Because all of those things suck. What’s going to keep that third wheel around? A child will only belong to two of them at most. Is the third one going to commit to waking up in the middle of the night for feeding and diaper changes? Is the third one going to commit to physical therapy appointments to deal with developmental delays? Is the third one going to be the only one that works when one gets fired and the second one gets ill? 

Some people say “I don’t feel jealousy.” They’re full of crap. Either a) they don’t care enough about the relationship or the people to have a problem with them not being fully emotionally invested in them, or b) they simply haven’t been through an experience that tests their commitment. They’re claiming they don’t feel a standard human emotion. I call bullshit. 

Think of all of the hard things life puts you through, and think of how important it is to have your partner with you for those things. Physically, emotionally, financially. None of that works with a third partner. We aren’t designed that way.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
