<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33912803773.0" user="howlin" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; There will be alot of jelaousy 

This is probably a projection of your emotions onto others. While jealousy can be an issue, many people simply don't feel it or can manage it to the point where it doesn't destroy relationships.

&amp;gt; if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.

You realize this is a bit of a warped perspective?  Jealousy is a negative emotion that causes a tremendous amount of harm.  People get killed over it regularly.  Not having jealousy doesn't prove much of anything other than you aren't irrationally possessive or can simply manage your emotions constructively.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912824460.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>Ok you really have a point there, but jealousy in those kind of situations is totally natural. Even poly people say that. My point is that you shouldn't ignore those kind of emotions in order to be with more partners, because when you do you kinda burn that fire you had towards your first partner.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912852242.0" user="howlin" delta="False">
    <text>There are many ways of dealing with negative emotions that don't require you to also snuff out your positive emotions towards someone. I think some people are better at it than others, and those people are best suited to polyamory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912865029.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>Well you're right. Most of people are not programmed that way but i guess there are some of them that are.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912862077.0" user="Sagasujin" delta="False">
    <text>Most poly people don't ignore jealousy. They work through it or they don't feel it in the first place. Not everyone has the same capacity for jealousy or the same intensity.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
