<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33929032056.0" user="EqualEquine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 

This is quite the claim, and I'm sorry you haven't met anyone that disproves this. I have had over 20 relationships with people in my life and only in one of them have I ever lived with and wanted to have in my life forever. That relationship was open and polyamorous and lasted for 4 years, and I can't see myself being with anyone who isn't also poly after that.

As for the jealousy aspect, I have to hard disagree. Jealousy happens when you either envy someone, or think it is an injustice for that person to have the good thing you don't. Neither of these seem healthy or mature to me. Do you get jealous of your friend who got a promotion at work, or are you happy for them and their success? If you are happy for them, this is called compersion, and it is the opposite of jealousy. This is what poly people feel when their partners are with other partners. We understand that one human can't satisfy every facet of another human's desires, so we don't try to. We just try to be a positive part in each other's lives and experiences.

&amp;gt;There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature.

You may have a skewed sample set. I will say you likely think this because these types are the most vocal about any aspect of their lifestyles.

&amp;gt;Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.

Is jealousy really about caring for other people, or is it about caring for yourself and your own ego? Think about what makes you jealous, what about your jealousy promotes the best wellbeing for the other person? What about jealousy cares about the other person's happiness, instead of your own?

&amp;gt;At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Well, technically aren't all romantic relationships ultimately about sex? You get into a relationship due to attraction to someone, fueled by your brain's mechanism to mate and continue the species. What separates a romantic relationship from a very close platonic friendship? You share secrets, you laugh, sometimes you live together, you care deeply about the other person, you support one another, both platonic and romantic partners do all of these. The only difference is that romantic partners touch each other's erogenous zones.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
