<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26822484403.0" user="raffraffraff" delta="False">
    <text>I live in a predominantly white neighborhood and if I see a bunch of white guys that I've never seen before, and they're all in their early 20s, just hanging around, I'd take notice. Racism aside, our brains notice differences, particularly when they relate to our personal safety. 

Most of the time racism isn't a personal safety issue. I live in Europe and racism here isn't a black/white thing either. Racism is really culturism. Differences between cultural norms are not celebrated, they're exaggerated and warped. Sometimes for comic value. Sometimes in earnest. German people have no sense of humour and are too serious. Italians are boisterous and misogynistic. Irish are drunks. Etc. 

Sometimes racism is a vast cultural chasm. If you meet a Nigerian who's just arrived in your country, you may find them hard to deal with. A substantial proportion of them skip queues in shops, are inconsiderate drivers and haggle in supermarkets. If you meet a Nigerian who has lived your country for a few years and integrated properly, they'll probably tell you that some Nigerian annoy them for similar reasons. (I've had this actual conversation with a Nigerian taxi driver). But they'll explain that in Nigeria, you have to be like that to get along.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
