<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26821927341.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>I think racist means you have a greater chance than others to act on those assumptions.  
  

We all know everyone is biased, but I think the useful definition of racist is someone who is more likely than someone who isn't racist to act on those biases, assumptions, or prejudices.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26821981020.0" user="GoyMeetsWorld" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but I think the useful definition of racist is someone who is more likely than someone who isn't racist to act on those biases

Well that leaves a gigantic gray area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822054988.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>Perhaps, if by gray you mean:  
  
is biased and racist then acts on it, is biased and racist and doesn't act on it, is biased and isn't racist and acts on it (what everyone is before being racist), is biased and doesn't act on it or isn't biased (which is impossible).  
  
Since I'm saying the useful definition covers all of these categories, I think that's less gray than it would seem, and I think it's a useful definition because it also covers people who have had negative prejudices toward race but later figures it out and stops thinking that way and had never acted in it.  
  
Obviously that person would say they used to be racist but the value for me is that we can actually say how likely this person was to act on their understanding of their racial prejudices and own actions and feelings regarding that self knowledge and world knowledge, and I think that creates a more nuanced and useful definition of racist for racists, people who aren't racist, and people who aren't anymore: because we rely on the chance to act on it, we're basically immediately jumping into the understanding associated with casting off prejudice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822009689.0" user="Uhfolks" delta="False">
    <text>Racist: A person who believes in racism, the doctrine that a certain human race is superior to any or all others.

Going by the literal definition, there's no way you could argue everybody is racist. You can't begin to convince me that every human in the world believes their race is completely superior to every other race.

However, using the regular use of the word racist, yes, I'd be very willing to say that virtually everybody, if not every single person in the world, is "racist". The way I've always seen most people use the term racist, is simply someone who judges a person upon their race. Whether it's assumption about their intelligence (i.e. positive for Asians, negative for blacks), their likelihood to commit crime, or their affluence, all of these are judgements people pass on a daily basis.

I would argue that you are lying to yourself if you think you aren't the slightest bit "racist", in the use of the word that has become ingrained in our culture. No, you may not think every black person you see is going to jump you. But I guarantee any human that has a bit of sense would feel more at ease walking on the same side of the sidewalk as an Asian teenager, rather than a black one.

Statistically speaking, certain races are more predisposition to certain actions or traits. No, this doesn't mean you can assume they will (or even are likely to) perpetrate any of these actions. However, everybody knows about these general stereotypes Whether they act upon them consciously, or sub-consciously, I'm sure ever person makes decisions based on these things they know to be true.

**TL;DR** No, not everybody is racist going by the literal definition. Yes, everybody is racist going by the popular-use definition of "racist".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822059405.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Statistically speaking, certain races are more predisposition to certain actions or traits.  

This really applies to culture, not race.  

&amp;gt;popular use definition of race  

I appreciate your long post, but the popular definition is exactly what I was seeking to nuance with my post. I feel it relies on the existence of bias (innate), prejudices (after a little 'knowledge' has been applied consciously), where the popular definition would involve statistics as you say.  
  
I think the popular definition, if it does in fact cover anyone, does so because what is actually talking about is bias. Or it really is the claim that most people on earth will act different towards someone who looks very different than they do, and do so in a negative way perhaps only by avoiding them, and I think that's a statistically impossible to prove. Unless relying on bias of course.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822073559.0" user="Uhfolks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This really applies to culture, not race.

I've never seen statistics on crime, drug use, academic performance, etc. sorted by culture. It's pretty much always sorted by race.

But other than that, I agree with everything else you're saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822077767.0" user="AnxiousPolitics" delta="False">
    <text>While statistics may be presented a certain way, because there are noticeable differences in how humans look, the actual divides are cultural. Like criminal culture, academic culture, etc. While culture may map to race quite easily, there's an obvious easy reason for why that is, and while statistics are presented by race they could just as easily denote culture instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822553406.0" user="Lorem_Ipsum" delta="False">
    <text>They sort statistics like that to judge socioeconomic conditions. If all races are equal, yet crime and academic performance are disproportionately represented by the different races, then you know there is a societal problem behind your differences.

One example could be poorer socioeconomic conditions for minorities. If you control your statistics for poverty, I bet everyone commits the same amount of crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
