<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26822180225.0" user="MoreDetailThanNeeded" delta="False">
    <text>I believe you are saying;

"I am a racist, and I am projecting my thoughts on to others".

We have all benefited from racism though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822246266.0" user="1infinitel00p" delta="False">
    <text>People of color do not benefit from racism AT ALL. White people have absolutely benefited from this system set up in their favor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822350493.0" user="MoreDetailThanNeeded" delta="False">
    <text>People of color have benefited from racism as well.

I am not attempting to deny the negative affects of racism in today's society. Not at all.

However, there are many examples of racism and bias positively affecting people of color if you approach it from an objective frame. Although I understand it can be a difficult subject, because people tend to bristle at that notion... If someone came up to me and said that, I would probably bristle as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822360138.0" user="1infinitel00p" delta="False">
    <text>Can you give me an example of this?
Also, no one is objective when it comes to race issues, everyone has their own experiences and ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822367887.0" user="MoreDetailThanNeeded" delta="False">
    <text>Well... I would rather not get into a debate about race and how racism has (mildly) benefited people of color , on the internet, in a forum populated with young ignorant racists... So... no.

It's kinda one of those things, either you've seen it or you haven't. Can't really teach anyone to see it, or point out examples without having them dissected by people who are only trying to argue.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26823054331.0" user="1infinitel00p" delta="False">
    <text>The entire point of this subreddit is to argue, and you make a statement in response to mine and refuse to back it up with any evidence whatsoever, and then insult me.
If you are afraid to have your worldview challenged, leave this subreddit, it's called /r/changemyview for a reason.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26823059440.0" user="MoreDetailThanNeeded" delta="False">
    <text>You're not OP.

I am not trying to change your view. Nor do I particularly care about your view on this issue.

You don't get to tell other adults what to do, so a statement like "leave this subreddit" is really just an asinine thing to say. I'll just throw you on my ignore list and forget about you, feel free to do the same.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
