<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26822031517.0" user="EternalArchon" delta="False">
    <text>Racism is the belief that ONE RACE is superior to another RACE.  If I throw a red apple into a bin of green apples, yes I'll notice the RED APPLE.  Why?  Because they're a different fucking color.  That doesn't mean I believe one is superior to another.

You are confusing Sterotypes, Racism, and Assumptions.

Sterotypes can involve race, yes, but they also involve gender, clothing, age, posture, and many vocal markers.

Racism is not the same thing as sterotyping someone, its not the same thing as having assumptions, and its not even the same thing as thinking races are different than one another.  Racism is not even the same thing as believing races shouldn't mix(though it often leads to that).

&amp;gt;I will say, then, that I am not, nor ever have been, in favor of bringing about in any way the social and political equality of the white and black races; that I am not, nor ever have been, in favor of making voters or jurors of negroes, nor of qualifying them to hold office, nor to intermarry with white people; and I will say, in addition to this, that there is a physical difference between the white and black races which I believe will forever forbid the two races living together on terms of social and political equality. And in as much as they cannot so live, while they do remain together there must be the position of superior and inferior, and I as much as any other man am in favor of having the superior position assigned to the white race.

That's racism.  Do you know who said that?  [This guy](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abraham_Lincoln)

You make good points about human cognition, but when you throw around the word "racist" with such flippancy its insulting to the historical reality of racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822072245.0" user="JizzOnRainbows" delta="False">
    <text>I should have rephrased this better and thanks for the clarification. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
