<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26822012235.0" user="Thootom" delta="False">
    <text>There's a small, but significant difference between racism and stereotyping. As a human being, your capacity to truly understand another human being, as a human being, with a history, personality, thoughts and feelings is actually severely limited. I doubt most people can think of over 50 people they recognize this way.

Because we live in a small world with lots of people, we end up stereotyping groups based on what we see and experience around us. Have you ever heard someone say "Ugh, I hate those kinds of people!" and wholeheartedly agreed? If you spin that a certain way, or have bad or malicious reasoning, you are contributing to an ism in society, but if it is just a general assumption about the culture or composure of a certain group, it is not racist, it's just a stereotype we use to deal with everyday life.

I have a lot of lesbian friends, and I don't feel hateful when I say that only lesbians can act like total douchenozzles and get away with it socially. Some lesbians get to be rude, womanizing pricks all throughout adolescence and we all let them get away with it because douchiness exuded from a female demeanor can be considered funny and charming. This isn't homophobic to say, it may be wrong, but it's what I've seen and actually talked with them about, and it's something we all agreed as a fact about a certain group of people.

Black people in certain parts of the states have really greasy diets (which can be attributed to what black people ate culturally in times of slavery), Indians sometimes smell bad (because their culture eats a lot of curry and curry makes your sweat smell really bad), and immigrants put a lot of pressure on their kids to succeed. These are stereotypes, and many are often true cultural attributions. Is is racist to think these things? No. Can stereotypes be racist? Yes, but not all of them are.

I think the problem that OP has is a case of too much politically correct culture. When OP has a stereotypical thought, the immediately following thought is "is that racist?" which it isn't. I mean, it would be ignorant not to know what certain cultures eat and what some of their traditions include. Are all people exactly like their cultural stereotype? No, but it's simply easier on our brains to sort things out that way and save face when caught in an unexpected social situation. If you run into someone who doesn't follow the preconceived notions of their culture you can immediately dismiss them as an exception, but unless you have an almost weirdly diverse group of friends those stereotypes are going to stick.

When you enter my house, you take off your shoes. This is a cultural thing in my home, everyone in my family does this. If you don't do this much where you live, you might think my family is "all finicky about their floors," and if you discovered that my sister didn't follow this custom, and you cared enough to get to know her, then you wouldn't simply forget about the shoe thing, you would just recognize her as a non-participant in this stereotype. There's nothing wrong with that, and being politically correct is something you should still do, but you shouldn't be ashamed that your mind works that way.

What you do do when you say "everyone's a little racist" is allow people to get away with mildly racist things. If I hear someone with a Jamaican accent it's not rude to ask if they're from Jamaica (I mean, Jamaicans speak a certain way, accents are a thing so it is reasonable to ask), but it is racist to start treating them like a member of a lesser race, or talk down to them because of who they are. If someone in the bible belt asked which church I went to I wouldn't be offended for their asking, most people from the bible belt go to church. If you tell me I'm a godless pig and deserve to die for not having faith, that's another thing entirely.

TL;DR: Lumping things together is how we get shit done, without stereotypes we'd be hopelessly lost. just because some stereotypes happen to be racial does not make them racist, and you shouldn't be ashamed about this or use stereotypes as an excuse to justify actual mild racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822278153.0" user="very_old_guy" delta="False">
    <text>It seems you define racism based on a person's words and actions, not their thoughts.  Is that a fair statement?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822874138.0" user="Thootom" delta="False">
    <text>I thought I stated this quite clearly. There are hateful racist actions and intents, and there are intentions and actions that rely on stereotyping. If I stereotype a race maliciously then it is racism, but not all stereotyping is racist or even involves specific races. A crazy, unfounded stereotype directed at a certain race is racist, but not all stereotypes are racist, some are quite good and allow us to maneuver ourselves through unexpected scenarios where we find ourselves undereducated.

I'm not a racist if I rely on a common stereotype where I would otherwise know nothing about what I'm doing. A stereotype such as "Indians consider cows sacred" isn't racist if I'm in India, planning a BBQ and inviting a bunch of my Indian neighbors over. In the least I'd avoid slaughtering a cow in my garage as my own culture would consider pretty hospitable of me to do. Preparing alternative meats or avoiding beef entirely isn't racist, it's courteous with stereotyped underpinnings. If it turns out 80% of them eat beef I won't consider myself racist for being preemptively respectful to other's possible cultures, and if it turns out I was completely wrong about my stereotype then I am open to education regarding it.

Another common stereotype would be that a lot of people are defensive about their religion. Saying that doesn't make me an anti-theist, but it does give me certain guidelines to watch out for when dealing with seemingly religious people. Whether they are religious or not, I lose nothing by avoiding awkward conversation and my vast repertoire or religious jokes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
