<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94237489.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1k3u41/i_believe_everyone_to_some_degree_is_racist_cmv/">
    <title>I believe everyone to some degree is racist. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>JizzOnRainbows</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe everyone is racist just some people are more racist than others.

No matter how tolerant we try to be we are all ignorant to certain group(s) and because of that ignorance we make assumptions about certain groups of people.


As human beings we still have the primitive instinct to attack or run away from anything that looks different than us and in this case people who look different from us.

We all make assumptions.  For example, if you live in a predominately white neighborhood and you happen to see a group of black people hanging out you will notice something is a bit off.  These black people might be law biding citizens who isn't doing anything wrong but you don't know that.  You can say the same for any race but the point is if you see something "different" it will stick out to you and everyone else.  The same example can be the other way around and there can be a group of whites in a black neighborhood and that will stick out and you'll still make assumptions.

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26821990106.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I'd like to further the children argument because I think that that's the strongest one. I know anecdotal evidence is poor, but as a child, the only racism I remember seeing were pictures like [this](http://t3.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSH8EcyJyNeSDq7rvrFXYRNQaRTRZbRJo8Oi1sdMYj5VjXYsC7F) that caricatured other races.

Children can see people with black skin, brown skin, short tall and they won't make any judgement other than "he looks different". Children have to be *told* racist stereotypes to even know what they are. 

I think your main argument is that people are *inherently* racist *no matter what*. I would argue that racism is passed down; it isn't something everyone has by default</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822009230.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>Mind you, my 2y.o. niece saw a dark skinned person the other day and asked my sister why his skin was like it was. My sister told her that some people just have darker skin than others, just like my other niece has darker hair. 

My little blonde-haired, blue-eyed neiece replied "I don't like it"

My sister had to scoop her up and walk away pretty quickly at that point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822020147.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I definitely agree, but that's just a judgement call, the same way we could argue about whether Jennifer Lawrence or Emma Watson is more attractive. 

OP seems to be talking about stereotypes, and saying you don't like black skin isn't a stereotype. It's the same as me saying I don't like Brunettes or people with curly hair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822026777.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>But my post does highlight that we are born to be adverse to things that are different, and racism stems from that. I am not saying my niece is racist or ever will be but if she doesn't like someone because of how their skin is, it wouldn't be that much of a leap to not liking everyone with that skin colour.

Most normal and rational people don't make that leap, of course</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822038751.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>Oh yeah, good call! I guess I'd never really thought about racism as being about others being different from you, thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822118313.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>Man, get off your high horse and drop the sarcasm. It doesn't add to discussion and it makes you sound like an ass.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822125365.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>That wasn't sarcasm, I just thought about racism as stereotypes, I honestly never thought about it like xenophobia before</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822171148.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>...that wasn't sarcasm? Wow, alrighty then, I apologise. I guess I am too jaded from Reddit to recognise a serious change of opinion... 

Again, my apologies. Now I am the ass</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822174815.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>No problem, I actually thought to myself that my comment sounded sarcastic, so it's my bad too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822178637.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>Sarcasm needs a symbol...
Like " " is for speaking. It would help online conversations so much!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822221863.0" user="Pimpin_In_A_Prius" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I feel like that and the sarcasm font would just make things weird rather than help though, I'd feel like so a need using them.

My comments always sound uninterested or haughty when I post so I try to add exclamation marks so that people know I'm interested. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822242468.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>Lol, perhaps just say THIS IS/IS NOT SARCASM at the end? Crude, but effectivr</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26822177441.0" user="YoureNotAGenius" delta="False">
    <text>But yes, I agree racism can be passed down by the family, most definitely, but I also think that humans are a little predisposed to having trouble accepting differences. We grow up to learn that it is not OK to not like someone because their skin is dark (like my niece will) but if there isn't that voice of reason from a parent or guardian telling him how to behave, then the child could grow up to be inclined to racism. A defence mechanism maybe? I don't know</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
