<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="94590213.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kbe9x/i_think_that_greenpeaces_radicalism_undermines/">
    <title>I think that Greenpeace's radicalism undermines their environmental cause. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>nickkokay</original_poster>
    <original_post>I accept and agree that something needs to be done about the environment, but refuse to support Greenpeace due to the radical, sometimes violent and often anti-scientific stances that they take on issues (e.g. nuclear energy, genetic modification). 

I believe that their refusal to compromise and accept that some technology can be used for good undermines their environmental motivations. Technology can be used for good (especially given that we know so very little about nuclear energy and genetic modification) and it can be used to help the environment, but Greenpeace, by refusing to change their stance, shoot themselves in the foot.

In the words of Wilson da Silva, Greenpeace has denigrated into a "sad, dogmatic, reactionary phalanx of anti-science zealots who care not for evidence, but for publicity" ([Source](http://www.cosmosmagazine.com/blog/the-sad-sad-demise-greenpeace/)).

Change my view :)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26825556524.0" user="noodlescup" delta="False">
    <text>If you think Greenpeace is radical, pretty much any activism is radical for you, because they've fallen id the lazy side of the fence. Greenpeace these days is more of a political lobbying organization, a PR machine, pushing environmental issues in a tough way, they're the bad guy, the relentless fighters. For media, that is. They don't do these days so many actions, and when they do, are specific and mediatic.

The reason for this is that they don't want to extra radical and borderline criminal, because they don't want to risk the losing donations.

The real activism is done by smaller NGO these days, that may or may not be endorsed by Greenpeace. Sea Shepherd, for example, is chasing whalers and have smaller campaigns, with more boats than GP and a small fraction of their funding.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
