<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832159363.0" user="DuckDuckDOUCHE" delta="False">
    <text>There's already a lot of good points in this thread, but as a person with a debilitating muscle disease I'd like to add my two cents. 

The annual costs of someone with my disease has been estimated to range somewhere in the hundreds of thousands. This includes both costs on the state and family. (I'll post the link if I can find it.)

I myself am going to college, but even so, there's no way I can ever "make up for" the losses I have caused/am causing/will cause. It's growth rate is too steady. I'd have to hit it big and become one of those "exceptions" you talked about, which is a nice thought but unrealistic.

Now I'll have you know that this "systemic strain" is not lost on the disabled, not even the mentally disabled. We're all well aware of what drains we put on others because we are at the center of that drain. 

It's in the back of our heads each and every day. From our perspective, people and things are orbiting around us and "falling in" all the time. You feel like a black-hole, like a negative.

We are made to feel this way because we live under an ideology that tells us a person's worth is equal to their paycheck. If you're not a movie star or a Steve Jobs Übermensch just kill yourself already, amirite?

I say that because I'm trying to make a point, as dramatic as it may sound. The modern mind *can't even conceive* of human worth as being measured in anything but marginal rates of productivity. Anything else is just fairy-tale BS.

The argument here is purely utilitarian. It states that all we want from life is for it to be easier and more pleasurable. All questions of ethics should then defer to how we can best achieve those states.

I think this is a mistaken view of life and I think the fact that it gets beaten into the brains of disabled people (let alone all people) is heinous.

Life is a struggle. Eliminate that struggle and you've eliminated life. This isn't to say that struggles are not to be overcome. Life indeed is the very process of overcoming. It's just that through overcoming, we should always expect more struggles on the horizon. 

Eugenics just blows that horizon up. The problem is that it exists on a slippery slope of "Why not blow up all the horizons of human existence and cease this striving nonsense from the outset?" 

Because why not? If the justification of eugenics is to eradicate suffering, then why not just eradicate life itself, which is the fundamental condition of suffering?  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
