<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831496519.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues.

Everyone carries genes that cause disease. You feel we should cut out reproduction all together?
&amp;gt;I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society.

So let them live until they show you they're a complete drain on society? Or just get rid of them before they can prove their worth?
&amp;gt;Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are?

I really take issue with you calling my son a "life ruiner". If anything he's taught me more than I ever cared to know before he hit the scene.
&amp;gt;Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

And if the doctor doesn't know? Autism doesn't present until around 2 years old, you saying every two year old who shows signs of autism should be killed?
&amp;gt;Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit?

Taking care of an autistic kid... or selling dope, probably going to prison. Those were my two choices when I found out my wife was pregnant.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831718609.0" user="Marvilloso" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Everyone carries genes that cause disease. You feel we should cut out reproduction all together?

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Slippery_slope</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831786437.0" user="frotc914" delta="False">
    <text>A slippery slope is a valid argument if you can't come up with a distinction. In this case, where does one draw the line of "likely enough to create a genetic abnormality" or "bad enough abnormality" that warrants abortion? You can't just say "HAHA SLIPPERY SLOPE" and dismiss the argument all together - you still need to show a dividing line. 

Like if you say "Homosexuality is ok because it's consenting adults", and I say "Oh yeah? Well what about incest?" - that's a slippery slope argument, but that doesn't make it invalid. You would then have to either agree that incest isn't bad or say "That's different because of the risk of genetic disorder in any offspring" - that's the distinction. You've then changed your argument to "homosexuality is ok because it's consenting adults and they don't create an undue risk of creating offspring with genetic disorders".

Here, OP said "we should control births in order to cleanse the gene pool", and the comment you replied to basically said "Well how clean do you want it?" - asking for just what exactly qualifies as risky enough to warrant control.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831823047.0" user="scienceagain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; you still need to show a dividing line.

We could always just arbitrarily choose one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832309998.0" user="Mo8ius" delta="False">
    <text>The "arbitrariness" of a dividing line generally indicates how likely it is to be challenged or thrown out by others thus making it a true "slippery slope" so to speak.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832394967.0" user="scienceagain" delta="False">
    <text>I mean "arbitrary" in the sense of "based on or determined by individual preference or convenience rather than by necessity or the intrinsic nature of something".  

That doesn't mean the slippery slope argument applies.  The voting age is arbitrary, but we're unlikely to decide to let one-year-olds vote any time soon.  Most laws are arbitrary, this one would be no different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832420917.0" user="Mo8ius" delta="False">
    <text>Your definition of arbitrary is not in line with what you are trying to imply. I am going to use a more straightforward definition (used in your context) with which I hope you will agree with; "Arbitrary: Based on random choice or personal whim, rather than any reason or system."

With regards to the overarching argument of eugenics, I will state that I believe a line should be drawn, but not "arbitrarily", but with regards to values that we hold in the majority, specifically the value of life. If a child risks being born with an illness that risks endangering their life in the short term, then all efforts should be made to either prevent such an illness through correction of the offending genetics, or at the very *least* having the option to abort given to the parents. The difference between what I have stated and what you have stated based on my definition of arbitrary is that it *is* based on some value that I hold, and some societies hold. 

I am going to further posit that rules, laws, and regulations that are subject to a real slippery slope tend not to be based on values that are not held strongly believed values within that society. Voting enfranchisement (and voting age) **IS* subject to the slippery slope in reality. Over the short span that our societies have had functioning democracies, there have been many groups (race, creed, class, and indeed, age) that have slowly but surely gained the vote. Without a strongly held belief of value in societies preventing someone who is 17 as opposed to 18 from voting may in the future inevitably overturn such a rule as has happened in many other countries. Although it is hard to argue that a 1-year old child should be allowed to vote, it is easy to see such a slope for the immediate vicinity of the current voting age.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832697789.0" user="scienceagain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I am going to use a more straightforward definition (used in your context) with which I hope you will agree with

No.  That's not what I meant, which is why I specified which definition of arbitrary I was using.  Reason can still be used to help draw the line (like we do with the voting age).

&amp;gt; Voting enfranchisement (and voting age) *IS subject to the slippery slope in reality.

No, it isn't.  Lowering the voting age from 21 to 18 does not put us at any more risk of eliminating age restrictions on voting.

&amp;gt; Although it is hard to argue that a 1-year old child should be allowed to vote, it is easy to see such a slope for the immediate vicinity of the current voting age.

That's why it's not a slippery slope.  I'm beginning to think you don't understand what "slippery slope" means.  The slope you're describing is quite stable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832714142.0" user="Mo8ius" delta="False">
    <text>I said hard to argue, not impossible. Try this; its unlikely for a child of 1 to walk up to the voting booth and cast a ballot on their own. At the same time, its not permissible to have more than one person in a booth at a time. Why have a law that forbids something that can't happen anyway? Or try this; our opinions and beliefs are all influenced by others, old are just as susceptible as the young when it comes to being uninformed, why discriminate? In fact, I think you'll find there are plenty of people who WILL argue to abolish voting age restrictions completely. This is *absolutely* a slippery slope.

The reason I am giving you an alternate definition of arbitrary is that your definition doesn't mean anything regarding making laws. What separates an arbitrary definition from a non-arbitrary definition? Reason is *also* the driving factor behind non-arbitrary laws using *your* definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832722959.0" user="scienceagain" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is absolutely a slippery slope.

The concept of a "slippery slope" is an informal fallacy.  I'm trying to explain to you why it's a fallacy.  With situations A, B, C, and D, going from A to B, doesn't necessarily mean we'll end up at D.  Being obtuse doesn't make you right.  In reality, there is evidence that the voting age is not a slippery slope, since we've lowered the voting age and very few people are proposing to lower it further.

&amp;gt; The reason I am giving you an alternate definition of arbitrary is that your definition doesn't mean anything regarding making laws.

This is amusing.  I'm not sure you understand how language works.  If I used the word "bat" in the sense of a baseball bat, would you try to tell me that I'm actually referring to a flying mammal?

&amp;gt; What separates an arbitrary definition from a non-arbitrary definition?

I don't understand what you're asking.

&amp;gt; Reason is also the driving factor behind non-arbitrary laws using your definition.

I should hope reason is used in making all laws.  Which laws are non-arbitrary?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832729914.0" user="Mo8ius" delta="False">
    <text>It remains to be seen that voting age will not be lowered further. It has already been lowered to 16 in other countries, I do not see why something similar could not happen in the future.

&amp;gt;This is amusing. I'm not sure you understand how language works. 

Are you really making ad hominem attacks now? I am not going to continue responding if that is how you would like to proceed here. I am discussing your use of the word "arbitrary" because I do not see this particular definition having any meaningful impact on our discussion. Arbitrary (as you mean it) as opposed to what?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832737982.0" user="scienceagain" delta="False">
    <text>If the slippery slope were true, you should think that we will eliminate it.

&amp;gt; Are you really making ad hominem attacks now?

Nope.  An *ad hominem* is an irrelevant argument made against an opponent instead of against their argument.  I also explained to you how you demonstrated a lack of linguistics proficiency.

&amp;gt; Arbitrary (as you mean it) as opposed to what?

Non-arbitrary.  Many people (possibly you, for all I know) believe in such a thing as "natural law" or some other objective framework for determining laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831804699.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>Eugenics is a slippery slope. 95% of anyone with a noticeable genetic co edition isn't going to get a chance to reproduce so their DNA isn't exactly pissing in the gene pool...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
