<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831666061.0" user="Robertbobby91" delta="False">
    <text>Humanity has tried to control many forces of nature. Extreme forced control has never lead to good things. 

Fire -&amp;gt; bombs

Water -&amp;gt; massive regional flooding

Air -&amp;gt; Unparalleled pollution.

Earth -&amp;gt; strip mining.


I cannot trust this species to rule totally over our genes. We tried that for a while. Marriage licenses lead to abuse against homosexuals. Racial purity lead to racism and genocide.

Current attempts at genetic control have lead to weaker, less nutritious crops and more susceptibility to blight.

While I'm sure, as a pro life individual, I'd sleep easier knowing nobody could kill a fetus without the permission of the government, just as nobody could create one either, I also know that the result would be a terrible one.

You can't just make 30 million people sterile and give them no hope for a future and expect them to peacefully go on.

I'd offer you a compromise. Eugenics should be practiced on our off world colonies. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
