<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="12" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831790877.0" user="Tommy2255" delta="False">
    <text>If I found out that I was going to be a father, and that the child would be born with severe mental retardation, I would want the mother to have an abortion. But even I, as the father of that child, would not force that decision upon her. And you would have her forced to abort the child by the government?

And when I say "forced", I mean that literally, because that's what it would come down to: the use of violence against an innocent, pregnant woman, for the sole purpose of destroying what could have become an innocent child, supposedly for her own good.

There's nobody more against the so-called "rights of the handicapped" than me. I've had to work with mentally handicapped people who were hired not because they could do the job, but out of charity, given the job specifically because they were incapable of doing it. I don't believe in making concessions for people. But I also don't believe in having them killed. The mother has that right, because it is her body that they need to grow before they're born. The father has some say because he will also have to (or should have to) support and help raise the child. But a woman giving birth to a child that will never grow to be the fullest measure of a human being is not harming anyone. And harming her protects nobody else.

It doesn't matter if it would be a wiser choice for her to abort the fetus. It isn't your choice to make. If she wants to ruin her own life, that's her decision. She won't thank you for stopping her. People resent being protected from themselves. And by "resent", I mean "despise with righteous fury". What if a pregnant woman runs? Are you going to send armed men to drag her to the abortion clinic? What if the woman and her husband are armed? Are you going to ask men to risk their lives to "protect" her? That isn't an unlikely outcome; it's an inevitability if such a law were passed.

People's lives are ruined by mentally ill children because they work themselves to death helping that child rather than accept a lost cause: because they cannot imagine anything more horrific than losing their child. Do you think they would welcome someone forcing their self-described worst case scenario upon them? Do you honestly believe you would meet anything less than violent resistance?

And at the end of the day, even if it worked, who would benefit? Who is this "humanity" that you would save? It isn't people like you and me. People without the capacity to dress themselves in the morning are not a threat to people with the capacity to actually accomplish things (at least not if the government didn't take our money to give to the incompetent and incapable. They aren't a threat by themselves is my point). It wouldn't be the parents. Many of them would commit suicide, the rest would live the rest of their lives in bitterness and depression (some wouldn't, but those are likely to mostly be the people who would have chosen to abort the child anyway). It wouldn't be the children who would have been born partly incapacitated either, they wouldn't exist anymore, and therefore could not be benefited or harmed by any action or inaction taken by anybody. If they were born, then perhaps one day they may decide that they don't want to live a cripple, but then they could make the choice to kill themselves. Or their parents could decide to stop supporting them and let them wither away. If they want to live, and their parents want them to live, by what kind of arrogance would you decide otherwise on their behalf?

For a parent about to give birth to a severely retarded child, the decision to abort could be their salvation, but being forced to abort would certainly be their destruction.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
