<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831705059.0" user="Migchao" delta="False">
    <text>1. What disabilities would be euthanasia-worthy?  Even disorders like Down's Syndrome and mental retardation have a mild form where the person can have a relatively normal, independent life with only a few setbacks.  Who decides what illnesses will warrant a forced abortion or euthanasia?

2. Who decides whether a person is a 'drain on society'?  Also, 'insanity' isn't a diagnosis.  It is strictly a legal term that questions whether a defendant knew right from wrong when committing the crime.  You would need a set of standards a person would need to meet in order to be 'insane', which is also an issue since psychology is a MUCH more subjective field than regular medicine is.  If every mentally ill person is to be judged as 'insane' and killed, you're literally offing the 50% of Americans who will experience a mental illness at least once in their lives.

3. That creates a huge issue and violates a woman's autonomy. I don't believe the government should be able to violate a woman's reproductive rights by banning abortion, and I also don't believe the government should be able to forcibly abort her fetus.  It strikes me as rape in a way: the most private areas of your body are being invaded, it is totally against your will and the sense of terror and helplessness is overwhelming.  Read about the forced abortion of Feng Jianmei.  Things like that happen in China and North Korea all the time.  Read the testimonies of women subject to forced abortions so you know just what you are advocating for.

4. You think that creates anxiety?  Imagine the fear of a pregnant woman who wants to keep her child but is being forced into an operating room, being held down while having an IV of anesthesia shoved into her arm, and having her fetus torn out of her while she is unconscious.  Or having her disabled child whisked away and euthanized without her even consenting to it.

6. It was their choice to have the child.  If they didn't want to get an abortion, adopt the kid out, take advantage of safe-haven laws etc., that is 100% their choice.  And if they aren't using taxpayer money to care for the kid, then you have even LESS of a say in what they decide to do with a disabled fetus or child.

7. Slippery slope in two ways.  First, once you give the government the right to decide whether you give birth or who should live/die, you open up a can of worms no one wants to have opened.  Second, YOUR intentions are good, but it doesn't mean the intentions of the people running the program 10, 30 or 50 years down the line are good.  If the government wants to wipe out a certain minority (racial, political, religious etc.) group, they could easily do that.  Maybe not in the US, but there are many countries right now that have minority groups they would LOVE to wipe out.  

I support late-term abortion (only in the case of the mother being in mortal danger and/or the child has a severe birth defect) and voluntary euthanasia.  But there is no way I can support a forced abortion and euthanasia program.  Yes, it sucks to see severely disabled people who are kept alive (in vain) through government money, and to see the impact it has on the caregivers.  But it is a small price to pay, because the potential consequences of a program like that would be huge.

Also, read about Action T4 (the Nazi program for forcibly euthanizing the disabled and mentally ill).  It was done with the intention of eradicating these serious disorders and illnesses, and ended up being a horrific program that violated the rights of everyone involved, tore over 70,000 families apart, etc.  I hate bringing up Nazis in these debates but Action T4 was one of the largest programs of its kind and it is something worth researching. It shows you how horribly wrong a euthanasia program can go and that making these things a choice is the best option.

All in all, I think your intentions are good.  But there a lot of moral and ethical issues and they're too large for me to ignore.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
