<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831664387.0" user="avantvernacular" delta="False">
    <text>The issue is here is how our genetic diversity as a species meets the unknown future. Things like genetic disorders, availabilities, abnormalities and anomalies may be advantages to the individual, but it is possible to prove advantageous in some situations like disease resistance. For example, individuals with [sickle cell disease](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sickle-cell_disease) have a greatly increased resistance to malaria over those with healthy blood cells.

Problem is, we don't know what new diseases or pathogens may become the next scourge of the human race, and we definitely don't know which genetic factors may give our specifies a chance to survive it. 

Consider that in less then a century, humanity has faced multiple pandemics that have seriously threatened the long term survival of our species, such as [Spanish flu,](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1918_flu_pandemic) which may have killed as many as 100 million people (to put in in perspective, in it's first 24 weeks it killed more people than AIDS did in 24 years.) We still don't know what caused it, and we still don't know why it simply seemed to just stop less than 2 years later, and in time we seemed to have simply forgotten about ir. However, it should serve as a excellent reminded that humanity's survival is not as safe a bet as we might have once thought.

We don't know what new disease may be on the horizon. We *definitely* don't know what genetics might give us hope to survive it, and be eliminating what we shortsightedly see as "undesirable," we may also be inadvertently hurting our chance to survive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831769519.0" user="nizo505" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly all of this, plus the tendency of humans to "fix" things (often breaking them worse). Cane toads (and pretty much every other invasive species purposely introduced) is a great example of our short shortsightedness.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26831786351.0" user="WalksAmongHeathens" delta="False">
    <text>*Bromus tectorum* will one day rule the world, I fear. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
