<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26833227008.0" user="ordersponge" delta="False">
    <text>I don't necessarily disagree with all of your points, but the serious problem with eugenics is that it necessarily demands a tyrannical (if not downright dystopian) government. Someone, somewhere, gets to decide where the line is between children who get to live and those who have to die. What basis are they using to make that decision? The amount of resources a child will generate over its lifespan versus those it will consume? If that's the case, then you'll have to deal with a lot of factors other than disability, such as (for example) drug addiction and traumatic injuries. You're making a value judgement about the worth and rights of a human being that extends far beyond their disabilities at birth.

So then suppose you have a person who, according to your calculus, is being a "complete drain on society." For your program to work, they need to die regardless of what they think or what their family thinks. There's no way you'd get everyone to voluntarily euthenize their loved ones, so you need to have someone whose job it is to take away a family's child and kill them against their wishes. 

I'm not making a slippery slope argument that eugenics leads to tyranny. I'm saying that tyranny is *necessary* for eugenics to work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
