<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95163485.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1knom5/i_think_eugenics_should_be_practiced_for/">
    <title>I think eugenics should be practiced for humanity's sake. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>throwed-away</original_poster>
    <original_post>1. Although some disabilities aren't hereditary, almost all disabilities and mental issues come from genetics and genetic issues. 

2. I only believe this for people who'd be a complete drain on society. Yes, there are exceptions like Stephen Hawking and what not, but that's exactly what they are. Exceptions. I believe there should be no debate over those who're mentally insane as well. 

3. I believe the government should force this because the parents wouldn't know right from wrong while being distraught by emotions. Ultimately, it would benefit the parents much more to abort the disabled child. Have you seen how much of a life-ruiner those disabled kids are? 

4. They also cause anxiety in the parents because of the thoughts of what will happen after they're not around. 

5. It may seem inhumane now, but keep in mind that I'm talking about abortion here. The disabled currently alive can live their lives and what not, I'm talking about those that aren't born yet. Right when the doctors find out that the kid will turn out fucked up, they should do something about it.

6. Okay, okay. So you're morally higher than me. I'm a monster for thinking this way. **Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?** </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26831671186.0" user="tiddlypeeps" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Can you honestly look me in the eyes and tell me that the lives of those parents of fucked up kids wouldn't be much, much better without all that bullshit? How many parents are having their money and time drained because of this stuff?

Shouldn't it be the parents decision if they want to take on that burden? What right has the government to force those parents to abort the child when they don't want to? If the only people who's lives are negatively impacted by the child are the parents then why is it an issue for anybody else if they want to put themselves in that position?

You say for humanities sake, but how does humanity benefit from this? I'll agree that some handicaps inhibit people from meaningfully contributing to society, but most people don't contribute to society in any meaningful way so why should they be treated differently.

Logistically a big issue with eugenics is deciding what criteria determines weather someone is genetically inferior or not and weather they should be culled because plenty of people with genetic disorders can contribute as much to society as any other person. You mention Stephen Hawking as an exception, but he is only an exception if you expect all people with genetic disorders to contribute to society at that level. Most people with no genetic disorders will never contribute to society at that level. There are plenty of people with genetic disorders that work paid jobs, pay taxes and live normal lives. At what point do you decide that someone's genetics are good enough to live? Do you only kill off the people that can't move and wont' likely make it past the toddler years and will spend those years in agony anyway or do you kill off all people with any genetic imperfections? Who makes these decisions? There is a huge grey area there.

Then there is the issue that a lot of mental disorders are not genetic, or at the very least there are no observable links to genetics. So even if you successfully cull all genetic disorders you are still going to be left with a lot of the mental disorders that can be truly disruptive to society, like psychosis, schizophrenia and other mental disorders that have strong links to a persons up bringing. So I don't think your solution really benefits society, it only takes imperfect babies away from parents that really want to raise them.

Your solution will also never breed out all imperfections as many are caused by genetic mutations, mistakes or glitches that happen when a sperm and egg fuse together. As far as I'm aware down syndrome is one of these. You could continue aborting those babies till the end of time, but I think the whole point of eugenics was to stop imperfect people breeding and producing more imperfect people. 

So if it doesn't work then what is the point?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832008297.0" user="Ausen" delta="False">
    <text>∆

I could feel like there was something up with eugenics that I just couldn't put my finger on. You described it perfectly- who decides what's genetically pleasing? Who decides what lives or die, who can reproduce or not? You essentially need a man to play God. Thank you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
