<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832152185.0" user="spasticus" delta="False">
    <text>Interesting point about only staying engaged for 20% of the time. I will agree with this to a certain extent but you are making too many assumptions. 

I work an office job and I am productive 2/8 hours a day. Is this productivity in a consistent and contiguous 2 hour block? For me the answer is no. I have to be at work for 8 hours to get my 2 hours of productivity. It also seems like this 2 hours of productivity comes to me at completely random times of the day with some days more than 2 hours some days less. If I am at work for 4 hours I may only get 1 hour of productivity. 

You are also, as others here have pointed out, completely discounting jobs in service industries, many of which physically require you to be there or do some activity. I also don't think people will ever choose to have their hair cut by robots so there is a limit to increasing technological productivity and there will always be a demand for 8 hour a day work.   

In the context of office work I think that people are capable of more than 2 hours work a day (think of the "work" I am doing right now on reddit that I could be applying to my job) but companies are not generally good at measuring and motivating this. Also I believe that if companies were able to correctly measure productivity and said - "Wow we see now that you do all your work in only 20 hours a week. You can get paid the same and come in 20 hours or we can pay you double and you can do 40 hours productive work". In almost all cases people will choose to work 40 hours and have more stuff. This is human nature. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832754411.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, some excellent points here.  There certainly is  a limit to what we want done through technology (your haircut example, for instance).  I do think that there are enough people, and enough unnecessary jobs and work-hours to eliminate, that we could, for instance, have twice as many barber working half as much time.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833885948.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In almost all cases people will choose to work 40 hours and have more stuff. This is human nature. 

This is the USA mentality, not human nature... elsewhere the priorities and choices are different.

But it's primarily the owners who decide that: "Wow we see now that you do all your work in only 20 hours a week. We'll fire your colleague, now you can do his work in the same time too! We'll give you a honorable mention on our yearly shareholders' diner (employees not allowed)."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
