<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832218949.0" user="ortho_engineer" delta="False">
    <text>Do you honestly think if you were only asked to work 6 hours a day, rather than 8, that you would not still 'screw around on reddit all day'?  You mentioned Pareto (80/20) in your reasoning, and  yet you ignore it in your conclusion - the rule would still apply whether you worked 8 hours a day, or 2.  
  
The fact of the matter is there will always be people that screw off most of the day while others put in an honest effort the whole time.  If you are one of the former, then you need to realize that you are not the corporation's focus in making 40 hours a week mandatory.  Requiring those from the latter to work 40 hours a week ensures the company gets 8 product hours out of their top employees, rather than 6 (if 30 hour week), which has a greater impact on the company's growth than the screw-off's output of 1.6 productive hours, instead of 1.2 (if 30 hour week).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832370510.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you honestly think if you were only asked to work 6 hours a day, rather than 8, that you would not still 'screw around on reddit all day'?

Maybe. We have no stats on this, I believe, so I have to use anecdote to make a plausible counter argument.

I'm a chemist. Some people in my field spend 14 hours a day in the lab, 7 days a week. On average, people work about 70-80 hours a week. We're all paid for 40, but there is competition to put in the most hours. A few mavericks work 40 hours a week: 9-5, Monday-Friday. They (we, actually) survive on their (our) results. They publish as often in as good journals and have the same body of work to show for a given time frame. The difference is that they *work* exclusively when they're at work. No facebook. No reddit. Just work. It's amazing how fucking about can turn an 8 hour workday into a 14 our one. 

To me, it seems that people have about 6 hours of productivity in them per work day. You can squeeze it out in 8 with lunch and a coffee break here and there, or you can extend it all the way to 14 plus overtime on weekends by working inefficiently and messing about instead of working. It seems to depend on how interesting your off time is. Kids and partner you like with plenty of fun activities? 40 hours a week. Partner you can't stand or live alone with no social life? Welcome to perpetual work. 

Obviously depends on the job, this is just the view from science. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832694660.0" user="someenglishrose" delta="False">
    <text>As a biologist, I have noticed a certain tendency of people without much of an outside life to spend more time in the lab, however even those of us who would love to go home and see our families/friends are sometimes unable to do so because we work with living things. For example, if something needs attention every three hours for 24, you've gotta stay all night (even if for two hours out of every three, you're not working). If something needs feeding once a day, you'll have to come in on Saturday and Sunday.

I was interested in OP's statement that

&amp;gt; science... but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

In my field, certainly, people will often work more than 40 hours a week not because they really love your work (although of course lots of people do) but because if they don't, they simply can't do their job.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832701708.0" user="h76CH36" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, I suppose that it depends on the PI, more than anything else. Certainly some types of science that are going to require odd hours but I feel that there are often ways to work around that (takes a lot of micromanaging and a certain willingness to not progress as quickly as otherwise). Not always possible,  to be sure. 

ON a side note, when I work too much, I find that the quality of my work suffers and that I don't get any good ideas. All of my best ideas occur to me on my free time. Perhaps a decent reason to purposely sacrifice productivity in the lab for creativity in science. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832752906.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The same thing happens where I work.  It's a non-profit, and sort of a "feel good" one, so that there is competition as to who's working the most/hardest.  I'm the only one who ever leaves right at 5.  Thankfully, my supervisor, as well as the ceo, are more similar to me than to the "who can work longest" folks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832456225.0" user="ns156" delta="False">
    <text>Have to disagree there. I work an 8 hour day in an office, and usually spend about half of that actually doing work. If I could come in at 10 AM, leave at 2, and bang out that four hours all in a row, I would never have time (presumably because people would be paying attention to how much I got done in that 4 hour block) or really the urge to start wasting time on my phone and/or on the internet. I'd be busy the entire time. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
