<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832285951.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>I would agree with you; however based on, your word choice ("The economic machine") and some of your other comments I'm doubtful I would agree on causes it; soooo... What do you believe causes it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832758847.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What causes the 40 hour work work?  On a socioeconomic level, being part of a system that focuses on economic growth as a net positive, discounting sustainability/ecological harm, etc.  On a personal level, replacing a present-minded lifestyle where non-material things satisfy you with a consumerist, almost addictive, mentality trying to fill the void.  This sounds REALLY cliche, I know, but I think there's some truth to it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833409556.0" user="monkyyy" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This sounds REALLY cliche, I know, but I think there's some truth to it.

I'm more a fan of blaming government growth, partially warfare; at the height of the iraq war the american military was using "400,000 and 800,000 barrels a day." (http://www.allgov.com/news/top-stories/us-military-uses-more-oil-per-day-than-the-entire-nation-of-pakistan?news=841674)

To put that into prospective; india uses 3,000 http://www.indexmundi.com/energy.aspx?country=in&amp;amp;product=oil&amp;amp;graph=consumption

If we are addicted to anything that wastes resources its warfare.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
