<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832089022.0" user="TylertheDouche" delta="False">
    <text>....so whats the other side? 40 hours a week are needed?

it is necessary for people who work for businesses that pay by the hour.

waiters/waitresses are engaged almost their entire 40 hours.

any retail employee is usually engaged almost their entire 40 hours

i think your cmv is too general. i almost dont get what you are arguing. Make all businesses enforce less hours?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832094503.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Okay, so I added to the title: I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week. CMV


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832146982.0" user="pppppatrick" delta="False">
    <text>so... you're saying "people will be happier if they had to work less"

isn't this still too general (and sort of undeniable, nobody wants to work long hours)

and judging from your other replies you really don't have a case

&amp;gt; I wish I could find a source on this (help?)

your argument stems from anecdotal evidence, and logically don't you think if management could cut hours and still produce the same amount of work, they would be doing so anyways?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832520761.0" user="screampuff" delta="False">
    <text>Would we be paid the same as if we worked 40? That would essentially double the cost of employees somewhere like a hospital which needs to run 24/7.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832750007.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying (and, as I've said before, this leans heavily socialist, which I is not the thrust of my argument) that we have the means to produce the same amount of valuable products/services/whatever where everyone works less.....so, no, in our current system if you were getting paid hourly you'd get less, but I think that there's a way to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833885070.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and, as I've said before, this leans heavily socialist, which I is not the thrust of my argument

It's actually what Marx saw as a necessary precondition for the communist society: rising productivity with capital goods producing most products, causing unemployment and impoverishment among the working class, inducing a revolt against the owning class.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832729453.0" user="sass_pea" delta="False">
    <text>i think saying "everyone" is too broad. look at the responses below. machinists, factory workers, people in agriculture, anyone in medicine and health care...they work their asses off for 8 hours with minimal down time. i think it's primarily office workers that this argument applies to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832748701.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So, I realize this starts to quickly verge on a state-socialist work-assignment sort of society, but what I was more thinking was that yes, everyone can work 20 hours a week, and maybe we have twice as many doctors and farmers to cover what needs to be done, and the empty and unproductive work just isn't done anymore...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832780876.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>What sort of specialization, historical knowledge, or facts do you have to support such a theory?

I am totally unaware of any sort of top down economy that hasn't resulted in essentially the opposite economy you profess to desire.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832788765.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>While I'm not proposing reverting to a hunter-gatherer lifestyle, there's ample evidence that they actually "worked" only 20 or 25 hours each week.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832794413.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, they were only supporting those they wanted to support. There was no welfare. The handicapped died. The old died. The ill died. Today we are forced to fund the life of those who can not work. Some (like family and friends) we do so voluntarily, others, against our will.

Many of our 'above 20 hours' work and productivity go to others.

Also, today there are 7 billion people.

Would you force people to not work as much as they want? Please expand on your top down economic planning ideas. What evidence do you have that top down ends up MORE efficient then 'invisible hand'?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832807575.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not proposing top-down economic planning, and my top priority is not EFFICIENCY, it is enjoyment of life.  I feel that the point you made are salient, for sure, but that we could still get what we wanted/needed (luxuries included) with less work.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832813105.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; my top priority is not EFFICIENCY, it is enjoyment of life.

A reduction in productivity means people die and suffer.

&amp;gt; but that we could still get what we wanted/needed (luxuries included) with less work.

How? You assert this, but I've seen no evidence that it is true. Does this include those who are totally unproductive? The lame?

What if I wanted to work 40 hours? What if I wanted to pay people to work 40 hours? What if I wanted to be employed for 40 hours? What are you going to do about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832820560.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A reduction in productivity means people die and suffer.

That seems like a ridiculous claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832827633.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>It is such an obviously true claim that I am lost as how you could not understand it.

If food was infinite, no one would starve to death. Food is finite. People currently starve to death. A reduction in quanitity of food means more people starve to death.

If wants were infinite no one would want. Wants are finite. People currently suffer for want. A reduction in quantity of wants means more people suffer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833883914.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Firstly, they were only supporting those they wanted to support. There was no welfare. The handicapped died. The old died. The ill died. 

Evidence contradicts this Hobbesian view on prehistory. There are skeletons with what would have been deadly injuries in a dog-eat-dog society, yet those injuries have partly healed, indicating that hopeless cases also received care.

&amp;gt;Would you force people to not work as much as they want? Please expand on your top down economic planning ideas. What evidence do you have that top down ends up MORE efficient then 'invisible hand'?

Given that we produce plenty of food but fail to get it to people who need it, I'd say there's plenty of room for improvement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833993216.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Evidence contradicts this Hobbesian view on prehistory. There are skeletons with what would have been deadly injuries in a dog-eat-dog society, yet those injuries have partly healed, indicating that hopeless cases also received care.

I'm aware. I was trying to use his own leftist views against him.

If a man argues that hands don't exist and that he is an expert juggler, you ask him how he juggles without hands.

People wont stop being charitable without the government, quite the opposite. Once shortages show up, governments are the first to load buses full of the handicapped for the gas chambers.

&amp;gt; Given that we produce plenty of food but fail to get it to people who need it, I'd say there's plenty of room for improvement.

In where in history does top down economic planning improve distribution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26835195162.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;People wont stop being charitable without the government, quite the opposite. Once shortages show up, governments are the first to load buses full of the handicapped for the gas chambers.

That must be why hunger and weak governments are commonly occuring in the same country in Africa? The lack of government is not a guarantee for prosperity, nor the other way around. It's just a tool that can be used or abused. 

&amp;gt;In where in history does top down economic planning improve distribution?

Easy. Everywhere where you have negative externalities to cope with. Central planning is more efficient. The only potential problem is coping with shocks.

Given that big companies are entities that make decisions at the top and pass them down below, what is the alternative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26835200437.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; that must be why hunger and weak governments are commonly occuring in the same country in Africa?

Ya, exactly. All the trouble with Africa is their weak governments. /s

&amp;gt; Everywhere where you have negative externalities to cope with. Central planning is more efficient.

I was looking for actual historical examples. I would love to hear one if you can wade through all the examples of central planning ended up in the largest genocides in history.

&amp;gt; Given that big companies are entities that make decisions at the top and pass them down below, what is the alternative?

That isn't a given. Without government favors, companies have to act in a way that maintains their income from voluntary customers.

As far as corporate structure goes, many successful businesses use diffuse power structures. These are usually non-publicly traded companies though. As soon as a company becomes public the incentive structure changes to try and grab as much stock money as they can in as short a time as possible. This money coming from government incentives. Tax free retirement money, tax free stock investments etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26835289208.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Ya, exactly. All the trouble with Africa is their weak governments. /s

Yes. Lacking governments that are reliable and robust enough not to become infected by corruption are one of the main hindrances for development in Africa.

&amp;gt;I was looking for actual historical examples.

Eg. Early civilizations like China, Babylonia, Egypt centralized water management and/or grain reserves.

&amp;gt;I would love to hear one if you can wade through all the examples of central planning ended up in the largest genocides in history.

As I said, central planning is a tool. Don't blame the axe, blame the maniac wielding it. Beats me how you're going to blame eg. the Yugoslavian genocides on central planning, since everyone was after everyone else there.

&amp;gt;That isn't a given.

Then it's your turn for historical examples :) 

&amp;gt;Without government favors, companies have to act in a way that maintains their income from voluntary customers.

All the government favor they need is unrestricted accumulation of property titles. Are you in favor of dropping that?

What stops these companies from enforcing their own desires without government, anyway?

&amp;gt;As far as corporate structure goes, many successful businesses use diffuse power structures. These are usually non-publicly traded companies though. As soon as a company becomes public the incentive structure changes to try and grab as much stock money as they can in as short a time as possible. This money coming from government incentives. Tax free retirement money, tax free stock investments etc.

I see no reason why that money needs to come from governments. A money grab is a money grab, and they're quite capable of doing that on their own. How on earth is that profit priority going to change anything for the better?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26835300980.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes. Lacking governments that are reliable and robust enough not to become infected by corruption are one of the main hindrances for development in Africa.

I guess I am confused what you think a strong government is. I would consider Nazi Germany a 'strong' government, rather lacking in corruption.

&amp;gt; Eg. Early civilizations like China, Babylonia, Egypt centralized water management and/or grain reserves.

Can I have some sort of citation. I am rather unfamiliar with this claim and would like to read about it.

&amp;gt; Then it's your turn for historical examples :)

Valve is the one that stand out in my mind.

&amp;gt; All the government favor they need is unrestricted accumulation of property titles. Are you in favor of dropping that?

Unsure what you are asking.

&amp;gt; What stops these companies from enforcing their own desires without government, anyway?

The fact that their income is dependent on people paying them. Armies are expensive.

&amp;gt; A money grab is a money grab, and they're quite capable of doing that on their own. How on earth is that profit priority going to change anything for the better?

I was claiming that the stock market is a reflection of the government's polices, and these policies are why publicly traded companies act the way they do.

If putting money into the stock market was not the only hedge against inflation and taxation then the quantity of money in the market would drop dramatically, and the money left would be comprised of much more competent investors (people who knew what they were doing).

Get rich quick schemes would fail more often, and sound long term companies would get a higher percent of the investments.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837503601.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I guess I am confused what you think a strong government is. I would consider Nazi Germany a 'strong' government, rather lacking in corruption.

Perhaps a *reliable* government is a better term for what I mean.

&amp;gt;Can I have some sort of citation. I am rather unfamiliar with this claim and would like to read about it.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hydraulic_empire
http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ancient_Egypt#Government_and_economy

&amp;gt;Valve is the one that stand out in my mind.

That is one single example, and the article on flat organization itself states that the practice is limited to small companies.

&amp;gt;Unsure what you are asking.

The main government boon they profit from is the enforcement and unlimited accumulation of property rights. Are you going to abolish property rights?

&amp;gt;The fact that their income is dependent on people paying them. Armies are expensive.

Not having one while your neighbour does is much, much more expensive. Sooner or later someone will try it.

&amp;gt;I was claiming that the stock market is a reflection of the government's polices, and these policies are why publicly traded companies act the way they do.
If putting money into the stock market was not the only hedge against inflation and taxation then the quantity of money in the market would drop dramatically, and the money left would be comprised of much more competent investors (people who knew what they were doing).
Get rich quick schemes would fail more often, and sound long term companies would get a higher percent of the investments.

That sounds *very* speculative.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837547458.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Perhaps a reliable government is a better term for what I mean.

I don't think anyone has figured out how to make one of those.

&amp;gt; That is one single example, and the article on flat organization itself states that the practice is limited to small companies.

That doesn't disagree with anything I said. And that in the current economy government incentives (and dis-incentives) cause 'large' companies to begin with.

&amp;gt; The main government boon they profit from is the enforcement and unlimited accumulation of property rights. Are you going to abolish property rights?

The government is the primary infringer of property rights. This is like saying you need a thief to guard your stuff.

No, I want the thief to stop telling me he is protecting my stuff while stealing it.

&amp;gt; Not having one while your neighbour does is much, much more expensive. Sooner or later someone will try it.

Do you find it humorous that your doomsday scenario looks like the world we have today?

&amp;gt; That sounds very speculative.

The fed is speculative. At least I'm not using violence or other people's money on my speculation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837788532.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't think anyone has figured out how to make one of those.

Trust is hard to gain and easy to lose, but it's possible.

&amp;gt;That doesn't disagree with anything I said. And that in the current economy government incentives (and dis-incentives) cause 'large' companies to begin with.

That's an unprovable statement.

&amp;gt;The government is the primary infringer of property rights. This is like saying you need a thief to guard your stuff.

That's ridiculous. How does government infringe on property rights? How would property rights exist without governments?

&amp;gt;Do you find it humorous that your doomsday scenario looks like the world we have today?

It's not a doomsday scenario, it's just an inevitable evolution.

&amp;gt;At least I'm not using violence or other people's money on my speculation.

How do you enforce your property rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837806200.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's ridiculous. How does government infringe on property rights? How would property rights exist without governments?

How would someone keep that which they produce or trade for without a monopoly on the use of force?

How would someone talk openly about whatever they want without a monopoly on the use of force?

How would someone have children? How would someone eat Cheetos? I see absolutely no positive connection between a monopoly on the use of force and an increase in property rights.

&amp;gt; How do you enforce your property rights?

Locks on my doors and a gun in my bedroom. But that doesn't work against the government very well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837867312.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How would someone keep that which they produce or trade for without a monopoly on the use of force?
How would someone talk openly about whatever they want without a monopoly on the use of force?
How would someone have children? How would someone eat Cheetos? I see absolutely no positive connection between a monopoly on the use of force and an increase in property rights.

I'll answer your questions if you answer mine.

&amp;gt; Locks on my doors and a gun in my bedroom. But that doesn't work against the government very well.

So you use violence as well. I don't see what the difference is.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837868973.0" user="Not_Pictured" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'll answer your questions if you answer mine.

What I mean is that I fundamentally do not understand your question. It's like asking me how I will avoid being raped if there isn't a monopoly on rape.

&amp;gt; So you use violence as well. I don't see what the difference is.

You do not see the difference between self defense and assault? I am not against violence, just the initiation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26837877970.0" user="silverionmox" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; What I mean is that I fundamentally do not understand your question. It's like asking me how I will avoid being raped if there isn't a monopoly on rape.

Why yes, how would the prevalence of rape be affected if suddenly there were no more laws enforced against it, and no recourse to justice afterwards?

&amp;gt;You do not see the difference between self defense and assault? I am not against violence, just the initiation.

You're threatening anyone that could use what you claim as your property. If that's not initiating violence, I don't know what is.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832798678.0" user="sass_pea" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you mean, but the jobs that work those long hours require a lot of specialized training and doubling their force would be quite a feat. Plus, how could surgeons who need to do 10 hour operations function? Would they just pass the baton mid-way through because it's time to clock out?  Anyone who's doing something that requires a lot of technical skill is going to have difficulty being very productive with this schedule. It just doesn't seem practical. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832407910.0" user="lesquee" delta="False">
    <text>Add to that list teachers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
