<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832161510.0" user="arksien" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so there's two parts to this issue, assuming we are talking about the same thing, as this is a fairly broad topic which could be interpreted in many ways. I'm going to try my best to come from the angle which I believe you are.

The first part of the issue is assuming that all fields, and all groups within all fields function the same way. We must first differentiate salaried fields and per-hour fields. Typically, the per-hour fields actually do require people to work as many hours as they are being paid. As for salaried fields, the actual input time isn't necessarily guaranteed to be 40 hours, and is rarely treated as such. Some people will work more, some will work less. Some positions take the time more seriously than others. This is extremely flexible and will differ from field to field. The industry standard for restaurant managers, for example, is 55-60 hours. I promise you that very few floor managers at chain restaurants are "pursuing their passion" the way an athlete or musician is. Each industry has a general ballpark of hours to work and what they get paid for, which often revolves around 40 hours. Going back to hourly employees, no one is forcing them to work 40 hours. They usually choose to because it's often the maximum and want to earn as much as possible. If you lowered the work week to 20 hours, these people would be devastated. It's not like their work could afford to double their hourly rate. Their employer would, under this scenario, need to hire twice as many workers. It's not like the coffers are magical and that they can pay people $15 an hour that were earning $7.50, while doubling their work force. Their labor budget just quadrupled. This wouldn't work. 

The second issue you actually pointed out but failed to see. As you said, not all people will stay focused for 8-9 hours a day. However, the lack of focus is usually not time based, it's usually linked to the persons work ethic. Lets limit this discussion to salaried workers since I already mentioned why changing the time of hourly employees wouldn't work. If the work requirement was 6 hours, or 4 hours, do you think they would magically work that? What will happen is that the people who already work 40 hours while on salary will work their 20 hours, and the people who don't work their 40 hours will work even less. The people who are not working the entire time often are not actually interested in doing so. This is not always a bad thing, because maybe these people just got efficient at their job and earned themselves a little paid time-off, they just have to take it in their building of work. However, this shouldn't be treated as a standard. If the one at the top of the curve gets more efficient, you can't expect everyone to. This leads to over-fatigue of the people who aren't the top 1%. Using your highest achiever as the bench mark is dangerous. Perhaps allowing that person a little free time because they got their work done sooner than the deadline is a better system then telling everyone they must meet that mark and then they get sent home. A LOT of people would fail to meet the mark and the work environment would become more hazardous. 

Also, the same problem of hourly workers applies here. If we really did cut people down to 20 hours, we'd need to double the workforce. This means either halving peoples pay, devastating their lifestyle, or keeping their salary the same, which just doubled the employers payroll. This is equally non-feasible.

**Perhaps a better solution to the problem would be a better system for time off and vacation time. The US is notoriously far behind the curve on these issues. However, these issues don't have as much to do with the actual duration of business hours, but would alleviate much of the fatigue and monotony of life.**
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832760317.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I think you've hit the nail on the head.  I feel like the U.S. doesn't value vacation time like many other industrialized countries; like you should almost feel guilty for it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
