<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832326822.0" user="Calypsee" delta="False">
    <text>So you think the 40hr work week is unnecessary on all levels but then put two qualifiers/exceptions in your OP? I feel like your view is already changed...

Anyway, what about service workers? Maybe you sit at a desk and browse reddit all day, but waiters and waitresses are likely busy their entire shift - sometimes these types of employees are even coerced into not taking the breaks they're entitled to and deserve because the restaurant is so busy. 

And what about police officers? They're busy too, you can't just cut out their work.

Unemployment where I am is around 7% I think, but I think overall there's enough work to go around. If everybody was capped at a 20hr work week [or alternatively working 2 ten-hour days?] then you'd need double the people to get the work done, especially in the industries I named, and that just wouldn't fly. 

Plus, with all the free time on everybody's hands, they'd need something to do. So then all these people are going to go out places, museums, parks, for food, movies, etc. Those entertainment places will have to employ more people to keep up with the demand for entertainment. 

And if the standard work week was only 20 hours, how do you think people in the recreational/entertainment industries would feel about having to work extra to keep the masses entertained?

Plus, how would finances work? If you work half the time [compared to 40hr week], you should get paid half as much, right? But your rent isn't going to halve, neither will your car payments, grocery bill, phone bill, or anything else. 

If you personally are stuck in an office for 8hrs a day and all you do is goof off, talk to your boss about picking up extra responsibilities, or do something productive with your free time [Coursera, for example?] and get a career that engages you. Or convince your boss that you're efficient and you should get paid the same salary to work less hours and take every Friday off.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
