<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="95220169.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1kowcp/i_believe_that_the_40hour_workweek_is_unnecessary/">
    <title>I believe that the 40-hour workweek is unnecessary on any level. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>hobbitforming</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe that working 40 hours a week is entirely unnecessary for even (and perhaps especially for) technologically advanced first-world countries to thrive.  I feel that it isn't even possible for the majority of people to stay engaged for 8 or 9 hours a day, and that the 80/20 principle applies beautifully here (80 percent of work gets done during 20 percent of the time).

Our technological productivity has outpace our wants and needs to such a vast degree that it seems there are only to reasons justifying such a long work-week:

1-The economic machine needs people to be occupied so that they fall into the consumer mentality and fill up their few remaining hours with purchased items to entertain and fulfill themselves.  If people worked less, even if they were as productive, our economic growth would slow (which ecologically needs to happen, but I suppose can be seen as a negative).

2-Certain endeavors demand 40 hours or more a week.  Athletics, science, writing...but these are passion-based, rather than need-based.

I believe we could live happily in a world where everyone worked 20 hours each week.  CMV

edit: An awesome article that sums up my points much better than I can (thanks /u/WishingForBadThings)

http://www.strikemag.org/bullshit-jobs/</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26832780646.0" user="anon-209384756" delta="False">
    <text>I've been working 40 hour weeks for the last couple months.  I really need to go back to 50 to 60 hour weeks.  A colleague worked 107 last week (though that is very uncommon).  I don't know what world you are living in where 80% of your time in unproductive, but its very different from mine.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832788270.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>What sort of job do you do?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832852223.0" user="anon-209384756" delta="False">
    <text>Consulting</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26832883411.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>So (and I mean this from a very inquisitive spot...not meaning for it to come off as rude)...why do you *need* to go back to 50 or 60 hours a week?  Money?  Are there people that need your services (and couldn't find it with another consultant) for 50 or 60 hrs a week?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26833371010.0" user="anon-209384756" delta="False">
    <text>Our whole company is slammed with work.  The project I am responsible for are progressing slower than I'd like.  Its bad for my reputation/Promotions/raises.

More Hours billed also equals more bonus, so its not a bad thing from that perspective.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
