<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="959418709.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fv7o7p/cmv_2000s_wcw_wasnt_that_bad/">
    <title>CMV: 2000s wcw wasnt that bad</title>
    <original_poster>Jimmykindaexists</original_poster>
    <original_post>Wcw was a failing company based on falling profits and creative nightmares. But in my opinion wcw wasnt that bad. The midcard for wcw was good and it was very entertaining. There was solid talent around such as Rey Mysterio and Billy Kidman. While booking may have not been the greatest 2000s wcw wasnt the worst thing and imo would pass off as a solid wrestling promotion in this time and only died because of just how powerful wwe had gotten


Wcw had an influx of talented wrestlers and if they were stable with profits plus if AOL after the buy out didn't full blown hate on wcw most likely Eric Bischoff could have taken over and ran it solidly. With a new investor it wouldnt have died. To put this in perspective they had AJ Styles in 2001 one of the best wrestlers in the world right now.  Plus great guys like DDP, Booker T, Sting, Goldberg, Nash. Also having young guys like the before mentioned Rey and Kidman, 3 count the boy band, Sean O'haire. This is a solid lineup of guys honestly that could easily do things also the underrated Buff Bagwell who could hold his own in the ring.


I'm willing to hear more on why it's a bad promotion as I am a fairly casual wrestling fan. I'm not super in depth with the business. I want to know more why people don't like 2000s wcw because right now I'm just very confused on all the hate.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34010768813.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with WCW wasn't the talent, it was the booking. Sure, they had great guys who could do great things, but they weren't being allowed to. Instead, the old guard were allowed to run roughshod with booking, leading to shit like the 'Fingerpoke of Doom' and Starcade's 1997 'botched' ending that made Hogan look great.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
