<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="96422727.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1leo93/i_think_that_if_israel_had_gained_its/">
    <title>I think that if Israel had gained it's independence fair and square. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>AlexiPwns</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I know this is kind of political, but let's try to keep this on subject.

I'm a Zionist who is also an atheist, so let's try and keep religion out of this, because this is definitely not the reason I support Israel.

Thing is, there's this thing called "Romantic Nationalism", it's a form of nationalism in which the state derives its political legitimacy as an organic consequence of the unity of those it governs. 

In Israel's case that's religion and I'm pretty sure that that's how it got recognized as a state. I understand that a lot of people disagree with this because the land wasn't theirs to begin with and that just because some group claims an old book told them it is, is just a logical fallacy.

Problem is, almost the exact scenario happened almost 200 years ago with Finland. 

The Kalevala was a compilation of old Finnish folklore and mythology (Kind of like a bible, written to sum up oral mythology) During the Russian reign, the Finns tried to used the Kalevala to legitimize their nationality and gain recognition as a state. (Pretty much like the Zionist movements during the British mandate).

In case number one, there were people (Swedes) who lived on a territory that they used to own but was then taken by another country (Russia). The "natives" just accepted their fate and either returned to their land (Sweden) or became part of the ruling country (Russia). 

While this was happening. There was a second, much smaller group of people (The Finns) that claimed that this was their land long before the "natives" took over. With the use of a book that contained their mythology (Kalevala), they tried to gain independence from the ruling country. They did. (The Swedes eventually either moved to Russia or came back to Sweden).

In case number two, we see the exact same scenario. The Russians are the Britts, the Swedes are the Palestinians, the small group is the (now) Israelites and the Kalevala is the Jewish Bible.

The only difference, is that Britain didn't want to get involved like Russia did, and left the mess to the two rivals.

If this were the late 19th century, this whole conflict would never have happened.

TL;DR : The British were pussies and this whole thing got started just because the Palestinians wanted more land.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26844609301.0" user="narcissus_goldmund" delta="False">
    <text>Your comparison to Finland is completely invalid. Ethnic Finns have continuously inhabited what is modern Finland throughout the history of Scandinavia. Although Swedes and later Russians claimed sovereignty over Finland in the last thousand years or so, the majority of the population remained ethnically Finnish. During this time, the ruling classes were almost all Swedish, but the Finnish peasantry was never displaced, so I'm not sure where you got the impression that they were a 'much smaller group of people.' There was no mass immigration of ethnic Finns into Finland after Finnish independence because they were already there.

In contrast, Jews were largely expelled from Israel after the destruction of the Second Temple and decisively so after the Bar Kokhba Revolt. After that, the vast majority of the Jewish population lived in exile, with a very small number remaining in the Levant. It was only after the founding of the Zionist movement and the eventual establishment of the state of Israel that a large number of Jews immigrated to the area.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844626331.0" user="AlexiPwns" delta="False">
    <text>So what you're saying is that the difference is that the Jews were exiled and the Finns weren't.

Well, there were still Jews living in Israel after the exile and during the middle ages, many of them were exiled from European countries so they came back to Israel.

All of this of course, before the Ottoman rule.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844658496.0" user="narcissus_goldmund" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, as I said, there were still Jewish communities in Israel, but they were always in the minority under the Roman and Islamic empires. The moral and ethical issue is that the massive influx of Jewish immigrants after Israeli independence has necessarily displaced people who had been living there before. This mass immigration simply did not happen after Finnish independence. Of course, this is not to say that the Jewish people do not deserve their own state, but because of the nature of the Jewish diaspora, the creation of Israel is a unique case in history and is not really comparable to any other independence movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844680565.0" user="AlexiPwns" delta="False">
    <text>But you have to agree that *at least to some extent* these two stories are very much alike.

Apart from the mass immigration (which I don't see *that* relevant to the conflict). I'd love to hear your opinion and view on that: how is the mass immigration of Jews relevant to the Palestinian-Israeli conflict?

(Btw, not being sarcastic, I really am interested)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844787672.0" user="narcissus_goldmund" delta="False">
    <text>Mass immigration is the reason many people believe that Israel is a [colonial state] (http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Settler_colonialism). Large parts of Israel like the West Bank continue to be militarily occupied, and Israeli settlements in these areas are among the most contentious issues in the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. By creating Jewish settlements in these areas, mostly populated by new immigrants, the Israeli government is trying to artificially assert a territorial claim by eventually displacing and making the Palestinians a minority. Furthermore, the Palestinians living in these areas receive no representation in the Israeli government. It is very difficult to characterize the creation of your state as an 'independence' movement when over half of the people in the land you claim are not even afforded the rights of citizenship. Israel has as much a right to exist as any other nation that is capable of militarily defending their territorial claims, but I don't think that it can be argued that its actions aren't much more similar to the colonization of Australia, for example, than other nationalist independence movements.

As a minor aside relating to your original post, I'd also point out that the Kalevala is not nearly as fundamental to the Finnish identity as the Torah is for Jews. One is a national epic while the other is a fundamental religious text which governs their daily lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844673346.0" user="maraSara" delta="False">
    <text>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1922_census_of_Palestine

&amp;gt;The division into religious groups was 590,390 Muslims, 83,694 Jews, 73,024 Christians, 7,028 Druze, 808 Sikhs, 265 Bahais, 156 Metawalis, and 163 Samaritans.[2]

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1931_census_of_Palestine

&amp;gt;The total population reported was 1,035,821 (1,033,314 excluding the numbers of H.M. Forces)[2] – an increase of 36.8% since 1922, of which the Jewish population increased by 108.4%.[1]
The population was divided by religion as follows: 759,717 Muslims, 174,610 Jews, 91,398 Christians, 9,148 Druzes, 350 Bahais, 182 Samaritans, and 421 "no religion".

The numbers aren't convincing at all. 



Pair that with the very intentional movement back to Israel which explains the 108% increase in Jewish population from 1922 to 1931. 

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aliyah#Zionist_Aliyah_.281882_on.29

___

http://jewua.info/russian-empire-population-census-1897-history-and-results/

"The first general census of the Russian Empire in 1897 – a general census of the Russian Empire (without the Grand Duchy of Finland)"

Funnily enough Russia didn't include Finland in its census, during its reign over there, which is circumstantial evidence that the Russians didn't want the world to know the demographics of the population there. So your assertion that Finns were a small minority are unfounded without further evidence.

___

Then:

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kingdom_of_Israel

The last Israeli Kingdom was 2000 years ago. 

And Finland was under Russian rule for about 100 years. Before that it was part of Sweden, but Swedish was only spoken by the nobility, while the peasants mainly spoke Finnish. Of course Swedish Finnish and Danish sound very similar, with on-going puns going back and fourth about who sounds like they have a potato in their mouth, or whether the Danish can even understand each other. 

___

On a more positive note, another example is Bulgaria and Macedonia. Macedonia used to be a part of Bulgaria, until the Ottoman rule, but after the Russian-Turkish wars, some people decided a separate nation was in order (ever heard of the term Balkanisation...) founded on ancient history, and some borrowed history, wrote the required schoolbooks and within a generation or two, the country had acquired a profound hatred for the Bulgarians, then lost it again, in modern times, partly because we can grant them EU citizenship within a week or two, if they testify that their parents or grandparents had Bulgarian origin... and partly because these things are just silly in today's world. 

The story is repeated over and over throughout history. Of course nobody really cares about those neighbor feuds anymore (unless people are actually getting killed over it) but they exist everywhere...

___

In the end historically it's never been about legitimacy in any meaningful sense, it's been about political segmentation of potential powerful new emergent players, in times allowing for segmentation. It was about geopolitical influence, where one could be extracted, such as the case of Israel, and about plain breaking apart of huge masses of land, as is the case with the Balkans. Whether the huge country that was expected to form was called Bulgaria, or Serbia, or The Great Big Slav Empire doesn't matter. The people at the Western-European conferences after the Russo-Turkish wars didn't want one, and we in the Balkans, made sure through our on-going feuds, that one never happened. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
