<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="96422727.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1leo93/i_think_that_if_israel_had_gained_its/">
    <title>I think that if Israel had gained it's independence fair and square. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>AlexiPwns</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I know this is kind of political, but let's try to keep this on subject.

I'm a Zionist who is also an atheist, so let's try and keep religion out of this, because this is definitely not the reason I support Israel.

Thing is, there's this thing called "Romantic Nationalism", it's a form of nationalism in which the state derives its political legitimacy as an organic consequence of the unity of those it governs. 

In Israel's case that's religion and I'm pretty sure that that's how it got recognized as a state. I understand that a lot of people disagree with this because the land wasn't theirs to begin with and that just because some group claims an old book told them it is, is just a logical fallacy.

Problem is, almost the exact scenario happened almost 200 years ago with Finland. 

The Kalevala was a compilation of old Finnish folklore and mythology (Kind of like a bible, written to sum up oral mythology) During the Russian reign, the Finns tried to used the Kalevala to legitimize their nationality and gain recognition as a state. (Pretty much like the Zionist movements during the British mandate).

In case number one, there were people (Swedes) who lived on a territory that they used to own but was then taken by another country (Russia). The "natives" just accepted their fate and either returned to their land (Sweden) or became part of the ruling country (Russia). 

While this was happening. There was a second, much smaller group of people (The Finns) that claimed that this was their land long before the "natives" took over. With the use of a book that contained their mythology (Kalevala), they tried to gain independence from the ruling country. They did. (The Swedes eventually either moved to Russia or came back to Sweden).

In case number two, we see the exact same scenario. The Russians are the Britts, the Swedes are the Palestinians, the small group is the (now) Israelites and the Kalevala is the Jewish Bible.

The only difference, is that Britain didn't want to get involved like Russia did, and left the mess to the two rivals.

If this were the late 19th century, this whole conflict would never have happened.

TL;DR : The British were pussies and this whole thing got started just because the Palestinians wanted more land.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26844407462.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>You don't feel Jewish control of western Europe's finances had anything to do with it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844507959.0" user="AlexiPwns" delta="False">
    <text>Explain..</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844882792.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>In short the financial industry was basically controlled by Zionists in Europe, which held a lot of French government bonds and had large investments in British interests, things like the [London Underground](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/London_Underground) and Britains purchase of Egypt's interest in the Suez Canal, to name a few. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26845210340.0" user="AlexiPwns" delta="False">
    <text>I'm sorry, but you don't have any sources to back up your claim. How do you know that the financial industry was controlled by Zionists?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26845271091.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>Mostly light reading. Most of what you're going to find on the internet speaks directly about the Rothschilds which doesn't get deep enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26846179926.0" user="EricTheHalibut" delta="False">
    <text>I would assume the fact that the British Government felt it necessary to make the deal involving the Balfour Declaration rather than just squeeze what the government needed out of Rothschild and the others using DORA (which gave almost unlimited powers to the PM).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844524521.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Uh.... care to elaborate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844811560.0" user="DJWalnut" delta="False">
    <text>troll</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844815956.0" user="Izzyisme" delta="False">
    <text>Got it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26844883334.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>The fuck???</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26845102225.0" user="DJWalnut" delta="False">
    <text>either that or neo-nazi, but it's usually the former</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26845262672.0" user="shayne1987" delta="False">
    <text>Or you're just reading to far into some shit written on the internet...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
