<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="967222694.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fzuxt2/cmv_reviewers_oscars_ignof_any_kind_are_worse/">
    <title>CMV: Reviewers (Oscars, IGN)of any kind are worse than random reviews of consumers</title>
    <original_poster>sploog_cruise</original_poster>
    <original_post>You see it with gaming, restaurants, movies, hotels and the like. I will say this that for some businesses like Hotels at least there is SOME incentive because theyll at least tell you if youre going to get ripped off, but with games they will lie about bugs as with F76.



Reviewers are so often rigged and bribed that their reviews become meaningless. Then the remaining reviews often rely on what fits their agenda, and then the occasional review that perfectly aligns with popular opinion to increase credibility. 

A review will tell you something about what you can expect, but they are also often misleading and therefor WORSE than a review by a customer. (although customer review are often also rigged) 

Really, if you base your opinion of anything from reviews or award, even stuff like the Oscars, you're likely less informed than someone who looks at it logically 

It honestly baffles me that anyone still respects these and people use things like "it won X oscars or IGN gave it an 9/10" as an argument to do something

The blandest mass produced stuff will get good reviews because its a large company that pays or scares the reviewers/awards with lawsuits to do their thing. Why does anybody even trust them?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34052969309.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>I've never heard of a critic being successfully sued. That would be protected under free speech and reviews don't usually contain anything that's potentially libelous. Reviewers aren't typically paid or bribed outright either. 

There are a couple of reasons that game sites like IGN tend to have positive reviews:

- pressure from publishers. They can withhold access to special events or press copies, so there's some pressure to not dunk on big publishers too hard.

- pressure from the audience. Let's face it, "hardcore Gamers" are crazy people. Well not really, they're just mostly teenagers and young adults with a lot of time on their hands and very impassioned opinions about their favorites properties. I mean would you risk a harassment campaign and death threats over your 5/10 review for the new Call of Killzone: Battle Royale? Or just give it a 9/10 because that's what the fans expect to see anyway?

- Time pressure and press kits. These websites live on fast turnaround and churning out content. Publishers take advantage of this by "helping" these sites with press kits that contain video clips, images and talking points about the game that writers can dip into if they're behind schedule. 

- If the publisher anticipates bad reviews for a game, they just won't send out any press copies. If nobody can review the game then it can't get any bad reviews until it's already out. 

As for films and the Oscars, well best picture this year went to South Korean black comedy/thriller. Not really the 'blandest mass produced stuff.' In fact for many years people complained that the Academy never honored mainstream films and only art films won awards. There's the issue of Oscar bait but that's hardly about bribes or lawsuits.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34053157958.0" user="sploog_cruise" delta="False">
    <text>oscars are outright bribes

Just because they finally, for one time, let a non english movie win doesnt make them credible


This video explain it in humurous way, some details are iffy but it gets the point across: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=qhfxo8xPNGU

I wouldnt know where to find it but Ive heard of cases of gaming devs suing for slander. And the publishers like you admit do hold power. 

All those factors combined make it so that reading an IGN review is frequently worse (assuming you already knew the gist of the game)  than reading random reviews because at least those have less incentive to lie to you</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
