<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="967222694.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fzuxt2/cmv_reviewers_oscars_ignof_any_kind_are_worse/">
    <title>CMV: Reviewers (Oscars, IGN)of any kind are worse than random reviews of consumers</title>
    <original_poster>sploog_cruise</original_poster>
    <original_post>You see it with gaming, restaurants, movies, hotels and the like. I will say this that for some businesses like Hotels at least there is SOME incentive because theyll at least tell you if youre going to get ripped off, but with games they will lie about bugs as with F76.



Reviewers are so often rigged and bribed that their reviews become meaningless. Then the remaining reviews often rely on what fits their agenda, and then the occasional review that perfectly aligns with popular opinion to increase credibility. 

A review will tell you something about what you can expect, but they are also often misleading and therefor WORSE than a review by a customer. (although customer review are often also rigged) 

Really, if you base your opinion of anything from reviews or award, even stuff like the Oscars, you're likely less informed than someone who looks at it logically 

It honestly baffles me that anyone still respects these and people use things like "it won X oscars or IGN gave it an 9/10" as an argument to do something

The blandest mass produced stuff will get good reviews because its a large company that pays or scares the reviewers/awards with lawsuits to do their thing. Why does anybody even trust them?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34053722955.0" user="giantrhino" delta="False">
    <text>I think the case can be made they are subjective and treating them as the ultimate review that supersedes public opinion is folly. I also think though that having a diversity in a set of reviews that remains consistent allows us to find reviewers who enjoy themes that resonate with us and follow them. 

It depends on what your goal is:

If your goal is to try to establish an objective way of determining an ordered ranking of movies, then you do need some kind of consistent body, or as close as you can get to it, to generate reviews off of a somewhat consistent set of criteria. If you crowd-source it, then unless you institute a controlled truly blind selection mechanism you are biasing your reviews. 

If your goal is to make the determination of watch/don’t watch, then once again having a varied set of consistent reviewers serves a purpose, as you can find one whose standards at least for the time being seem to align with your own and use this to get a review with standards that are at least correlated to your own, and go from there. 

This is not making the case that they are necisarily better, but they serve a purpose of trying to establish a **more** consistent way of evaluating movies than essentially a popular poll. Some of that turns into money grubbing, some of its a who do you know game, which obviously sucks, but they serve a purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
