<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="967222694.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fzuxt2/cmv_reviewers_oscars_ignof_any_kind_are_worse/">
    <title>CMV: Reviewers (Oscars, IGN)of any kind are worse than random reviews of consumers</title>
    <original_poster>sploog_cruise</original_poster>
    <original_post>You see it with gaming, restaurants, movies, hotels and the like. I will say this that for some businesses like Hotels at least there is SOME incentive because theyll at least tell you if youre going to get ripped off, but with games they will lie about bugs as with F76.



Reviewers are so often rigged and bribed that their reviews become meaningless. Then the remaining reviews often rely on what fits their agenda, and then the occasional review that perfectly aligns with popular opinion to increase credibility. 

A review will tell you something about what you can expect, but they are also often misleading and therefor WORSE than a review by a customer. (although customer review are often also rigged) 

Really, if you base your opinion of anything from reviews or award, even stuff like the Oscars, you're likely less informed than someone who looks at it logically 

It honestly baffles me that anyone still respects these and people use things like "it won X oscars or IGN gave it an 9/10" as an argument to do something

The blandest mass produced stuff will get good reviews because its a large company that pays or scares the reviewers/awards with lawsuits to do their thing. Why does anybody even trust them?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34053241927.0" user="SuperStallionDriver" delta="False">
    <text>I think it's all about balance and knowing what you like.

I've generally found that with movies at least, the critics and audience are often "looking" for different things than each other, and different things than I am often looking for as well.

Example: an action movie I was interested in due to the trailers.

Critic score: 25% audience score: 92%
I won't see this movie because I'm likely going to be annoyed by poor writing, a lazy plot, bad acting, etc. The audience at large for action movies may not care about that, and might just like anything directed by Micheal Bay.

Another example:
A drama I thought looked good:
Critic: 97% audience: 43%
I'm not going to like this movie either probably because it is probably great acting and directing, but probably too slow and you might nod off during a part that is later critical to everything lol.

So I see it this way: I don't trust either score more than the other, I accept that most critics scores are generally... Let's say "technical" than most audience scores, and for some good reasons.

Actual film critics have to watch movies. They watch them all. Audiences self select. So the critic has one bias in that they like certain types of movies. The audience has two biases in that they like certain things AND only review things they at least thought they might like.

My job is to try and use past experience and see if I think I'll like a movie based on both those data points.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
