<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="967222694.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fzuxt2/cmv_reviewers_oscars_ignof_any_kind_are_worse/">
    <title>CMV: Reviewers (Oscars, IGN)of any kind are worse than random reviews of consumers</title>
    <original_poster>sploog_cruise</original_poster>
    <original_post>You see it with gaming, restaurants, movies, hotels and the like. I will say this that for some businesses like Hotels at least there is SOME incentive because theyll at least tell you if youre going to get ripped off, but with games they will lie about bugs as with F76.



Reviewers are so often rigged and bribed that their reviews become meaningless. Then the remaining reviews often rely on what fits their agenda, and then the occasional review that perfectly aligns with popular opinion to increase credibility. 

A review will tell you something about what you can expect, but they are also often misleading and therefor WORSE than a review by a customer. (although customer review are often also rigged) 

Really, if you base your opinion of anything from reviews or award, even stuff like the Oscars, you're likely less informed than someone who looks at it logically 

It honestly baffles me that anyone still respects these and people use things like "it won X oscars or IGN gave it an 9/10" as an argument to do something

The blandest mass produced stuff will get good reviews because its a large company that pays or scares the reviewers/awards with lawsuits to do their thing. Why does anybody even trust them?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34055557414.0" user="xANoellex" delta="False">
    <text>Would you go eat at a resturaunt that consistently got bad reviews?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34055776540.0" user="sploog_cruise" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're completing missing the point I'm trying to make. I probably would, because I'm not going to be looking up reviews in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
