<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="96944778.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1lpv2i/childless_adults_should_not_go_to_disneyland_and/">
    <title>Childless adults should not go to Disneyland and Disneyworld. These are for children and families, and adults have the entire world to experience. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>dbarefoot</original_poster>
    <original_post>As an adult of moderate means, you have access to the adventures and experiences that Disneyland (and related parks) simulate. You can go whitewater rafting, tour Czech castles and Parisian catacombs and sail the actual Caribbean. Disneyland is obviously an amusement targeted at children, and so adults without children should seek alternative forms of entertainment.

As a more practical addendum to the above, I gather that Disneyland and other parks are exceptionally busy, often resulting in long lines for the attendees. If adults without children eschewed them, then they'd actually be enriching the experience for the parks' target audience.

EDIT (Sept. 4, 19:00 CET): I'm afraid I'm out of time to respond to other comments--thanks for the conversation.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26849638546.0" user="TheMentalist10" delta="False">
    <text>Why *should* they seek alternative forms of entertainment, merely because they fall outside of the maximally-targeted demographic? The same argument can be used to restrict the audience of anything to anyone: opera to the ancient, The Avengers to 12-year-olds. Your narrow view of the relationship between what people enjoy and what they ought spend their time/money on serves only to pointlessly pigeon-hole.

Do you hold that this argument works for anything, or is Disneyworld a special case? If the former, please provide evidence against my first paragraph; if the latter, please explain why.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26849654805.0" user="dbarefoot" delta="False">
    <text>Above, I said that adults "shouldn't settle for a manufactured simulacrum of an adventure or travel experience. That is, they ought to aspire to a greater level of emotional and intellectual engagement than Disneyland can possibly offer." And so I would extend that to other forms of simplistic entertainment aimed at children. 

I think Disneyland provides a good example because of the time, money and effort investment involved in getting one's adult self there. It's not just watching an episode of a children's show--it shows a real commitment to childish entertainment when endless alternatives abound.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26849663183.0" user="TheMentalist10" delta="False">
    <text>On what grounds do you consider that they're settling for *"a manufactured simulacrum of an adventure or travel experience"*? It's not intended to be such, I don't think, and should be considered an experience *per se*, not an attempt at representing another.

Your bit about aspiring to a greater level of engagement is puzzling; are we appealing to some Bentham-esque 'higher pleasures'? I find myself, for example, entirely emotionally-engaged by Disneyworld.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26849665358.0" user="jnr_77" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  That is, they ought to aspire to a greater level of emotional and intellectual engagement than Disneyland can possibly offer.

What if they are just there for the rides?  It's also my understanding that Animal Kingdom has a very large zoo. 

Miniature versions of World Attractions aside, I'm pretty sure Disney has some attractions that are unique, and why shouldn't someone be allowed to pay to experience them?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26849756260.0" user="FallingSnowAngel" delta="False">
    <text>I'm an artist. I was almost an animator, before illness took away my options. 

I see Disney in terms of shapes, lines, aesthetics, illusion...

I also have friends who work there.

Please explain the importance of eliminating fantasy, from your point of view? You're phrasing all this as if I'd never experience the real thing if I choose Disney. You're basing everything in this thread on the idea that any adult in Disney world is fleeing from an experience, rather than simply engaging with a new one. 

You're also missing out on the fact that Disney targets adults aggressively. Look! Some even [make](http://disneyweddings.disney.go.com/honeymoons) children there.

You knew that their fairy tale romances weren't made for the cootie quarantine crowd, right? 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26849803921.0" user="Amablue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're also missing out on the fact that Disney targets adults aggressively. Look! Some even make children there.

Hell, I got engaged at Epcot last year. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26850144440.0" user="ImQuiteCharming" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You're also missing out on the fact that Disney targets adults aggressively.

Agreed.  In fact, there are multiple adult-only themed [events](https://disneyworld.disney.go.com/events-tours/) throughout the year at Disney World such as backstage tours, food and wine festivals, driving experiences.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
