<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="973237900.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/cmv_it_makes_sense_that_police_would_be_more/">
    <title>CMV: It makes sense that police would be more violent on average than other people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.</title>
    <original_poster>tomthehipposlayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>(Disclaimer:This isn't an ACAB post. I think many cops are good people doing a job that society needs, and I'm not here to say that every cop is bad  or violent or that we should abolish police.)

A study in the 90s found that about 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.

The job largely entails enforcing rules, giving people orders that they have to obey, and physically coercing them if they don't comply. Even if the cop's order is unlawful, you're generally advised to obey anyway and take it to court later. If someone is naturally power-hungry, this is the kind of job that would appeal to them.

Again, I'm not saying every cop is bad or violent. I think their job is necessary and I think a lot of cops are good people, but the job itself  attracts control freaks.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34090975152.0" user="ZyraunO" delta="False">
    <text>One thing about this is that it suggests some universailism about police across the globe - that all police have that desire to enforce rules in a possibly violent or aggressive manner. Prima facie, I'm very hesitant to accept that, and sadly there aren't a lot of stats on that outside the US (will say, while looking I did find a poorly titled article saying "Over 40% of domestic abuse victims are male!")

Anyhow, one thing I wanna look at with this is the idea that (at least here in the US) cops can de facto make up laws while they work. I'm not going to disobey someone who has a gun on their belt, and can more or less shoot me, say I did something, and unless there's attention, get away with it. 

But, not every officer goes in with a desire to control. I'll use an anecdote here, names made up of course. I had a friend in high school, Trevor. His dad Dave worked for LAPD, and had become, over the years, an archetypical cop. If I recall, he had been shot twice and shot at a lot, but that's how it goes. Now, Trevor wanted to be a police officer too, and right out of high school he started that process. 

This is where I want to point out something. Trevor was not by any means a controlling person. He was very laid back, and generally kind, but had a strong sense of duty towards society. 

This is where I wanna change your view, and I wanna change it pretty substantially. When a lefty like me says "acab" I mean that the system of policing is bad. There may be people who are good at heart (like Trevor) but the system of policing will change that.

When you are trained as an officer (again, second hand accounts here) you are trained to use your gun, and to expect that a gun could be used on you at any time you walk into a situation. This, combined with a lack of de-escalation training, breeds a culture of fear of violence and of violent control. 

What I'm saying is that, while policing as a career may attract people who were already down a bad road, our police culture does a lot to make people more controlling and aggressive than they would normally be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34091078939.0" user="tomthehipposlayer" delta="False">
    <text>I specified at the very start that I wasn’t talking about all police.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34091183733.0" user="ZyraunO" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I should clarify what I'm saying - the reason that cops tend to be more violent isn't just that policing attracts control freaks, but that the career of being a cop trains one to be more violent and not to de-escalate.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
