<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="973237900.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/cmv_it_makes_sense_that_police_would_be_more/">
    <title>CMV: It makes sense that police would be more violent on average than other people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.</title>
    <original_poster>tomthehipposlayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>(Disclaimer:This isn't an ACAB post. I think many cops are good people doing a job that society needs, and I'm not here to say that every cop is bad  or violent or that we should abolish police.)

A study in the 90s found that about 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.

The job largely entails enforcing rules, giving people orders that they have to obey, and physically coercing them if they don't comply. Even if the cop's order is unlawful, you're generally advised to obey anyway and take it to court later. If someone is naturally power-hungry, this is the kind of job that would appeal to them.

Again, I'm not saying every cop is bad or violent. I think their job is necessary and I think a lot of cops are good people, but the job itself  attracts control freaks.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34088138167.0" user="Quint-V" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think this applies to police jobs globally, or is this mostly about the context of your country (presumably USA)?

At the very least, I think this view would crack in places where police education lasts multiple years, including topics such as de-escalation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34088243369.0" user="tomthehipposlayer" delta="False">
    <text>I think it could apply to police anywhere, but in places where police culture is less violent and controlling, the appeal of the job to control freaks probably isn't as strong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34088330087.0" user="Quint-V" delta="False">
    <text>In the interest of changing your view: how much weaker must this appeal be, in your mind? Any cutoffs/thresholds?

[Some countries have bachelor/master degrees in police academies.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Police_academy) Finland in particular requires 3 (basic training) + 3 (internal security) before 2-year-master (leadership related). Indonesia requires 4 years for *professional officers*. Romania: 3 (bachelor) + 2 (master) + 1 (doctorate). Slovenia effectively requires 6 years when including advanced courses. 

Even if a basic field duty police officer has the means to be needlessly violent, it rests on the condition that their  superiors do not transfer them to office duties instead. Without such a position oneself, they would be easy targets for their superiors. Only when shit gets *really* systemic are such violent officers going to start making an internal culture leading to problems that we see today. Additionally, such an internal culture must somehow overcome the local region's everyday culture too. Before anything else, even police officers are people. Cultures with lower likelihood for producing control freaks... are less susceptible to all this.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
