<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="973237900.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/cmv_it_makes_sense_that_police_would_be_more/">
    <title>CMV: It makes sense that police would be more violent on average than other people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.</title>
    <original_poster>tomthehipposlayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>(Disclaimer:This isn't an ACAB post. I think many cops are good people doing a job that society needs, and I'm not here to say that every cop is bad  or violent or that we should abolish police.)

A study in the 90s found that about 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.

The job largely entails enforcing rules, giving people orders that they have to obey, and physically coercing them if they don't comply. Even if the cop's order is unlawful, you're generally advised to obey anyway and take it to court later. If someone is naturally power-hungry, this is the kind of job that would appeal to them.

Again, I'm not saying every cop is bad or violent. I think their job is necessary and I think a lot of cops are good people, but the job itself  attracts control freaks.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34088464185.0" user="sqxleaxes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks. 

The most recent information shows officers perpetrate domestic violence at a rate of 28% versus 16% for non-officers, which is above the normal but much closer than the 40% - 10% number. This is most likely because the original study may have included incidents like using angry words without actual physical violence, which skews the results higher than normal.

I would highly advise you to review this congressional hearing on the information:  [https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED338997.pdf](https://files.eric.ed.gov/fulltext/ED338997.pdf)

The long and short of it is, police officers have an extremely stressful and often thankless job. They are on the front lines of society and often have to deal with people's intense emotional trauma, not to mention often being in danger. Add on top of this a culture that values bravado and strength and it is little wonder that those officers who need treatment rarely get it. The stress police are under puts them at higher risk for trauma, depression, and suicidal tendencies, and puts their spouses at greater risk of suffering domestic violence. This, however, is due more to the inavailability of psychological care and therapy for police than their inherent tendency towards being control freaks. Many police officers want to do the right thing for their community, and although they often have traditionalist views of law and order, this does not make them control freaks. They are generally normal people, but in the position of having to represent the cutting edge of our societal commitment to order rather than their own emotions or wants. The question is not what is wrong with them, but what we can do to help them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
