<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="973237900.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/cmv_it_makes_sense_that_police_would_be_more/">
    <title>CMV: It makes sense that police would be more violent on average than other people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.</title>
    <original_poster>tomthehipposlayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>(Disclaimer:This isn't an ACAB post. I think many cops are good people doing a job that society needs, and I'm not here to say that every cop is bad  or violent or that we should abolish police.)

A study in the 90s found that about 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.

The job largely entails enforcing rules, giving people orders that they have to obey, and physically coercing them if they don't comply. Even if the cop's order is unlawful, you're generally advised to obey anyway and take it to court later. If someone is naturally power-hungry, this is the kind of job that would appeal to them.

Again, I'm not saying every cop is bad or violent. I think their job is necessary and I think a lot of cops are good people, but the job itself  attracts control freaks.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34088171941.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34088237870.0" user="tomthehipposlayer" delta="False">
    <text>Both are great points. I think the Stanford experiment relates to this a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34090260865.0" user="Helpfulcloning" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/ansel65m – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 1:

&amp;gt; **Direct responses to a CMV post must challenge at least one aspect of OP’s stated view (however minor), or ask a clarifying question**. Arguments in favor of the view OP is willing to change must be restricted to replies to other comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1).  

If you would like to appeal, [**you must first check if your comment falls into the "Top level comments that are against rule 1" list**](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_1), review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+1+Appeal+ansel65m&amp;amp;message=ansel65m+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/-/fnr7tt1/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
