<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="973237900.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g3fv64/cmv_it_makes_sense_that_police_would_be_more/">
    <title>CMV: It makes sense that police would be more violent on average than other people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.</title>
    <original_poster>tomthehipposlayer</original_poster>
    <original_post>(Disclaimer:This isn't an ACAB post. I think many cops are good people doing a job that society needs, and I'm not here to say that every cop is bad  or violent or that we should abolish police.)

A study in the 90s found that about 40% of cops were reported for domestic violence as opposed to 10% of the general population. I know that study is outdated, and may not be entirely accurate, but it makes sense that cops would be more violent on average than regular people because the job naturally appeals to control freaks.

The job largely entails enforcing rules, giving people orders that they have to obey, and physically coercing them if they don't comply. Even if the cop's order is unlawful, you're generally advised to obey anyway and take it to court later. If someone is naturally power-hungry, this is the kind of job that would appeal to them.

Again, I'm not saying every cop is bad or violent. I think their job is necessary and I think a lot of cops are good people, but the job itself  attracts control freaks.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34088338970.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>You think that police have more instances of violence because violent inclined people gravitate to the field?

Have you considered the fact that it's one of a handful of jobs that consistently deals with violence on a routine basis?

How often does a chef or electrician have to get physical as a direct solution to a problem in their workplace?

It makes more sense that police are more prone to violence considering they're more prone to having to respond to violence. 

Even if the job does appeal to 'control freaks,' that doesn't necessarily predict violence. There are plenty of jobs that attract control freaks. Lawyers, judges, HR, doctors, chefs, car salesmen and Reddit mods. None of which have radical rates of violence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
