<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34100215432.0" user="Atomic_Fire" delta="False">
    <text>The experts in sociology use the power+prejudice definition. Academia uses it. It's really semantics.
Similarly, you wouldn't be inclined call working people discriminating against rich people classist, do you? In everyone's heads classism is always rich discriminating against poor.

I mean, if you just call it discrimination by race instead of racism, then you're not wrong and progressives can't argue with that definition. For the most part, all humans are discriminatory garbage, PoC and everyone alike.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102327999.0" user="Seeattle_Seehawks" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; you wouldn't be inclined call working people discriminating against rich people classist, do you?

Why wouldn’t I?

Or perhaps a better question: If not “classism”, what *would* you call it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
