<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099527070.0" user="drawinglizards" delta="False">
    <text>Doesn't your post contradict itself? Your definition of racism is 

&amp;gt;prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a  different race *based on the belief that one's own race is superior*

(emphasis mine) but then you say

&amp;gt; Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society.

The power/position stuff is in the definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099553906.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>*Based on belief that ones own race is superior.*

*ones own race*

Not that of the receiver of racism.

A black person being racist to a white person is possible because the black person may possibly think that black people are superior to white people.

So no, it doesn't contradict itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099677945.0" user="drawinglizards" delta="False">
    <text>If you're going to get technical about this definition, nobody could ever say anything is racist because it would require you to read minds.

Power and position are a proxy for systemic attitudes and beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
