<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099509419.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>The thing is there's a big difference between interacting with one racist and interacting with a racist society. One person that doesn't like you can call you names, but that's pretty much it. They can't beat you up, they can't fire you, they can't throw you in jail for no reason otherwise it comes back to bite them in the ass when you call the cops or get a lawyer. It becomes a serious problem when its not just an asshole beating you up, but then the bystanders "didn't see anything", the cops won't make an arrest based on your story etc.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099596325.0" user="HTC1830" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t studies say that cops are less likely to shoot black perpetrators compared to white? For the fear of shame and other consequences.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099609407.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Don’t studies say

https://youtu.be/-NYXkM7460U

That's a creative remix of the oldest trick in the book. Got anything to back it up?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099664142.0" user="HTC1830" delta="False">
    <text>I’ll have to do my homework and get back to you.

Got any evidence that cops are more likely to shoot black people in the same circumstances that a white person is committing the same crime?

While you’re at it, is it also true that 6% of the US population (black males) commit close to 50% of the total murders? And it’s mostly against other black males?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099671612.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>I never made any claims that contradict any of that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34101943202.0" user="Yirby" delta="False">
    <text>"A claim made without evidence can be dismissed without evidence."

Well done, sir.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34107745186.0" user="jasoncain142" delta="False">
    <text>Research Summary Race-related debates often assume that implicit racial bias will result in racially biased decisions to shoot. Previous research has examined racial bias in police decisions by pressing “shoot” or “don't-shoot” buttons in response to pictures of armed and unarmed suspects. As a result of its lack of external validity, however, this methodology provides limited insight into officer behavior in the field. In response, we conducted the first series of experimental research studies that tested police officers and civilians in strikingly realistic deadly force simulators. Policy Implications This article reports the results of our most recent experiment, which tested 80 police patrol officers by applying this leading edge method. We found that, despite clear evidence of implicit bias against Black suspects, officers were slower to shoot armed Black suspects than armed White suspects, and they were less likely to shoot unarmed Black suspects than unarmed White suspects. These findings challenge the assumption that implicit racial bias affects police behavior in deadly encounters with Black suspects. http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/1745-9133.12187/abstract

Found this

Edit: adding another source to show some consensus https://www.pnas.org/content/116/32/15877</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099615106.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>Im having trouble understanding this. Genuinely, I'm not making fun of you.

Are you talking about say, a black person being a victim of a single white person being racist to them, then comparing it to say, police brutality by white police and white onlookers don't say anything about it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099661415.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>Pretty much what I am getting at. Systematic racism is a much bigger problem than just I'm calling you mean names racism so whats wrong with in the vernacular calling one the "real" one. That's how language works. We call other things not "real" in comparison to other things that are more intense all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100332758.0" user="lebanese-tiger" delta="False">
    <text>You have changed the argument from "can racism towards whites exist" to "what racism is worse".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100355914.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>I mean I would assume the inciting incident to this CMV is OP heard a black person calling a white person a "cracker" isn't really racism or something like that. I may not be attacking OPs thesis directly but I think this undermines their view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100537804.0" user="lebanese-tiger" delta="False">
    <text>If you see a person outside a house looking inside, he can either be the owner or a burglar.

Assuming other people's motives and what's in other people's minds is your own mind making stuff up, creating conjectures.

An assumption like the one you made therefore, in my view, does not undermine OPs view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100617323.0" user="SwivelSeats" delta="False">
    <text>OP is free to correct me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34103812971.0" user="romansapprentice" delta="False">
    <text>Systematic racism is a specific kind of racism, but not the only example of it. 

One does not need institutional power to be racist to someone else. By your logic, a hate crime perpetrated by one minority against another wouldn't actually be racist or a hate crime because neither has institutional power.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
