<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34102025629.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>Words mean what people believe they mean. If people internalize the prejudice + power definition, than that's what the word means, regardless of what any dictionary says. 

If I start a campaign, racism and bananas are synonyms. If I can get 500 million English speakers to agree with me, the that definition would become correct. The sentence "racism is high in potassium" would be true, for anyone who accepted that definition. 

Therefore, just because a definition is invented or contrived, doesn't mean that the definition is wrong. A definition can only be wrong, if it isn't believed. 

In this way, talking to you, the only definition of racism is race based prejudice. But if I were talking to one of my hypothetical converts, then racism would mean banana. If I were to talk to many people today, then racism does mean prejudice plus cultural power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102201493.0" user="TheContrabandWagon" delta="False">
    <text>The dictionary is the agreed upon authority for what words mean.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102963125.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>No, it isn't actually. 

I can leave you to Google the distinction between prescriptive and descriptive linguistics. 

But in short, if the people use a word one way, and the dictionary defines it another way, it is the dictionary which is wrong. (Which is why dictionaries have to update). You probably saw the news that "they" is now a singular noun according to Merriam Webster. This is because common usage was discordant with the dictionary definition, and Merriam was the one that had to change, not the people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34103414576.0" user="TheContrabandWagon" delta="False">
    <text>I understand how words and the dictionary work. I want to distinguish the example you used from racism. As you mentioned, the dictionary is updated to include word usage changes over time. Further, there is a process by which additional definitions can be added over time based on updated connotations. 

However, racism’s definition has not yet changed in this manner nor for those reasons. Rather, people’s explanation of the definition has changed as a result of a communication and perception barrier that exists between the races as a consequence of the proliferation of racist thought. I find the insistence on these modified definitions to be counterproductive and ineffective at bridging the divide between the races in our understanding of what racism is, how it operates, and how to eliminate it, but that seems to be the modus operandi of most Antiracist activists/intellectuals right now. 

Language is a tool for us to understand each other, so of course we can collectively decide what words mean. That’s what the dictionary is meant to memorialize. However, racism has complications that other words don’t have. It has quite a large amount of neglected baggage, and I am suggesting that the new age definitions that have emerged are emerging primarily as a weapon against racism’s legacy. 

Regardless of what you think about all of that, the definition of racism has always included the idea of superiority and inferiority, and I don’t see that changing. Nor do I think we would still be talking about racism without talking about a superiority/inferiority complex.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34103536617.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>I largely agree with what you just wrote, but do you not see how this is almost entirely contradictory with what you just wrote or what you wrote at the start. 

Just because you believe something is counterproductive or ineffective, doesn't mean that it isn't happening. (In fact it must be or we wouldn't be talking about it). If you acknowledge that people are using the word this way, and that usage defines the word, then that usage is correct - even if you don't like it. 

Somethings correctness, doesn't mean that it is morally good or that we ought to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34103551993.0" user="TheContrabandWagon" delta="False">
    <text>My point was that the dictionary hasn’t acknowledged these new ways of conceptualizing racism, and I’m not sure that will ever happen and in my opinion should ever happen. There has to be more than just people are using it this way now. There’s a process, and the word racism hasn’t gone through it, and I doubt it ever will. The only thing I said is that the dictionary represents our shared understanding of words, and that’s still true.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
