<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099510905.0" user="Quint-V" delta="False">
    <text>The title alone is trivially true. Unfortunately, language is fluid and prone to misuse developing into standard usage. Whether you like it or not, widespread adoption of a word with a different meaning, is going to cause confusion. At that point the problem cannot be removed, it's yours to deal with; in the exact same way that life presents a series of problems that you might have done nothing to earn, but they are all yours to solve.

[This removed thread](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/g3k4yt/cmv_minorities_are_capable_of_being_racist_to/) was basically about the exact same thing and has far more arguments in there, with 2500+ comments. If nothing there convinces you, I'm not sure this thread would.

I don't know what is prompting these threads. Is this suddenly the hot topic in the USA?

You can at least accept that while some definitions are arguably bad, or contribute to needless confusion, they make sense with the specific caveats to them. Otherwise, what are you doing with this thread?

edit: 

&amp;gt; People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism.

If racism is *ideological* to you, then "reverse racism" is simply to discriminate back due to oneself being discriminated against. No ideological motivations are needed for "reverse racism", only that one has been a victim of it. At which point, "reverse racism" denotes a reactionary behaviour, **not any ideology**.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099532263.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Is this suddenly the hot topic in the USA?

I don't know. I'm not from there.

What am I doing with this thread? Seeing other peoples opinions on the topic and conversing about it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
