<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="28" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34104439546.0" user="SingleMaltMouthwash" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

First, a quibble: You don't have to believe your race is **superior** to be prejudiced against another. You may believe in the equality of all races and yet believe that people of a particular race will be consistently unfair or untrustworthy or behave unethically or immorally towards another race or races. This is racism as well.

Second: in the case of white Americans, that kind of racism has been well and truly earned.

White colonists imported African slaves to this continent, treated them abominably for 250 years, freed them and treated them not much better for another century and for the last 50 years the duly constituted governments of more than half the states have done everything they could to deny them the rights enshrined in the Civil Rights Act.

Native Americans have been slaughtered wholesale, treaties broken upon a whim, sequestered on reservations so effectively that they were the model for german concentration camps in the thirties.

Asian minorities have been exploited, marginalized suffered discrimination, mass incarceration and the theft of their businesses and homes. Irish, Italian and Jewish minorities have suffered discrimination as well, but blend in to the white majority population more easily.

This contemptible behavior has not been true, and is not true today, of every white person individually, but it is certainly true of white culture generally. Things are better than they were, but they're not fixed. And you only have to watch the news to see how eager some white people are to go back to the way it was.

There is one indisputable racial truth in this country and that is white Americans have earned the distrust of everyone else and have no grounds to expect that our best neighborly, even brotherly intentions should be given the benefit of the doubt untested.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
