<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099631197.0" user="tadhs" delta="False">
    <text>Simple answer: In the N American context, other people can be racist against white people, but white people can be racist towards other people in ways the others don't even have access to. 

Longer answer: Racism has a few different definitions. By at least one of them- what some would say is the simplest or most formalistic one- you would be right. To act in a certain way to someone in a certain manner based off of their skin color would be a racially-influenced or racist behaviour. If you treat someone differently than you treat others simply because they are white, then sure, that can be "racist." 

But "racism" can be defined in other ways as well. I think "systemic racism" is closer to what you're getting at when you say mention power+prejudice. And yes, this absolutely does exist as well, and you would be hard-pressed to find an example of it being used against a white person in a majority-white society. The reason is because, presumably, the majority member of a society, or the demographic who otherwise holds the most power, builds and influences the society to work to **their** advantage. This creates a number of systems where "Others" become prejudiced against (either on purpose, or because the more powerful demographic can't be bothered to build with their considerations in mind). Either way, the Others become left out of the main streams of participation in that society. 

One example of this: minority communities forming in North America over the last few decades based on historic settlement patterns. Some large concentrations of minority communities exist because historically, **they weren't allowed to settle in the main towns.** This is "racist" because it is an action based on a person's race. It's "systemic racism" because the white people who held the power- the most population, the majority of economic holdings, the most property ownership, etc- was designing the society in a way that purposely left others to the wayside. This systemic racism propagates over time. For instance, there is another type of racism being talked about these days- "environmental racism." Env. Racism\* is when a minority group largely lives in an area with poor drinking water, poor air quality, less access to municipal resources etc because **they were made to settle in that area** by the majority group (in N America, that majority would be white people). Even today, where making someone live somewhere else because you don't like the color of their skin is illegal, these communities still exist and experience lesser conditions because that's where they were historically forced to settle. 

Racism isn't one simple definition, and it can get incredibly complicated, to the point where laws and policies are still being reworked and rewritten in order to remove barriers to inclusiveness that are based on race. I think the nuance in the word "racism" is lost when you combine the simple-definition "racism" with its other forms, that are absolutely dependent on power. 

It's also possible that at times, people claiming they "can't be racist" because they are of x race is just them trying to excuse lousy behaviour. Those bad eggs shouldn't distract from the fact that the forms of racism minority populations experience are not comparable to those that are currently experienced by white people in N America. That being said, there are a lot of intense, complicated, intersectional cultural rules at play when it comes to what is acceptable and what is offensive between different peoples of different cultures, but that is a whole other discussion. I bring it up only to emphasize the point that there's lots of nuance in this topic, and boiling it down to "racism is based purely off race, not power or position in society" is an extremely small part of an extremely big picture. 

\*I loathe the term environmental racism because it sounds like a strange accusatory buzzword, and I've seen it turn off people who don't experience Env. R from having the conversation, and understanding what it is, in the first place. But, for lack of a better term, it's the one that's been popularized.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100088982.0" user="World_Spank_Bank" delta="False">
    <text>In regards to P+P, we're not living in the 1700s. Black people can and do hold positions of power in this country. Policemen, lawyers, judges, CEOs, doctors, landlords, managers, politicians, and even recently the presidency. And if they hold power they can abuse it for racist reasons. A very simple example might be a black manager firing or not hiring you because they're racist against white people. That's P+P racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100180893.0" user="Martinsson88" delta="False">
    <text>To add to your good answer...Power merely scales the effect of the prejudice. 

To illustrate...ask whether it is possible for someone to be racist on their own, on a deserted island, where they have no power over anyone else. If they shout out racial epithets all day that no one else hears, are they still racist?
Clearly racism is possible in the absence of “power”.

I’d also say it’s a bad definition as it ignores the fact that we each have “power” over our own thoughts, words and actions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34101191682.0" user="tadhs" delta="False">
    <text>We certainly aren't in the 1700s anymore. Affirmative action in the employment context (and programs similar to it) are another great example of this; ensuring those with minority status can break through the ceilings (glass ceilings or explicit ones) that had previously been so common in the workplace. **There are lots of other examples besides the ones you and I just gave where what I've written above is not a nuanced enough block of text to give the whole picture.** But my answer is a direct response to the things in OP's CMV, it isn't a unified theory of Racism. It's a good starting point and a generalization designed to change a view, and not altogether incorrect. 

Actually, another demonstration of my point now that I've mentioned glass ceilings: Representation. The reason certain job postings look for women or people of minority status is for representation. If a company (or government) is made up of a varied demographic, reflecting the demographic it operates within, in theory it can better represent the people it interacts with. Also, if you are a member of a minority, and you never see anyone who looks like you in a powerful position, you're less likely to think you can achieve that for yourself. When it comes to media, if you are a member of a minority and never see yourself represented positively on TV or in movies, it can be isolating. And the reason why there's been such a big push for representation over the last few years is because **minorities were left out of such roles because often, they weren't the ones designing companies and governments and media outlets.** This demonstrates systemic racism; such systems were constructed in N America with the explicit or implicit exclusion of minorities built into them (I say that generally and not regarding every specific case or person, let's not get stuck in the weeds again). It is changing today, and to some big extents- you're right, the US had a black president. But historically, systemic racism was a one-way street, and I don't think the progress that's been made so far to reduce its manifestations and effects has evened the playing field so much as you might suggest. [For instance](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wealth_inequality_in_the_United_States#Racial_disparities).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
