<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="23" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34101808417.0" user="EccentricKnight" delta="False">
    <text> Yes, this is often overlooked, as a minority I really don't face to much racism because there's a lot of stigma around it but there is none around being racist to whites so many people are. Thanks for drawing attention to this</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102140928.0" user="TheContrabandWagon" delta="False">
    <text>In what country do you live?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102143544.0" user="EccentricKnight" delta="False">
    <text> America, I am Hispanic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102269882.0" user="TheContrabandWagon" delta="False">
    <text>It’s shocking to me how many people in minority groups living in America believe that prejudice against white people has somehow eclipsed prejudice against minorities. There is zero evidence to support that idea and a ton to support the opposite, so I’m curious how you came to the conclusion that (a) there’s more stigma regarding prejudice against minorities than against whites (and how does this prejudice manifest itself?) and (b) that you don’t experience much racism. 

I think people have a misconception that the effects of racism are always visible and known to the person who is affected (or not), and that is OFTEN not the case. As you mentioned, there is a stigma against being a racist, but that doesn’t stop people from posting videos of themselves being racist (for a recent example check out the video those two Georgia HS students created and posted on social media). 

In terms of prejudice against white people, there has absolutely been an increase, but to suggest that white people’s present experience is more than remotely relatable to the generational racism African Americans and other minority groups have experienced is wild to me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
