<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099420511.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>Words can have multiple definitions. Your view rests on there being only one ~correct~ definition of the word "racism."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099428468.0" user="dahuterschuter" delta="False">
    <text>Why have needless definitions cluttering an already defined word?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099434664.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>There are plenty of words with multiple definitions, not just this one. It clearly isn't "needless" to the people who developed and use the "power and prejudice" definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099473596.0" user="samuelgato" delta="False">
    <text>This is a ridiculous argument. You don't get to change the definition of words just because doing so suits your agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099490495.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't "changing the definition" to have a shorthand available.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099491115.0" user="Tinie_Snipah" delta="False">
    <text>Do you believe Apartheid South Africa was a racist state?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099724896.0" user="klip_twings" delta="False">
    <text>The argument you are saying is ridiculous is that "plenty of words have multiple meanings" but that statement didn't go far enough, **almost all words have multiple meanings.**

I challenge you to find a popular word right now from a living language that doesn't have more than one meaning.

The **original** etymology of the word "racist" included [descriptions of systemic and institutional racism.](https://www.etymonline.com/word/racist)

It is a **brand new thought invention** to claim that the word racism **never** included topics of institutional and systemic racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099475056.0" user="justbrowsn1235813" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It clearly isn't "needless" to the people who developed and use the "power and prejudice" definition.

Just because short hands exist, does not necessarily mean they are useful in terms of general communication. Most jargon is, I think, obfuscating at best in terms of the general population, though of course it is useful for scholar, professors, practitioners, etc.

The problem is when one person is talking about "racism" and the other is talking about "(institutional) racism". And it seems to me that the people who use the prejudice + power definition often fail to mention it in discussion or do not want to recognize the other, more well known definition.

I have seen this mentioned enough times that the prejudice + power definition seems to do more to divide people and to hamper discussion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099487857.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Just because short hands exist, does not necessarily mean they are useful in terms of general communication.

I didn't say it was useful for general communication. 

&amp;gt;The problem is when one person is talking about "racism" and the other is talking about "(institutional) racism". And it seems to me that the people who use the prejudice + power definition often fail to mention it in discussion or do not want to recognize the other, more well known definition.

I agree, discussions of systemic issues often suffer from a lack of establishing shared definitions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099510711.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>There is definitely a need for both definitions, but using a single word to cover both is needlessly confusing and conflating. It would be far better to come up with a second word, so it's clear which "kind" of racism people are referring to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099521249.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>I agree, in most cases it's better to discussed "systemic racism." That doesn't mean that in academia, it's not appropriate to discuss "racism" using a different definition than the layperson's.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099545920.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>It's not inappropriate, but it's a topic that pretty much everyone talks about, so it adds the need to "translate" between layperson and academic, for little to no gain. Having a different definition just adds confusion, which is not the best idea for a topic that is already a tough one to tackle.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100332506.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but using a single word to cover both is needlessly confusing and conflating. It would be far better to come up with a second word

It would be, but in this case, the convention was adopted as is from academia. Hence the inertia.

It's not entirely uncommon for jargon like this, since academia tends to explicitly define terms before using them anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102361909.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>How and why did academia and the common definition diverge? Academia's definition is significantly nuanced, which makes it confusing when people are informally discussing racism, where it's rare to define the term or clarify which definition is in use prior to using the term.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34104635294.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How and why did academia and the common definition diverge? 

Not my area of academia, so my understanding is pretty limited. But a bit of googling says it was first proposed by Patricia Bidol:

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prejudice_plus_power

Basically, because it was clear that issues of power needed to be taken into account in order to understand racism. For example, Italian didn't used to be considered white, but it is today. A lot of that goes back to the need for the 'white' voting bloc to expand the tent or losing a voting majority across that time period. (The wikipedia link probably has some resources if you want to get into the deep history of it).


The exact wording used is unfortunate, but my guess is Bidol or someone else influential early on chose it. Once that happens, it tends to stick even if it's not ideal, the same way that Edison's choice for current lives on despite being "backwards". Social inertia is a hurdle.

But it wasn't necessarily intended to be adopted by the general public, any more than quantum mechanics was. The public just kind of co-opted it, again because there was need for that type of analysis/term and it was already formulated.

If you're trying to talk about race and power, it's kind of natural to look to the academic literature as a developed expertise and take pieces of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34106228373.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks for linking, it's an interesting read! Now I can clarify one as the stipulative definition and the other as lexical. Always nice learning new terms!

The complaint I have with the stipulative definition is that people tend to use it in commonplace discussions without first clarifying that is the definition they're using. Given that most discussions on racism aren't academic and use common vernacular, I think most people assume the lexical definition is in use. This only causes outrage and confusion when someone says "that's not racism" without first clarifying that they're talking about prejudice plus power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099530392.0" user="klip_twings" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; ~~There are plenty of words with~~ *Almost all words have* multiple definitions

To find words (in a living language) with only a *single* meaning probably entails a scavenger hunt into the outer-reaches of niche jargons. *Every* word used in popular vernacular has multiple meanings.

It's a fundamental aspect of a living language, that words and their definitions suit the context of the people who are using them, words are always changing and evolving, so long as people are always changing and evolving. We all know what happens when people stop changing and evolving, and language is similar, in that the only languages that are frozen in time, that will no longer change or evolve, are the dead languages.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099592498.0" user="dahuterschuter" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are plenty of words with multiple definitions, not just this one

Hence the "needless" qualifier.

&amp;gt;It clearly isn't "needless" to the people who developed and use the "power and prejudice" definition.

They don't need that definition no, they want it for the reasons stated by the OP, essentially.  An intellectually honest alternative is "institutional racism" to qualify the sort of racism  Using "racism" as "privilege plus power" is simply an equivocation fallacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099619271.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>No one "needs" any definition, then.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099669572.0" user="klip_twings" delta="False">
    <text>If you look at the [etymology](https://www.etymonline.com/word/racist) of the word, the original use and definition included descriptions of systemic and institutional racism:

&amp;gt;    Returning recently from a six months' visit to Europe, the Rev. John LaFarge, noted Catholic writer, warned at a dinner given in his honor that the destructive forces of "racism" are increasing in the United States, and that they could cause irreparable harm among the American people if immediate steps are not taken to combat them.

&amp;gt;    Father LaFarge said that American racism is directed principally against Negroes, Jews, and foreigners. He described it as "the pale but venomous cousin" of Nazi racism. Like its Nazi counterpart, he added, it has erected impassable barriers between extensive regions and large groups of people, has formed its own myths and moulded its own social institutions, and above all has come consistently into conflict with Christian teachings. ["Opportunity, Journal of Negro Life," vol. XVII, No. 2, Feb. 1939]

&amp;gt; In the U.S., race hatred, race prejudice had been used, and, especially in 19c. political contexts, negrophobia. Anglo-Saxonism as "belief in the superiority of the English race" had been used (disparagingly) from 1860. Anti-Negro (adj.) is attested in British and American English from 1819.

Honestly, the definition you propose, "Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior." is a **new** way that people have **just started** interpreting the definition of the word. 

Where did you come to understand that the definition you proposed is the original, the authoritative definition? This is your last sentence in OP: "The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term." But racism, if you simply glance at the etymology of the word, has **always** included the topics of institutional and systemic racism. You are saying one thing has been invented recently, but that declaration itself is **a recent invention.**

Here's the difference between "racism" and "prejudice," as I have come to understand it (but I'm not an expert): A person gets to decide if they are a prejudiced bigot, or not, but *everybody* is a little bit racist... at least we all belong to institutions and systems of getting along in the world that were created with some racism baked in.

EDIT: My bad, I mistook you for OP when I wrote this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100243457.0" user="dahuterschuter" delta="False">
    <text>The origin of the term "racism" was Leninists wishing to create a way to sew social unrest.  I don't think this is an argument you want to pull a genetic fallacy in.

Regardless, the bottom line is that the "prejudice" plus power" redefinition attempt is simply equivocation fallacy strategically used to discount legitimate forms of racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099481117.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>**racism**

1. prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior."a programme to combat racism"
2. the belief that all members of each race possess characteristics, abilities, or qualities specific to that race, especially so as to distinguish it as inferior or superior to another race or races."theories of racism"

I pulled this off google. 1st one is the one i used in my initial post, 2nd is basically about racial stereotypes. 

Let's go for another definition then shall we?

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Racism takes many forms and can happen in many places. It includes prejudice, discrimination or hatred directed at someone because of their colour, ethnicity or national origin.

This is off the human rights website. Nowhere does it say that white people are exempt from racism. 

Hmm, there must be ONE definition somewhere that says that racism towards white people doesn't exist.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

**Racism**, also called **racialism**, any action, practice, or [belief](https://www.britannica.com/topic/belief) that reflects the racial worldview—the [ideology](https://www.britannica.com/topic/ideology-society) that humans may be divided into separate and [exclusive](https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/exclusive) biological entities called “races”; that there is a causal link between inherited physical traits and traits of personality, intellect, [morality](https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/morality), and other cultural and behavioral features; and that some [races](https://www.britannica.com/topic/race-human) are innately superior to others. 

This is off Britannica, and it seems to line up with the other definitions in saying that white people are not exempt and that racism CAN happen towards anyone, regardless of their position in society.

You are correct in saying that my view stands on only one definition of racism being correct, because there is only one correct definition for racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099499935.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;You are correct in saying that my view stands on only one definition of racism being correct, because there is only one correct definition for racism.

You acknowledge the existence of the "power plus prejudice" definition. That's an equally correct, if not equally common, definition of the word. The people using it are referring to what you might prefer to call "systemic racism." It's not incorrect to use a shorthand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099519313.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>How did you derive me acknowledging that power+prejudice exists from me saying that my view is correct because the definitions I gave are the only correct ones for racism?

If the power+prejudice definition is equally correct and equally common then why cant I find any definitions from reputable sources stating that the definition of racism involves power+prejudice</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099543412.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; How did you derive me acknowledging that power+prejudice exists from me saying that my view is correct because the definitions I gave are the only correct ones for racism?

This sentence: "People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice" implicitly acknowledges that the other definition exists, even if you clearly disagree with it. 

&amp;gt;If the power+prejudice definition is equally correct and equally common then why cant I find any definitions from reputable sources stating that the definition of racism involves power+prejudice

I very explicitly said it *isn't* equally common. 

But sure, here's [a whole wikipedia page](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prejudice_plus_power) about the other definition of the term. It's jargon, not a common use.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099652489.0" user="OnlyNineteenLetters" delta="False">
    <text>If I acknowledge the other side of the argument at all, does that mean I indirectly think that it exists? No, it does not. If I was having an argument with someone who thought dragons were real and I said 'You think that dragons are real, but I disagree.', I've acknowledged that he thinks dragons are real, but that doesn't mean I do, thats the whole point of my argument.

You make a fair point with the wikipedia article, but its a stipulative definition of racism. You cant just change a words meaning just so it can fit with a particular ideology. If the wikipedia article is right then how come the sources I gave don't say prejudice + power.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099692009.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I acknowledge the other side of the argument at all, does that mean I indirectly think that it exists? No, it does not. If I was having an argument with someone who thought dragons were real and I said 'You think that dragons are real, but I disagree.', I've acknowledged that he thinks dragons are real, but that doesn't mean I do, thats the whole point of my argument.

Right, but the definition of "racism" isn't a physical object that either does or doesn't exist. It's a term being used in a certain way, and that usage absolutely exists. 

&amp;gt;You make a fair point with the wikipedia article, but its a stipulative definition of racism. You cant just change a words meaning just so it can fit with a particular ideology. If the wikipedia article is right then how come the sources I gave don't say prejudice + power.

So now you're arguing that it *shouldn't* be used in this way. It very much *does* exist, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100325374.0" user="Arianity" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If the wikipedia article is right then how come the sources I gave don't say prejudice + power.

Google (and similar sources) generally use simpler (and older, in this case) definitions. In the particular case of Google, it licenses it's definitions from Oxford Online Dictionaries.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxford_Dictionaries

In particular, that version of the Oxford Dictionary prioritizes

" the most important and common meanings in modern English are given first, and less common and more specialist or technical uses are listed below." [1](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Oxford_Dictionaries)

as well as "practical usage".[2](https://web.archive.org/web/20180228084422/http://public.oed.com/about/the-oed-and-oxford-dictionaries/)

The prejudice+power one is the more technical definition. It's less common, although it's usage has been becoming more and more popular (it originated in Academia in ~60s or so, but it's been increasingly adopted since).

The goal of those dictionaries are easy of use, not necessarily being as broad or technical as possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099532431.0" user="HeftyRain7" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that systemic racism is an important definition. But I don't understand why we would shorten it to just racism when racism is such an important topic, and saying things such as "racism towards x group of people doesn't exist" can lead to quite a few heated arguments. Plus, arguments like "you cannot be racist towards white people" can lead people who don't know of both definitions to the wrong conclusion. It adds quite a lot of confusion to discussions, so I agree with op and think that, for the sake of clarity, we should use systemic racism and only shorten it to racism once we are sure everyone in the conversation knows we are talking about systemic racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099556913.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>The "power plus prejudice" definition is jargon from academia that has, arguably inappropriately, shifted into the common vernacular. Being able to more quickly - with fewer written or spoken words - is useful in academia. It's the move from academia to society more broadly that led to issues.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099645375.0" user="plushiemancer" delta="False">
    <text>That dictionary is descriptive, not prescriptive.

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dictionary#Prescriptive_vs._descriptive</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100541900.0" user="PrettyGayPegasus" delta="False">
    <text>You realize that language is *descriptive* not *prescriptive* right?

All you've proved here is that Google lists the definitions of racism as 

&amp;gt; 1. prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior."a programme to combat racism"
&amp;gt; 2. the belief that all members of each race possess characteristics, abilities, or qualities specific to that race, especially so as to distinguish it as inferior or superior to another race or races."theories of racism"

You have *not* established that the word racism doesn't also refer to power + privilege defintion, which isn't my preferred definition but I'm not self proclaimed arbiter of language here.

Like if I link the word being used differently in some other context and claimed *that* to be the real and only defintion I'd be wrong but I'd be using *your* argument. And we can't both be right but we can both be wrong.

Hell, even first and foremost dictionaries merely document how people use words.

When you read a dictionary, your basically reading how people tend to uses words; their (most) common usages. You aren't reading some divine law that dictates how people must use words, because people are ultimately going to use words however they want to use them.

You might as well be arguing that when I call my mom a cow what I'm actually saying is that she is a "bovine four legged mammal that is often domesticated and as she is actually a human, you are therefore incorrect because the dictionary says so." When I'm *actually* just calling her fat.

It's moooOOOoot.🐄</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102100135.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34102655631.0" user="thedylanackerman" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/3superfrank – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 5: 

&amp;gt; **Comments must contribute meaningfully to the conversation**. 
Comments that are only links, jokes or "written upvotes" will be removed. Humor and affirmations of agreement can be contained within more substantial comments. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_5).

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+5+Appeal+3superfrank&amp;amp;message=3superfrank+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/-/fnzicvb/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34101139184.0" user="neurealis" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that we should use more precise terms we clearly define, just to prevent this exact debate from happening.

When people talk about the power+prejudice definition of racism, they tend to mean institutional racism. In the US, black people have fewer opportunities than white people, have to work harder to get to the same socioeconomic level and are disproportionately harmed by the criminal justice system. This is why people say there is racism against black people in US society that cannot affect white people in the same way.

However, that doesn't mean individual people can't have prejudice or discriminate against white people, just that it hasn't pervaded the institutions in the same way.

So racism against white people exists, but institutional racism doesn't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34100512625.0" user="Fatgaytrump" delta="False">
    <text>That's unarguably how words work.

But why would people use "racism" to mean "power and privilege" when we already had a term for that...

**institutional racism** 

Why not use this, more accurate definition?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
