<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="29" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34108588108.0" user="Whooplaah" delta="False">
    <text>Racism can take multiple forms, and therefore has multiple meanings. You are taking one definition and ignoring the others. For instance:

**Person A says "Person B is a \*\*\*."**  
Anyone can do this, regardless of their power in society. Anyone can be a victim of this, regardless of their power. By textbook, this is *individual* racism. White people are just as likely to be victims of this as any other race.

**Person A uses race as an excuse to not hire Person B.**  
Not everyone can do this. Person A can only perform this racism if Person A has the *power* to make a decision affecting Person B. This racism can only take place in a system that allowed Person A to gain decision making power. By textbook, this is still *individual* racism. White people can experience this, *but they are less likely to be on the receiving end.* Why? Because White people are more likely to have power, and therefore Person A is more likely to be White.

**Person A makes a rule that new hires must have a college degree. Person B applies for the job.**  
This does not look like racism. However, this rule results in a *racial bias.* If Person B is born a race that has less power in society then they will have less money, which means that obtaining a college degree is harder, which means getting this job is harder. Since most high paying jobs require advanced education, this results in low-power races having a harder time obtaining enough money to have more power in society. This by textbook is *systemic racism*. That means that people are not racist, and the rules are not racist, but some races are still marginalized as a result. The *system* is racist. By definition, White people will not experience this type of racism (except in a small handful of countries).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
