<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="13" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099923289.0" user="Rufus_Reddit" delta="False">
    <text>If there's a disagreement about what the word "racism" means, does it really help if one person keeps saying "No, racism means &amp;lt;&amp;lt;X&amp;gt;&amp;gt;!" and the other person keeps saying "No, racism means &amp;lt;&amp;lt;Y&amp;gt;&amp;gt;!"?

&amp;gt; ... The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.

How do you know that this alternative definition is not the result of someone accidentally conflating "institutional racism" with "racism?"  It's like a genetic fallacy in reverse.  Sure, people like to invoke that definition in straw man rhetoric, but that doesn't tell us what the origin of the definition is.   ( If we must speculate about motivated thinking leading to a definition like that, narratives about cognitive dissonance seem much more credible to me than ones about stigma or rhetoric.  https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cognitive_dissonance )

On a more fundamental level, does it even make sense to talk about "racism towards white people?"  If racism is about discriminating between different groups of people, then there should be at least two different groups, right?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
