<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="25" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34102389118.0" user="Struijk_a" delta="False">
    <text>By definition, yes, someone insulting and discriminating you because of race is being racist towards you. However, the world is not such a simple place and in practice things get more complicated. 

Black people have suffered tremendously over hundreds of years with true racism, slavery and all the inhumane aspects of it. Over the years slavery wasn't a thing anymore, but black people still suffered with prejudice, lack of opportunity and education. They have been fighting this vicious battle for a long time and there's still some more to be done. 

So in reality, somebody being "racist" to a white person is hardly harmful, in my opinion. In the end, they are still white and do not have to deal with weird looks, being stopped by police for no apparent reason but their skin color, etc. White people have enjoyed luxury for hundreds of years on an economy based on slavery.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
