<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="20" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34101090436.0" user="MHB483" delta="False">
    <text>Racism, against an entire population, such as white people in america, can not exist if that population is the majority power because they are the creators, and beneficiaries of the racist systems in place. So, systematically, racism towards white people can not exist in America at this time because white people can not oppress themselves racially. 

On a micro level, anyone can hate anyone for any reason... and i hate to break it to you, but unless you know the person personally, your reason for hating them is probably invalid and formed on your own bias and conclusions. So yes, someone from another race might say they don't like you because you are white, but a white person will never have to face the racial oppression of an entire system which is designed to oppress. So, its not really the same even though we use the same word for two different scenarios in the English language.  

It is one thing for a few people of color to dislike those who enable the racist system that adversely affects them, though this is rarely the case. People of color might personify a racist white person's actions as something a white person would do, because they are the biggest players in the racist system, but rarely do they presume someone is an active racist without seeing them as active and ouvert racists, and they do not believe this to be true for all white people.

I would like to clarify, this does not give people of color immunity for being racist, they just can not be racist towards white people. For example, social hierarchies exist within the African- American community between light and dark skins, and could be argued that light skins receive much more due to their lighter skin tones in their own communities. 

However, it is nothing compared to a white person to be a passive beneficiary of a racist system and not understand the benefits they are given from it, or be a white person who actively participates in preserving or ignoring the racist system in place.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
