<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="975116834.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g4k4yq/cmv_racism_towards_white_people_exists/">
    <title>CMV: Racism towards white people exists</title>
    <original_poster>OnlyNineteenLetters</original_poster>
    <original_post>Racism by definition is prejudice, discrimination, or antagonism directed against someone of a different race based on the belief that one's own race is superior.

People throw around that racism is based off power+prejudice but that is incorrect according to the definition. They seem to think that because white people are 'dominant' in society that you can't be racist to them because of their position, but that is not true. People who say reverse racism does not exist are right, because it is normal racism. Racism is based purely off that: Race. Not power or position in society. 

The power+prejudice argument was invented so that certain parties could espouse racist views without the negative stigma of the term.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34099518183.0" user="sinthesinner" delta="False">
    <text>Living outside a western/mainly white country is uncommon for whites thus most of them don't even get to experience "raw" racism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34099592709.0" user="HTC1830" delta="False">
    <text>Where is raw racism in the west today?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34101183208.0" user="sinthesinner" delta="False">
    <text>I live in Germany being a grandchild of Turkish guest workers and I mostly don't experience direct racism (luckily). But I've seen it more than enough to tell it's here. Mostly people with little to no language skills get to experience it. But it also depends on the city you live in. When saying raw racism, I meant being in a place where you are in the smaller group. Imagine being the only white person living in a third world country. You'd encounter prejudices and a lot of negativity over time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
