<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860408528.0" user="randomgrunt1" delta="False">
    <text>By pouring money into sports and stadiums, schools gain funding through ticket sales, food vendors, and admissions with the desire to play on a specific team. It's a great money maker, which helps fund other programs at the school. While over half of a tuition is being spent of sports might be a bit much, but when a school has a thriving sports program it brings in money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860446740.0" user="runragged" delta="False">
    <text>You missed alumni.  Sports is a major draw for donating alumni.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860450265.0" user="mindphaser" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; and admissions with the desire to play on a specific team

If they only gain admissions from kids who want to play ball, how does that help academia at all? I'm with the OP here. I think sports are a huge waste of time and money, for the most part. I get that they teach teamwork and social skills, and that's important, but the amount of money and hooplah that goes into sports pisses me off to no end.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860749357.0" user="themcos" delta="False">
    <text>Its not just admissions from people who want to play sports. It also serves a similar purpose as any general advertising. It raises the visibility of the school and makes athletes and non-athletes alike interested in it.

Remember, schools aren't purely about "advancing academia". They're also in constant competition with one another to attract students. Part of their goals are to become a shining beacon of learning or whatever, but they also want to do whatever they can to make themselves an attractive place to spend four years of ones life. This comes in many forms, including academic prestige, but also nicer dorms, interesting location, better food, attractive campuses, and yes, funding sports teams.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860474997.0" user="math_is_pretty_hard" delta="False">
    <text>Not every school makes money off of its sports teams.  In fact, there is a growing sentiment that college sports are a pretty large drain on schools' finances.  I'm intimately familiar with this dilemma since my alma mater is one of the [worst offenders](http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2012-05-03/rutgers-football-fails-profit-test-as-students-pay-1-000.html).   For a larger sample size of schools, check [NBC's coverage on the subject](http://collegefootballtalk.nbcsports.com/2010/08/25/ncaa-report-shows-many-college-programs-in-the-red/).  I admit however that I cannot speak to alumni's donations garnered by the school spirit fostered by a football/basketball program.

That being said, I only agree with OP on the matter of college sports. The rest of this post will be to support that sports are not a waste of funds. The way I interpret the original post, OP also has a problem with professional sports, but this view neglects to fully appreciate the nature of pro sports.  The NFL, MLB, NBA, etc.,  form an industry that produces consumer goods in the way of entertainment and merchandise.  Pro sports are no more or less a waste of time than pop music or Hollywood.

Now its possible that you think those things are a waste as well.  But even if you dismiss mainstream media as vacuous and superficial, having no cultural or social merit, you still must appreciate the economic impact of these industries.  I won't include a trite statement about all the people sports employs because I'm sure you're already aware as you said in your closing statements.

And even if you don't agree with the above sentiments, I'd close by saying that outside of college athletics (whose cost/benefit I agree is debatable), sports are not a waste of money simply because people are allowed to spend money as they damn well please.  If they want to blow $100 to watch their NFL team from the nosebleeds while wearing a $150 jersey, they're entitled to spend that money.

NB: sorry if my links and whatnot are not properly formatted, I'm still learning how to do this new-fangled reddit thing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
