<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860321827.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>The correct way of changing your view applies to every "I think this thing that society does is unnecessary/wasteful/evil/bad" statement, and is also generally a good thing to be familiar with.

In short, the response is this: define "necessary". From your post, I might guess that you would define "necessary" as, say "something that improves society, or provides utility to all those who bear the cost, etc".

The problem is that that definition is completely arbitrary. The word "necessary" (and, for that matter, the word "need") has no uncontroversial meaning that meshes with its use to dictate what other people do with their money.

Sports makes a lot of money. Because it does this in a vaguely free market, we can safely conclude that some segment of the population derives utility from the existence of sports programs. Depending on your definition of "necessary", this fact alone either makes sports programs necessary or makes everything except subsistence farming an unnecessary waste of effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860441250.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>You completely missed the point. Just because the 51% would rather spend money on sports instead of education or giving food to the hungry doesn't mean it's the right thing to do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860477796.0" user="ensanguine" delta="False">
    <text>In that case we should get rid of movies, TV, video games, art museums, etc. Entertainment is important, and sports not only provides that but brings in a ton of revenue with it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860494197.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>Missing the point. You're saying "Oh, you don't like it? Then let's get rid of it!" But what what I'm saying, and what I think OP is saying, is "We could spend **some** of that money on other things!"

The problem for me at least is: why do athletes need *so much* money? If we halve the paychecks of all the top professional athletes and put that money into feeding the starving, just in America, we would have athletes who still get paid a lot, and much less hunger and malnutrition.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860497334.0" user="ensanguine" delta="False">
    <text>They make that much money because what they do generates that much revenue, and what they do is that difficult. I think you can take your argument and apply it to almost any high paying job, which would be totally unfair. The reason a CEO is paid such a high salary is that not everyone can do that job, and not everyone can be an athlete.

Also, why do actors need that much money?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860509174.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>Actors don't need so much money. Neither do CEOs. And instead of saying "they earned it" I'd say "It's how much they can get away with." Just because actors are paid a lot doesn't mean they deserve it, it just means that western culture enjoys movies. And again, the point isn't how much money they can earn or get, but with how much money they *need.*

I'd say, by your logic, that if someone breaks into your house and steals your tv, they deserve to keep it. After all, they have the tv through their own effort. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860600292.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Actors don't need so much money. Neither do CEOs. And instead of saying "they earned it" I'd say "It's how much they can get away with." Just because actors are paid a lot doesn't mean they deserve it, it just means that western culture enjoys movies. And again, the point isn't how much money they can earn or get, but with how much money they need.

So, we've now broken this whole thing down into who "deserves" what. This is now 100% subjective and pointless to discuss. Everyone thinks everyone else deserve less and they deserve more. It's a pointless topic</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861394053.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, let's all sit on our armchairs with fedoras perched atop our brows, debating the ethics of who deserves what from hard work, and whether or not the CEO of Google really *needs* a golden toilet seat, while people are starving in the streets and children are going without warmth and food and education. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861468141.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; CEO of Google really needs a golden toilet seat

Because this is clearly what rich people do with their money. They literally just sit around and buy stuff out of gold or burn it because they think it's hilarious.

You're extremely out of touch</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861521205.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>And you're to stupid to into metaphors or exaggeration. And yes, I said it that way on purpose. 

No they didn't literally have golden toilet seats. They have private jets and suits that cost more money than a blue color worker makes in a week, at least. Plenty of other things too. Good job missing the point and using an ad hominem. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860728045.0" user="ensanguine" delta="False">
    <text>So, basically, no one should ever make more than they need is what you're saying?

That's called socialism.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861392181.0" user="rageraptor" delta="False">
    <text>Oh no, the dreaded "socialism" insult. Well, I'm not one of those middle class college philosophy/art majors that thinks true communism is the way to go. 

Anyone who has payed any attention in history class knows that pure democracy and pure republics are just as bad as pure socialism. 

That's why America has a few concepts from each. Back when the government was more laissez-faire, the first person who came along to make a monopoly could easily have been the new dictator of America if the government hadn't stepped in to put a stop to it.

To be clear, I'm not advocating a switch to socialism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860663043.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>Define "need".

You might notice I already headed off that argument in the first post, because you've just changed the word and done the same thing again.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860909687.0" user="Tsuruta64" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it athletes that people focus all their attacks on, and not the owner?

Take Lebron James.  He will earn 19 million this upcoming basketball season.  Sounds like a lot, right?  Well, what if you realized that the value of the Miami Heat, the team he joined, has grown by hundreds of millions since he joined in 2010?  Lebron is almost singlehandedly responsible for that, why shouldn't he get a fat cut of it?  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861056767.0" user="myusernameranoutofsp" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If we halve the paychecks of all the top professional athletes...

Isn't that what tax is for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26861057349.0" user="myusernameranoutofsp" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If we halve the paychecks of all the top professional athletes...

Isn't that what tax is for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860662525.0" user="kznlol" delta="False">
    <text>No, you've completely missed the point. There is no way to define "the right thing to do" in an objective fashion that doesn't invite argument.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
