<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860590623.0" user="reddittroll111" delta="False">
    <text>I think a lot of people miss the big picture. Sports are not all about the football players and basketball players. At any given University their may be dozens, hundreds of thousands of students athletes living their dream of playing college sports in college. I think spending a little money **helping hundreds of people live their dreams** is not too bad on an investment, even if it doesn't happen to you

My second point is just because you don't go doesn't mean other people shouldn't go. A mid-size college's football team might have an attendance of 30,000 people per week. Over the course of a season that's close to 200,000, which doesn't come close to counting all of the people watching on TV, following online or listening to the game on the radio. That is a lot of interest and happiness generated. Just because it doesn't effect you doesn't mean it's bad. **If you don't use the bus system, would you lobby for mass transit to be eliminated at the expense of the people who do use it?**

You also assume that all the money spent on the sports teams goes right into the teams and out of the university, which is not true. Some of that money might be spent on better facilities for student recreation, or on new buildings for athletes which would leave average students with more facilities once the team vacate their olds ones. Maybe you REALLY don't like sports and wouldn't care at all if you guys got the football team's old 20,000 square foot gym but that's certainly one way that **money put into sports can help student infrastructure.** That money might also go to improving stadiums, which might seem like it wouldn't effect you. However more than just college sports games are hosted at stadiums. There could be concerts, drama and other performances held in sports arenas because other places are simply not large enough. For instance, I remember watching Circe du Soloeil live in the local basketball stadium, which was a **pretty thrilling performance anyone could enjoy and appreciate,** regardless of sports affiliation. If the basketball stadium did not exist, then they would not have been able to have their performance in my city, which would have been bad for them, bad for the city and bad for anyone watching</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
