<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860206434.0" user="Daedalus1907" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Universities putting money into sports isn't just a money pit though. They do get it back from tickets, merchandise, etc. If they turn a profit on sports then the school could go back and put even more money into these things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860225859.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>[Most schools don't make a profit, though.](http://www.dallasnews.com/sports/college-sports/texas-longhorns/20100823-Texas-one-of-just-14-FBS-8872.ece)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860298516.0" user="fadingthought" delta="False">
    <text>Correct, but alumni with big checkbooks love sports. I went to college at the University of Oklahoma and I got to go to an excellent private box last season...for a donation to the general academic fund. 

Things are subjective, to some people having people go to the Olympics in their sport from their school is very worthwhile, to others, they like the school to have a very nice art museum and have their students cultivate art skills.

Is one more worthwhile than the other? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860299289.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>I think both should lose out over actual academics, personally, but I suppose I'm just weird in thinking that schools should spend money on actually teaching.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860304618.0" user="fadingthought" delta="False">
    <text>The implication is that humans should only value academics, but college has never been about that. The arts, athletic competition, have been apart of human culture for all of recorded history. A great artist can bring great joy to the world, just like a fantastic athletic competition can. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860308192.0" user="perpetual_motion" delta="False">
    <text>No, saying we should value X over Y is not the same as saying we should only value X.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860312842.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly. I think that we should put EXCESS cash towards sports and the arts or money donated specifically towards those purposes (obviously, you can't take sports donations and put them into engineering). Especially in this age of huge budget cuts it's not reasonable to put a bunch of money into football.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860460935.0" user="fadingthought" delta="False">
    <text>We do value academics over athletics. The University of Oklahoma spends 94 million a year on athletics but the annual budget of the school is 1.5 billion. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
