<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860221712.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>Wellness is a term that is very popular within the health community, and by examining sport from a wellness perspective, I think you might gain a better appreciation for sport. Wellness basically refers to the idea that human beings are "healthiest" or functionally more effective when their physical, social, emotional, and mental needs are met, and when they are stimulated in those areas. There is almost no single activity on earth that completely encompasses all aspects of wellness as well as sports.

Physically - The most obvious one. People who play sports are staying physically fit. Head over to fittit if you would like to debate the merits of staying physically fit.

Socially - When you become involved with a sport at a recreational or a competitive level, you immediately make contact with anywhere from dozens to thousands of people who share at least one common interest with you. It is not uncommon for people to develop their social circles from contacts they've made participating in sport. Even if you don't play a sport, simply becoming a fan of a sport gives you similar access to that community. The best example of this is fantasy football. I can go to just about any bar in North America and find at least one person who plays fantasy football, and have a conversation.

Emotional - This is a side effect of the social aspect, but by participating in sports as a competitor or a fan, you share an emotional connection with a group of people. Those emotions can be good or bad depending on the situation, but for some people who rarely get to connect emotionally with someone, having a chance to experience a shared emotion with 12 other people can be extremely rewarding. As well, participation in sports can lead to some of the most intense and rewarding emotional experiences that some people will ever have. Think of the local high school team winning a state championship.

Mentally - This is what I think most people overlook the most. Every sport requires a degree of mental agility and acuity to be successful. The more competitive the competition, the higher the complexity of the mental strategies. The most common phrase I hear people use to describe their sport is "human chess" or "physical chess," which refers to the idea that you are using your mind to defeat your opponent, and your body is simply a vehicle for, or an extension of, your mind. Coaches, athletes and fans who learn about the intricate details of sports are exercising their mental abilities regularly, something which some people don't get nearly enough of. 

The fact of the matter is, if we had a society where people stayed active, socialized regularly, sought emotional connections with their peers, and regularly engaged in mental exercise we would all be better off. Sport can be that vehicle, and is that vehicle for some people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860244981.0" user="clawclawbite" delta="False">
    <text>Unless the money is spend on sport activities intended for large scale participation, then most of the physical and social wellness factors do not apply.

Moreover, the social aspects are likely not a good return on investment, especially as they are targeted at the fan community, which is not all members of the school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860308439.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>I absolutely disagree. Tailgaiting is a distinctly social activity that entirely being around being a fan of the game. I have no evidence of any sort for this as a phenoment, but I do know that at my university, intramural team enrollment was highest the years we had two extremely successful sports teams.

Regardless, I think I may not have been clear in my point. My point was not necessarily about simply college athletics spending, but rather that participation of sports was a benefit to society because it benefits individuals. You claim that participation in sport is individualistic and provides no benefit to society. I disagree, sports are inherently social and encourage behaviour and actions that benefit society by improving the interaction between people. As well, society benefits if each person is able to enrich their own lives through the hobbies they participate in. 

For curiousity's sake, what do you feel is the return on investment for money that would go to for social and physical sciences or the arts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860335391.0" user="clawclawbite" delta="False">
    <text>There is a difference between sports are good, and sports are worth spending half of tuition on.

For a school, spending money on actual education supports the stated mission of the institution for everyone who is attending. Smaller classes, more class options, better instructors all provide a direct improvement in the education of the tuition paying students.

Why should tailgating be supported by a school, and not be an opt in at your own expense activity with a self-funding professional sports team? 

What is the difference between the lowest and highest level of intramural participation? What was that high level?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860359889.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be hung up on the money spending aspect of sports in college, so I'll address that as best I can.

Do you think that Kinesiology, Health Studies, Physical Education, and physiotherapy are worthwhile academic pursuits? I have a Phys. Ed degree, so I'm admittedly biased, but I believe they are. In order for those programs to function schools need gymnasium(s), sports equipment, specialized equipment, professionals in the field, sport equipment, and volunteers, among other things. Unfortunately, most of these things are expensive, so schools need to find a way to generate the money necessary to fund those things. The most effective way to do that is to use sports programs and offer services to the public. Grants and federal funding help out, but the single biggest generator of money is a successful sports team. However, those programs do require investment from the university to function. 

As a byproduct of that system, students now have access to facilities and programs such as fitness centres, open gym times, health services, intramural programs, and more. These are programs that cash strapped students often wouldn't have access to outside of the school. They provide a benefit to the student body, because as important as knowledge and learning is in university, the ability to keep your body healthy and participate in enjoyable hobbies outside of class.

Do you feel that half your tuition is worth contributing to keeping the doors open on a handful of faculties and providing discounted services for students?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860366491.0" user="clawclawbite" delta="False">
    <text>The topic was Sports are an excessive use of funds, and referenced that in the context of a school budget.

I think Health studies are a fine field, as are the others, but evaluating their budgetary needs and facilities should be done on an even basis with other fields. 

Cash strapped students may be able to afford access to sports out of their own budget, if tuition was lower.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860398499.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that the funds are not excessive. Within the context of a school budget, if a school wishes to have those fields as an option for their students, they require an immense amount of funding. 

Schools then, are put into a tough spot. That funding can come from essentially one of two ways, either directly from students through tuition costs, or by creating sport programs to generate regular income. Both strategies require an investment from the school, via tuition. The amount of money that students see in their tuition would be astronomically higher if the school decided to forego the sport program.

The other major option is of course to decide to scrap those programs and not offer them at all, which some universities/colleges have done. Balancing the funds necessary to run a university is more complicated than simply deciding which department gets how much money.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
