<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860223939.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.

If you think that improving your standard of learning is an effective use of funds, then I think I can change your view.
&amp;gt; the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs.

This is because the college is a business, or, if state-funded, trying to offset the cost of running the school. Athletics (football, basketball, etc.) can generate a lot of revenue, and that revenue in turn can go back to the students, improving your experience at the college.

In this case, using the funds helps to improve the standard of learning at your college via the profit enabled by those funds. If you think that improving your standard of learning is an effective use of funds, then I think I can change your view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860226219.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>[Most colleges don't make a profit on sports.](http://www.dallasnews.com/sports/college-sports/texas-longhorns/20100823-Texas-one-of-just-14-FBS-8872.ece)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860250570.0" user="Znyper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Sixty-eight FBS schools reported turning a profit on football, with a median value of $8.8 million. The 52 FBS schools that lost money on football reported median losses of $2.7 million.

&amp;gt;The breakdown for basketball programs at those 120 schools was nearly identical, though the median values for profitable programs ($2.9 million) and money-losing ones ($873,000) were smaller.

.
&amp;gt;Fulks pointed out that many schools funnel profits from football and men's basketball - which for the top schools can mean millions in Bowl Championship Series payments and NCAA tournament payments - into lower-profile sports that can't rely on season ticket plans, TV packages and well-heeled donors.

&amp;gt;More teams generally means larger subsidies from the school.

&amp;gt;"Football and men's basketball are the only two sports you any have chance of making money," he said. "If you start splitting that up between 30 or 40 sports, you start losing money."

This article takes into account all of the athletics supported by a school. The major sports, basketball and football, generate revenue more often than not, even during a deep recession. The less profitable sports take money from the major sports to fund themselves, essentially diluting the possible profit from those sports. Perhaps the schools should only focus on the profitable sports, and ignore the ones that cannot generate revenue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860274630.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>So,would you be cool with most schools (remember, there a tons of schools outside of the big leagues with sports) cutting their entire sport programs and only a handful of schools retaining just a couple of sports each? Because I am.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860417355.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>Do you see any value in college sports programs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860420452.0" user="TOUCHER_OF_SHEEP" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but not to the expensive extent they're at now- I wrestled in high school, you see, and think college sports should be how that was: actually about the sport. Due to a lack of potential monetization, we were only given $1000 a year by our school. Thus, we would only use money on equipment and traveling, all of which we had to obtain through our own private efforts of fundraising (the thousand dollars was always saved for kids who couldn't afford travel fees and for putting towards new mats, since wrestling mats are expensive). 

We wrestled to wrestle and love the sport, not to make money. It seems much healthier than how the current system is set up (which is to benefit the school rather than the athletes). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26860668317.0" user="dukew008" delta="False">
    <text>I played high school sports as well, basketball and voleyball, and we had a similar type of budget allowance. However, I got a chance to work in the recreation services for my university, and got a little more in-depth look at how they have to juggle finances than most students.

I really don't know if there is anything more I can say, that I haven't already said to the OP that will change your view, because I don't have access to specific numbers. However, I will say this.

Finding the finances to run a Kin/Health Studies faculty and provide students with access to fitness services is a giant expense, and a lot more complicated than I think you understand. From the outside looking in, it is very easy for us to point fingers at how much they're spending on "sports" and cry foul without understanding the myriad of benefits that the investment in sports brings back to a school. The money spent on athletics programs in universities creates a net positive for students and the institution, even though it may not look like it from the outside.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
