<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="97998841.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1mcge1/cmv_i_think_that_sports_are_an_excessive/">
    <title>CMV- I think that sports are an excessive unnecessary use of funds.</title>
    <original_poster>anlcntrox</original_poster>
    <original_post>I see nothing wrong with sports, or the individual pursuit of physical health. But I believe that it's one of those individualistic pursuits that does very little to improve society. Some of this is based on stereotypes of professional athletes, I'll admit, but here's an example: the last college I attended released a pie-chart breakdown of how our tuition was used, and over half, HALF, was put into sports programs. As someone who wouldn't plan on attending a single event of that type (unless a close friend was competing), I couldn't help but feel a bit jaded towards the whole thing. I had a discussion with a friend and he pointed out to me how many jobs are created by sports, so there's a definite advantage, but I still think that money could be better spent on social and physical sciences and the arts.

Edit: I accidentally a word.

Update: Hey guys, thanks for all the feedback! I unfortunately work on weekends so I've had limited time to respond to individual comments. So here's the conclusion I've reached after reading your responses-- I'll admit that the 'individualistic' label that I've applied to sports also applies to the arts, this is a bias that I have and knew I had before I posted. I hold the arts as more important than sporting events, but that is my personal opinion and I can't stand in a place to judge the rest of humanity for differing. 

I've also learned that more successful sports teams generally require less funding from their colleges, so if anything I should be rooting for the home team to win more games so I can see my tuition money go towards something that I deem more 'useful' in my own biased opinion. Thanks beigebaron for pointing this out to me.

I won't say that I've had a full turnaround on the subject, but I'm going to be more open minded in the future. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26860529732.0" user="Raudskeggr" delta="False">
    <text>As they exist today, yes they are.  But the existence of academic sports was once thought to serve a higher purpose, based on the ancient Greek ideal of "Arete", which is best translated as "excellence".  

The idea of Arete is not just about being really good at one thing, but being a well-rounded person who is competent in any arena needed, be physical or mental.  The pursuit of this excellence is one of the paramount ideals of classical Greco-Roman culture.  

In modern times we might refer to such a person  as a "Renaissance Man".   </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
