<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="980463745.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g7qqo1/cmv_anti_gentrification_activists_propose/">
    <title>CMV: Anti Gentrification activists propose measures that harm society and the people they advocate for.</title>
    <original_poster>brianlefevre87</original_poster>
    <original_post>Anti Gentrification activists oppose the creation of new market housing and advocate for only affordable housing to be created. This often comes with the demand that the character of the built environment and demographics remain largely unchanged. 

The end result is the cost of market housing skyrocketing even faster, leaving an area full of very wealthy residents with enclaves of low income communities poorly served by government housing. All families with anywhere near an average income leave. 

The 'luxury housing' opposed by such groups is rarely actually luxurious sky villas with swimming pools inhabited by Martin skraelli. It is usually good quality housing built at market rates. The high cost is due to high land prices caused by not enough homes being built to meet demand. Unless enough housing is built, housing will never be 'affordable' it can only be subsidised. 

Under such conditions, the provision of enough subsidised housing is ruinously expensive for local governments, or is cross subsidised by demanding affordable units in market developments which pushes the price of market units even higher. Waiting lists for subsidised units increase and they are often overcrowded. 

There is also an element of reverse snobbery with anti Gentrification groups. Opposing people moving into the area of a different ethnicity or social class is very ironic for a supposedly progressive movement. 

The idea that the demographics of any area have, should or will remain largely unchanged is not realistic. And it would be a massive waste of public money to try and achieve it. Its just a progressive form of nimbyism. 

I understand these groups may be well intentioned, and that the shortage of housing is not solely from their opposition to it. I also firmly believe in government regulating markets if the end result is a better net outcome for society.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34135082889.0" user="goofygoobermeseeks" delta="False">
    <text>This may be an issue in America where people are being priced out of areas but in the UK it’s less because of social housing. Which literally anyone can get</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135144820.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I live in London. Getting to the top of social housing lists is extremely hard. You need to either inherit it, be in a desperate situation, or wait a very long time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135152481.0" user="goofygoobermeseeks" delta="False">
    <text>Yh. Anyone can get it. Not immediately. The current list time is 5 years. Which if your 20 isn’t very long. Most people don’t get their own house till married at 35</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135166093.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I doubt someone on an average income would qualify. Even so, this is a really bad situation. You wait five years to get an apartment, and then it's hard to swap flats and move to a new area if you want to get a job somewhere else. It's really bad for Labour mobility and productivity, and makes people poorer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135272346.0" user="goofygoobermeseeks" delta="False">
    <text>The real issue with this is actually private developers. They only use something like 20% of the land they own for developments. The rest they just hold onto so prices increase. That’s why there is a 5 year wait list</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135378039.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>No it's not. The long waiting lists are due to council housing being sold off, and no replacements built. 

Some developers do build out sites slowly. Mainly because it's very time consuming, risky and difficult to get development permission in the UK. This means only a few massive companies dominate the market.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135678166.0" user="goofygoobermeseeks" delta="False">
    <text>Councils have been seeking houses since the early 80’s under thatcher. The reason they can’t build properties is due to the lack of available space not owned by private developers hoarding land</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136075191.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>Councils were forbidden from using any revenue for selling council houses to build new ones.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
