<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="980463745.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g7qqo1/cmv_anti_gentrification_activists_propose/">
    <title>CMV: Anti Gentrification activists propose measures that harm society and the people they advocate for.</title>
    <original_poster>brianlefevre87</original_poster>
    <original_post>Anti Gentrification activists oppose the creation of new market housing and advocate for only affordable housing to be created. This often comes with the demand that the character of the built environment and demographics remain largely unchanged. 

The end result is the cost of market housing skyrocketing even faster, leaving an area full of very wealthy residents with enclaves of low income communities poorly served by government housing. All families with anywhere near an average income leave. 

The 'luxury housing' opposed by such groups is rarely actually luxurious sky villas with swimming pools inhabited by Martin skraelli. It is usually good quality housing built at market rates. The high cost is due to high land prices caused by not enough homes being built to meet demand. Unless enough housing is built, housing will never be 'affordable' it can only be subsidised. 

Under such conditions, the provision of enough subsidised housing is ruinously expensive for local governments, or is cross subsidised by demanding affordable units in market developments which pushes the price of market units even higher. Waiting lists for subsidised units increase and they are often overcrowded. 

There is also an element of reverse snobbery with anti Gentrification groups. Opposing people moving into the area of a different ethnicity or social class is very ironic for a supposedly progressive movement. 

The idea that the demographics of any area have, should or will remain largely unchanged is not realistic. And it would be a massive waste of public money to try and achieve it. Its just a progressive form of nimbyism. 

I understand these groups may be well intentioned, and that the shortage of housing is not solely from their opposition to it. I also firmly believe in government regulating markets if the end result is a better net outcome for society.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34135589527.0" user="spastikatenpraedikat" delta="False">
    <text>Did I undrerstand correctly that your opinion is, that anti gentrification movements harm society because they advocate social housing, which in your opinion is doomed to fail and even worsens the housing situation? Because then I hope I am not missing your point, when I argue that social housing can work if done correctly:

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Case study: Vienna vs. Munich. Overall Munich and Vienna are quite similar cities, having similar cultural background, same level of industrialization, both beeing massive economic and cultural centers of their respective area, and both having a similar number of inhabitants. Therefore they make an ideal pair to analyze the effects social housing can have on city, as Vienna has one of the biggest social housing programms on earth, whereas Munich pretty much has none at all. Let's first investigate some properties of the viennese social housing program.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

First, it is massive. 1 in 4 people of Vienna live in social housing. Every district of Vienna (even the city center) has social housing. It was a deliberate decision in the early 50s to spread social housing all over the city and to have a minimal distance between to "Gemeindebau", so no "slummification" can take place. The results can be seen in [this](https://kurier.at/politik/inland/steuerreform-in-welchen-bezirken-die-spitzenverdiener-wohnen/167.788.599) graph, which shows a pretty smooth distribution of average incomes by district in Vienna (exept for the city center of course). In contrast for example look at the income distribution of [London](https://www.towerhamlets.gov.uk/Documents/Borough_statistics/Income_poverty_and_welfare/Household_Income_2017_Factsheet.pdf) (I couldn't find one for Munich). The average costs of housing in Vienna for a one bedroom apartment outside the city center is 688$ (which puts it at the lower end of one-million-inhabitant-or-above-cities in Europe), whereas the costs in Munich are 975$ ([source](https://www.numbeo.com/cost-of-living/city_price_rankings?displayCurrency=USD&amp;amp;itemId=27&amp;amp;regionCode=150)). Furthermore Vienna has now been awarded [city with the highest qualitiy of living](https://mobilityexchange.mercer.com/Insights/quality-of-living-rankings) several times in a row. Admittedly Munich has always been in the top 10, but if you compare their individual scores you can see that Vienna and Munich are pretty much level everywhere, except at "Housing" and "Consumer Goods", which allows Vienna to take the titel. This shows that social hosuing doesn't need to have any negative side effects at all.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Overall this comparison shows, that not only social housing can work, but there already cities which have figured out a way to make it work. So just looking at the data, you have to admit, that anti gentrification movements promoting social housing have a point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135682465.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not against social housing per se. Social housing, when done right, has an important rile to play in keeping prices affordable. It works great in Vienna and Singapore too. What I'm opposed to is anti Gentrification activists opposing any market rate housing as 'luxury housing' while demanding all housing is 'affordable' 

Singapore, Vienna etc also build lots of market rate housing. Enough to meet demand. 

What's most important to me is that is that housing is affordable, rather than more subsidised units are being built. 


To do that you need to build a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136043525.0" user="ondrap" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have more data on this? I have looked at some articles comparing e.g. Vienna to Berlin or Prague and what striked me was that in Vienna they were actually building houses, while in Prague/Berlin the government/cities were effectively trying to stop people from building them (stringent rules, bureaucracy etc.). Obviously, if the city is the main builder, they have a stake in the bureaucracy being reasonable. Still, it seems to me that Vienna is quite OK because "houses are being built", not because "the city builds houses".

I have serious economic trouble seeing how the city building social houses could fix the prices. Either there is "enough" housing for prices to be affordable - or there is not. If there is not enough housing, you either get higher price or scarcity. I just don't see how social housing or any regulation could change that.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
