<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="980463745.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/g7qqo1/cmv_anti_gentrification_activists_propose/">
    <title>CMV: Anti Gentrification activists propose measures that harm society and the people they advocate for.</title>
    <original_poster>brianlefevre87</original_poster>
    <original_post>Anti Gentrification activists oppose the creation of new market housing and advocate for only affordable housing to be created. This often comes with the demand that the character of the built environment and demographics remain largely unchanged. 

The end result is the cost of market housing skyrocketing even faster, leaving an area full of very wealthy residents with enclaves of low income communities poorly served by government housing. All families with anywhere near an average income leave. 

The 'luxury housing' opposed by such groups is rarely actually luxurious sky villas with swimming pools inhabited by Martin skraelli. It is usually good quality housing built at market rates. The high cost is due to high land prices caused by not enough homes being built to meet demand. Unless enough housing is built, housing will never be 'affordable' it can only be subsidised. 

Under such conditions, the provision of enough subsidised housing is ruinously expensive for local governments, or is cross subsidised by demanding affordable units in market developments which pushes the price of market units even higher. Waiting lists for subsidised units increase and they are often overcrowded. 

There is also an element of reverse snobbery with anti Gentrification groups. Opposing people moving into the area of a different ethnicity or social class is very ironic for a supposedly progressive movement. 

The idea that the demographics of any area have, should or will remain largely unchanged is not realistic. And it would be a massive waste of public money to try and achieve it. Its just a progressive form of nimbyism. 

I understand these groups may be well intentioned, and that the shortage of housing is not solely from their opposition to it. I also firmly believe in government regulating markets if the end result is a better net outcome for society.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34134995198.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	The high cost is due to high land prices caused by not enough homes being built to meet demand.

Isn’t the whole point of gentrification buying low-cost land, developing it, and then charging a significantly higher price?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135089935.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>No, gentrification isn't necessarily a strategy or a result of strategy, it can occur as a result of many people moving to a desirable area for varied reasons that are unrelated to the hopes of the area itself having rising property values as the demand increases.

It refers to an "effect" that can have varied causes in other words. It only describes how as wealthier people and businesses migrate to an area the area itself changes in nature - there are disputes about the varied pros and cons of the kinds of changes that may occur. Crime lowers, typically, but rising prices may displace locals and cause problems elsewhere.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135155412.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not disputing that Gentrification is an effect, or that it negatively impacts some people. 

My view is that blocking 'luxury' aka market housing and demanding more subsidised units, is a blunt solution to the symptom. It makes the root cause, the rising shortage of housing in an area, much worse.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135166647.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>I was responding only to the comment above.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135169269.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>Oh sorry :/ [climbs down from soap box]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135214285.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>Well, for what it is worth, while I actually mostly agree with your post, there are some contentions or at least concerns I'll share.

For one, there are different forms of Nimbyism. An anti-gentrification activist is seemingly in certain ways like an anti-immigration..ist? but the key difference is the opposition to marketplace forces upending local cultures and destabilizing communities. This is different than simply not wanting poor people in your backyard, because sometimes the concern is actually *keeping the poor people* who are your local artists and small business people who will be forced out by rising prices and then the area gradually turns to corporate blandyland and the kinds of people who thrive in that environment. That isn't about ethnicity or social class as much as it is about maintaining a way of life judged to genuinely be better than the way the impending gentrification threatens to bring upon them. 

The other minor thing I'd note that it isn't always an issue of not enough homes being built. Sometimes the homes are there, but they are simply priced too high and they rather sit there unused or being rented out while people wait for the influx of wealthy people to fill them, rather than sell lower.

I am also not sure exactly why subsidized housing is ruinously expensive or why affordable units drive up market housing. That is my ignorance but it isn't clearly explained in your post and I'm curious.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135437117.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>When land prices get very high due to not enough supply, it costs a lot for local governments to build more. For example, in Central London an acre of land with permission to build would cost millions of pounds. 

For the local government to buy that land and build on it would be very expensive. That money could have been spent on improving schools, transport, social schemes to reduce crime. The things that actually improve an area and make it a better place to live. 

An alternative is to demand private developments set aside a few subsidised units. The developers sell/ rent these units at no profit and increase their profit margin on the market units to compensate. 

There are cities that build a lot of subsidised housing and keep housing cheap, like Singapore and various German cities. But these cities also build lots of market housing, and enough housing to meet demand in general.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137438368.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think housing and land obeys 'supply and demand' rules like this. Housing costs are high due to various perceptions of their value whether it's current or anticipating. Housing is among the most limited resources you can hoard and rent-seek with. The 'perceived demand' - so to speak - can pretty much stay astronomically high as long as an area still seems to be generally stable(unlike, say, areas where the few industries relied upon for wage earning leave). It isn't a typical product and the typical economic models really don't adequately predict or explain the housing situation well.

Housing can be plentiful and still extremely expensive, as long as people have enough capability and incentive to maintain control over it. Very wealthy people and organizations have that capability and incentive right now. 

When that happens you get more economically stressed or displaced lower class, and the middle class starts receding into the lower class. This isn't something that a government can afford not to address if it wants to maintain social stability long term. Better schools, transport, crime prevention don't resolve the problems they target very well if the economic stress of low wages and high rent/housing cost is constantly pushing people into poverty regardless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137695232.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I see your point that housing doesn't work like the supply of most other goods.

However as far as I know every city with a serious affordability crisis has failed to build enough housing to meet population growth. Stopping some 'yuppie flats' being put up or smashing up a hipster cafe isn't going to change that. London and San Francisco are particularly egregious examples. 

If you have examples of cities that add housing faster than population growth and still have spiralling prices, I'd be interested to hear about them.  

Houston seems to be doing very well at keeping housing affordable, as does Singapore and also Vienna as another poster mentioned. All places with very different models but all places that build a lot of houses. 

I've heard of Chinese ghost cities which seem an absolutely bonkers phenomenon I don't fully understand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137895062.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>Portland(my city), Vancouver, Seattle, Manhattan, Aspen. Honestly the list goes on. There's tons of vacant housing it just happens to be owned by wealthy people who don't use it. San Francisco and London would be included actually.

You can view the stats here -

https://www.census.gov/housing/hvs/index.html

There was a huge spike from 2005-2010 in particular which hasn't settled down yet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138193344.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>Just had a quick Google and Oregon has built fewer homes than its population has grown. I believe its the case for all those other cities as well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138197499.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138282271.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>*Available* homes, or homes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136236007.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>It can also refer to the action if developing the property that spurs the movement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137300423.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>If the action of using a building in a certain way triggers wealthuer eople to move in, what would the solution be? Ban vegan cafes and art galleries?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135140330.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>If you develop land you are spending money to create a better quality building and you can charge more. I don't have an issue with this. 

Land values are different. They increase with scarcity or with local conditions improving (better jobs available, less crime, better schools). Obviously the latter is better than the former. 

Land owners don't have a direct impact on land prices increasing, but get all the windfall from rising land values. This is an old and worthy argument for taxing the rental value of land, which would solve this issue. 

The board game Monopoly was originally created to argue for a tax on land (not buildings) and figures from Winston Churchill, Adam Smith to Milton freedman have argued it is the 'least bad tax'

Alas it is a very progressive wealth tax that is impossible to avoid, so the powers that be would never implement it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34135751139.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>True, but from the other side of the coin - the housing market went up, where are the people who couldn't afford higher rent going to go? It's not like alternative low income housing just magically appears when one goes away. 

And granted, they might find other housing, but living location impacts most people's daily activities. Someone who can't afford the new cost of living may not be able to afford an additional hr on their commute to work when the only affordable housing is on the other side of town.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136046275.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>By that logic, shouldn't we stop maintaining existing buildings, so they are worth less and it becomes more affordable?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136343337.0" user="stewshi" delta="False">
    <text>No the point is different. The area is seen as undesirable so the prices are down. Gentrifiers push the price of the property well outside of what the people in that neighborhood were currently paying. Other things that happen is people repurpose buildings. If it would cost to much to renovate your apartment building to cash in on the rent jump? You stop re newing leases  and turn it into office space. Or as a case in Colorado shows they turned a low income trailer park into a parking lot.  The people live in these areas because that's what they could afford. Gentrification also destroys the neighborhoods and their history. Five points in Denver has been considered the "ghetto" and "black bottom" since the state was founded. It became a center of Colorado's balck population. Now that community has been gentrified and so many of the people in that neighborhood that have lived their for generations have been pushed out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136555348.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>The bulk of what I talked about had little to do (if at all) with the structures themselves. It was about the diaspora caused from the economical shift in the neighborhood. You're coming at it entirely from a landowner perspective with no regard for the tenants.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137272557.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I kind of addressed this in my original point. If you oppose all market rate housing you are actually increasing displacement.

Also, most areas change over time. Most city neighbourhoods have changed demographically many times, and are no worse for it.

Whitechapel in London used to be a working class English area, then a Jewish enclave. Now it isn't so much, more of an Asian area. And some middle class people are moving in too. But there are still other Jewish enclaves in the city, the area just changed. No one is any worse for it. 

People from these communities aren't being relocated to the moon.

What matters most is that they can find an area in the city that is affordable to live in and nice. Not that it's in precisely the same spot their grandparents lived.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137344318.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>Out of curiosity, what part of the world are you coming from?

southeast United States here</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137355165.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>I live in London.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138323458.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>Kk

I'll split this into 2 parts, as I think it's important for you to understand my cultural background with the topic. At the same time, I do think there is an argument that's more acceptable universally.

Pt1: my history

The development of the neighborhoods at risk for gentrification over on our side of the pond can generally be traced back to during &amp;amp; shortly after the civil rights movement in what is known as the [White Flight] (https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/White_flight). TL;DR - bc of government subsidies increasing as a byproduct of the movement, middle &amp;amp; upper middle white families moved out into suburbia as inner-city started filling out w/ black Americans. This left inner city to be built with more apartment complexes as it's a more affordable alternative to houses.

Due to Reagan's economic policies (commonly refered to as reaganomics) a burst of entrepreneurship hit the country, ultimately causing a lot of major cities to shift from producing goods to office based work. This left a lot of the work force in inner-city areas unemployed. And turned low income neighborhoods into the ghetto, with lots of low-cost industrial property sitting around. Artists ate this up as they could rent a warehouse &amp;amp; split it between a few heads. This former industrial areas became art districts by the turn of the century which offered a quieter alternative to the crowded bar scene downtown.

Around 2005 gas prices started skyrocketing &amp;amp; there was an economic collapse around the corner. Living way outside in suburbia costed a lot in gas &amp;amp; a lot of people began losing their houses due to struggling to keep the mortgage paid. These middle &amp;amp; upper middle class white families began eyeing these art districts as they were trendy &amp;amp; much closer to work. Even if they didn't stay there, it was a quick fix &amp;amp; a potential investment.

Throughout all of this, more &amp;amp; more of the rural population is migrating towards metropolitan areas as the industrialization of agriculture &amp;amp; farms becoming increasingly corporate leads to many independently owned family farms to sell out. Not to mention the increase of immigration due to the corporate world becoming more global.

That's led us to about where we are currently.


Pt2: the argument

Ok, so economic changes happen locally. So what?

The important part to think about when it comes to gentrification is that the first things changed are generally apartment complexes, typically torndown w/ new buildings put in their place.

This creates a logistic nightmare where a landowner tells a large group of people (sometimes in the hundreds) that they have 3mo to find a new place to live. Now, this isn't just any group of people, this is predominantly black Americans, single mothers &amp;amp; college grads fresh out of uni. Finding housing for that many is already hard, but finding housing somewhere outside of their neighborhood has tons of problems including transportation &amp;amp; time. In many times it leads the former residents towards homelessness.

An addition to this is the practice of landowners demolishing structures on their property simply to wait out until the value goes up. These leaves business owners &amp;amp; home leasers out on the streets for little to no reason.

One thing your argument lacks is where this new affordable housing is coming from. Cities rarely shrink. So all the old housing developments in the suburbs are still growing with increasing costs, so that's out. All the old subsidized housing is turning into private condos that cost many times more than they did before, so that's out. We're talking potentially thousands of people in a city are having to relocate, and those housing options need to be lower cost. 

So, where are they?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138335188.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>PS - I looked up all apartments &amp;amp; condos built in my town since 2000 (around when neighborhoods started becoming gentrified here) &amp;amp; all of them have swimming pools</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34138958468.0" user="tablair" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; One thing your argument lacks is where this new affordable housing is coming from

There's a logical fallacy in your argument. Namely, you're only considering existing residents rather than taking a holistic view. That's great if you're a baby boomer who's been in your home for ages, but what if you're a millennial/gen-z who needs a place to live? Perhaps you even live in the area but your family has grown too large for your current home and you're looking to move out and get your own place. Programs that seek to cement the status quo are great for those who have their situation sorted and don't need to change. But they're counterproductive to everyone else, including many who are not gentrifiers. What needs to happen to make the situation better for everyone is to drastically increase housing density. Studies have shown that adding high-end supply to the market actually exerts downward pressure on rents across the board provided that housing is higher density.

Richer people are never going to get shut out of a market. If there isn't high-end supply, they'll bid up the next nicest supply and force those who would otherwise be in those homes to bid up the nicest place they can buy. There's a cascading effect. By creating supply at the top end, you create space at the lower end. The problem we've seen in high-demand housing areas is that even new construction is not keeping up with demand. So people make the faulty assumption that the addition of high-density, high-end apartments is not exerting downward pressure on lower-end rents because those rents are going up. In reality, absent that high-end housing, those rents would have gone up by even more.

So the answer to your question, if we can spur enough building (high-end or otherwise, so long as it increases density) to satisfy demand for housing, is that the down-market housing comes from the existing supply. We've created enough new housing for wealthier people that the remaining housing stays affordable. It's really the only solution to keep housing affordable...have more housing that people who want it. We just need to build a lot more and ignore anyone who complains about the "character of the neighborhood" because those people are advocating for policies that fundamentally limit the number of people that can live in a certain area. And even a basic understanding of economics will tell you what happens when you have strong demand for a fixed-supply resource. You can't keep both the size and the cost fixed in the face of increased demand any more than you can keep the pressure and volume of a container fixed when the temperature increases. These are basic laws of nature and too many housing advocates argue for policies that deny those basic laws.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34141348997.0" user="FatStephen" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Namely, you're only considering existing residents rather than taking a holistic view.

I'm not looking at it holistically bc it's not that kind of a problem. These people don't have the time it'll take for the housing market to resettle so they can find something affordable, they need something in that 3 months they have before they're on the streets.

And I'm only talking about the people bc that's the glaring problem w/ gentrification, &amp;amp; TBH I'm not sure why you're trying to dodge it. According to [the 2019 state of housing report for my hometown, Charlotte, NC] (https://realestate.uncc.edu/sites/realestate.uncc.edu/files/media/State%2520of%2520Housing%2520in%2520Charlotte%2520Report%25202019_FINAL.pdf&amp;amp;ved=2ahUKEwjsqK6Ah4bpAhUmh-AKHZs0C4AQFjALegQIBBAB&amp;amp;usg=AOvVaw13I2W_GSThmf0ZFI4xHMCK) the cost of property has skyrocketed, and there's a huge problem with no real affordable housing options. This is 20yrs after neighborhoods started becoming gentrified here, and there still isn't enough low income housing to offset the demand. Hell, [Baltimore, MD stopped accepting applications for public housing last November] (www.baltimoresun.com/maryland/baltimore-city/-ci-housing-authority-20191112-20191112-to7xezy6s5bn3afcou4wtrqzl4-story.html) bc there's a 5yr wait &amp;amp; it's had new development from gentrification going on since the 90s with no real growth in subsidized options.

So, I'm going to ask again - where is the housing for the newly evicted low income people coming from?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34142101350.0" user="tablair" delta="False">
    <text>You’re still not getting my message and you’re still looking at it through the flawed perspective of most affordable housing advocates, which is why we continue to have housing crises. I want there to be affordable housing for *everyone*, not just affordable housing for *existing residents*. And, fundamentally, the only way that can happen is to build much, much more housing. The reason that there is no affordable housing 20 years after gentrification started is because not enough building happened. These areas never fully committed to the massive amount of new high-density construction necessary to keep prices affordable. It is the one and only way that we can keep rents affordable.

Artificially keeping rents low for existing residents has huge problems. For one, it encourages underutilization since residents cannot downsize when they’re done raising their kids. Second, it means subsequent generations cannot afford to live in the area where they grew up. These areas need to fully commit to massively increasing the number of people they can house and stop worrying about “Manhattanization” or preserving “the character of the neighborhood.” The character of these neighborhoods will fundamentally change no matter what. Either it becomes a densely-packed big city, with lots of tall apartment buildings, or it becomes a highly gentrified area where poor people can’t afford to live. There’s no third option when an area is desirable to live in.

So I’ll say again, the housing comes from existing supply, **but only if public policy commits to building enough supply for everyone**. To date, nowhere in America has been willing to make that commitment. That is the reason we continue to have problems with gentrification. And you can’t use the urgency of individual situations that are the result of flawed policy making over a 30-year history as evidence that more flawed policy is justified. Two wrongs don’t make a right, they make an even more wrong. Yes, it sucks for those individuals that will get displaced because of the history of poor public policy decisions. But that doesn’t mean that adopting the correct public policy stance now isn’t the right way to go. Existing residents do not have a fundamentally greater right to affordable housing than prospective residents. It boggles my mind that so many progressives see this when it comes to an issue like immigration and yet are so blind to it when it comes to localized housing policy. There will always be pain as we dig ourselves out a hole that’s 30-50 years in the making. But we need to start that process now and anyone preventing us from doing that in any way needs to be ignored.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34136255812.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	If you develop land you are spending money to create a better quality building and you can charge more. I don’t have an issue with this.

The issue is when wealthy people buy up land and force people out of adjacent land due to rising property values making it unaffordable for them. 

&amp;gt;	Land owners don’t have a direct impact on land prices increasing, but get all the windfall from rising land values. 

Right, but I’m more concerned about the people renting from those owners. 

&amp;gt;	The board game Monopoly was originally created to argue for a tax on land

Taxing land has no bearing on whether gentrification is harmful.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137189542.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>How would wealthy people force neighbouring people out of adjacent land? What exactly do you mean by this? 

I am also more concerned about renters than the landowners. 

Taxing land does have a lot to do with it. If land was taxed the rising land value would be captured by local government at the expense of the landowner. The tenant wouldn't pay any of it. 

The tenants would at least benefit from increased local government income for schools, hospitals, or affordable housing construction. 

At the moment, tenants get a double whammy of a rent hike and no improved local government services.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34137217334.0" user="waldrop02" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;	How would wealthy people force neighbouring people out of adjacent land? What exactly do you mean by this?

By raising the rent on business property or rental units to an extent that they become unaffordable to the current tenants. 

&amp;gt;	Taxing land does have a lot to do with it. If land was taxed the rising land value would be captured by local government at the expense of the landowner. The tenant wouldn’t pay any of it.

Taxes are paid in an economic sense by the less elastic party to a transaction, regardless of who pays the taxes on paper. I’d argue tenants are almost always the less elastic party. 

&amp;gt;	The tenants would at least benefit from increased local government income for schools, hospitals, or affordable housing construction.

&amp;gt;	At the moment, tenants get a double whammy of a rent hike and no improved local government services.

These wouldn’t be the same tenants though. That’s my point - without ensuring that the benefit of increasing property values and economic development accrues directly to the existing population, they’re priced out.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34146331675.0" user="StuffChecker" delta="False">
    <text>I think you’re a little confused here. I’ll give you an example of a typical gentrification issue: 

Mid-sized southern town, well say 100-250,00 people or less. A local popular brewery build a new location on the edge of a traditionally poor part of town. Here’s what happens: more affluent patrons start visiting the area and wanting to spend money there. Supply will meet demand, nicer restaurants will want to open near this location to get drunk-ish people in to spend meals, they rent an empty suite in a strip mall. The affluent people start going there. Other businesses want to move into this strip mall to capitalize on the increase in people, but there’s no new space in the strip mall. The landlord realizes he can charge more to these new businesses and the typically local owned businesses are told they cannot renew their lease. These businesses belonged to members of the poor community who now have to relocate their business. Now that the strip mall has “better” businesses and the brewery is there, more affluent people will want to live in these areas. Same thing happens with residential that happened with the strip malls. They’re leases will not be renewed or they’ll be told they can’t renew. Now, an entire community has been forced to relocate. This is bad and they are uprooted from their traditional communities and lose ties to one another and their neighbors, and likely jobs, access to public transportation, etc. This results in keeping these communities stuck in the poverty cycle, increases violence, and leads to drug related crimes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34146904909.0" user="brianlefevre87" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I see your point more clearly. A trendy business opening up could be the vanguard for more wealthy people moving in. Kind of a reverse 'there goes the neighbourhood' 

In your example the increased demand could lead to vacant sites being put to use or extra apartments and commercial added to existing sites e.g. mixed use buildings over parking lots, adding stories to apartments. That's if its allowed / easy to do zoning wise. 

In time, enough space could be added to accommodate new businesses and residents. This would result in less displacement.

However in many cities it's risky, slow and expensive to build up sites, if it's allowed at all. Richer people will still want to move in, prices go up a lot faster, and existing residents get bid out. 

In my view this makes displacement much worse and in some places inevitable. 

What would alternative solutions be? Not allow new, more profitable businesses to open in an area? Not allow wealthier residents to move in?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
