<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="985655549.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gau0ot/cmv_the_us_general_election_is_a_fantasy_there_is/">
    <title>CMV: the US General election is a fantasy, there is no "better" candidate.</title>
    <original_poster>NotAnthonysThrowAway</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not heavily involved in politics, I'm a lurker at best. So I won't pretend I know a tremendous amount about policy, economics, foreign affairs or any of that stuff. But what I see is a popularity contest between two people who are effectively identical in their arrogance, egocentrism, stupidity, and ability to sway masses of idiots. For the purpose of this argument, we'll say the race is between Donald Trump and Joe Biden and that's it. If Trump wins we will probably be stuck in some weird dystopian authoritarian oligarchy where the entire paradigm of federal government will become something completely alien and astronomically oppressive on America, its people, culture, policy, freedoms, etc. On the other hand, if Biden wins, we will have another Obama presidency where the vocal minority on the liberal end will scream in celebration of "all the great things democrats are getting done" when really its just more of the corporate elite and the political elite robbing working class people, starting illegal wars, caging children because they're immigrants and ignoring the needs of the american people. Honestly, The only reason I can possibly imagine somebody looking at this race and thinking one side is better or that America will be better off with one or the other as the POTUS, is because they aren't looking at the full picture. This isnt about Democrats vs Republicans, or Progressives vs Conservatives, or Leftists vs Neo-Liberals. It is about the same thing it has always been about since Bush. Its about the rich finding more ways to screw the poor. The only way we as a nation are going to shed our divisiveness and stand on the grounds of logic, critical thinking, and problem solving, is if we stand together and overthrow the current paradigm of administration and create a new party by force. There is no such thing as doing it legally, or going through official channels, or negotiating with legislators/public officials. If you give them an inch, they take a mile. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34166461684.0" user="approachingreality" delta="False">
    <text>You'll never get people to work together when the media is so controlled and seems to have complete control of the population.  Nobody is calm and rational anymore.   The country has been successfully divided into highly emotional,  easily offended groups that are effectively manipulated through social media like reddit.

I think we're gonna have to go through some actual trying times,  unfortunately.  Society is falling apart just a few years after the influence of the greatest generation left us.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
