<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="985655549.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gau0ot/cmv_the_us_general_election_is_a_fantasy_there_is/">
    <title>CMV: the US General election is a fantasy, there is no "better" candidate.</title>
    <original_poster>NotAnthonysThrowAway</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not heavily involved in politics, I'm a lurker at best. So I won't pretend I know a tremendous amount about policy, economics, foreign affairs or any of that stuff. But what I see is a popularity contest between two people who are effectively identical in their arrogance, egocentrism, stupidity, and ability to sway masses of idiots. For the purpose of this argument, we'll say the race is between Donald Trump and Joe Biden and that's it. If Trump wins we will probably be stuck in some weird dystopian authoritarian oligarchy where the entire paradigm of federal government will become something completely alien and astronomically oppressive on America, its people, culture, policy, freedoms, etc. On the other hand, if Biden wins, we will have another Obama presidency where the vocal minority on the liberal end will scream in celebration of "all the great things democrats are getting done" when really its just more of the corporate elite and the political elite robbing working class people, starting illegal wars, caging children because they're immigrants and ignoring the needs of the american people. Honestly, The only reason I can possibly imagine somebody looking at this race and thinking one side is better or that America will be better off with one or the other as the POTUS, is because they aren't looking at the full picture. This isnt about Democrats vs Republicans, or Progressives vs Conservatives, or Leftists vs Neo-Liberals. It is about the same thing it has always been about since Bush. Its about the rich finding more ways to screw the poor. The only way we as a nation are going to shed our divisiveness and stand on the grounds of logic, critical thinking, and problem solving, is if we stand together and overthrow the current paradigm of administration and create a new party by force. There is no such thing as doing it legally, or going through official channels, or negotiating with legislators/public officials. If you give them an inch, they take a mile. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34166466579.0" user="Improverished" delta="False">
    <text>Who do you think is better on climate change and healthcare?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34166534738.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Unquestionably the guy who acknowledges climate change is real is better on it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34166898452.0" user="Improverished" delta="False">
    <text>Follow up, who do you think is better on lgbt issues and fighting for labor standards?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34167003309.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>Trump *says* he supports the LGBT community, but he then also tried to ban trans people from serving in the military and appoints judges who have said they want to overturn Obergefell. Biden has also had some troubling positions on lgbt rights in the past, but he came out in favor of same-sex marriage notably *before* Obama did, and the party he would be leading unquestionably is better on LGBT issues than the GOP. Even if you don't quite trust Biden, any judge he nominates would have to be approved by the Senate, which means he would need support from an overwhelming number of Democratic Senators. The Democratic Party's platform has included support for lgbt for a long time. I don't think a Democratic Senator would get re-elected if they suddenly dropped that support. Therefore, even if Biden himself were secretly as opposed to lgbt equality as, say, Trump's VP Pence is, the party backing him would never support him rolling back their rights. For this reason I believe a Biden presidency would be far better for the LGBT community than Trump.

I don't think Biden would be overly great for labor, but, again, I *do* think he would be far better than Trump. In Trump's personal businesses he treats workers terribly. He regularly tries to get out of paying for work. His administration has rolled back protections for workers across the board and has empowered companies to retaliate against workers. I believe Biden would represent a return to the Obama-era status quo with regards to workers' rights, which is bad, to be clear. Trump would continue to roll back protections and would continue to appoint judges who side with bosses over workers.

So on both accounts I think Biden is better. What do you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34167108823.0" user="Improverished" delta="False">
    <text>I’m totally behind Biden, I feel we are way closer on civic, social, and economic issues then I would be to trump. I don’t think I like the idea of status quo I feel as though it’s more of an issue of democracy. Things just take a long time to happen like getting a unified position/goal on like reducing our carbon output, promoting green energy, establishing a public healthcare option, or advancing lgbt rights. We can have a person like trump come in and set us back by years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34167155091.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>The way I view this election, "my side" lost when Bernie lost the nomination. At this point, I'm not voting for a win. That ship has sailed.

To me, Biden represents maintaining the conditions which make it possible for "my side" to win, even just a little bit, sometime in the future. If Trump wins I believe he will get to replace RBG and/or Stephen Breyer on the Supreme Court. If that happens, it's all over. He'll appoint a 40-something arch-conservative who will sit on the court for at least the next 30 years. That will give the Supreme Court either a 6-3 or 7-2 conservative majority for almost the rest of my life. With that kind of court, even if we had a President Bernie, Democratic House with Speaker AOC, and Democratic Senate with Majority Leader Elizabeth Warren, every single thing they passed would get overturned by the conservative court.

If Trump gets those two Supreme Court seats, I don't see any policies I want happening within my lifetime. That's the number one reason why I'm voting for Biden.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
