<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="985655549.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gau0ot/cmv_the_us_general_election_is_a_fantasy_there_is/">
    <title>CMV: the US General election is a fantasy, there is no "better" candidate.</title>
    <original_poster>NotAnthonysThrowAway</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not heavily involved in politics, I'm a lurker at best. So I won't pretend I know a tremendous amount about policy, economics, foreign affairs or any of that stuff. But what I see is a popularity contest between two people who are effectively identical in their arrogance, egocentrism, stupidity, and ability to sway masses of idiots. For the purpose of this argument, we'll say the race is between Donald Trump and Joe Biden and that's it. If Trump wins we will probably be stuck in some weird dystopian authoritarian oligarchy where the entire paradigm of federal government will become something completely alien and astronomically oppressive on America, its people, culture, policy, freedoms, etc. On the other hand, if Biden wins, we will have another Obama presidency where the vocal minority on the liberal end will scream in celebration of "all the great things democrats are getting done" when really its just more of the corporate elite and the political elite robbing working class people, starting illegal wars, caging children because they're immigrants and ignoring the needs of the american people. Honestly, The only reason I can possibly imagine somebody looking at this race and thinking one side is better or that America will be better off with one or the other as the POTUS, is because they aren't looking at the full picture. This isnt about Democrats vs Republicans, or Progressives vs Conservatives, or Leftists vs Neo-Liberals. It is about the same thing it has always been about since Bush. Its about the rich finding more ways to screw the poor. The only way we as a nation are going to shed our divisiveness and stand on the grounds of logic, critical thinking, and problem solving, is if we stand together and overthrow the current paradigm of administration and create a new party by force. There is no such thing as doing it legally, or going through official channels, or negotiating with legislators/public officials. If you give them an inch, they take a mile. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34167152381.0" user="parentheticalobject" delta="False">
    <text>If you think that both Biden and Trump are terrible, I can respect that. I also agree that we should change our fptp system for something that allows more parties to feasibly exist.

I don't think there is *any* system that won't force you or most citizens to accept someone you think of as terrible and a "lesser evil."

In modern America, there is no possible set of policies that will make someone seem like a truly great candidate to any more than maybe 30% of the population, tops. Lots of people are dissatisfied with the two options we have, but switch them for something else and you'll just get a different set of dissatisfied people. 

Who do you imagine wouldn't have 45% of Americans hating them and another 25% saying "they're awful, and I wish I had a better alternative, but I'd vote for them if I had to."?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
