<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="985655549.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gau0ot/cmv_the_us_general_election_is_a_fantasy_there_is/">
    <title>CMV: the US General election is a fantasy, there is no "better" candidate.</title>
    <original_poster>NotAnthonysThrowAway</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not heavily involved in politics, I'm a lurker at best. So I won't pretend I know a tremendous amount about policy, economics, foreign affairs or any of that stuff. But what I see is a popularity contest between two people who are effectively identical in their arrogance, egocentrism, stupidity, and ability to sway masses of idiots. For the purpose of this argument, we'll say the race is between Donald Trump and Joe Biden and that's it. If Trump wins we will probably be stuck in some weird dystopian authoritarian oligarchy where the entire paradigm of federal government will become something completely alien and astronomically oppressive on America, its people, culture, policy, freedoms, etc. On the other hand, if Biden wins, we will have another Obama presidency where the vocal minority on the liberal end will scream in celebration of "all the great things democrats are getting done" when really its just more of the corporate elite and the political elite robbing working class people, starting illegal wars, caging children because they're immigrants and ignoring the needs of the american people. Honestly, The only reason I can possibly imagine somebody looking at this race and thinking one side is better or that America will be better off with one or the other as the POTUS, is because they aren't looking at the full picture. This isnt about Democrats vs Republicans, or Progressives vs Conservatives, or Leftists vs Neo-Liberals. It is about the same thing it has always been about since Bush. Its about the rich finding more ways to screw the poor. The only way we as a nation are going to shed our divisiveness and stand on the grounds of logic, critical thinking, and problem solving, is if we stand together and overthrow the current paradigm of administration and create a new party by force. There is no such thing as doing it legally, or going through official channels, or negotiating with legislators/public officials. If you give them an inch, they take a mile. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34166530381.0" user="VVillyD" delta="False">
    <text>There are several reasons why Biden would be better than Trump, and most of them boil down to the same thing: in order to govern a President needs support from his party in Congress.

1. Climate Change. This is an easy no-brainer. Trump believes climate change is not happening, and that it's a Chinese hoax. Biden believes the science that tells us climate change is happening and is a **BIG** deal. I do not believe that Biden would do anything nearly as impactful as, say, Bernie or Jay Inslee would have if they had been the Democratic nominee, but Biden will certainly do more than Trump. If you believe Climate Change is a big deal we need to address, then Biden is better for you than Trump.

2. Competence. Regardless of policy, competent leadership in government can have a huge impact in people's day-to-day lives. Look at the two major (and connected) crises we're facing right now: coronavirus and the economy. Trump's utter incompetence as a leader has made both situations dramatically worse than they could have been. Trump has been receiving intelligence briefings since January warning him of the impact of coronavirus, yet until middle of March he was saying it wasn't a big deal, that it would be over by April, and that it would barely effect us. A competent leader would have started ramping up healthcare capacity, started making test kits, putting policies in place to help healthcare providers and states, etc as soon as he found out about the virus. Then a competent president would have coordinated and direct national efforts to fight the crisis. Trump did none of this. This has nothing to do with ideology or policy. It's just about ability to lead. Given Biden's experience in the Obama administration, we know he has *some* experience dealing with both a massive economic crisis (the Great Recession) and global pandemics (Ebola, MERS, H1N1). While I would probably disagree with some of the policy choices Biden would make, I at least trust that his team would be competent enough to manage the situation much better than Trump.

2. The Supreme Court. This is the big one, and the only one that really matters. Ruth Bader Ginsburg is 87 years old. Stephen Breyer is 81. They are the oldest two justices, and represent half of the Democratically appointed justices. I personally do not believe both, and probably not either, will last another full Presidential term. That means whoever wins the election this November will likely replace both of them. If Biden is the President, that means the current 5-4 conservative-liberal split will be maintained. That's not overly good, but it's status quo. None of the far more left wing policies I want will be enacted, but the split in the court leaves the possibility that whoever comes after Biden can try to get some of those policies passed. If Trump wins the election he'll replace 2 of the liberals on the court with 40-something arch-conservatives who will sit on the court for the next 30+ years. That's the whole ball game. With a 7-2 conservative majority **nothing** anyone to the left of the GOP wants to see will happen in our lifetimes. No Medicare for All. No Green New Deal. No overturning Citizen's United. Nothing. In fact, whatever progress has been made over the past 40+ years will be overturned. Roe v Wade will be gone. Obergefell will be overturned. Obamacare will be abolished. DACA will be gone. Regulations and restrictions on the private sector across the board will be undone. Think the banking sector is too underregulated now? Wait until Trump has an overwhelming majority on the court. Want the courts to do something about partisan Gerrymandering? Not with a 7-2 conservative majority. Literally every single Democratic, Progressive, Liberal, or Leftist policy will be dead for at least 30 years. Personally, I think with a 7-2 conservative majority the Republicans can institute enough changes to the election system that they will ensure their minority rule for generations.

This election isn't about winning right now. I fully acknowledge that I lost when Bernie lost the nomination. This election is now about ensuring the conditions exist to be able to fight with any hope of winning in the future. I'll vote for Biden, but from the first day of his presidency I'll be fighting to push him and the Democratic party to the left. I'll support a left-wing primary challenger in 2024. I'll be critical of every single moderate or conservative decision/policy Biden makes. But at least I will have hope that someday I might be able to see *something* that I want.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
