<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="11" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34190662902.0" user="MooseOrgy" delta="False">
    <text>Idk man I think the GOP is fighting a losing battle.  Trump skated by 2016 against an abysmal lazy corporate dem in Hilary.  The “dems” you’re referring to I take it you mean corporate moderate democrats? Look how the moderates just rallied around Biden and handed a Bernie his ass.  Moderate Dems are winning primaries and I fully expect Biden to beat trump.  The dems needed a centrist to appeal to moderate republicans and they got one and trump hasn’t fulfilled his promises of 2016.

The losing battle I refer to is more so the culture battle.  Social conservatism is losing everywhere.  The GOP have to stop being the party of the religious fundamentalist and need to become the party of the fiscal conservative.  You’re seeing states like Virgina starting to elect local dems.  A relative nobody in Beto fought a good fight against an entrenched republican in Cruz.  States that have always been locks are now becoming purple.

The GOP have to change their platform or they will not win anymore imo.  I won’t even get into things like voter suppression or the dems recent election wins because others have pointed that out.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
