<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187707355.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Democrats have actually been doing quite well in the polls, and it seems to be because they are taking, or at least splitting, the gains from the rally around the flag effect. Trump has gotten a few points, far less than the double digit bumps that other unpopular leaders are getting, while Democrats are (according to fivethirtyeight) 8 points ahead on the congressional generic ballot. That's a landslide. Whatever they are doing, it's working. 

They have also nearly all lined up behind Biden. Sanders and Warren, the two candidates least likely to endorse him, have done so. You think infighting is bad now? You should look at the riot that happened in the 68 primary.

It should also be noted that Democrats, from 1933-1995, held the house for all but 4 years. They also mostly controlled the Senate as well, and the presidency roughly half the time. The recent Republican hegemony, one they are barely keeping up for more than term or two, is a blip compared to that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187853755.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I get that all, but our political history starts at 1968, and I am old enough to remember it. 

I believe that the history books will write that the second big break in the Democrats was in 1995 with, if you remember, the blue dog Democrats, and the third modern one being the debacle in 2016 which I believe actually started in 2008. 

I misstated my CMV and I am referí g to recent politics. I would not say that the republicans are a blip on the map, and that is clearly evident by the superior strategy of stacking the courts and passing legislation solely meant to get them re elected. 

I find your argument compelling, and as someone who use to run people against Democrats, I don’t mean to suggest they are a roll over.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
