<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187726207.0" user="Afghanistanimation-" delta="False">
    <text>I'll zero in on one aspect of what you said, "I depend on a strong opposition to keep a fair and balanced society." 

I question whether the premise of the question, Democrats winning elections is even the important focal point. They don't need to win half the time to be a positive force for change. 

One of the best and most unifying ways of characterizing the delineation of the parties is that Republicans seek to maintain the status quo, and Democrats work to update it and advocate for the dispossesed. That's a rough paraphrase, and I heard Jordan Peterson state it this way. I'm not sure if it's his original thought. However, the point is if the status quo is working for 75% of people, Democrats have the challenge of convincing at least 50% of voters that they should take a haircut or compromise to improve life for the 25% of persons who are disadvantaged. They are unlikely to win this argument half of the time, particularly with ever evolving and often unrealistic or utopian endeavors (not possible to implement, or the damage of implementation far outweighs potential benefits.)

The fact that Democrats are fractionated in my opinion, is a good thing. It fosters a "free market" style of competition, allowing the truly popular and/or good ideas to rise to the top, while fringe positions lead to the fractionation. In this fashion, when a Democrat IS elected, their often more left-center positions encompass common factors from these fractionalized groups. These are more likely to be logical, and cause less collateral damage when implemented. 

There are very few places I can see any entrenched policies or positions moving back to the right. The only examples I can think of are environmental protections and banking regulations. Meanwhile, it's hard to see things like healthcare, housing and employment protections, social welfare and general social policies trending anywhere but to the progressive side. 

In short, winning percentage is irrelevant; furthering progress is what's important. In my opinion, the system is working as it works best: slowly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188066926.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I just wrote a really long post thanking your for being Insite full. 

I also stated what I stated before, that catering to the percentages is the democrates weak point and the fuck em all if they don’t like it works for republicans. 

It is important to keep a balance. We want a Supreme Court that is reasonable. Laws like citizen united voted out. As Americans we should strive for balance. 

Stupid Apolo app.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188258389.0" user="wellillbeamonkeysunc" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Insite full.

Wow you really *are* a Republican.  May I ask, what keeps you in the party even though you felt compelled to abandon "the machine"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188426074.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t really see a choice. I believe in the principles more than the principles of the democratic party. 

Also typing on a phone doesn’t always help in spelling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
