<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187248483.0" user="privForReddit1" delta="False">
    <text>Didnt they just win the house? After winning the popular vote for president? After winning the previous two presidencies?  

Im a Republican too, but if I had to say, it seems fairly even to me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34198067260.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>From a post elsewhere, just to clarify my position. 

Yes, that is my argument. 

If you remember, in 2008, the democrat machine really wanted Hillary and did not want Obama. And since we are on the subject, Obama lost the popular vote in the primaries to Hillary by almost 300,000 votes. 

I believe that while he was an effective leader, he was not a good politician (at least at first). His public opinion, and one that he practiced at first, was that government should be run by congress, and invited all the members to have a say in his first two year agenda. Do you remember him inviting all the republicans to sit down and discuss health care, it was a political disaster. 

In 2010, the republicans made a huge gain with a wildly popular president because the democrats didn’t come out and vote and the republicans were successfully running the narrative. 

In 2012, a democratic presidential year, the democrats didn’t really make a dent in the republican gains. Again, the democrates let the republicans run the narrative. The also mostly ignored the local races that the Republicans were really entrenching themselves. 

In 2014, again under a popluar president with. inreal scandels and a growing economy, the republicans made a big gain in the house and took control of the senate, under a growing ecomomy. 

In 2016, the republicans picked a shit show for a canidates and the democrates, not learning from 2008, not only told everyone that hillary was going to be thier only caniadate in the primary, but when bernie sanders said, you cant do that, you at least have to appear to let the peope choose, he was actively sabatoged.  let me repeat, the republican party let the democratic process play out to the dismay of a majority of republicans, while the democratic leadership forced a canidatr on the people. in 2016, if the democrates that had voted in the last 3 elections had voted, they would have won the presidents, seated 2 or more supreme court justices, and have taken the high road. 

In 2018, the blue wave turned into a blue trickle under a wildy unpopular president 

in 2020, you are doing everything you can to lose the presidency. 

so yes, that is my stance.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
