<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187211790.0" user="wajubop" delta="False">
    <text>They flipped the house in 2018 and won a presidential election in 2012. Aren’t you massively over-extrapolating?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187253187.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t  believe I am.  Obama was a good President and it is hard for a halfway decent President to lose, no matter what party. 2018, and I believe 2020 is going to be a gift to the Democrats despite, not because of themselves.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187718020.0" user="wajubop" delta="False">
    <text>Look, you might be right. I know the saying, “Democrats fall in love. Republicans fall in line.” I have observed and participated in tons of hand wringing about the ideological split on the left side of the political spectrum. There is a ground level resentment toward the neoliberal managerial class. Republicans have been able to capitalize on it; Democrats have not. Liberals keep clustering in coastal cities. And the GOP has seized a decisive majority of state houses. It all seems very imposing. 

But the thing with national elections is that we end up rewriting big sweeping narratives. Before 2016 people were saying the GOP might not be able to win another presidential election, and if the Comey letter hadn’t come out and Hillary has one we might’ve kept thinking that even though materially things wouldn’t be much different than they are right now.

We might fucking lose in November. By a lot. All I’m really saying is that it’s easy to predict things will keep going how they’ve been going because, with national elections in particular, the ideological forces at play are always changing and the elections are spaced out in such a way that it’s tough to draw a trend line that goes back much more than 15-20 years in any coherent way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187978713.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>But I am trying to draw a line from 2008 to now, specifically stopping at 2010, 2012, 2016 and now. Each time the Democratic Party has a chance to put a dagger in the republican surge of the tea party and it never happened. People like me were ousted and only people they swore to never work with a Democrat or publicly agree would be able to stay under Mitch McConnell’s decree. 

As I have stated before, democrats made the wrong decision at each point. Obama thinking that the president should be weakened and the country should have more involvement from congress left the door open for republicans in 2010, which they gladly stepped through. Subsequently when Obama caught on it was too late. He was a good president, but was a bad party boss. 

2016 Hillary and wasserman shultz vs Bernie was a worse blow to the party than the fbi letter. She would have one in a bunch of ways had the party not played in bad faith with Bernie ( as well as not running a good campaign). If the would have Bernie run, and possiblie lose, then it would net carried over to 2018 and now the 2020 election cycle. 

McConnell is a war politician, no doubt, and has no rival on the democratic side, which I guess is the point I’m making. 

I do hope that trump loses, even though I think I would have rather had almost anyone else running against trump.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
