<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187187431.0" user="leahsimsxo" delta="False">
    <text>Odd, because Democrats win the popular vote quite often. The votes are there.. it’s not the people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187193389.0" user="Aaaaaaandyy" delta="False">
    <text>That’s not how elections are won.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187220196.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, but my post is that Democrats can’t win election. Is your retort that they don’t know the rules?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187710913.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I think the argument is that the rules are rigged in the favor of the opposition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188203282.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>That’s a different animal. I strongly disagree with taking the vote away from anyone. I think felons who have paid their debt should vote. I think voting should be easy. 

That being said, I would be interested in a conversation where it is unreasonable for someone to have to have an I’d to vote. I don’t think the voter suppression argument is as sound as the popular wisdom makes it sound.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188234625.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think voting should be easy.

You may say you're a Republican but this is not what the mainstream GOP thinks. They think it should be difficult to vote as evidenced by their resistance to all measures that make it easier to vote.

Take the recent example in WI where they decided to block mail-in-voting (and that's just the most recent example) which they are also trying to block at the federal level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188278647.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I get it, and my point here is I need help to wrestle my party back from this current leadership. 

But as far as voting. I still don’t see how a block to mail in voting is a direct republican win and a Democrat loose. The effort is exactly the same. 

Not saying there should not be mail in voting, there already is absentee balloting, so it’s not un precedented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188626339.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>That's why it's silly, there's no clear evidence mail voting would benefit Dems and still Republicans are against it because it makes it easier to vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188654932.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text> It it does work in The republicans favor. 

But it leaves a bad taste in good peoples mouth when groups do things like this that are overtly for the sole purpose to disenfranchise voters, any voters.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34190367331.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I mean why do you identify as a Republican if what they do so disgusts you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34191517805.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Because I am a Republican. My pillar of beliefs and priorities were set a long time ago. 

When I first became aware of politics, I quickly realized that there was no rhyme or reason to a vast majority of politics on both sides. This was back in the late 70s and it was the Carter Reagan years. The first time I was involved with politics, I campaigned for McGovern  ( I was very young)  and was kinda mindless during the Nixon ford years. 

As an adult during the 80’s election, a friend took me to tasks as to why I was going to vote for Reagan, and I took the question seriously.  At that time, government regulation and tax structure was killing the country, and had been through the late 60s and 70s, so my inclination was for less government control, smaller federal government overreach ( as I am to this day). This is not to say I don’t think the federal government doesn’t have a place, just post FDR recovery never loosened up to let businesses thrive again. 

I value people over persons. I don’t think the federal government should cater to the lowest common denominator. This is a stark break from any Democrat ideals. This can be applied in many situations. 

I value privacy, which honestly is the biggest let down of both parties. I believe Paine or Franklin, whoever said it, when you tried privacy for security, you end up with neither. 

I hunt and fish and believe in a reasonable 2nd amendment. I think the polarization of this has caused bad results on both sides, republicans favoring no restrictions and dems favoring total appeal of the amendment. Also I hate apologist that feel the need to say that guns are for hunting. This leads to the false argument, that leads down the road of “ can you hunt with this gun? How about this one? “. Just like free speech is reasonably curtailed, so should the 2nd amendment, but people shouldn’t have to justify it, just as they don’t have to justify free speach. 

I could go on and on, but you get that I’m not Democrat material. 


What disgust me is the open door that was left to hardline republicans and they took it. The irony of the thing is that I believed in the tea party in its first version. I was a fan of Ron Paul. It, along with the Republican Party, was hijacked into this spending hateful vitriol thing we have today. 

So I fight from inside hoping that the enemy of my enemy will get strong and help me from outside, hence my post.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34191746223.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you don't really have a party... honestly I'd peg you as libertarian. Why not identify as third party who votes Republican?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34198095665.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I’m not a libertarian because I endorse world politics.

Also have you seen the libertarian party, they are kinda crazy tin foil hat people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187978894.0" user="leahsimsxo" delta="False">
    <text>You literally said democrats don’t vote. I said that’s incorrect. That’s all I said.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188184518.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>My point is they don’t win elections, but your point is taken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188867875.0" user="leahsimsxo" delta="False">
    <text>You literally said Democrats “sit at home” when the popular vote says otherwise. Yeah, we don’t win elections, but that’s not because we aren’t voting...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188908548.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Enthusiasm gap. Too tired to add more. Tomorrow.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188928452.0" user="leahsimsxo" delta="False">
    <text>Don’t bother, I don’t care</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34198091634.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Exactly</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
