<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187213051.0" user="darbbl1080" delta="False">
    <text>I would challenge your idea that infighting is bad.  300 million people represented by 2 political parties is not practical.  Don’t you wish there was a Conservative party you could support now that your values have diverged from the contemporary Republican Party?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187239435.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>My point is this is they way it is and not what should be. 
My point is also that a weak Democratic Party hurts the Republican Party and the nation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187302255.0" user="darbbl1080" delta="False">
    <text>You have to have infighting before you have more than 2 parties.  The Marijuana Now party isn’t going to be a contender tomorrow out of the blue.   My hope is this infighting and discomfort your experiencing with your party leads to more and better options.  Maybe then people will vote based on their values instead of market identity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187338124.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I will hope with you on that. We keep our infighting quite, but it is there. Problem is on a national scale, I don’t think you picked the best  candidate for president. 

The presidential candidate pick is the glaring example of my CMV.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187427848.0" user="darbbl1080" delta="False">
    <text>I think we will only be able cyv if November turns for the D’s.   Here is my hypothesis:  the markets have been shifting towards giving consumers more control of deciding what they want, at some point this is going to hit the political industry.  I think we would be better for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187249300.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>I for one wish there was a conservative party that didn't stand by racist, homophobic, and explicitly religiously-driven policies. You know, a moderate one.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187284132.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>But you generalize an entire section of the population. This is the weakness I see I. The Democrats. I hate it. I work it from the inside and I’m. It going to quit. But a braid statement like that makes my job harder</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187317142.0" user="RuroniHS" delta="False">
    <text>Cool. Try being a republican candidate who supports gay marriage and see how that goes for ya.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187342150.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Oddly enough, a strong Democratic Party at the time has made this more of a none issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187329573.0" user="darbbl1080" delta="False">
    <text>He’s talking about the Republican Party.   I vote D in national elections bc of the reasons he stated.  The R’s were exasperated by deficit spending and subsidies by the Obama administration.  I generally supported them, but understood their position.  Now the R president has also gave out subsidies increased deficit spending and the size of government, while decreasing revenues.  When we have a conservative President I’d like some conservatism to go with it.   It seems like R’s dont mind deficit spending and subsidies if it goes to an interest group they ID with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187456695.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>To be clear, I cannot vote out trump fast enough, and I’m sad to say I cannot vote out more of these bad politicians. I not only agree that we don’t have a conservative president, but I’m not really sure of the Republican agenda at all except selling out. 

I would get my life that if Biden loses in 2020, there will be a backlash and the Democrats will find a unifying voice, but I think the damage will be done for my lifetime at least. 

So far no CMV that the current Democratic Party cannot win elections that aren’t handed to them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
