<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34188305141.0" user="VypreStrike" delta="False">
    <text>It's not as much of a Democrat problem as it is a 2-party problem. The GOP basically represents all right-wing ideologies from moderate to extreme, and the Democratic Party tries to do the same. The issue is, most Republicans tend to be more moderate, so the GOP isn't split as much. On the other end, Democrats tend to be split pretty much 50-50 between moderate and far left, which causes really big issues when the party can only nominate one person for a position, since naturally Republicans won't support a Democrat, but also, that Democratic candidate can only attract half of all Democrats.

This issue is solved in most countries by splitting the Left wing into two parties, a moderate left and far left party. The moderate and far left form a coalition so that they together still make up a good chunk of the voting base, but since they can each nominate a candidate, everyone's ideas get represented.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34198085919.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I left you a longer post the other day, but Apollo app seems to be buggy. 

As someone said here. Republicans fall in line and democrates fall in love. Another quote was in order to go fast, go alone, in order to go far, go as a team. 

Taking out policy and what’s best, this kind of proves my point.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
