<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34188915346.0" user="1917fuckordie" delta="False">
    <text>I think I know what you're getting at and why people are confused about your CMV.

I think you're making a true statement in your title, and I won't be able to change that view. But the view I can change is the idea that the democrats want to win. They don't. At least not in the way the GOP wants to win.

The Republicans have no problem with powerful, emotive, rather over the top appeals to their core values. They had no problem with saying stuff like "This is communism" with something as tame as Obamacare. You said you saw this yourself with the tea party. That's a good example of the GOP getting every thing they want by being more extreme.

The Democrats can't or won't do that and don't want to win elections by appealing to the left. They want Obama type candidates. Why? Because they're smart technocratic beurecrats that can govern without changing much and while not angering the very powerful special interest groups.

They don't want a Bernie Sanders candidate that has to do all this work implementing medicare for all and going up against every interest group and reworking everything. Its hard work and it's often not successful straight away. Growing pains go along with any big reforms.

And the democrats certainly don't want to radicalize the left the way the republicans can radicalize the right. This is the main point. What happens when republicans go on and on about how the evil communist democrats have destroyed America? What are the consequences?

You get morons going to the government of Michigan's office with guns during a quarantine. Or you get psychos sending pipe bombs to the offices of NYT. This isn't good but it's really not that bad for conservatives.

What happens if the left gets radicalized? Strikes. Protests. Riots. Clashes with police. Open challenges to state authority. This is very very bad for democrats in a way that republicans never have to worry about.

This is why democrats refuse to move from their centrist position. This is why they won't give an inch to people like Sanders while talk about compromising with Republicans. And it's why they can't get people to vote for them. If you make voting sound like your saving America, as the GOP does, then lots of people will vote for them. If you frame it as "vote for us and we will maintain the status quo in a proper manner" then no one who wasn't paying attention will start to.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
