<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="14" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26873141950.0" user="Octavian-" delta="False">
    <text>Am I the only one that reads ESPN here?

You need to understand something about the name "Redskins": It's not a racist term and native americans overwhelmingly don't find offense in it. In fact, the term was coined by native americans themselves and often serves as the self selected mascots for high schools on reservations. The people being offended by the name are a bunch of dominantly white, politically correct people who have no real idea of the word's context. They just assume it's racist, and run with it.

Just because something refers to skin color does not make it racist. If you can't have a team called the Redskins, then you shouldn't have teams called the patriots, saints, vikings, or anything named after any group of people. Because really, the "Redskins" isn't any more offensive than a mascot referring to our founding fathers (patriots). People just see the word skin and jump to the conclusion of racism.

Read this column: http://espn.go.com/nfl/story/_/id/9689220/redskins-name-change-not-easy-sounds</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
