<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26872633621.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>I am not familiar with the history of the word redskin as a slur, so perhaps this won't be particularly persuasive, but here goes:

The Redskins franchise was established about 80 years ago, when you very definitely could have established a franchise called the [insert city] Black People without anyone batting an eye (at least, in terms of leaving folks offended). 

Maybe it was an offensive name then as well and was allowed due to a culture not as invested in political correctness as ours is today, but I think it would be wildly unfair to say that any malice is intended by the continued use of the name that now has a storied history in the league. It is kept because it is a brand that has been recognizable for decades and beloved by many--there is clearly no malice intended, and like any other word, the only stigma it can have or harm it can cause is a direct result of people allowing it to do so. 

In this day and age, if you were to try to establish a new team called the Blacks, I imagine you'd be dealing with a backlash. If you had created that team in 1935, and in that time won several national championships and remained in the league through today, I think it would be likely be treated the same way the Redskins are treated today -- that is, implicitly accepted without a second thought. 

Is it an offensive thing? To many, I am sure. Is it inherently evil or wrong? I don't think so. If your goal is to be offended by something, you will always succeed. If you stop trying to turn words poisonous, they lose any negative power they might have. [Lenny Bruce nailed it. (NSFW)](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=gfNhiRGQ-js)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872661610.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Maybe it was an offensive name then as well and was allowed due to a culture not as invested in political correctness as ours is today, but I think it would be wildly unfair to say that any malice is intended by the continued use of the name that now has a storied history in the league. 

Really? Imagine the Washington Cotton-Pickers were a team that had existed since the early 1800s. Do you really think that that team name wouldn't be offensive today, just because it was seen as relatively benign at the time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872667961.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>But Cotton-Pickers is a direct reference to a period of history with nothing but malevolent connotations. Are you saying that "The Blacks" is equivalent to "the Cotton-Pickers?" If, conversely, you are suggesting that "Redskin" is on the same level as "Cotton-picker" then I probably just don't have enough experience with the word's history, as I said up front, but that doesn't seem fair off the cuff.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872681612.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>My hypothetical was supposed to suggest that Cotton-Pickers wasn't viewed as a malevolent term in, say, 1800, and maybe would have simply been descriptive. 

But even if you don't think that Cotton-picker is the appropriate analogue to "Redskin" I would argue that neither, really, is even "Blacks" because black people are fine calling themselves black - it's not considered a slur (although maybe it is when used as a noun rather than a descriptor). Maybe something like ["darkie"](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Darlie) would work better (though still imperfect) - it came from a context in which it wasn't viewed as offensive, but [over time](http://www.printmag.com/imprint/from-darkie-to-darlie/) came to be regarded as a slur. I would posit that the Washington Darkies would also be offensive.

Anyway, at the root of it is the contention in your post that the original meaning of the term seems to be the only thing that should matter, rather than the meaning it has taken on in society since then. That seems to me to be a wild assumption, and especially indefensible given how long people have been castigating the Redskins for their name (meaning that everybody is clearly aware that the team name is racist), Dan Snyder's [continued forceful rebuffs to the idea that the team should change its name](http://espn.go.com/nfl/story/_/id/9259866/daniel-snyder-says-washington-redskins-never-change-team-name), and the fact that even [Congressmen](http://www.nfl.com/news/story/0ap1000000207158/article/redskins-name-change-congressmen-urge-dan-snyder) have taken note of the issue. At this point it feels like very purposeful dickishness. 

Edit - And anyway, I think that if the team was called the Washington Blacks and its mascot was a black person, it would generate huge outrage and would have been changed decades ago.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872693428.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>Point taken, although if you mean "purposeful dickishness" as in "I am deliberately trying to offend people by keeping this name" I think you are off the mark. I think that goes back to "This name has a history in this league and it is a brand important to me and fans, and I won't change it on those accounts." Not to defend Dan Snyder though. Moving on.

I guess the argument I am trying to make is that by changing the name of the Redskins we are doing less for the cause of racial tolerance than we would be by trying to destroy any negative power that the word Redskin has in the first place. Changing the name would be brushing it under the rug and sending a message of "The word is the important thing, just don't use the bad word and everything is okay."

While "darkie" is a much more fair analogue, I think if the team had been called that 80 years ago instead, I'd be making this same argument today. 

But I'm a white guy who has faced comparably little racial tension in my life, so maybe I'm off base here.

EDIT: It now occurs to me that the point of this was to change the OP's view that his team should be allowed and I am basically trying to do the opposite of that with these posts, so, I should probably shut up. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872699076.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I guess the argument I am trying to make is that by changing the name of the Redskins we are doing less for the cause of racial tolerance than we would be by trying to destroy any negative power that the word Redskin has in the first place. Changing the name would be brushing it under the rug and sending a message of "The word is the important thing, just don't use the bad word and everything is okay."

How is this argument different from walking around using the n-word daily and telling people to simply change their perception of it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872707591.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't. 

Again, Lenny Bruce.

Obviously I don't do this, and I don't know people that do. If it turns out that Lenny and I are wrong in theory, it could cause a lot more harm than good. It just seems that the power a word has over us is the power we give that word. Obviously **MUCH** has been done to give the n-word power, and maybe removing that power is an insurmountable challenge. 

The idea is to destroy racism, not simply just to bury it and make racist words/statements socially frowned upon. I'd rather everyone be able to say redskin and not think twice about whether it was meant to harm than everyone have to go "Can we start calling it the r-word and make sure no one says it so that if someone DOES say it we know they're trying to be hurtful?" </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872712276.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Obviously MUCH has been done to give the n-word power, and maybe removing that power is an insurmountable challenge.

Maybe removing that power is not the task of anybody except the group in question? It seems a little ridiculous for white people to freely throw around words that Native Americans and black people believe are offensive and tell them not to take umbrage. If the words are to lose their power, it should be because the group that believes it is harmed by the term says so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872737409.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>I am not suggesting it is the responsibility of white people more so than Native Americans in OP's case, nor black people in ours. I am out of my depth here because I have trouble imagining what it is like to identify with a group you are part of simply by the random chance of who your parents were, or who their parents were, etc. 

When I hear "redskin," I think, "football team." And then some other unrelated things I happen to think because I am a Cowboys fan.

I think that is the case for most. I would suggest, to a Native American offended by the team's name, that if ever it was used to try to hurt them, the team's name has helped to remove that negative charge by changing people's impressions of the word, and it will not be used by those people to hurt them any further. Whether that is any consolation, I don't know.

But again, this is me living in my idealized bubble where I don't think twice about race and forget that other people do. I'd like for words that have been used to divide us in the past to lose the power to divide us in the future, and that we're not constantly tripping over ourselves wondering what we are allowed and not allowed to say around people who look different from ourselves. All we are doing is marking our differences and separating ourselves further. 

I hope I have not given the impression that I was trying to speak for anyone but myself here. Apologies if that was the case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872744487.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; All we are doing is marking our differences and separating ourselves further.

I think this is a commonly-made argument that sounds good on its face, but in practice comes off as hugely tone-deaf to the experiences of minorities. Of course, as neither a black person or a native American myself, I can't speak for them either, but if I were, I don't think I would find most arguments about why white people should be allowed to throw around terms for people of my background despite me saying that it is offensive to do so particularly persuasive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872761267.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>I am not arguing for the ability of white people to throw the word around. I am saying that anyone, regardless of whether they are white, or black, or any other color that people happen to be should not have to worry about what words they are allowed to say to this other person because they look different. 

I recognize that we can and do hurt others by using these words. I would hope that the recourse could be to see what we, as a human species (not as white people or Americans or whatever the hell else) could do about enabling people to rise above any power the words ever had on them. If there's nothing to be done but sweeping the bad words under the rug and teaching people not to use them, I feel like all we're doing is allowing racism to fester under the surface and leaving groups of people vulnerable to attack by people who would use those words anyway, and with intent to harm.

My argument is that keeping the Redskins team name as it is works to that purpose for Native Americans. I don't have any data or credibility to confirm that it does, but that's my belief so there ya go. 

I'm gonna step out now--been fun. Tagged you as "Guy who knows his shit."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873418121.0" user="hiptobecubic" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with your argument here is that it can't reasonably be applied in any other situation. Let's make a team called the "Alabama Fats" and have a fat white woman in a motor scooter be the mascot. She might be hurt but I don't think anyone should let words control how they feel. Or we could make the "Philedelphia Ex-Nazis" and just have the logo be a German guy. Or maybe the "San Francisco Chinks" and we'll use a picture of Mao.

You only see the difference in these examples because the offend *you*. It's not like the pictures are offensive on their own, right? Sure maybe the names are a little offensive, but words shouldn't hold any power. They are just words. It's best not to sweep them under the rug.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873428859.0" user="Kingreaper" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;EDIT: It now occurs to me that the point of this was to change the OP's view that his team should be allowed and I am basically trying to do the opposite of that with these posts, so, I should probably shut up. :)

It's perfectly acceptable to try and change the view of the people trying to change the OPs view :-)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873170665.0" user="thekick1" delta="False">
    <text>Why don't you stop saying I don't have enough experience with the word, take 2 seconds and google it or wikipedia it.  Cotton Pickers would be on the same level as Redskins.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872702175.0" user="Fire42uck" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; no malice intended

The intentions of actions are meaningless if the effects go contrary to them. Suppose you playfully punch your friend on the shoulder. You don't attempt to hurt them, but you unintentionally do. Can you tell them that they shouldn't be in pain because you didn't mean to inflict pain?

&amp;gt;If you stop trying to turn words poisonous, they lose any negative power they might have.

On "trying to turn..." well, nobody's trying to change anything about the word. It's *already* racist, and it shouldn't be used because of that. For offensive terms specifically, the *offended party* needs to decide whether or not something offends them. 

It's not just a situation where someone can just nut up and recite "sticks and stones." Especially in this case, it's a problem of representation. In the case of the Seminoles (team), the Seminole tribe officially allows them to use the name. They've chosen how they can be represented. In the case of "redskin," well, who's being represented? Every Native American tribe ever? We're just lumping them all into one group, which trivializes their cultures. No one's being represented in a way that's complimentary to them. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872751986.0" user="omgimonfire" delta="False">
    <text>You make some excellent points, and I don't have the time to address them right now (Maybe later if I am still feeling conversational), but I did wanna say:

&amp;gt; The intentions of actions are meaningless if the effects go contrary to them.

Not sure if this is something you just came up with or a quote that I am unfamiliar with, but it's a really eloquent piece of language I reserve the right to steal it in future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873401512.0" user="nklim" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with this.
&amp;gt;The intentions of actions are meaningless if the effects go contrary to them.

Say I'm helping you move, and I accidentally drop one of the boxes on your foot. I think that's a million light years different from coming over, throwing a box at your foot, and leaving. The results are exactly the same, but the intention is very, *very* different. One is clearly worse than the other.

Or even in the case of hitting your friend in the shoulder. The difference between hitting someone because you're being aggressive and hitting someone because you thought it would be funny and didn't mean to punch so hard are very different scenarios. The results might be the same, but the intention is very different. I would absolutely have a separate reaction to each.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873844193.0" user="Fire42uck" delta="False">
    <text>That's simply because of related actions. Helping you move would be something that will help you evaluate your friend favorably even though he hurt you. I would imagine that the accident would be followed up with an apology or some sort of acknowledgement that a wrongdoing occurred. The action itself is not better or worse, it's what you perceive it may lead to: if someone attacks you with a box in your own home, you might be worried about similar attacks in the future. 

The fact is, there's no way of telling for sure what someone's intentions are. Maybe the guy helping you move just likes seeing you in pain, but apologizes profusely to hide his intentions. There's no way for you to know, you're just judging him based on his past and present actions. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
