<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26872713013.0" user="POHoudini" delta="False">
    <text>Certainly could if you wanted. Nobody bats an eye at the New Zealand National Rugby team.

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Zealand_national_rugby_union_team

They are called the All Blacks. It only matters if you want it to. The term Redskin is a Native word for themselves. White people at the time, had much much worse names for natives. 

Oklahoma means land of the Red People, why aren't you trying to change that? Because it is a native term much like Redskin. Not to mention the Redskins team does not have a silly mascot or otherwise parody it's origin. The logo is always straight faced on purpose. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872751162.0" user="reducedosprey" delta="False">
    <text>The New Zealand rugby team is called the 'All Blacks' because they were an all black [uniform,](http://www4.pictures.zimbio.com/gi/New+Zealand+Blacks+Portrait+Session+eAgigQdE1GQl.jpg) it has nothing to do with the colour of anybodys skin.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872752528.0" user="fryguy101" delta="False">
    <text>Uh. Not trying to argue against your point, but... they're called the All Blacks because their uniforms were all black.

Just like New Zealand's national association football team is the All Whites.

It has nothing to do with race.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872972017.0" user="POHoudini" delta="False">
    <text>That was my point, color a color and it what you associate it with that gives it the entirely subjective meaning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872988183.0" user="Probably-Lying" delta="False">
    <text>yikes. no. 
Just because it has the word "black" in it, doesnt mean its a comment on race. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872998815.0" user="POHoudini" delta="False">
    <text>Same with Redskin to me, It was the point I was trying to make, but I concede that I am horrible at expressing that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873004061.0" user="Probably-Lying" delta="False">
    <text>except that many native american groups see it as a racial epitaph. 

Furthermore, if the all blacks mascot was this guy http://www.otrcat.com/z/blackface_AlJolson.png, who did silly dances and shit during half time and fans dressed up similarly for the games, it would be treated differently.

the redskins mascot is a african american guy dressed up to be a comical dramatization of what an actual indian would look like, wearing a exaggerated headdress, barefooted, riding a horse.  do you see what im getting at? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873019940.0" user="POHoudini" delta="False">
    <text>I do but, I do not remember ever seeing a guy wearing anything and riding a horse at a redskins game. They do not parody the namesake. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873205015.0" user="Fire42uck" delta="False">
    <text>"Red***skin***" is most definitely a comment on race. So is black *people*, as in the OP's example.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873071163.0" user="Trackpad94" delta="False">
    <text>The Maori which are responsible for most of the All Black's traditions including their haka aren't even black. They're islanders. I don't know what you're on about. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873077835.0" user="POHoudini" delta="False">
    <text>The point I was making was that OP certainly could name a team the blacks and such, but that the color is not point. He was beholden to Redskins as a racial slur that described skin color of a certain people. My point (poorly expressed) was that the color has no meaning (as he stated with black people) it is the representation of the team as a whole that determines its meanings, however subjective it may be.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
