<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26873788727.0" user="JamesPSullivan" delta="False">
    <text>Keith Olberman did a great segment on this on his show a couple weeks back, citing it as the "last racial slur you can say at work without getting fired." Link: http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JXsfcVvZbXE

And the implication you raise is absolutely right. It's morally reprehensible to use a term which in every light is a racial slur as a team for a major sport. 

Many, many teams over the years have had to change their names, or due away with their mascots over the past couple of decades just to not be so outwardly racist. I briefly attended a school in western Illinois called Knox College, where the mascot/team name was "The Knox College Siwash" which is a racial slur to some tribes indigenous to that area. Knox changed their name a while back, and they were absolutely right in doing so. On the other hand you have institutions like the Florida State Seminoles which pays massive royalties to the real Seminole tribe to be allowed to use the mascot, and their portrayal is dignified and respectful.

So your argument absolutely holds some weight, but the fact is that the name is likely on it's way out. The tides are changing against the organization, and there is absolutely public outcry to change the team name. So no, you shouldn't be allowed to have a team called the Black People.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
