<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26873380500.0" user="MeddlingMike" delta="False">
    <text>Two things here:

1) I'd say that teams like the Redskins and the Indians are sort of grandfathered in past the offensive name clause. People have already bought the gear and had decades to warm up to the team name. If you were starting an expansion team today I think you would have a difficult time calling a team something like that because the world has changed and people would not feel the affinity for the current team name like they do with the Redskins.

2) I'm not black, but I don't believe that calling somebody "black" should be/is considered an offensive term. I think it's a better term than "African-American" because it doesn't risk being misused on black people who have no American roots. I believe it's the only accepted term used by the Associated Press for that reason. I think the problem with this as a team name is just that it's not a very good name. It doesn't evoke any of the emotion or enthusiasm that you would like for a team name. Any sort of "[Insert Race] People" wouldn't work for the same reason. Now, maybe if you wanted something more specific like the Zulu Warriors that ties to a proud fighting tradition you'd be on the right track. If you think about it the Patriots and Vikings work off a similar principle for white people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
