<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34234795225.0" user="HeftyRain7" delta="False">
    <text>There are actually Christians who struggle to understand this as well. But, even though I'm an athiest, I think I can explain.

If humans didn't have free will, they wouldn't chose to be good willingly. They would choose to be good based off of God's will. A fair God wouldn't condemn someone for being cruel if They were the reason the human was cruel.

God might know exactly what you'll choose, but forcing you to make a choice would make things like morality meaningless. 

I find it also helps to think of god like a parent. A parent could force their child to make good choices in school. They know the outcome of a child slacking off will be that they fail a class, for example. A good parent also knows if their child is succeeding or failing in school. While they could force their kid to do the work, once their child is a certain age, most parents let them succeed or fail on their own, so that they can learn from it and grow as a person.

Many Christians view God in a similar way. If God controlled everything we do, we wouldn't learn and grow and make the right choices on our own. Free will is required for our choices and actions to have any meaning, and God couldn't punish people for their choices if free will didn't exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34234834714.0" user="Protagoras67" delta="False">
    <text>I mean, I understand that argument. But God doesn’t technically need for us to grow or have us fear it in order to act “good” God is omnipotent and could just create us in God’s ideal form of what a human being should be without deviation because God is the designer of the universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34234942969.0" user="HeftyRain7" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah, he COULD. But, that's technically what angels are. Angels are beings God designed to serve him with no free will. God wanted to create people who had free will as he does. As for why, it's likely because being surrounded by people who always do what you say, every second of every day, would get very boring.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235046268.0" user="Savagemaw" delta="False">
    <text>This is just some shit from the movie *Dogma*.  There is no biblical support for the idea that heavenly beings lack free will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235082574.0" user="HeftyRain7" delta="False">
    <text>I haven't even seen the movie Dogma, so I have no idea what you're talking about.

I mean, the second any angel sins though, they're immediately banished to hell, whereas humans can sin and still get into heaven. Furthermore, angels are said to exist to praise God. "sinning" for an angel could be simply ceasing to praise him.

So I guess they technically have free will, but they have much less freedom of choice than humans do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235322371.0" user="Savagemaw" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I mean, the second any angel sins though, they're immediately banished to hell, whereas humans can sin and still get into heaven. 

Sin is separation from God which is what happens when humans disobey God.  God gave Adam specific instructions which he disobeyed.  Adams plan was not God's plan, and Genesis describes a conversation that God has (either with himself, or with the heavenly host) where it is said basically that the man and his wife can't stay in Eden anymore because now that they've eaten from the tree of knowledge, they are more likely to eat also from the tree of life, and become like 'us'.  

That separation is what is known as sin, and the desire to do unclean things is a symptom of that separation.  This is recognized by different terms by many faith systems and spiritualists around the world.  We are broken, and because we are broken, we do bad things.  When we become whole, and one with our divine nature, we no longer do these bad things.  We are not sinners because we 'sin'.  We sin because we are sinners.  We draw away from God, because it is in our nature, as beings separated from God.

&amp;gt;Furthermore, angels are said to exist to praise God. "sinning" for an angel could be simply ceasing to praise him.

In Judeo-christian theology, *creation* exists for the glory of God.  Everything is meant to praise God.  There are four specific heavenly beings (that are not Angels, but cherubim) who sing around the throne of God without ceasing.  They are surrounded by 24 elders who bow down and worship God.  But the heavenly host is numbered like the stars in the sky.  That's just 28 members.  

We have a record in Genesis 6, the story of the Elohim (Sons of God) coming down against God's will and taking wives of the daughters of man. They are not sent to hell immediately.  They are punished later, but hell isn't even introduced as a concept until Greek thought began to make its way into Judaism.   

Even in Revelation, hell is a temporary holding place until the *Great White Throne Judgement* when death and Hades are cast into the lake of fire, with the dragon, the beast and the false prophet.  (Feel free to speculate on what those actually are because Judeo-Christian philosophy is inconsistent on that matter, depending on the time period and the writer).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237484549.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It is written in the Bible that God created us in His perfect image, IIRC. Therefore, we already are His ideal form of a human being. We were created, not to fear God, but to make choices of our own that He has already foreseen.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
