<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="17" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34236073741.0" user="Tibaltdidnothinwrong" delta="False">
    <text>God is OOO. Omnipotent, omniscient, and omnibenevolent. 

Having free will is good. 

Therefore, being omnibenevolent, God gave man free will. 

God didn't give man free will, "so we could be tested", that is silly, God is omnipotent, he already knows us to our bones. 

If you believe free will is inherently a good thing, then it follows that a moral diety would bestow that thing upon it's creation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236209127.0" user="Protagoras67" delta="False">
    <text>But free will allows us to do things many religious people will deem to be immoral. Wouldn't it make more sense to program the universe so that immorality did not exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237161730.0" user="HidingImmortal" delta="False">
    <text>The argument goes:

Free will also allows us to do things many religious people seem to be moral.  If we can't choose, then we can't choose morality. If the universe was programmed so that immorality didn't exist then neither would morality.

The good of morality is seen as out weighing immorality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237286345.0" user="Protagoras67" delta="False">
    <text>God is the alleged arbiter of universally morality. If we were programmed to follow the exact universal morality without being capable from deviating, it would be true that we would not be able to reflect on morality, but we would exist in a perfectly moral world so it would not matter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
