<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34235017491.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>The Jewish response is a step by step answer:

Step 1) god made the world purely for our enjoyment 

Step 2) god recognized that the best form of enjoyment was a spiritual closeness to him

Step 3) in order to make the closeness more enjoyable, he made it possible to achieve higher levels of enjoyment by doing the right thing

Step 4) god recognized that hard work is enjoyed more then a free gift ( this is quite logical if you think about it)

Step 5) in order to make the choices real work and not a gift He had to make the world with free will so that one is free to choose</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235533208.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Step 1) god made the world purely for our enjoyment 

Without even getting into the logical impossibility of free will, this rationale seems absolutely daft. If he didn't create any sentient creatures, there would be nobody needing to enjoy the world, except for god himself. So what god is doing here is creating a need for the sake of imperfectly satisfying the need that he created. It's absurd. If I can see how absurd that rationale is, I'm sure that the omniscient fount of all knowledge ought to be able to see it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235743894.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>Nobody needs to enjoy the world 

What I meant was god wanted to create the world for our enjoyment (if you are of the opinion that god can’t have desires then that’s your opinion)

Also the logical impossibility of free will are you talking about the contradiction between free will and omniscience?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235779674.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nobody needs to enjoy the world 

We have the psychological need to enjoy the world, because suffering is what we experience when we are not enjoying.

&amp;gt;What I meant was god wanted to create the world for our enjoyment (if you are of the opinion that god can’t have desires then that’s your opinion)

So we existed before the world? If not, then it is not logical to create the desire for enjoyment for the sake of partially satisfying that desire. Why would you do that (create a desire for the sake of partially satisfying a desire) when it comes with huge collateral damage?

&amp;gt;Also the logical impossibility of free will are you talking about the contradiction between free will and omniscience?

It's not just that, it's the fact that free will would require us to be self-causing. We would need to have chosen our own nature, our own preferences, our own disposition, etc. We act according to our will, but we cannot choose our own will, because that would entail an infinite regression.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235818066.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>What I meant by nobody needs to enjoy the world is that god didn’t create the world for that need he created it so that people could enjoy their existence 

He obviously created the desire for enjoyment as well but he didn’t create the universe to fulfill our desire it was to fulfill his (of causing us to have enjoyment)

As well we can fight against our nature even if it’s not chosen by us that’s the basic concept of free will that even though we have thoughts desires and emotions ultimately we get to choose how to act</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34235860613.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;What I meant by nobody needs to enjoy the world is that god didn’t create the world for that need he created it so that people could enjoy their existence

You're not getting it. Why create people with our desires, in order for us to enjoy existence, when there would have been nobody missing out on that enjoyment if god hadn't created us to begin with? And what of all the people and sentient life forms that aren't enjoying existence?

&amp;gt; He obviously created the desire for enjoyment as well but he didn’t  create the universe to fulfill our desire it was to fulfill his (of  causing us to have enjoyment) 

His rationale doesn't make sense, because there would have been no need for us to have had enjoyment without him creating us to want and need enjoyment. So he cannot justify it as anything other than a reckless and selfish act, given that he opened the door to great suffering for the sake of creating unneeded needs and desires for ways to alleviate the suffering that he caused by creating us in the first place. I don't see how anyone can see this creator as benevolent and competent.

&amp;gt; As well we can fight against our nature even if it’s not chosen by us  that’s the basic concept of free will that even though we have thoughts  desires and emotions ultimately we get to choose how to act 

Neural activity in my brain produces thoughts. I don't direct the neurons to produce the thought that I want to think before I have the thought. My brain has to produce the thought before it enters conscious awareness. If I wanted to fight against my nature, my brain would have to have generated that thought without conscious input in the first place, and the generation of that thought would need to have been outside of my control, because I cannot choose which thought my brain is going to think before my brain thinks it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236056040.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>Yes the human desire for enjoyment wouldn’t need to be fulfilled if they had not been created but god desired to fulfill it so did create the universe( wether or not you see that as Kind or selfish is your choice, I choose to see it as kind )and the suffering people endure is physical anyhow notice I mentioned a spiritual enjoyment as the the desire god had


As for the neural pathways discussion, I didn’t say one could control his thoughts, in fact many have tried and all have failed. No thoughts cannot be controlled but actions can and as well reactions 

P.s sorry for not doing the thing you’re doing with the quotes and stuff I don’t know how</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236081695.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see how you could see it as kind to create unneeded problems for the sake of creating desires that didn't have to exist and then having some of those desires satisfied. 

&amp;gt;As for the neural pathways discussion, I didn’t say one could control his thoughts, in fact many have tried and all have failed. No thoughts cannot be controlled but actions can and as well reactions

You have to have the thought to act before you can act. So if you can't choose the thoughts that you have before having them, then your actions are also pre-determined. If you want to change your actions, you have to have the thought to want to change your actions first, and that thought arises unbidden in your consciousness as a result of prior causes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236121544.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t exactly see what you mean 

actions aren’t predetermined like thoughts they occur after you have already decided to act as for the desire to act that may come as a result of your conscience of which their are two sides your good inclination and your bad inclination your desires maybe predetermined and maybe only your bad inclination is speaking at the moment 

but ultimately you can consider the right course of action and then perform along that course</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236142902.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>You have to have the thought to decide which action you are finally going to take. You act after you have gone through the process of thinking through all of the different options, but you did not choose for those thoughts to emerge in your consciousness. If you were to rewind to a certain point in time, keeping all parameters the same and without knowledge of the future, you would always make the same decision. It wouldn't matter how many times the scenario replayed, it would always end up with the same decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236152334.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>The decision you speak of do you mean the mental descion or the actual physical action that is preformed because of that decision</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236160662.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>The mental decision and the physical action are both pre-determined. The physical action obviously results from the mental decision that was made, and the mental decision was the result of thoughts that you did not choose to think before thinking them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236246651.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>Okay so we have established that you will act on that thought right? Okay. 

Now we are getting into Jewish territory

According to the belief that Jews have that god gave the Torah then we don’t have to decide what is the proper decision only if we will follow it 

You would like to propose that the choice is predetermined 


I would like to offer a conjecture that every decision is isolated and it is not affected by ones nature it’s certainly calculated by the considerations of past experiences  

To use the concept of nerves and signals I would say that the brain is conscious and sentient so it has decided the best course of action based on past experiences (ie emotions and stuff) that  the thoughts of these actions are not like desires and they are not like desires that god controls instead he restricts his control and allows for your brain to make its own decisions 

As to your point that the neurones (is that how you spell it) are predetermined that is not the case because it’s still you thinking these ideas</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236280683.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>Calculating based on past experiences would also be a thought process and those past experiences would have been deterministic. And I didn't say that god controlled desires. Our brain making its own decisions is a deterministic process, because actions follow thoughts, and you cannot choose which thoughts to think before thinking them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236386130.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>I did say god chooses desire that’s part of Judaism that your desires are predetermined

The past experiences would not be deterministic because others actions were chosen and so were yours in those situations</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236395359.0" user="existentialgoof" delta="False">
    <text>To have chosen the past experiences, you would need to have had the thoughts which precipitated action, before thinking those thoughts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236436069.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text>And therefore we are at a Standstill because I am of the position that every action is based on previous experiences and you say those experiences were predetermined which is not true if you  believe in my opinion so 🤷🏻‍♂️</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236556039.0" user="ezrago" delta="False">
    <text> I would like to thank you for the civil discussion and the answers</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
