<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34234755181.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, you're saying you don't believe in God and then making assumptions about what god would and wouldn't do. I also don't believe in god, but if you put forth and idea of an omnipotent god then you simply have to say "god decided to give people free will" and the conversation is over - there is no argument beyond that that makes any logical sense.

You can of course argue that the world doesn't seem to have this god in it, or that specific _versions_ of god from some doctrine or dogma don't seem consistent with god having given freewill (e.g you might argue that the good god would not abide by freewill since it leads to choices that are sometimes not good, and so on).

So..to the Christian you _don't have to understand_ - in fact figuring all that out is very much part of the lifelong pursuit of the Christian.  You know you have freewill, you know God is good and you know god is omnipotent.  Figuring out how to be the best Christian in that context _is the pursuit_ that god has set people up for.  Since ultimately God is the arbiter of what is "really good", then you are gonna operate within that construct. God DID design it how he wants, but that doesn't mean it's obvious to you or I why he did that.  Being a Christian is about leading a life of inquirty into _how to be most good_.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237040261.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>I gotta say I disagree. To force love from someone isn't love. Forcing your wife to have sex with you while saying you love her is clearly not love. If I choose to accept that God exists and loves me, then it is also very logical to accept that God has given me the choice to do so. Well logical to me at least.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237447941.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>What that I said are you disagreeing with?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237572155.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree with the thought that God wants to "test" us, and so He gives us free will as some sort of test of love. He wants a loving relationship with us. You cannot have a loving relationship if you force a partner to do or think a certain way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34238340684.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah...i didn't say anything like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34239515085.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I realize I mixed up my responses. Your initial statement of there is no logical explanation/response after the statement that God gave us free-will is what I was referring to in my first response.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34239544216.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>I don't understand your response.  I didn't talking anywhere about forcing anything or testing anything.  you're putting a lot of words in my mouth there...not sure why!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34239828115.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>You stated that there is no logical argument that can be made to support the idea of free-will and an omnipotent God beyond that of "he's God and that's what he did". And so Christians just accept that. I presented the topic of the difference of forced and unforced love to be a logical argument in support of the idea that free-will and an omnipotent God can indeed co-exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34240021170.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>No.  There is no _need_ for an argument beyond "god is omnipotent...".  If god's reason is about love, then so be it.  But...his will alone is sufficient.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
