<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="18" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34236329999.0" user="Praeconium2501" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just curious, how would you justify there being no free will without a god figure? I would actually think that yeah, presence of god would make free will less likely. So what would be controlling our will if there is no god?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236447227.0" user="Protagoras67" delta="False">
    <text>While the neuroscience community has not completely disproven free will, there has been a lot of research  that our thoughts and actions are decided prior to our conscious thinking of performing those actions. When you are deciding what flavor ice cream you want, your subconscious mental processes have already predetermined what flavor to choose while you still think you are deciding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34236490293.0" user="Praeconium2501" delta="False">
    <text>Okay interesting, thanks!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237012218.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>I have heard of that idea before, but I always questioned in response to that, if we are nothing but  organisms that are controlled by a plethora of hormonal and chemical changes and releases in the body, how then can we trust what each other says?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237475380.0" user="mnesiptolema" delta="False">
    <text>I don't quite understand what you mean.  Could you rephrase or explain more?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34237559083.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah rereading that I realize that I don't understand what I wrote either lol. In other words, if scientist x proclaims to have the truth of life in that free will is a myth and all our choices are results of chemical and hormonal releases in our brains, why then should we trust what scientist x says as true? He clearly isn't voluntarily making that statement, it's only a result of chemical releases, why then should we trust his word?

This may be a situation where I know what I want to say, but I can't put it into words so yeah...my bad for wasting your time lol.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34239640208.0" user="Kirito_Alfheim" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe I can respond to what I think you mean. Yes he was determined to say those things and you can argue that that determination could be so even if it were not true. But if we accept that our perception are real and if we accept logic then determination based on physical properties of the world points towards a state where entities as ourselves have evolved to understand the world correctly otherwise we would not have and evolutionary advantage. This means that even if our actions are predetermined, logical reasoning is possible still.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34239886869.0" user="Goodman2099" delta="False">
    <text>Kind of, but you did give me the vocabulary to better explain. And forgive my colloquial terms. If we are effectually slaves to our hormonal and chemical reactions, then we cannot make a truth claim. To make a truth claim about determinism is to rise above the bondage of total subjectivity and therefore cannot coincide with the notion that we are nothing but slaves to our separate chemical processes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
