<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="16" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34235621819.0" user="tintacao" delta="False">
    <text>So the core of your issue is free will, not necessarily god. The question of how God then relates to free will is fascinating, but arguably doesn’t change any understandings of free will at all. A “common Christian” trope is that to believe in god is to make things easier, to give one a back door where any unanswerables about free will can be explained by some “Will of the Lord.” Though he is incredibly hard to read (he purposely wrote convoluted) Kierkegaard has a lot to say about our free will and the despair it causes.

So the root question seems to be what is free will. If I’m born into a religious family and grow up religious, is that my free will? If I need to go to work tomorrow to make money so I can buy food, do I clock in under my free will? Even without a conception of god there is still the despair of a life that is both wholly free and pragmatically limited. As Kierkegaard showed, believing in a God doesn’t suddenly solve that conundrum, only changes the parameters so to speak. There is a wealth of theological undertaking others have mentioned (Augustine, Kant, Maimonides, etc) that have really powerfully intriguing positions you should look into, since the typical watered-down Christianity is just that - watered down.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
