<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34242652918.0" user="Speed_of_Night" delta="False">
    <text>I would actually say that, if God is omnipotent, relative to our universe, it is logically impossible for him to give free will. There are two camps regarding free will: libertarian and compatablist. I am incapable of understanding what it would even mean for libertarian free will to truly exist. The Universe itself can only be made sense of to the degree that you are able to understand the underlying mechanics of each part. This reduces down until you reach the smallest precursor quanta which would be a necessary precondition for all existence which exists for no reason. Basically, you regress through quantum causes as you find out their cause, or "reason" for existence, until you get to something without a cause, which has no reason. It's the physical equivalent of an assumed axiom: true by definition, it is defining itself. If the universe does not exist for no reason, then the most parsimonious explanation is that the universe exists because of a precursor and that precursor exists for no reason, and on and on until you find the truly uncaused precursor to all of the causality which we could theoretically deduce exists as the simplest coherent explanation for observed data. It is logically impossible for us to be free of the influence of some quantum basis for causality. Even if we had souls, those souls would, in essence, be a part of our universe in how directly they are tied to the physics of our bodies (if the soul is part of a mind, then it must have mechanisms through which it entangles itself to the material of our mind, and to define through discrimination the difference between material which is our minds and material which is not). In that way, we cannot have TRULY libertarian free will, because we cannot have a will which is liberated from all circumstance, if the superphysical exists because if it does, then it is a determining circumstance of our nature.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Compatablism makes the concept of free will useful by making a differentiation between circumstances which are overly constrained by the will of other beings, and defines will as able to be free relative to those relative external constraints, and the degree to which the internal constrains are able to act freely within the constraints of the external world. So like, sure, if you see a bowl full of salad and a bowl full of candy, your brain chemistry is going to force you to pick either salad or candy, but as long as no one has a gun to your head, forcing you to pick one or the other, your internal brain chemistry is not limited by some external chemistry forcing you one way or the other, at least in any way that is considered "unfair". Like, if you see some candy propaganda and your mom and dad gives you addiction to candy genes, and that makes you choose candy, that is fair game between the interplay of chemistry inside of you and outside of you. Or, maybe it isn't and society decides to ban candy propaganda. Where the line is between fair game in influencing your will and what isn't is ultimately up to society. Candy propaganda works really well on some people, and not well on others, so candy propaganda is itself, not an autocratic influence on your eating behavior. And genes are not able to be picked and chosen, at least not right now, so when your dad and mom made you, they were not making you with an autocratic intent on how you would turn out. That separation between intention of outcome and ability to control outcome is where the range of "free will" lies.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

If god had relative autocracy in the section of our universe which houses the physical AND the part which houses the superphysical: the super material mechanics which define the nature of souls, then God would be definitively forcing us to do everything we do with complete autonomy over the precise nature of our actions. And, of course, if he created the universe and has autonomy over other super-physical mechanisms that grant him definitively complete determining control over the physical, with how he can control the super-physical to interact with the physical, then he is ultimately forcing all physical and superphysical reactions perfectly in line with his intent, because he is logically incapable of doing otherwise: If you know the outcome of any action, and you can force any outcome with intentional force, then you must logically intentionally force any causal phenomenon which occurs. So if god were omnipotent, then that gap between intended outcomes and actual outcomes would be eliminated, because he knows the actual outcome of all actions, and therefore his intended outcome would always be an actual outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
