<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="996266069.0" index="22" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gh5fth/cmv_there_is_no_reason_a_god_should_give_free_will/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reason a “God” should give Free Will</title>
    <original_poster>Protagoras67</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to disclose that I am both an atheist and a hard determinist. I do not believe in any sort of creator and I have a hard time believing in Free Will. From what I understand from a Christian perspective, God gives humans free will in an effort to test them. But what i don’t understand from their point of view is why would God do that in the first place? Isn’t God omnipotent? God could just design the universe however it wants, we could have all been programmed to behave a certain way from birth and believe in God from birth and follow one religion as opposed to having a myriad of them. There is no reason to test us, it’s completely unnecessary.

Again, I’m not challenging anyone to prove God exists, I am just trying to understand the theological logic of this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34238950543.0" user="dawgtop" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe in any God's but I can understand why one would create free will if one does exist. Because he wants to. Just because you know something and create something does not mean you know why or even how. If we are made in his image then this makes sense. He would be a human at an impossible level greater then we could understand.

Maybe he has a question that he needs an answer to just like we will work out a math problem by writing it out, we are his math problem. Our decision make up his equation and gives him the answers he had been looking for. 

Maybe this is his millionth attempt at a successful universe and now is trying it with free will. 

Maybe decisions are the fuel that feeds God. Making decisions takes a lot of brain power and the energy generated when doing this expands God's experiences and knowledge making him greater. That explains this religion silliness. Force people to have something silly to believe in and then give them proof that it is silly. The amount of brain power generated in getting past the cognitive dissonance created by religion is probably like crack to God... Oh I like that last one. I will absolutely be repeating that one in the future. My brain comes up with some weird crap.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
