<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1007191701.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gnnm39/cmv_the_raising_of_the_minimum_wage_and/">
    <title>CMV: The raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to a decrease or in my country's case, an almost annihilation, in your typical "American" or for me "Australian" manufacturing at home.</title>
    <original_poster>PhoenixBekfast</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, I'm not saying that minimum wage and globalisation are a bad thing, so don't say I'm a protectionist, because I'm not.

The raising of the minimum wage and the increase of globalisation has led to a decrease in manufacturing because companies have realised it's cheaper to pay a Chinese guy 20 bucks a day than here in Australia where you have to pay a person with the same skills 20 bucks an hour. For businesses, it's not economically sustainable, so I'm sick of people asking why our manufacturing has declined because the answer is rather obvious. Australia has had even greater raises in the minimum wage to the US (workers must be paid 11.58 AUD in the US, and here in Australia you must pay the worker 19.49 AUD) which is why you will see at least a remnant of the once great manufacturing industry in the US, while here it has almost completely disappeared. The only places that Western regions lead in manufacturing are typically highly specialised industries where the skills needed by the worker are more valuable than their brute labour force. In conclusion, the raising of the minimum wage and globalisation has led to an decrease in manufacturing because it is cheaper to manufacture overseas. We are simply not competitive to manufacture at home.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34302435171.0" user="ArmchairSlacktavist" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t think it’s fair to blame the rising of the minimum wage, a thing that (in the US at least) hasn’t really risen all that much. There’s just no realistic way to undercut overseas manufacturing without paying people such low wages that they won’t even be able to feed themselves let alone afford housing or transportation.

I think it’s better to “blame” a rising standard of living and most importantly the *cost* of that standard of living rather than the minimum wage, which lags greatly behind the standard of living.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34302511393.0" user="PhoenixBekfast" delta="False">
    <text>The minimum wage has allowed the worker to go further toward the cost of standard of living, because people shouldn't be paid "such low wages that they won’t even be able to feed themselves let alone afford housing or transportation". The reason that the minimum wage exists is to guard against this, but in China they have not made as much of an effort to do so catch up to the cost of standard of living as Western Countries have (probably due to Western countries' increased freedom of speech and freedom to protest). Because the cost of standard of living has risen so high in comparison to China, the minimum wage has had to try and catch up with it (but not all the way). However even the partial increase in minimum wage (not all the way to cost of living, mind you, it hasn't caught up yet) has led to a decline in the manufacturing industry, because it's cheaper to go overseas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34302532212.0" user="ArmchairSlacktavist" delta="True">
    <text>The manufacturing industry has declined because it's cheaper to go overseas, but this has nothing to do with the minimum wage. That's what you're missing.

If you snapped your fingers and tomorrow there was no minimum wage, manufacturing jobs wouldn't suddenly come rushing back just because now they can pay Americans $1 a day or whatever, because they *can't* pay Americans $1 a day. No American is able to sustain themselves on such a low wage.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
