<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1057425222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hhkaiu/cmv_owning_fish_should_be_banned/">
    <title>CMV: Owning fish should be banned</title>
    <original_poster>BowenEdwards</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start by saying I'm not some kind of extreme animal activist I regularly eat meat but it seems to me that owning any fish is needlessly cruel. Your taking a living breathing animal that can think and feel, ripping it from its environment and putting it in a tiny box so you can have something pretty to look at. 

Goldfish normally have huge amounts of space to swim around in and people will keep them in actually bowls. They're like a house plant they just sit there you feed it and admire it but with a fish, they're more alive and aware they're in a tiny box and normally have a lot more space. I think that owning a dog is different since they actually enjoy being with you, you can walk them and let them see and smell new things. Nobody is taking their fish down to the lake for a little swim. If you locked a human in one small room it doesn't matter how good the room is, you could give them all the games, tv, internet they could ever want and it'd still be cruel. I don't see what a fish has, or doesn't have that makes it perfectly fine to do that exact thing to them. 

I'm all for people owning pets but it just seems like taking an animal that should have a huge amount of space and putting it in a bowl, just so we can look at the pretty colours, is a bit horrifically cruel on the animal and I don't really see any reason to not just outright ban it. That said, if a zoo can provide it as much space as it would normally have or if it's endangered and we want to stop it becoming extinct then they should be allowed to keep them. 

But individual people owning them in small tanks should be banned. CMV</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34604361021.0" user="y________tho" delta="False">
    <text>Goldfish bowls are bullshit - this is true.

Now imagine you're a fish in one of [Takeshi Amano's aquariums](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NP0Qk4DnLis). 

Alternatively, imagine your life during the Covid lockdown except your apartment is several hundred square feet, filled with plants and comfy places to hide out while you get delicious food from God every single day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604379845.0" user="BowenEdwards" delta="False">
    <text>I did say if someone can provide enough space for the fish then it's not so bad but most people can't. And with lockdown, I can still leave my house if I want and eventually the lockdown will end I'm not stuck here forever against my will.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34604422530.0" user="YouTubeLawyer1" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I did say if someone can provide enough space for the fish then it's not so bad but most people can't.

1. There is no science to support that claim that living in a sizable-enough tank is detrimental to the fish's health (physical or psychological).

2. There are plenty of fish that were born on fish-farms and who have spent their whole lives effectively in tanks. They have never seen the wild and were never ripped from it. 

3. You have yourself admitted that there are people who have tanks large enough to comfortably house their fish 

4. With these three aforementioned conditions, we can find that owning fish raises none of the objections you have raised. So why should we ban people who have fish hitting all these check marks from owning fish? Because that is what your ban would do. It would ban these good people from owning fish.

Wouldn't it be better and safer and kinder for all parties involved to regulate the ownership of fish moreso than just banning it outright?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
