<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1062071645.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hkbvq5/cmv_youtube_was_right_in_agerestricting_prager_us/">
    <title>CMV: YouTube was right in age-restricting Prager U's videos because a significant portion of their audience were children that didn't know better.</title>
    <original_poster>AneurysmicKidney</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL:DR: &amp;gt;!PragerU was targeting a young audience that didn't understand what they were watching, and YouTube was right in age restricting PragerU's videos.!&amp;lt;

PragerU, a far right-wing media outlet popular on YouTube had it's videos age-restricted by YouTube so that only users &amp;gt;15 years old could watch them.

PragerU claimed that YouTube was censoring them and responded by suing YouTube on the grounds that they were behaving like a publisher while enjoying the protections of a platform.

(The following story should is and should be treated as an anecdote. Because the demographic data of PragerU's viewer base is not public information, this is all I have to go on.)

When I was younger (~9) I came across a video titled "[The] War on Boys". Being a boy myself, I had clicked on the video because of the title and the cartoonish graphics in the thumbnail. Being just over five minutes long, it was perfect for my young, short, attention span.

I have since forgotten the content of the video, but because videos from the same channel as the one you're currently watching are more likely to get suggested, I clicked on a few more blue-background cartoons.

I remember seeing Ben Shapiro, and through the next 3 years I would think of him as some sort of Genius who was always right, because of his childish argument strategies and constant insulting.

I have since disengrained the bullshit that PragerU puts out from my head, but I believe that they were targeting a younger audience with their cartoon drawings, short videos, and simple arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34634002909.0" user="BeatriceBernardo" delta="False">
    <text>So, let's say you are completely right that PragerU videos are bad for children. However

&amp;gt; PragerU claimed that YouTube was censoring them and responded by suing YouTube on the grounds that they were behaving like a publisher while enjoying the protections of a platform.

So now here's the question, is PragerU a publisher or a platform?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34635128479.0" user="AneurysmicKidney" delta="False">
    <text>PragerU is a publisher.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636308900.0" user="elcuban27" delta="False">
    <text>Oops. I think he meant to ask if Youtube is a platform or publisher.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636313024.0" user="AneurysmicKidney" delta="False">
    <text>They're a platform.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636327277.0" user="elcuban27" delta="False">
    <text>In that case, they should have the protections of a platform, and provide unfettered and equal access to everyone (except as required by law), like a platform. Would it be ok for your phone carrier to scrutinize your text messages and decide which ones to send or not?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636393398.0" user="AneurysmicKidney" delta="False">
    <text>Cellular communication and video streaming platforms are not analogous. One is private, while the other is public.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34636500733.0" user="elcuban27" delta="True">
    <text>Not technically relevant, but I will humor you. What if your phone carrier decided to pick and choose which of your social media posts to allow on their network?  Want to tweet something bad about their preferred candidate and suddenly your data stops working. Is this fine?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
