<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1082495263.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hwhmov/cmv_donald_trump_has_taken_concrete_steps_toward/">
    <title>CMV: Donald Trump has taken concrete steps toward establishing a fascist regime, and "losing an election" won't be enough to successfully remove him.</title>
    <original_poster>MaichenM</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not here to argue whether Trump will win the election, I'm here to argue that it may not matter whether he does.

Right now, what is happening in Portland is what I've come to understand through observation as Trump "flexing" against the barriers that constrain him. No one has been permanently harmed by federal agents purely because that would be too big of a step, too early. He is normalizing the relatively minor violence of terrorizing protesters without actually charging them, and priming the GOP base that supports him to readily accept more severe violence against those that do not support him.

This kind of flexing has gotten Trump really far. He throws something out that sounds insane at first and lets people digest it. Then he does a relatively minor version of it. Once that is normalized, he ups the ante.

The one that worries me the most is his continuous teasing over whether he will accept the election results, and casting doubt on the validity of the election in general. This is coupled with the fact that he still has four months to look at polls, reflect that he is losing, and decide that he must maintain his power undemocratically if necessary. Even if he doesn't come up with a plan to do so, now, there will still be a two-month gap until Biden's reelection that is usually expected to serve as a nice buffer for an orderly transition of power. I know I've mentioned plans, but Trump doesn't need a plan, here. All he has to do is say: "No." At this point, all the resources of the federal government will still be under his control, and his supporters will have already been primed to accept violence toward protesters.

For the purpose of this view, I don't need Trump to successfully install fascism in the US. If he is removed through force, I will still consider myself "right" in the sense that a peaceful election was not enough. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

EDIT: I have already awarded Deltas to some people who argued in good faith. Starting now, I can't promise that I will respond to everyone, but I definitely will no longer engage with anyone who argues with me on bad faith, or uses personal insults. Thanks to everyone who has presented good arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34767443607.0" user="letstrythisagain30" delta="False">
    <text>Our institutions are too strong for this kind of thing to happen. Any other fascist dictator that started coming into power with decent institutions in place has always changed them or straight out dismantled them. So they changed or threw out the constitution. They made the military loyal to them, instead of the constitution for example. They changed congressional proceedings and changed term limits. They straight out rigged elections, etc. Trump has not and I argue cannot do these things. If he loses the election, aside from the craziest Trump supporters, no one will support him if he decides to not vacate office. No one of any consequence at least. Nobody in congress will agree with him. No judge will. No general/admiral will. He will only have the craziest and dumbest of supporters calling for him to stay. That won't mean anything.

&amp;gt;My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit. My view will be changed if I'm led to believe that Trump will lose the presidency without necessitating violence, or inciting it for his benefit.

Does it count if security personnel personally escort him out of office as he pouts and refuses to get out of the oval office? Or do you mean like, actual revolutionary like stand off with the administration as a whole? I'd say the former is more likely.

Do you mean violence in that crazy Trump supporters doing crazy shit because their guy lost, or do you mean like Trump retaining control of some part of the military and directing them in some conflict? Again, the former seems way more likely than the latter.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767725079.0" user="MaichenM" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Do you mean violence in that crazy Trump supporters doing crazy shit because their guy lost, or do you mean like Trump retaining control of some part of the military and directing them in some conflict? Again, the former seems way more likely than the latter.

I actually really respect this argument because it's true that my definition of "violence" in the initial post was vague.

In my thoughts I believed that security personnel escorting him out would count as "violence" because it is a scenario in which he doesn't want to go, and is being forced to. I do believe upon consideration that the biggest threat in this case would be the violence from his supporters that you mention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34767861624.0" user="letstrythisagain30" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;In my thoughts I believed that security personnel escorting him out would count as "violence" because it is a scenario in which he doesn't want to go, and is being forced to.

That has more to do with Trump being a manchild cry baby narcissistic ego maniac than fascism though. Its something that was even been discussed on the news because of how everyone knows Trump is as a person.

&amp;gt;I do believe upon consideration that the biggest threat in this case would be the violence from his supporters that you mention.

Thats possibly the most likely outcome, but even then it would be at most a handful of isolated incidents without much violence to speak of. Maybe a fight or two between people protesting Trump's loss and people calling them idiots for it on the street.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
