<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1101758559.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i7yicf/cmv_colleges_in_the_us_only_care_about_profits/">
    <title>CMV: Colleges in the U.S. only care about profits and protecting profit generators in the middle of a pandemic</title>
    <original_poster>usr27181663</original_poster>
    <original_post>Okay so, as I'm sure other sports fans have noticed, the NCAA has suspended all fall championships outside of division 1 and the Big Ten has officially opted out of the 2020 fall sports season.  Basically universities are recognizing that travel and the inevitable proximity to one another is unsafe and unpredictable.  So, to protect athletes that make them millions, they are preventing competition.  This is completely reasonable and is best practice for navigating the dangers to the health of student-athletes.  

However, they seem to take no issue with bringing in students from all across the country, and in some cases different countries, to live in highly close proximity on campus and go to massive lecture halls.  Why?  As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students.  So, they value their profit generators (student-athletes) and want to protect them, but health and safety is out the window if that means losing out on room and board (which would occur if the fall semester was declared online only) and tuition (many students refuse to pay the same price for an online tuition and are opting to take gap years if this is the case).   

It's certainly a financially tough situation for many schools, but should maintaining revenue truly be the driving force behind holding classes in person when big univeristies are signaling that they fully understand how unsafe travelling and being in close contact with people is at this point in the U.S.?  Further, by making this choice to have classes held in person, I believe the vast majority of universities have zero actual regard for the health and well-being of their students if it hurts their pockets.  Change my view?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34897445786.0" user="TitanCubes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; As some economists have noted, many universities without huge endowments may go bankrupt without tuition and room and board expenses being maintained by students. 

&amp;gt; Should maintains revenue truly be the driving force

You said it yourself. Many schools will go bankrupt if they are not in person. This isn’t about profits this is about survival. 

Economics aside, let’s not forget that attending college is an individual choice that no one has to do. If you are uncomfortable going to school in person, all the schools I am aware of have online options, and if you think online school isn’t worth your tuition than you can defer. Not to mention that a lot (I’d say a large majority) of college students want to be back at school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34897703055.0" user="usr27181663" delta="False">
    <text>Attending college is technically an individual choice, but it is also one of the few available methods (albeit heavily flawed) for social mobility.  So, for people of lower income backgrounds, it isn't really a choice if they have the opportunity available to them.  Further, shouldn't we be more concerned about actual survival than economic survival?  Also, would you apply the same economic survival argument at the individual level?  I mean to say, do you feel it is the correct thing for a person of a lower income background to risk their own health in, for example, a service industry job like waiting tables or bartending to have to work purely in the name of economic survival?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34897800699.0" user="TitanCubes" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Attending college is technically an individual choice, but it is also one of the few available methods. 

But you’re advocating for no in person college. If the only issue was social mobility you would definitely be advocating to give students the choice to go back to school. 

&amp;gt; Shouldn’t we be more concerned about actual survival than economic survival?

This implies that there is a significant risk for college aged students going back to school which is not true. Also if you give any business the opportunity to continue their business or go bankrupt they are obviously going to choose to continue. 

&amp;gt; Would you apply the same economic survival argument at the individual level?

Your analogy here isn’t really correct. Obviously on the individual level we have government supported options to make that choice not have to exist. For a college this choice doesn’t exist. They either open up in the fall or go bankrupt. This would be the equivalent of an individual having the choice to go back to their job otherwise they will never have any job again, and government intervention is not an option.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
