<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1102614149.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i8guit/cmv_i_dont_think_ted_cruz_is_eligible_to_be/">
    <title>CMV: I dont think Ted Cruz is eligible to be president of the United State</title>
    <original_poster>PuckSR</original_poster>
    <original_post>Kamala Harris was recently selected as Biden's running mate, and it re-sparked a common misunderstanding of the Constitution. The definition of "natural born citizen". Clearly, Kamala Harris is eligible.

John McCain, however, was not so clearly a "natural born citizen" as he had been born in the Panama Canal Zone to two US citizens. It was contentious enough of an issue that the Senate passed a resolution saying he was eligible. Specifically, McCain was born to two US citizens who were overseas at the direct orders of the US govt. If McCain was ineligible then every child born to US servicemembers overseas would be ineligible and most people agreed that this was not the founders intent.

However, Rafael "Ted" Cruz was born to an American and a Cuban while they worked in Canada for a private company. If Ted Cruz is eligible to be a US president, then basically anyone who has a claim to citizenship is eligible, even if they have never lived in the United States.

*Example: A young woman is born in China. Her mother is American, her father is Chinese. She lives her entire life in China, but claims dual citizenship for legal purposes. At the age of 42, she decides to move to the United States. She becomes a popular politician and runs for President, only 14 years after being elected to the US House of Representatives.*

Would she be eligible? This seems like the exact scenario the founders were trying to prevent. Someone with loyalties to another country taking the reins of power of the USA.If Ted Cruz is eligible, then this woman would be eligible. At that point, why wouldn't we extend the presidency to citizens like Arnold Schwarzenegger?

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause)

Edit: adjusted for the residency requirement

**For all mentions of the Nationality Act of 1790.**The law, as written in 1790 said the following:

* Only free white males could become citizens
* Provided, that the right of [citizenship](https://immigrationhistory.org/item/1790-nationality-act/#) shall not descend to persons whose fathers have never been resident in the United States

First, we obviously don't still have this law on the books. It was fully and totally cancelled and the phrase about "natural born citizen" was removed. You can't point to a law that is not currently applicable as your definition. They clearly felt the need to define the term, and they later rescinded that definition

Further, I think you could make a strong argument that it only applied to children of the father with that definition. This fits with what I have read of citizenship laws in Europe, which stated that citizenship status descended from the paternal line. (I know this because it was a big controversy when people started raping slaves, as it would make the children citizens and free. Most countries made a law explicitly exempting this rule in the case of slave-master relationships)

**Naturalized vs natural born**

The term naturalized wasn't created until the 1940s, when international travel became much more common. The term presently means "conferred after birth", but that term was not used during prior to that period. In fact, "natural born" was used in the US and the UK to imply a citizen granted citizenship by their birth in the USA.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34902813641.0" user="miguelguajiro" delta="False">
    <text>She would have to resided in the country for at least 14 years, so if I’m reading correctly, no, she’s not eligible. Cruz doesn’t have that problem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902821059.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Why doesn't he have that problem?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902847195.0" user="miguelguajiro" delta="False">
    <text>He’s resided in the US for more than 14 years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902862367.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, and I apologize for forgetting the residency requirement.  


But, I thought that many people had interpreted the "natural born citizen" clause to mean that they must have been born in the USA.   
My understanding was that this clause existed to stop people like Alexander Hamilton from being elected President.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902948060.0" user="TFHC" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;My understanding was that this clause existed to stop people like Alexander Hamilton from being elected President.

The full text is "No Person except a natural born Citizen, or a Citizen of the United States, at the time of the Adoption of this Constitution, shall be eligible to the Office of President; neither shall any person be eligible to that Office who shall not have attained to the Age of thirty five Years, and been fourteen Years a Resident within the United States.", so as a citizen at the time of the adoption of the Constitution, Hamilton was entirely eligible for election to the presidency.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
