<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="112874326.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1v7ady/there_is_no_such_thing_as_a_waste_of_time_cmv/">
    <title>There is no such thing as a "waste of time" - CMV</title>
    <original_poster>MorganaLeFaye</original_poster>
    <original_post>I hear (and read) it all the time. 

"Video games are a waste of time." 

"Watching TV is a waste of time." 

"Reddit is a waste of time."

"Watching paint dry is a waste of time." 

OK, so I don't hear that last one too frequently, but it still applies. What qualifies one person to decide how other people should spend their time, or what activities are worth engaging in while others are not? 

It is totally possible to waste the time you have available (i.e. procrastination), **which is not what I am talking about.** However, in terms of leisure activities and personal time, I don't think there is such a thing as a "waste of time." 

**EDIT** - I should clarify that when I say "there is no such thing as a waste of time" what I mean to say is that no one can tell another person what a waste of time is, or that a general activity cannot be broadly condemned as a waste of time. 

Change my view. 
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27010630070.0" user="quantumquixote" delta="False">
    <text>Let me tell you a story. This story was about me in my first semester of college. 

I was having a great time in college. There were friends everywhere, no parents for the first time, seeing the sights, blah blah blah.

After I got my grades back for the semester, I freaked out. With my grades that low, I could no longer afford to stay in college, as several of my scholarships were GPA based.

I didn't intentionally slack off, I just got too lazy because no one was telling me what to do.

When I got back home, my parents cracked down on me hard. After them yelling at me about how much time I waste on video games, on the internet, on facebook, and doing so many other pointless things, I got kinda mad. 

Next semester, and I actually cut back on everything, hard. I realize that they were completely right and that I was legitimately wasting my time. Thanks to the intervention, I brought my grades back up and I'm still enrolled. Sometimes it is obvious to everyone when you're wasting time.

THE END</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27010688434.0" user="MorganaLeFaye" delta="False">
    <text>I specifically said in my OP that this was not about "wast of available time"  or procrastination, which is what your story is about. It's not that those activities are inherently a waste of time, it's just that you specifically wasted the time you had before deadlines...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27011002857.0" user="limes_limes_limes" delta="False">
    <text>In this case consider one important deadline being "when you die." Now by playing video games you are using up your ability to do alternative activities in your limited lifespan.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27011042968.0" user="MorganaLeFaye" delta="False">
    <text>The most [common deathbed confessions](http://www.inspirationandchai.com/Regrets-of-the-Dying.html) are:

* I wish I'd had the courage to live a life true to myself, not the life others expected of me. 
* I wish I didn't work so hard. 
* I wish I'd had the courage to express my feelings.
* I wish I had stayed in touch with my friends. 
* I wish that I had let myself be happier.

Playing video games (specifically) can help you achieve nearly all of these wishes. 

If that is what people enjoy doing, then at the end of their life do you really think they would say "I wish I'd played less video games"? For me, a life spent playing video games would mean a life spent not doing other things I actively wanted to do. So it would be a problem for me, but I couldn't say that video games themselves are a waste of time because some people are perfectly content with their video game filled lives. 
 </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27011089247.0" user="limes_limes_limes" delta="True">
    <text>I think it's the difference between [short term and long term happiness](http://opinionator.blogs.nytimes.com/2009/09/15/the-long-and-the-short-of-it/?_r=0). Something like playing video games will lead to immediate near term happiness, whereas planning a trip to the Grand Canyon takes a lot of work before it ever pays off in happiness. But I find it more likely that someone on their death bed would say "I wish I saw the Grand Canyon" than "I wish I played a few more levels of video games."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
