<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1146362973.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/iyijbx/cmv_aaron_burr_gets_a_bad_rap/">
    <title>CMV: Aaron Burr gets a bad rap</title>
    <original_poster>HotSauce2910</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like a lot of people have a really negative view of Burr, in large part because of Hamilton (which I do love btw : /). I think I mean this specifically that his reputation/legacy is negative relative to Hamilton's, at least from a progressive point of view.   


* He tried to abolish slavery in the 1780s as a NY Assemblyman and worked with the Manumission Society. He was admittedly hypocritical here, being a slaveowner himself (so fuck that). But Hamilton's relationship with slavery was also [pretty complicated](https://www.womenshealthmag.com/life/a33023827/was-hamilton-a-slave-owner/). Despite that, I think there is a perception out there that was clearly anti-slavery while Burr was clearly pro-slavery. 
* Burr was a feminist. He was a big fan of Mary Wollstonecraft, believe that women were intellectually equal to men (which was rather radical at the time), and wanted equal education opportunities. Apparently Hamilton attacked Burr over this opinion. 
   * Wikipedia also says he submitted a proposal to give women the right to vote, but w/ no citation and I couldn't find a source that confirms it. 
* He started the first bank that extended credit to small businessmen instead of just the aristocracy. His methods/motives were dubious, but the result were meaningful. Hamilton, as I understand it, was rather elitist and wanted a strong aristocracy.
* Burr supported the rights of naturalized citizens and opposed a constitutional amendment (that the Fedarlist party was pushing) to bar naturalized foreigners from holding office. 
* He was accused of ["'revolutionizing the state,' because in the state legislature he backed progressive policies for funding internal improvements such as roads and bridges, debtor relief, and establishing a more democratic method of electing state senators."](https://www.washingtonpost.com/posteverything/wp/2016/03/30/liberals-love-alexander-hamilton-but-aaron-burr-was-a-real-progressive-hero/)     


I am curious about if I'm just missing something, if I just drank some counterculture kool aid, or if there's something actually here.   


Also, I noticed after typing out the title that it almost counts a pun... was not intended...</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35212925586.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>Burr still murdered a founding father. That kind of outweighs his progressive views by a large margin. You can't recover from that and he gad a poor reputation well before Hamiltion. He actually probably has a better reputation now, sonce Leslie Odom Jr. is so likeanle in the role abd the musical portrays him as more remorseful than he actually was, He was also put on trial for treason which is a really big freaking deal even if we will never know if he was actually guilty.

It's not Burr's politics that have earned him a negative historical reputation but his character.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35212976364.0" user="HotSauce2910" delta="False">
    <text>His reputation was poor, but before Hamilton I think he was pretty unknown. After the musical, it was a lot more negative.   


I'm mainly trying to compare his legacy to Hamilton'ss

&amp;gt; Burr still murdered a founding father 

It was a duel, which Hamilton accepted. I know they were illegal, but there was no necessity for Hamilton to accept it. There's also no evidence that Hamilton shot the air during the duel.   


&amp;gt; That kind of outweighs his progressive views by a large margin 

I think a large part of my point is that people perceive Hamilton as a progressive and Burr as his opponent/anti-progressive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35213039609.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;know they were illegal, but there was no necessity for Hamilton to accept it. 

It's still murder and Burr was charged with murder though it was never brought to trial.

&amp;gt;There's also no evidence that Hamilton shot the air during the duel. 

There were letters he wrote beforehand saying he intended to throw away his first shot and that was the story published in papers at the time. There's a good amount of evidence that is what happened since Hamilton's shot did miss Burr.

&amp;gt;I think a large part of my point is that people perceive Hamilton as a progressive and Burr as his opponent/anti-progressive.

Do they? They were members of the same party. Their disputes were personal moreso than ideological and I think the musical demonstrates this pretty clearly when the conflict between the two arises after Burr goes after Philip Schuyler's seat. 

The musical frames Burr as faulty for his ambition, it doesn't attack him on his political beliefs, but rather that he had none.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
