<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1172678506.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/je6kiy/cmv_human_life_has_no_innate_worth_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: Human Life has no innate worth due to the Laws of Supply and Demand</title>
    <original_poster>Flare-Crow</original_poster>
    <original_post>Please put the torches away and stick with me for just a moment; I'm not a monster, I swear!

&amp;amp;nbsp;

So first I'd like to define the difference between Human Life and a Human Being. My premise rests on defining the two separately. Let me assure you that I feel that a Human Being with a developed consciousness is irreplaceable. However, due to the recent surge in discussions on abortion, I've been hammering out the details on a premise I'd like to present here in an effort to determine any flaws in it: **Human Life has no innate value, as there are over 7 billion humans on this planet, and the Laws of Supply and Demand dictate that an unborn child therefore only holds subjective worth.**


I noticed that many people seem to innately assume that unborn children are a highly valuable commodity, which confuses me, as any of 2-4 billion women could essentially produce billions more embryos at any given time. While a specific embryo or fetus can absolutely hold subjective value to a person, which is why I support laws that punish the murder of a pregnant person as though it was a double homicide, I don't see the issue with a person choosing to rid themselves of an unwanted pregnancy; nothing of inherent or subjective value was lost. While I'm not a fan of abortions used as matter of convenience (I'd much prefer universal healthcare and a robust Sex Ed curriculum), I see an abortion as nothing more than a medical procedure with no morality involved any more than a kidney transplant is "moral."


Change My View</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35394090004.0" user="I_Boomer" delta="False">
    <text>If you buy wholly into capitalism then you are right. Human life is cheap. Human life, all life for that matter, is bigger than a fake value system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394105264.0" user="Flare-Crow" delta="False">
    <text>Is killing an ant morally wrong? It could possibly achieve great things, one can never know; but if it was more problematic to keep the ant alive than to get rid of it, would I be morally wrong for doing so? How is an embryo any different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35394180416.0" user="I_Boomer" delta="True">
    <text>If it was your responsibility to care for the ant (or the embryo) and you didn't fulfill your responsibility, then you would be morally wrong (and selfish/lazy because it was problematic for you). There sure is no easy answer for all test cases, that's for sure (i.e., going back in time to kill Hitler).</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
