<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628180906.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it need a solution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628214641.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Because of ISIS, because of isolation which they feel, they see movies and culture all point to virtuousness of pursuing love and creating a family, they realise their success rate is abolsutely abysmal, they open tinder and get shocked, they see their attractive friends get way more than them, solution is needed because the same reason capitalism creates monopoly, complete sexual freedom leads to monopoly and sooner or later it becomes unfair, a minority of men have connections and means to truly jump between women and the other part has to put more time and effort for a far less success rate, this is truly immoral and not addressing it is a disservice to men who feel abandoned by society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628281278.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Why is that unfair and immoral? That sounds completely fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628307798.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>No, for a modern society which is based on maintaining equality and to care about every individual it is immoral to rely on evolutionary pressures which are for the jungle not a modern technological civilization, I propose effort to make prosthetic penises possible, for a society who spend so much on curimg alzaihmers it would be moral to also research on ways to increase height and change facial structure just as importantly as cancer, if society look at a portion and considers them in any way better you cannot be true egalitarian society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628325593.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>In this case, the equality is the equal right to make a consensual choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628361177.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, equal rights to make a choice doesn't mean there won't be an irregular distribution, although it created a unhealthy balance, its the same as capitalism but much more immoral, although a man can become rich and act charismatic nothing can make a man grow taller, capitalism has its merit on creating incentive for growth but the sexual capitalism does not encourage growth among the fringes, men with micro penis, extremely short or deformed</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628378038.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>So? Nothing immoral in a person not agreeing to spend time with a person they do not wish to spend time with.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628417001.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but exclusion of them from social circles connection to less people and therefore less economic opportunities, this sure must be immoral to exclude a certain part of society from what others have easy access to, if the need for social interaction wasn't there and we were like big cats yeah, I simply want the society to acknowledge and widely recognise these matters, yes personal liberties aboautely will be violated but to teach women to be kind to men is it bad? Is won't solve anything unless genetic engineering is viable but its a reconciliation, no?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628433279.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>No, you have no entitlement to not be excluded from anyone's social circle. There is no moral question there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628526289.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>No entitlement to the outcome but i am entitled to a fair chance of being able to be included if I have a merit. If people accept at an attractive person into their circle while ignoring another it needs to be acknowledged that it isn't because unattractive person has less worth  this is immoral not the action but why they do it people can be educated about their biases and instead of being in ignorance of it just refuse to hear the voice of men who they feel uneasy laughing to.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628794637.0" user="MysticInept" delta="True">
    <text>I as an individual have a right to think you have less worth to me than other people. And you do. and you have no moral right to me to extend personal opportunities to you.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
