<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628230335.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Women consider most men undesirable

This is not in your study.

&amp;gt;all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this

This is not in your study

&amp;gt;current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.

This is not in your study.

You have taken an article on a very limited study, and then attached to it a wide range of conclusions and assumptions that are completely unrelated to the actual material that was studied. The study itself doesn't say much.

This is a link to the actual study :

https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40806-017-0092-x

Note that it is very limited. People chose between a grand total of 3 photos.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628249952.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Δ but these are well known, I'm sorry, I may need to compile more resources but I just want to get to the discussion. Most men is based on an OKcupid study which women rate most men as ugly</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35629126071.0" user="iamasecretthrowaway" delta="True">
    <text>We need an r/cmv pinned comment about how bullshitty that ok cupid data is and how grossly it's been misinterpreted. 

Firstly, the "study" had users rate an individual's attractiveness and then tracked their message sending. Despite rating men as less attractive than a standard bell curve, women sent an expected number of messages. Assuming that means women think men are unappealing or that women have too high standards is kind of ridiculous. 

A) maybe a dating website *isn't* a normal bell curve of attractiveness. 

B) maybe women are conditioned to be less comfortable opening admitting sexual attraction to strangers, particularly in a potentially sexual situation. 

C) maybe women dont base their level of attraction solely on physical attraction to a photograph so they wouldn't rate people as very attractive without getting to know them. 

D)or maybe the physical things women do find attractive are harder to convey in a photo than the physical things men find attractive. 

E)maybe men on Ok cupid, on average, put less effort into their photos than women did. 

F)maybe a dating website from a time when dting websites were less ubiquitous is just a bad, self selected group of subjects. 

G)maybe there were other factors that affected women's ratings more than men - like maybe they were unconsciously taking things like clothing, props, backgrounds, or even usernames into account in their ratings. 

H) maybe women rate men as below average attraction more often because they view themselves as below their level of attraction also. If my siblings are super smart, I might think of myself as relatively dumb. And if I think (rightfully) you're about as smart as i am, wouldn't I probably rate you as below average intelligence too? The issue there isn't your intelligence or even my perception of it, its that my whole baseline is shifted - my idea of intelligence isn't a standard bell curve.  

But most importantly, the "research" found that men disproportionately messaged the women they rated as most attractive while the women messaged a much broader range of people. 2/3 of men only messaged the top 1/3 of women, but women's messages almost exactly mirrored their attractiveness rating - ie, *they may have rated men as being less physically attractive but were* **far** *more likely to give them a chance and try to get to know them.*

Why arent men ever ranting about that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
