<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628230335.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Women consider most men undesirable

This is not in your study.

&amp;gt;all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this

This is not in your study

&amp;gt;current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.

This is not in your study.

You have taken an article on a very limited study, and then attached to it a wide range of conclusions and assumptions that are completely unrelated to the actual material that was studied. The study itself doesn't say much.

This is a link to the actual study :

https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007/s40806-017-0092-x

Note that it is very limited. People chose between a grand total of 3 photos.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628267541.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>I found this on the ugliness: https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/okcupid/yourlooksandyourinbox.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628302353.0" user="10ebbor10" delta="True">
    <text>I know that study, but it doesn't support your views.

The first problem is that OkCupid's rating is not an objective measure of attractiveness. 

See, if you rate someone highly, the algorithm will suggest you to them. If you rate someone low, the algorithm will ignore them.
Since men message women far, far more often than women message men, women are incentivized to rate men low, else they get spammed with a thousand messages.

On top of that, look what happens if we look at who messages whom.

[Women are perfectly willing to message lower rated men](https://techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/female-messaging-curve.png).

[Men focus most of their effort solely on high rated men](https://beta.techcrunch.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/11/male-messaging-curve.png)

This thus indicates that it is not women being the picky gender, but men.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
