<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628180906.0" user="MysticInept" delta="False">
    <text>Why does it need a solution?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628214641.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Because of ISIS, because of isolation which they feel, they see movies and culture all point to virtuousness of pursuing love and creating a family, they realise their success rate is abolsutely abysmal, they open tinder and get shocked, they see their attractive friends get way more than them, solution is needed because the same reason capitalism creates monopoly, complete sexual freedom leads to monopoly and sooner or later it becomes unfair, a minority of men have connections and means to truly jump between women and the other part has to put more time and effort for a far less success rate, this is truly immoral and not addressing it is a disservice to men who feel abandoned by society</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628244554.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't the path of least resistance be to stop making those movies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628281894.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, this is a proposed solution, culture must not romanticise a mass murder path, natural selection is based on the removal of the weakest from the gene pool and it is not moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628390482.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>If the solution is changing the movies we watch and the games we play, then is it right to say that women are the disease? It seems like you're saying the disease is really the culture, and that's what we need to fix</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628469376.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Disease is the culture but women have to educated and taught about their bias or their advantages is as much of disease as a rich guy wearing gold and sticking a pile of cash in front of a homeless person, society expect men to be tough but women to be sensitive in need to be protected form hurt feelings, this hypocrisy is the disease, since It arises from natural instincts of female in our species to prioritize taller, stronger more square jawed men I call women the disease too, definitely intended to be offensive as making dick jokes and laughing at short men</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628669792.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>Men are also exclusionary towards other men, though. For instance, [tall people make more money](https://slate.com/culture/2002/03/it-pays-to-be-tall.html) even though women aren't often the ones behind those salary decisions. If you're saying that there's a bias against a certain kind of man, it seems like:

1. It's not women perpetuating that bias. Women don't hold the levers of power over media or culture which disseminate the idea that being a certain kind of man is wrong or undesirable, and

2. That bias is held by other men, who would also need to be "educated and taught about their bias or their advantages." If anything, it's *more* important to reach out to other men about it, because even if we assume that dating is a marketplace where more desirable mates are chosen based on some apparently objective standard (which I don't the evidence is really there to support), then success in other markets will lead to success in the dating market, i.e., wealth gets dates. And it's other men who are keeping your conception of undesirable men from attaining that success.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
