<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1207508597.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/jyx3lh/cmv_women_are_a_disease_for_an_egalitarian/">
    <title>CMV: women are a disease for an egalitarian society their mate selection instincts are not designed for modern society if left unleashed it will alienate men they consider shy, weak or ugly and increases instability and leads to massive struggle as nature intended.</title>
    <original_poster>xeus2095</original_poster>
    <original_post>As studies have shown: https://www.livescience.com/58607-mens-looks-may-matter-more-than-personality.html
Women consider most men undesirable and although this an evolutionary pressure to choose better traits like masculine features or any physical advantage, it is a nightmare for society, all throughout the world suicides have risen among men and sperms counts have been dropped, it seems as if the current structure of society causes this, scrawny men, shy men, men who been in accidents and suffer from disabilities, I do not care about the solution I would not like it to be any inhumane way but current structure radicalises men, unless there are programs to specifically address the issue which is the mental health of undesired men there can not be peace.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="35628213034.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="True">
    <text>'May' means the study hasn't shown it. 

If I say it may rain tomorrow, it doesn't mean I know it's going to.

There's a big difference between studies somehow proving something, and the results 'suggesting' a certain conclusion to people prepared to assume that the behavior of a sample size of people under study conditions generalizes in some fashion to the general population.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628265704.0" user="xeus2095" delta="False">
    <text>Δ about the connection I make you are right. But my point is that if you look at OKcupid data (https://www.gwern.net/docs/psychology/okcupid/yourlooksandyourinbox.html) it shows a real problem for a society that does not live in jungle and survival of the fittest is considered immoral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="35628430157.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="True">
    <text>Internet dating sites involves people evaluating profiles. That's pretty limited information. They don't have access to a person's personality, they have a little list of traits that may or may not be accurate. That appearance is valued over "personality" when the only information you have on a person is mostly their appearance according to a picture and their personality is just a short description in text... isn't surprising. 

Survival of the fittest is pretty much an empty tautology.

What survives is presumed to be what was most suited to surviving in its environment ... because it survived. Of course, environments are always changing, and fitness in one context isn't the same in another, so it doesn't do explanatory work it merely describes what mechanically happens. 

At the level of mechanism we can use it in a larger account, but morality doesn't factor in. Survival is a precondition for maintaining some structures of an organism but it doesn't determine how any organism ought to behave while surviving. There are multiple ways to survive, and surviving in an environment necessarily involves changing that environment. If I ask how we ought to change the environment, appealing to survival accomplishes nothing.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
