<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="125791631.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/22w5fz/cmv_romantic_love_is_a_manifestation_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Romantic love is a manifestation of the broader phenomenon of addiction</title>
    <original_poster>O_OY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I derive this view mainly from observing breakups, and drawing similarities to addiction.

1. When a breakup happens, often there is a craving for human contact (most of the time the subject is craving the ex). This craving is physiologically similar to the one that addiction uses (the VTA pathway).

2. Relationships often have the honeymoon phase, comfortable phase, etc. (I realize I'm not being very scientific here, but romantic love doesn't exactly have many scientific journals on it) This seems very similar to the tolerance that many addicts experience (first experience with a drug seems to be the most intense).

Please CMV! =(</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27134163931.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="False">
    <text>You're missing the fact that an addiction includes continuing the behavior despite adverse consequences. This is why we don't speak of people being addicted to water or air (generally). Cravings and repetition do not make an addiction on their own, they just make a habit.

Other examples would be watching football because you enjoy it. It doesn't mean you're addicted unless you're missing work, sucking dick for tickets, or your life is suffering in other ways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134177584.0" user="O_OY" delta="False">
    <text>hmm the term adverse consequences is hard to define. For example, abusive relationships happen sometimes because of love. Is this not an adverse consequence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27134184706.0" user="hyperbolical" delta="True">
    <text>Sure, and you could perhaps argue that love has become an addiction there. However, remember that abuse victims also sometimes stay out of a sense of powerlessness or fear, not necessarily because they love their abuser.

You can be addicted to love much like you can be addicted to just about anything. Same would go for sex; enjoying and wanting sex is not an addiction unless the activity/desire is causing you real harm.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
