<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1280235175.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l67vs7/cmv_countries_like_canada_and_the_uk_have_a_more/">
    <title>CMV: Countries like Canada and the UK have a more illogical system of units then the US</title>
    <original_poster>Tommyblockhead20</original_poster>
    <original_post>Foreigners and even many Americans like to criticize or make fun of the United States for being one of the few countries to not adopt the metric system de facto, and talk about how illogical their system is. However I see little to no criticism aimed at countries like Canada or the UK that I find to have much more illogical systems of units. 

These countries use a mix of both metric and imperial. While the US may learn a worse system then metric, at least it is consistent in its usage (yes there are a number of specific areas metric is used but a vast majority of Americans don’t know the metric system because they don’t need to). But in Canada and the UK, they have to learn 2 completely different systems and switch between the two based on the context and usage. [There’s this popular post](https://www.reddit.com/r/coolguides/comments/e1hx4f/how_to_choose_measuring_units_in_canada/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=mweb) on r/coolguides about all the different times when metric or imperial is used, this is the only time I have really seen either of these countries be made fun of.

Now I’m not surprised and I don’t blame the citizens, it is inevitable old systems stick around when they are so ingrained in a culture. But I think that’s one of the reasons it’s best the US doesn’t try to switch systems, we’ve already seen what will happen, but that’s a whole nother discussion.

Is having 2 systems not more illogical then 1? Why does the US receive the most criticism for its system of units?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36096191554.0" user="joopface" delta="False">
    <text>It's a bit like that where I'm from in Ireland, also. Height - feet and inches, weight - stones and pounds. But, speed limits are in km per hour, distances are measured in kilometers mostly. Metric is taught exclusively in schools etc.

But.... this is because it's still transitioning. It's not an accepted permanent state of things. 

Is it less logical to accept a permanent state of indeterminacy of units of measurement? Sure, yes, it is. But, my parents learned imperial units in school and they changed over to metric when they were adults. 

I use far fewer imperial measures than my parents do. My kids have no idea what inches are. They're all centimetres. The transition will take time, but it'll complete.

Now, compare to the US. No such transition is taking place. 

You can't compare countries in transition to a country in an accepted final state. Compare the final state of imperial units being used and the intended final state of metric units being used. Which makes more sense?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36096309949.0" user="Tommyblockhead20" delta="False">
    <text>In willing to give a delta if you can show more then anecdotally there is a transition happening. (because while I don’t doubt your experience, how do I know this applies to your entire country?)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36096459493.0" user="joopface" delta="True">
    <text>Evidence of a transition? How about....

1. [1951 parliamentary question](https://web.archive.org/web/20120925022355/http://historical-debates.oireachtas.ie/D/0125/D.0125.195104100006.html)on metric conversion
2. [1964 parliamentary question](https://web.archive.org/web/20120901232358/http://www.oireachtas-debates.gov.ie/D/0209/D.0209.196405120011.html) on switch to metric coinage
3. [1987 parliamentary question](https://web.archive.org/web/20120901232253/http://www.oireachtas-debates.gov.ie/D/0375/D.0375.198711240050.html) on conversion to kilos for food
4. [2003 parliamentary question](https://web.archive.org/web/20120901232407/http://www.oireachtas-debates.gov.ie/D/0572/D.0572.200310140033.html) on the changes to speed limits</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
