<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1281410057.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/l6x2bt/cmv_imposing_extreme_regulatory_controls_on_the/">
    <title>cmv: Imposing extreme regulatory controls on the stock market would benefit the economy for most people.</title>
    <original_poster>brickses</original_poster>
    <original_post>The fundamental virtue of the stock market to the economy is that it:

* Allows any person to easily invest their wealth in capital ventures for profit (the basis of our capitalist society).
* Efficiently grants the leverage to secure capital to the firms which investors believe have the most propensity to produce value to society.
	
Imposing even the most drastic regulatory constraints on the market would not fundamentally impact these benefits, and would only impact the ability of traders to extract arbitrage out of the market at the expense of other investors.

Liquidity has no significant inherent value to the stock market in terms of it's value to the economy as a whole.

Prohibiting the use of all speculative instruments/derivatives and imposing small per-trade tax would not negatively impact the stock market in it's value to most people, it would reduce the volatility of the market and the likelihood of national or global market events, and if anything it would increase the returns of low risk index funds and value investments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36105611567.0" user="yumyumnom" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are conflating the term "stock market" for "securities markets in general" , which is causing several erroneous conclusions in your post.

For example:

&amp;gt; Liquidity has no significant inherent value to the stock market in terms of it's value to the economy as a whole. 

This is flatly incorrect. Liquidity is of massive value to financial markets, as recent crisis events have shown (global financial crisis, covid crisis, silver sunday, to name just a few). When liquidity dries up asset prices begin to collapse, which is why the government has to step in and start buying up assets, as the Fed did in the corporate bond market last year for example.

Another example:

&amp;gt; Prohibiting the use of all speculative instruments/derivatives and imposing small per-trade tax would not negatively impact the stock market in it's value to most people it would reduce the volatility of the market and the likelihood of national or global market events, and if anything it would increase the returns of low risk index funds and value investments. 

Derivatives are used primarily to hedge exposure, not to speculate. The exposure could be commodity prices, interest rates, or security specific exposure, but irrespective of what the underlying exposure is a hedge is a hedge. If producers of goods like gas or pork or financial institutions like banks can no longer hedge, you would actually see volatility levels rise, not fall, because institutions have lost their ability to reduce or eliminate price risk. If banks can't use swaps to hedge interest rate exposure, daily fluctuations in bond markets are going to have material impacts on mortgage rates for example. Same thing with oil producers not being able to use futures markets to hedge their crude price exposure. Suddenly there are wild swings in gas prices because short term supply/demand conditions are going to determine breakeven points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36105807906.0" user="brickses" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;When liquidity dries up asset prices begin to collapse

I understand that when there is an expectation of liquidity then the risk of a reduction in liquidity can cause a run. No one wants to own something if they're not sure they will be able to sell it right away if the norm is that they are always able to sell it immediately. If the status-quo shifted such that there were an expectation of lower liquidity then the steady-state investment would surely remain roughly equivalent - lower liquidity wouldn't reduce peoples desire to earn capital gains. Is there another factor to this I'm not understanding?

&amp;gt;If producers of goods like gas or pork or financial institutions like banks can no longer hedge, you would actually see volatility levels rise, not fall, because institutions have lost their ability to reduce or eliminate price risk.

Surely this risk mitigation could be achieved through more traditional insurance models without being significantly disruptive. The effect should be the same but would limited to hedging the risk for the people who produce the commodities. Letting others who have no stake in the market hedge against it is like letting random people take out an insurance policy against me crashing my car.

&amp;gt;If banks can't use swaps to hedge interest rate exposure, daily fluctuations in bond markets are going to have material impacts on mortgage rates for example.

I'll need to think more on this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36105901300.0" user="yumyumnom" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; I understand that when there is an expectation of liquidity then the risk of a reduction in liquidity can cause a run. No one wants to own something if they're not sure they will be able to sell it right away if the norm is that they are always able to sell it immediately. If the status-quo shifted such that there were an expectation of lower liquidity then the steady-state investment would surely remain roughly equivalent - lower liquidity wouldn't reduce peoples desire to earn capital gains. Is there another factor to this I'm not understanding? 

So you are acknowledging that there would be a shift from one status quo to another and that expectation of liquidity is currently of value. Do you not then see that shifting from scenario A where you have liquidity which you find valuable, to scenario B where you have less of said liquidity, would lead prices to move lower?

&amp;gt; Surely this risk mitigation could be achieved through more traditional insurance models without being significantly disruptive. The effect should be the same but would limited to hedging the risk for the people who produce the commodities. Letting others who have no stake in the market hedge against it is like letting random people take out an insurance policy against me crashing my car. 

It's interesting that you bring up insurance, because insurance companies also use derivatives extensively to hedge. You should look into reinsurance companies and how they hedge the exposure they take on from retail insurers. It can get pretty esoteric, hedging disaster insurance like floods or fires with things like weather derivatives (which yes actually exist). These types of derivatives are also used in agriculture to hedge for things like crop yield fluctuations as well. Letting people who have no stake in the market take on risks associated with said market is a fundamental element of insurance.

&amp;gt; I'll need to think more on this. 

Ok, but it's fundamentally no different from any other type of hedging.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
