<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1293341010.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/le0sb6/cmv_every_disney_princess_could_be_reasonably/">
    <title>CMV: Every Disney Princess could be reasonably interpreted as a metaphor for mental illness or diagnosed as having one</title>
    <original_poster>DaisyChained23</original_poster>
    <original_post>Examples:

Belle- Stockholm Syndrome. Also maybe NPD (the scene where the villages are singing about how beautiful and special she is could be seen as a grandiose delusion).

Rapunzel - Anxiety (her "tower" is a mental one) and PTSD from an abusive mother.

Elsa and Anna- BPD. Anna is impulsive and reckless and doesn't really have a clear sense of identity. Elsa is impulsive in a different way and cold. They could be seen as two sides of "splitting".

Ariel- body dysphoria. She literally changes the entire lower half of her body.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36173495698.0" user="That_Uno_Dude" delta="False">
    <text>What about, Snow White, Cinderella, Aurora, Jasmine, Pocahontas, Mulan, Tiana, Merida, and Moana.

Also, Elsa and Anna aren’t a Disney Princess™</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173684419.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>I've discussed Jasmine, Merida, and Moana elsewhere in this thread.

Snow White takes a poisoned apple from a stranger and wakes up believing she is able to speak to animals. This shows impulsivity and a lack of understanding of consequences and speaking to animals is a delusion perhaps explained by schizophrenia.

Cinderella is similar. She believes her clothes were sewn by rats and she has a coach made of a pumpkin. This could perhaps be a delusion caused by schizophrenia but in context seems likely to simply be a false reality she made up because she couldn't cope with her existence and the abuse from her stepsisters.

Aurora has narcolepsy. 

Pocahontas was a real person so I'm reluctant to count her here, but I guess she also counts so I must. The Disney character of Pocahontas (rather than the real person) is impulsive and reckless and shows a disregard for social norms and her own safety. This could be explained by ASPD or hypomania. Also taking into account what actually happened to the real Pocahontas, the Disney story of Pocahontas could be seen as a metaphor for PTSD and Stockholm Syndrome.

Mulan could be seen as a metaphor for gender dysphoria. She presents herself as a man far more often and for far longer than was actually necessary in the situations she was in. Her obsessions with bringing honour to her family show that she is insecure and perhaps obsessed with success which could be a sign of something like covert NPD. Also Mushu could be a hallucination.

Tiana works way too hard; harder than is healthy or productive. She's a "workoholic" which is often a sign of anxiety, OCD, or NPD. Also there's the whole turning into a frog thing which might be seems as low self-esteem and negative self-talk.

Elsa meets the definition of a Disney Princess that Disney itself provided. Anna was a princess (and then a queen) in the Disney universe and is necessary to understand the metaphor behind Elsa.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173731994.0" user="spiderbabyinapram" delta="False">
    <text>Neither Elsa nor Anna are in the trademarked Disney Princess range. That's a fact. Other than that, most of this is reaching, as pretty much every protagonist in every story could be viewed as a metaphor of some kind of mental condition, especially if you're reaching as hard as you are here. If all the princesses are, then every fictional protagonist is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173785046.0" user="DaisyChained23" delta="False">
    <text>Disney specifically defines a Disney Princess as anyone who meets all of the following:

-Is the primary female protagonist in a Disney movie that is not a sequel or spin-off
-Was either born royal or married royal, or performed a great act of heroism (that last bit they made up specifically to include Mulan).

Elsa meets Disney's own definition of a Disney Princess. Anna does not but she is a necessary part of the metaphor surrounding Elsa and is also a princess in the Disney universe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36173960022.0" user="spiderbabyinapram" delta="True">
    <text>I don't think you understand. Disney Princess is a brand, that very specifically doesn't include the Frozen pair. This is splitting hairs, but also annoying as multiple folk have told you this but you won't accept it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
