<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1299493392.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/lhonio/cmv_a_better_way_to_pay_for_college_would_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: a better way to pay for college would be a wage percentage system</title>
    <original_poster>SaltySpursSupporter</original_poster>
    <original_post>instead of needing to take out thousands of dollars for student loans, maybe this is a better idea. instead of needing to pay money outright, negotiate a percentage of your future wage. depending on the program you're entering and the amount of years in that system, you can negotiate the percentage and the amount of years. if the person has a minimum wage job for the chosen amount of years, that's still all they get. i'm sure there are problems here that I haven't thought of. you're welcome to change my mind.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36216582150.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>they would have a financial incentive to get you the best paying jobs, not the one the economy needs.

it would incentive cheating as any without a good grade or needing another year would be bad business for them</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216615965.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>To your first point, don’t the jobs the economy needs eventually become the higher paying jobs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216720577.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>nope, there is a large amount of teachers needed, but since the salary is so low people won't do it,   

salary depends on how they are paid,  a football player who goes pro can make millions in adds, but a goverment worker that handles your info only gets what the goverment is willing to pay.

not to mention jobs change, an absence in one part of the job market can be filled before said students graduate, (pilots for example are now grounded with covid and a certain number of flight hours are needed, so a new pilot would find no work even though before covid there was plenty)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216753893.0" user="SaltySpursSupporter" delta="False">
    <text>True, didn’t think of teachers. 
Ok, after you chose a program, then you start negotiating. So you still do something you want. How’s that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36216851196.0" user="muyamable" delta="True">
    <text>But this system also incentivizes the university to offer degrees for more higher paying jobs than lower paying jobs. It costs a similar amount to educate an elementary school teacher as it does to educate a structural engineer, but the university is going to earn more from the structural engineer than the teacher. So what does it do? It offers more engineering degrees than teaching degrees, even if society needs more teachers than engineers.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
