<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1333574087.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/m1z4cn/cmv_we_should_allow_trans_women_in_us_womens/">
    <title>CMV: We should allow Trans women in US women’s sports to gain more viewers.</title>
    <original_poster>handologon</original_poster>
    <original_post>Let’s be honest here: no one was talking about US women’s sports before Trans women starting joining the teams. 

Only 4% sports coverage has been devoted to women athletes. But now that Trans women are coming out to play, maybe it’ll be more interesting? I honestly was against the idea of Trans women competing in women’s teams until I realized this. 

Allow a limit of 1-2 Trans women per team so they don’t completely dominate, but it is enough to make people actually want to watch. The increased coverage can make more money for Colleges and official leagues, allowing biological females in leagues to make more money. In order to evenly disperse transgender athletes, there can be full ride sports scholarships given at each university for one to two transgender student. Of course biological females will get full ride scholarships as well, and likely there can be more given out due to more viewers. If our concern is safety, extra safety measures can be put in place. Also we should only start this with non-fighting sports, so no wrestling, cage fighting, or boxing. 

This is the video that inspired my thoughts:
https://youtu.be/iJe82yniZQo

Does this make sense? If not, change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36427957145.0" user="NOOBEv14" delta="False">
    <text>It sounds like you’re saying that trans women do have a default advantage in women’s sports (I agree, but this one is hotly contested as is), and that we should embrace that and just let one hop on each team, so we can see them dominate cis women?

There are some pretty specific discriminatory problems here. “They’re too good, but they make it fun, so the rule is you can only have one black guy per basketball team” type stuff. This is DOA for that reason alone. Plus I assume segregating the trans vs cis women would not go over well. “We’re all women regardless of how we got here” or whatever. 

Beyond that, I think most female athletes would take offense to this “no one talks about women’s sports” thing, and the implication that their sports need to be turned into a spectacle to get viewers. I think most would resist that. 

Finally, i just don’t think we need a new wrinkle in this transgender sports conversation. You’re basically giving the win to one side of the argument, but saying we should let it happen anyway, so you’re a step past where we need to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428208745.0" user="handologon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; It sounds like you’re saying that trans women do have a default advantage in women’s sports 

They may, they may not. But if we know anything about testosterone and male puberty, it has a long lasting effect on the body. Even former Trans men who take testosterone end up with permanent side effects after they stop taking it. The muscle mass and density is usually advantageous. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; Plus I assume segregating the trans vs cis women would not go over well. 

First of all, only 0.6% of the population identifies as transgender. There actually might be more of an issue of not having enough of them to play period. And they were literately born with the capacity of competing in the men's league, now they changed to the female gender. Definitely not anything like a black guy on the basketball team, he does not have the ability to change his racial complexion.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt;  Beyond that, I think most female athletes would take offense to this “no one talks about women’s sports” thing, and the implication that their sports need to be turned into a spectacle to get viewers. 

I mean, I would expect they'd want more money and ability to make a career out of their sport though, right? 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

&amp;gt; You’re basically giving the win to one side of the argument, but saying we should let it happen anyway, so you’re a step past where we need to be. 

It's possible to except something as being truthful, and then using that truth in a way to benefit everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36428747365.0" user="neurealis" delta="True">
    <text>First of all, there is no empirical evidence which indicates that trans women are better at sports than cis women. Especially for kids who transition before they go through puberty (and with acceptance and awareness of trans people increasing, this will becone the case for the vast majority of trans people), physical differences between trans and cis women aren't actually that big compared to the variability between individual women. Especially in team sports, where a lot of success is dependent on things that aren't related to strength, like teamwork, reflexes and situational awareness, it probably won't make that much of a difference if you're a cis woman or a trans woman who transitioned before puberty. 

Also, one of the main reasons why women's sports isn't more popular is that sports organisations have deliberately tried to stop women's sports from being publicly viewed at all, and still continue to choose not to promote it more. Women's soccer used to be more popular in the UK than men's soccer, until the FA banned women from playing on official pitches. The women's soccer world cup final in 2019 was scheduled on the same day as the final games for men's soccer tournaments, but still managed to attract more viewers than both of the combined in the US, as well as the previous years men's soccer world cup. It also had double the viewership of both the Stanley cup final and the MLB all-star game held that year.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
