<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321439000.0" user="inquisitive_idgit" delta="False">
    <text>You absolutely have a point--  the video is an important piece of the puzzle of what happened that day.   To see why people are so upset, you have to look at the timing of the release and you have to look at what they're still not doing. 

The community has a right to see the police report on the shooting, the autopsy report, and to know the shooter's record.   Instead, after all this time, the police have still released none of this information.  

What _DID_ they find time to release?   The one video that makes the victim look bad.   

If the police were releasing all the relevant information, people wouldn't be upset.  Instead, they are holding back all information except the information that protects the shooter.   This destroys any illusions that the local police are working for the victim.   

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321651285.0" user="DaSilence" delta="True">
    <text>Tagging /u/Thorax123 as this needs to be seen.

I think the fundamental issue you're encountering is that you don't understand how investigations like this work.

You need first to understand the agencies and players (the cast of characters, if you will):

* The Ferguson Police Department
* The St. Louis County Police Department
* The Office of the Prosecuting Attorney, St. Louis County
* The US Department of Justice
* The Missouri State Highway Patrol

Now, you need to understand how they intersect.

The Ferguson Police Department employed the officer involved in the shooting. As soon as the shooting occurred, they called in the St. Louis County PD, and turned over the shooting investigation to them.

The St. Louis County PD is the lead agency on the SHOOTING investigation. They report their findings to the Office of the Prosecuting Attorney.

The PA's office is the final say for the release of any and all information about the shooting investigation. If they don't approve it for release, it's not released.

The DOJ is conducting a parallel civil rights investigation, and performing about a million interviews. In perhaps the first recorded occasion of this EVER happening, their agents are going door to door.

The MSHP is the lead agency for running the combined unit that's responding to the riots and looting. They have nothing to do with the shooting investigation whatsoever.

Now, as you know, the public is clamoring for the release of the shooting investigation and associated documentation (including the autopsy report). The PA's office has repeatedly refused to release any of this information, and has clearly laid out the circumstances upon which they will release it.

The Ferguson PD, who had no part of this investigative process, and does not control the report or the release of it, literally can't do anything.

The analogy would be that you and my friend Pete are on a street corner. I ask you for some gummy bears, you tell me Pete has them, Pete's dad says I can't have any, and in response I burn your house down.

Now, as to the video and investigation of the strong-arm robbery. This is a case that DOES belong to the Ferguson PD. They investigated it, collected evidence, and then asked the PA's office for what is called exceptional clearance. 

Exceptionally Cleared means that we know who did it, but because of exceptional means (death, usually), there is no reason to continue the investigation or prosecution.

Once the PA's office signs off on the exceptional clearance, the Ferguson PD released the report and evidence to the media, pursuant to the poorly-worded FOIA request from a media member. 

People are upset because they, like you, don't understand why things are done the way they're done.

For more information on why the Ferguson PD officer has not yet been charged, please see this fantastic article from our friends at St. Louis Public Radio:

http://news.stlpublicradio.org/post/so-why-wasnt-officer-wilson-arrested-plus-answers-other-questions-about-law</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
