<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="149345306.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2gwzkq/cmv_its_a_good_idea_for_bank_tellers_to_be_armed/">
    <title>CMV: It's a good idea for bank tellers to be armed.</title>
    <original_poster>ImAwesomeLMAO</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm not entirely passionate about second amendment rights, but it just seems like a rational solution to the problem of an armed robber coming in every now and then. This won't help with any nonviolent thieves that use sneaking, hacking or bad checks, but mostly just to protect the customers and the employees themselves.

Assuming the employees are at least a little trustworthy, there's nothing to worry about. 

This isn't something I've done more than some Googling on, but it just occurred to me. Happy Friday guys.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27369897720.0" user="cysghost" delta="False">
    <text>Are you saying all bank tellers should be armed, or just that they should be able to carry? 

Not everyone has the temperament or judgement to be able to carry a firearm, but I'm guessing you meant they should be allowed to carry, if they want and are qualified (I.e. no offenses on record that disbar them from owning a gun). Is that your view? (No arguments, just asking clarifications)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27369911801.0" user="ImAwesomeLMAO" delta="False">
    <text>Not as a requirement but slightly higher on the recommendation scale than going either way. Like "Hey it'd be pretty handy to be armed."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27369937081.0" user="amaru1572" delta="True">
    <text>Handy for who? If you were running a bank, you wouldn't want a teller to shoot at anybody. Between insurance and the many anti-theft measure already in place, banks have very little to fear from armed robberies where tellers are involved. The worst thing that could happen is a shootout where the teller, or worse yet, bystanders or a customer mistaken as a robber could be killed. If you were a teller, or a low level employee of any establishment, would you be willing to kill (let alone increase the risk to your own life) to protect its money, which isn't even really at risk anyway? I know I wouldn't. The potential for liability goes through the roof relative to making tellers just hand money over. 

Besides, the would-be robbers will know that tellers are armed, as opposed to the current well-known policy of just handing it over, they'll be prepared and get the jump on them every time.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
