<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1561033788.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pteddo/cmv_pregnant_women_should_be_automatically/">
    <title>CMV: Pregnant women should be automatically registered to donate their afterbirths for stem cell research (with an opt-out option).</title>
    <original_poster>Ragdoll_Proletariat</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a Catholic and my father received stem cell treatment a few years ago. It massively improved his quality of life. I learned shortly beforehand that a woman's afterbirth and its core blood contains a lot of stem cells which can be used, to the point that women can actually donate them. I think this should be made an automatic process because of the following reasons:

1. There's no religious debate about harming an embryo because the baby has already been born, meaning that Christian women could help move this forward.
2. Afterbirths normally go in the bin which is a waste of stem cells.
3. Most women don't know this is an option so wouldn't opt into it.

I believe this would hasten research opportunities and consequently medical developments.

I write this with the caveat that women who want to eat it/frame it/etc can opt out in the same way as with UK organ donation. I'm not a doctor of course so I'm wondering if there's anything I'm missing here. I'm interested in seeing people's thoughts on this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37844952118.0" user="DefiantRadish8" delta="False">
    <text>There are alternative options for cord blood, including donating it, freezing it for potential future use by your own child or a family member, or delaying cord cutting by a minute to allow the bit of extra blood in the cord to be absorbed by the newborn. Given all these options can have potential benefits it seems like we should lean to opening the conversation with pregnant women rather than assuming everybody should be donating the cord blood. 

Unlike with organ donation, which is sometimes on opt-out process, pregnant and postpartum patients are generally alive and capable of having the discussion as to whether to donate or not at the time the donation is possible (or a few months before when it’s reasonably foreseeable).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37845196961.0" user="Ragdoll_Proletariat" delta="False">
    <text>That is an important distinction. At the same time, I would also say there is a significant difference between organ donation and afterbirth donation because the afterbirth is something you're body coughs out when it's done with it. Looking at it it's probably more akin to donating pus-filled bandages than donating a lung.

Those options are things that would fall under the opt out I suggested but you have piqued my curiosity. Does delaying the cord cutting have any health benefits for the baby?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37922813789.0" user="ConsistentNumber6" delta="True">
    <text>Yes, delayed cord clamping greatly reduces anemia at 6 months (most important if you're breastfeeding, since milk doesn't have much iron) and is now standard in many hospitals. I considered donating cord blood, but decided not to for this reason.

I didn't know that the placenta could be used for research. If I'd been asked I'd have been all over that...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
