<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1562786393.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/pufxp5/cmv_roe_v_wade_was_decided_incorrectly/">
    <title>CMV: Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly</title>
    <original_poster>Angel33Demon666</original_poster>
    <original_post>__Rationale__

I believe that Roe v Wade was decided incorrectly by the Supreme Court. The reasoning for this is that the right to privacy should not, and could not, be said to be derived from the Fourteenth Amendment by any reasonable reading of the text. The argument given from Griswold is wholly insufficient—it cites searching bedrooms for contraceptives as an unacceptable infringement of privacy, and thereby cites the Fourteenth Amendment as the source of this right to privacy, when the amendment really does not create such a right. (As an aside, I would’ve decided it using the Fourth Amendment and declared that searching bedrooms like that is an ‘unreasonable search and seizure’) Given that a constitutional right to privacy does not exist, the case was decided incorrectly. The correct way to legalize abortions nationwide should either be legislation legalizing abortions and conditions, or a constitutional amendment adopting an amendment similar to Article 8 of the ECHR.  Change my mind.  

__Note__

This is not a post about the merits of abortion, it is a discussion of the legal merits of the judgement handed down by the Supreme Court. Any such comments about the merits of abortion will be ignored. For those curious, I support abortion rights. Further, I anticipate some arguments along the lines of ‘by any means necessary’, which do not convince me, because I have a strong belief in the Rule of Law.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="37857550441.0" user="Xiibe" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so, Roe’s reasoning is actually quite convoluted. To understand the reasoning in Roe, you have to understand the Griswald reasoning and the idea of due process.

The due process clause of the fourteenth amendment says, among other things, that no state shall deprive any person of liberty without due process of law. What happened in the early 20th century is the court began to, and still does, give this idea of liberty quite a bit of weight. Liberty has been read to guarantee fundamental rights implicit to ordered liberty. There are a lot of legal theories as to where these fundamental rights come from and one of them is they are the express AND implied rights in the Bill of Rights. Most things decided using this liberty idea (substantive due process) are very personal things like reproduction, use of contraceptives, marriage, sexuality, etc. 

Now onto Griswold, what Douglas is saying is Griswold is if you read several provisions of the bill of rights together (I think it was the first, third, fourth and fifth) you find the idea there are zones where the government simply isn’t allowed to intrude. (They are called zones fo privacy in the opinion, but that is confusing I think). The reasoning didn’t turn so much of searching bedrooms or homes, it was that married couples have the right to privately decide if they want to use contraceptives and the state cannot intrude on that decision. 

Now, Roe is a very poorly written opinion. But, it takes this Griswold idea and in a very matter of fact way says it’s expansive enough to cover abortion and then sets out the trimester system. Thankfully, the reasoning in Roe has been overruled and placed in a much stronger place in Planned Parenthood v. Casey. However, the current Dobbs v. Jackson’s Women’s Health case is irreconcilable with either Casey or Roe. So, we will see what happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858644066.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>But the thing is the whole Griswald reasoning is wrong. It’s creating new law where none existed. That’s not the job of the courts, it’s congress’ (for legislation) as well as the states’ (for amendments). 

In Rehnquist’s dissent, he noted that none of the laws which banned abortions were struck down after the 14th amendment was passed, so clearly the amendment didn’t mean to include the privacy right as stated in the majority opinion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37858772435.0" user="Xiibe" delta="False">
    <text>Rehnquist’s dissent is pretty unpersuasive. The Supreme Court didn’t start incorporating the bill of rights against the states immediately after the 14th amendment bill as adopted. So, is incorporation wrong then? I don’t think many people would say yes. 

The due process clause specifically protects people from the deprivation of liberty without due process of law. Why couldn’t bodily autonomy be covered under liberty? Liberty has been interpreted to many a great many things, sure Douglas does a poor job of supporting it, but there isn’t a reason the personal choice to have an abortion isn’t covered under liberty. Douglas just puts it too plainly. His reasoning that liberty can be read to include the protection of certain things derived from other provisions in the constitution. 

&amp;gt; It’s creating law where none existed.

That’s kinda what the Supreme Court has ALWAYS done. You can see it in any number of opinions: Marbury, Barron, Heller, Roe, Terry, Citizen’s United, Baker, any of the incorporation cases.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37863641355.0" user="Angel33Demon666" delta="False">
    <text>Well if that’s what they wanted, make a constitutional amendment. This practice of writing egregiously vague amendments and then letting the courts loose on interpreting is terrible. If you want incorporation, write an amendment saying ‘The above amendments x to y will henceforth apply to the states’, or something. If you want a right to privacy, amend ‘congress shall make no law infringing the privacy of citizens…’, etc.  

I’d argue that courts should interpret the law, not make new law.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="37865977335.0" user="chaching65" delta="True">
    <text>The justices are not allowed to strike laws down as they are passed.  The law, especially for things like abortion, sodomy, contraceptives, etc, needs to be put in practice and an actual case needs to be presented to them.  So after the 14th amendment was passed no abortion case was brought to the supreme court until RvW.  Like how the congressional act that extended judicial jurisdiction wasn't struck down until a case was brought to them in Marbury vs Madison.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
