<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="156866222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2le6r2/cmvi_believe_torture_to_be_perfectly_ok_if_guilt/">
    <title>CMV:I believe torture to be perfectly ok if guilt is established beyond reasonable doubt.</title>
    <original_poster>Disgustingoldslob</original_poster>
    <original_post>Simple as the title, I believe that if someone is guilty of a serious crime against another (rape, murder, child abuse, etcetc) the victim or the family of the victim should be legally allowed to torture the guilty party as part of the punishment. I do not believe doing so lowers you to the level of the guilty, as you would be acting out violence on someone who harmed an innocent, while they were completely unjustified in their actions. I also do not believe the moral objections of others should interfere with the legal right of the family/victim.

Edit for clarification, I don't believe it should be mandatory, but I believe it should be an available option. I'm speaking of cases in which guilt is almost perfectly assured. (e.g sound witness testimony, DNA, caught in the act, admission of guilt, etc.)
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27441436098.0" user="cwenham" delta="False">
    <text>To help our members, can you expand on why you believe this? EG: what is the purpose of this torture?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441470998.0" user="Disgustingoldslob" delta="False">
    <text>I don't believe it should be mandatory, as in "x is guilty and his sentence is death/torture, so as such the victim or his family *must* be the ones to carry out said sentence", but I believe it should be an available option. I believe it could be cathartic to victims in some cases, serve as a strong deterrent to others from committing crimes of that nature, and functions as a more robust punishment to offenders than 3 hots and a cot with the possibility to freely go about life in a few years after release.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27441627715.0" user="insurrecto" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe it could be cathartic to victims in some cases

Torturing the perpetrator is not therapeutic to the victim. Therapy and counseling are therapeutic. 

[Psychologists have already proven that getting revenge does not make a victim feel better.](http://www.psychologytoday.com/blog/pieces-mind/201309/revenge-will-you-feel-better)

&amp;gt;serve as a strong deterrent to others from committing crimes of that nature

Prison is already a horrible experience. Beatings, fights, and rape are all common in prison. 

&amp;gt;functions as a more robust punishment to offenders than 3 hots and a cot with the possibility to freely go about life in a few years after release.

The purpose of prison is two-fold: 1) punishment for the crime committed, 2) rehabilitation which will allow a prisoner to return to society and not commit another serious crime.

You have completely ignored the second purpose of prison.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
