<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="160170780.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2nd0kc/cmvrredditarmie_should_be_banned_for_the/">
    <title>CMV:/r/redditarmie should be banned for the continuous raiding and vote-manipulation of YouTube comments.</title>
    <original_poster>Very_Juicy</original_poster>
    <original_post>*"Those who spend their time pretending to be obnoxious idiots aren't really pretending."*

In case anyone's unfamiliar with the subreddit and its users, they're the guys that leave comments like [this](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) on all YouTube videos that are trending on Reddit.

It was fun the first few times or so, but at this point it's just obnoxious and annoying, to a degree where there are more than 10 'joke' comments before you can even get to normal comments that actually refer to the video.

Since it's not uncommon to see entire subreddits get banned for downvote-and commentraiding other subreddits, why is it okay for a sub to be entirely devoted to raiding YouTube videos and manipulating comment vote counts?

I don't see this discussed often on Reddit and when it does get mentioned it's often downvoted to a very heavy degree, so please CMV because I'm obviously not getting the 'joke' here. Even if the joke is being annoying on purpose.

[tl;dr](http://i.imgur.com/PRBfq1g.jpg)

EDIT: Forgot a link to the sub in question: /r/redditarmie

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27472660073.0" user="420fag420fag" delta="False">
    <text>I will have to politely disagree with you. 

Subreddits get banned for linking to other subreddits and interfering with other communities through commenting or upvoting. The problem with your argument is that 

1. /r/redditarmie does not vote manipulate on reddit (Can you show me an example of this? I do my best to prevent these sort of episodes. As you can see, we disallow all reddit links for that reason.)
2. /r/redditarmie does not vote manipulate on youtube

Read our sidebar. We have no method of coordination and actively discourage it. There is no secret raiding subsection or anything of the sort. The admins can peek in our modmail to verify this. The subreddit is an archive or a memory vault of sorts. That was my intention when I made those buttons above the links. 

We are not a top down structure. We don't issue commands or requests. We are all equals. Each individual of the armie comes and goes as he or she pleases. Whether they vote or comment is entirely up to the individual. The content of a post is entirely dictated by the member. I like to believe that we are not an ideologically driven subreddit as we have an extremely diverse set of 'view points' such as feminists, MRAs, liberals, conservatives, Christians, atheists, etc. My point is, everyone in the armie has a slightly different motivation for posting. Everyone is uncoordinated, decentralized and most importantly outside the subreddit.

If the admins were to ban the subreddit right now, the comments would still exist today and the day after and so forth. The idea, I think, is already self propagating. But if the admins decide the time has come, then so be it. I will accept their decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27472806099.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>As a moderator of that subreddit though, you are providing a place where people are encouraged to behave badly ... you are trying to squirm your way out of any responsibility for what your ''armie'' does, after encouraging them to do it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473098488.0" user="420fag420fag" delta="False">
    <text>But - we're not vote manipulating are we? We do vote for each other, yes. But we aren't vote manipulating. There are many redditors outside of the group that vote for us as well. The silent minority.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473102150.0" user="moonflower" delta="False">
    <text>Vote manipulating is not the only form of bad behaviour on the internet.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473299086.0" user="jsauce2" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think he/she is disagreeing with the 'bad'. But Reddit admins don't ban people for being 'bad'. They have a barebones set of rules and attempt to enforce only those from what I understand. I think that subreddit is ridiculous, but I don't see any reason to ban it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473455833.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Really? Reddit admins don't ban people for being "bad"? What about the racist subs or the jailbait one? Reddit definitely makes sure that shit doesn't fly, why is it okay to raid another website and the video of unsuspecting uploaders then?

Imagine yourself in a situation where you are a one-time youtube uploader, that doesn't use social media much, whose video goes viral and comments like [these](http://i.imgur.com/LQcYICz.png) are appearing under your video, talking about your teenage daughter or something. Or the retarded Bertha Lovejoy comments which just boil down to calling everything and everyone sexist (it was funny the first 2587 times... not). Imagine you are that uploader and get that shit into your feed. Imagine you have friends and family who have to read shit like that under the video. Some people will feel uncomfortable when comments like these start appearing under their videos and think that reddit must be some really shitty place (which it is, if it breeds shit like /r/redditarmie). They are more often than not malicious and uncreative comments. 

And most importantly, the people doing it became the kind of people who they are parodying. I mean, what kind of person tries to desperately get a rise out of unsuspecting people over the internet by pretending to be retarded? Probably some basement dweller who got nothing better to do.

Now I am apologizing for my choice of words and for the rant in general but this shit just lowered the quality of two sites I really enjoy visiting and I know that for most people just not caring about it is a viable option. But whenever I have to remember myself to not even bother to scroll down into the cesspool of a youtube comment section to get additional information, insight or commentary from a community that was overall perfectly fine before youtube fucked the comment system up, because these epic le master trolees think they are hot shit by baiting an answer out of some 13 year old kid who sees that the first time, I get a little angry.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27473589748.0" user="jsauce2" delta="True">
    <text>I understand your argument and fully support your point of view. My only point is that I'm under the impression that Reddit wants to create an open platform. While attempting to maintain this openness, they support many disagreeable people, ideas, etc. They only want to moderate/ban when it's breaking the law or violating one of their few rules. Mostly reflecting their arguments [here](http://www.redditblog.com/2014/09/every-man-is-responsible-for-his-own.html)  

I'm not agreeing or disagreeing, just pointing out what I understand Reddit's current stance to be. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
