<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="162950857.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2p0lop/cmv_a_direct_online_democracy_where_people_vote/">
    <title>CMV: A direct online democracy where people vote on issues instead of candidates would be better than always having to vote for the less bad of 2 candidates.</title>
    <original_poster>spappletrap</original_poster>
    <original_post>A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists.

Before, geography limited people so that they couldn't all participate in an election.  Now we have the internet.  True democracy hasn't been around since Athens--the last time all the people in a society was feasibly able to get together in a forum to vote.  But now it's possible.

I think it would work just fine, and it would even mesh well with our current system.

It's very frustrating how our current parties align. It's like they're perfectly aligned to create maximum fighting between themselves, but in the end up being exactly the same on all the most important issues, like war, monetary policy, labor rights, and energy investment--where the policy of both is pretty much "Fuck you."

Voting on issues would make it so someone who is very religious could vote pro-life, but also pro-environmentalist.

Someone could vote for gay marriage, but also against gun control.  Right now, these things are essentially impossible in national elections.

CMV

Or go to /r/openparty/ and start working it out if you agree:



Edit.  One thing that has been brought up, that affects the discussion pretty deeply is the distinction between: 

a)a system where every single vote has to be done through every single person.  

b) a system where people can then vote on policies related to the system itself, and so could evolve.

I was imagining (b) when I posted this, but there's a lot of discussion around (a) as well.

Edit2.  Just to pre-empt a few of the common counter-arguments:

-Most people are stupid

OK, that's a common opinion, not one that I personally hold.  But even if people are stupid, we now have a science committee full of people who don't believe in evolution or climate change.  I would trust randomly selected people from the country over that.  It's been shown time and time again that crowdsourcing performs just fine.  

-Voter Turnout

People wouldn't be forced to vote on topics that don't apply to them or they don't understand.  In fact, they could just as well be encouraged not to.  I see it as a negative that I vote for Obama because I want public healthcare, but then I also have to go with his opinion on farm subsidies, when I don't know what that is, and I don't have time to research it.  In this system, I wouldn't have to.  

-Hackers

I think if the vast majority of the internet can run on open-source software, we can figure something out on this front.  There are security issues with our current methods, too, but we figured it out.


Edit 3:

OK people, we can throw it in.  Cmall2 C-ed my V.  It was pretty good.
The basic points were:

-The dynamics of when a minority would get totally screwed would be very hard to predict.

-The whole system would potentially be very volatile.  Some things which should probably change slowly could change very quickly.

While I still think a variation on such a system could be more effective, the statement I made is that this particular kind of system would be better than the one we have now, and now I don't know if that's true.  So it's no longer my view!

Thanks for the good times guys!
https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nSz16ngdsG0



Edit 4:  One last edit for posterity:  It's kind of funny all these people who are deathly afraid of people voting in their own interest, yet believe firmly in the invisible hand.  

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27499192471.0" user="Cmall2" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; True democracy hasn't been around since Athens

really? a democracy in which only white, male natives to the country who had completed military service could vote is a "true" democracy? and Athens was one city-state. the US is a country that spans a continent and has MANY times the population and diversity of Athens.

&amp;gt; A direct online representative democracy would work better than a republic now that the internet exists

whether a direct democracy would work better than an indirect democracy is better is a question independent of the existence of the internet. here are a few points against direct democracy itself that i find convincing:

* the rapid voting of a direct democracy would make policies and laws very sporadic and inconsistent. changes in laws, government, and the economy usually take many years to show if they are better worse for society, so the time between elections gives us time to appraise the officials we elect and their policies. for example, support of the death penalty usually spikes shortly after a horrific crime, since people want to see the criminal punished as harshly as possible, but swiftly drops as time passes. so policies would just be a constant to and fro swing in accordance to the immediate popular mood, to no helpful effect

* a great many people are already not welly informed or interested in politics. and look how in our current system we have companies and advertising campaigns pushing people to vote for a particular candidate, even when that candidate maybe doesn't represent the interests of the people very well, and how the people are so readily convinced to vote for them anyway. so instead of advertising for a candidate that will pass bills in their favor, companies will just advertise the bill itself directly to the people in the same way, essentially changing nothing and giving them the same, if not more sway than they already have.

* direct democracy is mob rule. minority groups would be shut out of the political process and picked apart by majorities, thus lacking proper representation of the full population. conversely, if there is a minority group that is extremely passionate about a bill, many of them will turn out to vote, possibly more than everyone else because everyone else didn't care enough to vote. thus the minority would then get their way purely out of the apathy of the majority. and we should expect low turnouts on many votes, considering how you cant expect every citizen to feel strongly about or simply even understand every bill or law proposed, every time it is proposed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499208267.0" user="spappletrap" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;a democracy in which only white, male natives to the country who had completed military service could vote is a "true" democracy?

Sorry, "true" is loaded language.  I meant, direct, where people vote on issues rather than representatives.

&amp;gt;the rapid voting of a direct democracy would make policies and laws very sporadic and inconsistent. 

This is 100% true, but I think this is something that could be worked out through voting on the policy of the system itself.  Monetary policy could be voted on every 4 years or something.  As it stands, the public has no direct input into monetary policy at all.

&amp;gt;a great many people are already not welly informed or interested in politics

In my system, people wouldn't have time to pay attention to votes they don't care about.  And the corporations would have to launch a campaign for every issue instead of just funding/paying off a few candidates.

&amp;gt;minority groups would be shut out of the political process and picked apart by majorities

I tend to agree, and you're the closest that anyone's gotten to changing my view. But I think that the low turnouts would tend to be a feature.  The minorities could get shut out if both sides are passionate, but if the majority just doesn't care much, they will probably have their way much quicker than if they have to get a majority of people in congress paying attention to and agreeing on something that most people don't care about.

For instance, most people support native american rights, but nothing ever gets done about it.  There aren't many people who would vote against more protections for Native Americans, but it would be a major task to get congress to pay attention to something like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27499349401.0" user="Cmall2" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; this is something that could be worked out through voting on the policy of the system itself...As it stands, the public has no direct input into monetary policy at all

is it perhaps true that maybe some things *shouldn't* be changeable? the years between voting, for example? because you yourself said the years between voting could be voted on. and what if when those 4 years are up, the people decide now they only want 2 years between voting? and after that, 1 year? 6 years? a decade? the inconsistency wont stop. and when it comes to monetary legislation, is that a bad thing that we don't get a say? if we did, what would we say? what would 316 million people who have no idea what the first thing about monetary legislation say? do you honestly trust every single person to take the considerable time and effort to receive a proper understanding of the intricacies of monetary legislation, and then cast a well informed and welly thought out vote on it? or do you think no one will, and will instead remain ignorant and clueless, and jump on to whatever is suggested to them by mass hype (which we've established is very inconsistent and sporadic), advertising campaigns, and personal bias? you know, **just like they do now**?

&amp;gt; In my system, people wouldn't have time to pay attention to votes they don't care about. And the corporations would have to launch a campaign for every issue instead of just funding/paying off a few candidates

that still doesn't clear up the issue with the lack of representation. If anything, that's just a tacit admission that a large part of legislation wont be decided by a majority vote, like you desire, but by the whim of a few, independent from the majority of people, like you accuse representative democracy of doing. at least in a rep. democracy, the majority consent to these few having the legislative power, since they voted for them. and i doubt companies will pour so much time and resources into EVERY issue. after all, many issues will be ignored by the majority of people (as has been established) who don't really care about it, and will thus be completely at the whim of minorities already devout to a particular position, one which they aren't likely to change if it differs from what the corporation wants, regardless of any advertising to the contrary. instead, they will pour it into the big, important issues that hold many people's passion and attention, **just like they do now** in our current system. so companies will just ignore the smaller, trivial, unalterable votes and still push for only a few big things, just in your system it will be for the legislation itself instead of a candidate.

&amp;gt;  I think that the low turnouts would tend to be a feature

low turnouts on voting, in a society whose progress and activity is decided solely on voting, is a very bad feature

&amp;gt;  they will probably have their way much quicker than if they have to get a majority of people in congress paying attention to and agreeing on something that most people don't care about...it would be a major task to get congress to pay attention to something like that

but is that necessarily a good thing? what if the minority wants a bad thing? speed isn't the point. ensuring good, agreed upon legislation is the point. even if it is good legislation, like your native american example, it is still unfair for anyone besides the majority of the pouplation to have such power in a majority-wins system. i mean, doesn't the notion of a minority having unfettered decision making power undermine the notion of majority rule, the point of direct democracy and everything you want in your system?

&amp;gt; you're the closest that anyone's gotten to changing my view

sweet! i'll keep trying. im thirsty for my first delta :-)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
