<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1630071154.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/qyi2ya/cmv_sellside_equity_research_is_useless_to_retail/">
    <title>CMV: Sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market</title>
    <original_poster>BAIIIPLUS</original_poster>
    <original_post>What is the value of information for investors? The most valuable information to generate superior return is getting inside information. However, it is not usually available and you will be prosecuted if you trade on such information.

In addition to traditional media, brokers offer sell-side equity research. I don't think is is useful for retail investors to generate return above index.

1. Accuracy of recommendation  
 No one knows the future price. I don't see sufficient evidence to believe an analyst can accurately predict the future price. If he/she has such a predictive power, he/she should've quitted the job and made money by his/herself.
2. Knowledge  
 Some people may argue that we can accumulate knowledge reading sell-side equity research. However, could you generate superior return above index by knowing more? I don't think so because what you learned is already known by other rich investors who would have more significant influence on market prices.

Therefore, sell-side equity research is useless to retail investors to beat the market. They are marketing materials of brokers. To beat the market, there are more important factors than information from brokers such as investment experience and mental control.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38302424795.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; No one knows the future price. I don't see sufficient evidence to believe an analyst can accurately predict the future price. If he/she has such a predictive power, he/she should've quitted the job and made money by his/herself.

There is a few issues there.

* Just because they don't *know* the future price doesn't mean they can't be slightly better than the market at predicting it.  Even slightly better than market can make it worth listening to.
* Making a slightly better than market return doesn't necessarily mean you'll make more money doing that as your main job.  For example, Jim Cramer makes $5 million/year salary.  Even if his full estimated $100 million net worth was invested into stocks, he would have to beat the market by a full 5% in order to top what he gets paid as an analyst.  Even then it is still riskier and may just not be as enjoyable for him.
* Sell-side equity research influences the market, so even if it really was no better than throwing darts, its a factor that could influence the price so belongs in your research just like anything else that can influence company price.

&amp;gt; Some people may argue that we can accumulate knowledge reading sell-side equity research. However, could you generate superior return above index by knowing more? I don't think so because what you learned is already known by other rich investors who would have more significant influence on market prices.

Just because rich investors know what, say, Beta is doesn't mean it isn't worth learning and sell-side equity research is a place where you can learn about a lot of things like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38302554322.0" user="BAIIIPLUS" delta="False">
    <text>5Δ

Thank you for your comment. Your logic was very clear and easy to follow. I like some points that you have made. Especially, it's worth listening to them even if they are not perfect predictors.

I would like to discuss more about two points.  
1. Analyst predictions  
Your point is based on the assumption that analysts have slightly better ability at predicting future prices. When we discuss prices, we need to incorporate their ability to predict appropriate P/E. To simplify the discussion, let's talk about their ability to predict EPS and revenue.

One interesting finding is this.

* EPS Surprise: In the fourth quarter of 2020, 81% of companies listed on the S&amp;amp;P 500 reported a positive EPS surprise, meaning that these companies beat analyst expectations. That’s a huge miss on a key valuation metric used by most investors.
* Revenue: In the fourth quarter of 2020, 79% of companies listed on the S&amp;amp;P 500 beat analyst expectations in terms of revenue.

[https://www.moneycrashers.com/stock-market-analyst-rating-accuracy/](https://www.moneycrashers.com/stock-market-analyst-rating-accuracy/)

Would you say analysts are slightly better than average investors?

2. Known facts/observations  
I agree with your idea that we can learn about a lot of things. Personally, I learned a lot to be a less worth investor. However, it is kind of indirect causal argument. Would you say reading the report could be direct cause of performance above the market?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38302652592.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="True">
    <text>Thanks for the delta!

&amp;gt; that these companies beat analyst expectations

Analysts missing on mass like that isn't really a criticism unless they missed by more than the rest of the market did.  They could miss by a lot and still potentially beat the market.  Not sure if that is true here or not, don't know enough about that EPS surprise.

&amp;gt; Would you say analysts are slightly better than average investors?

The significant majority of analysts, personal investors, mutual fund managers, etc that beat the market are only beating the market due to luck and not the quality of their strategy.  But that shouldn't be confused with none of them actually have strategies that are better than the market, though identifying which analysts should be listened to in general is likely as hard an activity as just beating the market (since successfully listening to the right analysts would also lead to beating the market).

But ultimately, I do think that "Jim Cramer said this is a buy" is useless.  Their final recommendation aren't what I would suggest you listen to.  It's the reasoning and how you incorporate their reasoning into your analysis that matters.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
