<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="163717378.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2ph14y/cmv_debt_forgiveness_is_one_of_the_stupidest/">
    <title>CMV: Debt forgiveness is one of the stupidest ideas ever conceived</title>
    <original_poster>Ndlaxfan</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'll start this off by saying that I am in my last year of high school, and I will hopefully be attending a school that is about 60k a year. However, I will be graduating with under 5k in debt. I've worked my ass off for scholarships, and so far I've gotten about 205 k paid for. Most of the debt-forgiveness advocates are students who bit off more than they can chew, and will be swimming in piles of debt. If the government completely forgave debts, then they completely dick every financial institution in America. I view it like this: why would you go to an upscale restaurant, gorge yourself with food, and then be pissed off and demand that you can't pay the bill?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27506361684.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think people are calling for a true [Jubilee](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jubilee_%28biblical%29) but rather for student loans to be treated like other debts in bankruptcy.  We do allow people who get over their heads in debt to get out from it through bankruptcy.  Unless the debt arises from severe moral turpitude (e.g. OJ's debt from the lawsuit over killing Nicole Brown Simpson), it can normally be discharged in bankruptcy if your income is too low and you can show that you have no assets with which to possibly pay it.

Your restaurant example is one where the debt would be bankruptable.  Credit card debt is one of the most common debts to be voided in bankruptcy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506477416.0" user="thrawtes" delta="False">
    <text>The problem is that you can't repossess education. With the ability to keep the asset in its entireity but pay none of the charges for it, there's very little incentive to *not* take on a ton of student debt and then declare bankruptcy. It will destroy your credit rating for a decade, but many people would sell their credit rating for &amp;gt;$100,000 in an instant, which is essentially what this would allow. 

Lenders won't simply eat this risk, instead they'll raise interest rates and fees to offset this newfound risk, or simply not allow students to borrow money.

This may eventually "fix" tuition inflation by making loans less available, but it would be very painful in the interim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27506495783.0" user="huadpe" delta="True">
    <text>I agree with most of what you say here, but have a big caveat: the government.

&amp;gt;Lenders won't simply eat this risk, instead they'll raise interest rates and fees to offset this newfound risk, or simply not allow students to borrow money.

The United States government is far and away the largest lender of student loans.  Private market lenders will likely act as you describe, but there's no reason the government has to.  They do money-losing things all the time.  IIRC, something like 3/4 of student loan dollars come from the feds.

Second, student loans used to be bankruptable.  There were some scandals with med students finishing school and promptly filing BK.  

Discretionary authority exists among bankruptcy judges already to refuse discharge of debts entered into when the debtor planned to file, for example.  That authority could be expanded on and guidelines established to look specifically at immediate post-graduation/disnerollment bankruptcies.

Another possible solution would be to require that student loans can only be discharged through Chapter 13 bankruptcy.  On Chapter 13, you have to enter a payment plan and live on a pretty strict budget, with all excess income going to your debts for 3-5 years.

But I think that bringing student loans into a well-established legal institution for dealing with debt is a good idea in the long run, even if some special rules need to be adopted to prevent abuses.  </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
