<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1642402331.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/r5udqz/cmv_the_onus_of_sustainability_is_excessively/">
    <title>CMV: The onus of sustainability is excessively placed on consumers and the obligation should instead be placed on corporations.</title>
    <original_poster>Fluffy_Owl4316</original_poster>
    <original_post>Much of the media we read today about sustainability is focused on what consumers should be doing to move the needle. This includes things such as recycling food containers, composting food scraps, repairing and reusing clothing rather than purchasing new, etc. As corporations continue to produce these items, the proper disposal and thus environmental impact, is placed on the consumer. 

On the other hand, corporations are publishing lofty goals about recycled materials and reduced carbon footprint by 2050 or other far-off timeframes. Yet, there is little regulation to ensure that these goals are achieved. There isn’t a single governing body which is responsible for measuring the attainment of these statements, which doesn’t hinder the goodwill of creating the goals, but does little to hold corporations accountable for achieving them. 

At the end of the day, large corporations are responsible for much of the waste which harms the environment and should have a greater obligation and more enforcement of sustainable methods and materials. While end users are also responsible, humans fall victim to common errors and shortcomings which make true environmental impact, one that moves the needle, nearly impossible for individual users, even collectively as compared to large businesses. While the responsibility for sustainability and carbon footprint is often targeted towards consumers, the narrative should instead be on large corporations and how to hold them accountable to finding sustainable solutions.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38377849769.0" user="Echoos1" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with putting the obligation solely on corporations is that they have no incentives to do become sustainable. Sustainable practices are usually more expensive, more time consuming, and far less convenient. Corporations that are big enough to fit within your ideal responsible party are only that big because they save every penny and have streamlined their business based on profit, which sustainable practice don't work with.

Sustainability is extremely inconvenient, or at least, too inconvenient for the general mass to bother with, so any corporation trying to fill the sustainable market will fail to reach most people. Businesses *need* the support of the people to survive. They wouldn't be able to maintain supplying *our* unsustainable lifestyles while themselves being sustainable.

The assumption that corporations should be the ones to assume responsibility for changing the world into more sustainable practices takes the accountability from the unsustainable lifestyles consumers lead, which are the root cause of the business practices you seek to change. In truth, both parties need to change face to make any reasonable difference


Edit: My view opposing the OP has been changed through conversation. The way I now see it: on an individual level, it's important for each person to take an interest in sustainability and how it benefits them, as this interest will allow businesses and policy to alter their course. The actual responsibility for the change however, rests on the shoulders of corporations and the government</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38379972944.0" user="ristoril" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; the unsustainable lifestyles consumers lead

Tell me how CD packaging in the 1990s was the consumers' fault, please.  Just as a specific example.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380103200.0" user="Echoos1" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't the fault of the consumers. The issue has been a collaborative effort by all humans since forever. 

The quality of life enjoyed by most middle class westerners is undeniably unsustainable, and most would be object to ever giving it up without understanding *and identifying with* the long term benefits of doing so. Certainly this lifestyle was not entirely *created* by consumers, but it has been embraced by us.

Single-use plastic packaging is an easy, convenient, and cheap way to package products. We are only just realizing the environmental cost of these choices, but are backed into a corner with our lack of alternatives that match the pros plastic. 

This is really about how to get the solution started, placing blame on a group from a time when very few people cared or even had an opportunity to care isn't quite fair.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38380607364.0" user="ristoril" delta="True">
    <text>Nobody's placing blame except the people blaming consumers for their consumption practices. 

The important thing to figure out is who to hold accountable and how to do it.  Most of the time "accountability" is thought of as a synonym for "punishment," but the real meaning has to do with how do we make sure entities don't just do what they want but rather do things with intention and a full appreciation of the full consequences of their actions. 

This isn't even about the past, really.  It is what it is.  We can clean it up but cleaning up after the fact isn't a good as preventing the mess in the first place.  

So can *consumers* stop producers from producing in a messy fashion?  No.  At best they can not reward producers who make huge messes, but the mess is there at that point. 

The only entities who can prevent producers from making messes are producers.  They'll only do it if we use the tool of government to create the guidelines and regulations and other guardrails that will lead them to least messy production choices. 

After the fact is too late, and it's the only lever consumers have.  Before a mess is made is the perfect time, and that's something voters and their elected representatives can do.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
