<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1669442084.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/rlxxr8/cmv_kim_potter_is_guilty_of_2nd_degree/">
    <title>CMV: Kim Potter is guilty of 2nd degree manslaughter</title>
    <original_poster>StoopSign</original_poster>
    <original_post>The facts of the case aren't really disputed. She thought she grabbed her taser but grabbed her gun instead and shot Daunte Wright while he attempted to flee. Potter knew that it wasn't a lethal force scenario by *intending* to grab her taser and yelling "taser." If her years of experience taught her to use lethal force she would have not attempted to draw the taser, and she wouldn't have cried on the ground knowing she'd made a mistake. That's what it was. A mistake. A deadly mistake. 

"A person who causes the death of another by any of the following means is guilty of manslaughter in the second degree and may be sentenced to imprisonment for not more than ten years or to payment of a fine of not more than $20,000, or both:

(1) by the person's culpable negligence whereby the person creates an unreasonable risk, and consciously takes chances of causing death or great bodily harm to another;"

 
https://www.revisor.mn.gov/statutes/cite/609.205

Culpable negligence includes mistakes. Even honest mistakes. She's not charged with murder. She didn't need have to have criminal intent to commit 2nd degree manslaughter by way of culpable negligence.

Explained online:

"Examples of culpable negligence might include a healthcare professional giving a patient a medication that they are allergic to; a teacher leaving a class unsupervised, resulting in a child getting hurt; a car driver injuring someone in an accident that occurred while the driver was texting – the list goes on, but the most infamous example of culpable negligence concerns firearms."

https://www.centralflalaw.com/culpable-negligence.html

Edit: Just wanna point out how I'm totally part of a new stereotype of liberals/civil libertarians, who remember the incident, then get all confused by media portrayals of events and the possible mistrial. MSM is indeed bullshit. They never get down in the weeds. CourtTV is a bit better. I've amended my view to have some doubt on the jurisprudence side. I dunno if its a reasonable doubt. Some quantify reasonable doubt as a 10% doubt but every legal professional I've met says that's bs.

I do think everyone in that room except the jury has a pro-police bias. I think DAs were a bit eager to overcharge both Rittenhouse and Potter. This muddies the waters for jurors. I suppose there's something to be said for complaints about "actavist DAs." I want them to focus more on releasing non-violent offenders and not bow to public pressure and end up charging the woman with two crimes that are substantially similar. The key difference is whether she recklessly intended to injure and didn't care if he died (man 1) or whether she acted with disregard for any possible injury he could sustain (man 2). These states of mind are contradictory. Even though they are substantially similar. So the defense can easily assert a state of mind that falls short of culpability

I don't believe in lengthy sentences. 3yrs on the protective cop n snitch block is enough if convicted</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38548953967.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; **might** include a healthcare professional giving a patient a medication that they are allergic to

That *might* is extremely important.  That is an example of something that is negligent, but its level of negligence depends on the details of the situation.

From your link:

&amp;gt; culpable negligence is “more than a failure to use ordinary care for others” and is instead “a course of conduct showing reckless disregard for human life” which can include “a conscious indifference to consequences”

That is absolutely NOT met by an "honest mistake".  When you are showing a "reckless disregard for human life" that goes way beyond an honest mistake.  Note that this link is quoting Florida (not Minnesota) Jury instructions, so lets take a look at the Jury [instructions in this case](https://www.kare11.com/article/news/local/judge-decides-on-jury-instructions-in-kim-potter-case-shaping-strategies-ahead-of-opening-statements/89-5d081964-b797-4490-9aa6-dd5331033489) and see if it is any different:

&amp;gt; An accident isn't a crime unless it involves some level of "carelessness" or "recklessness" — terms the jury will spend a lot of time defining in deliberations.

&amp;gt; Judge Regina Chu decided she will instruct the jury that recklessness in first-degree manslaughter requires "proof of a conscious or intentional act... that creates a substantial and unjustifiable risk that the actor is aware of and disregards."

Again, same as Florida, an honest mistake just doesn't meet the threshold.

The conscious act that Potter took was reaching for and discharging a taser.  This is what her intention was.  Unless merely discharging a taser in the same situation would've been a reckless behavior (for example if the taser was completely uncalled for, which the prosecution is trying to show), then there is no intentional act that was reckless and especially doesn't arise to the level of "the actor is aware of and disregards".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549048049.0" user="StoopSign" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;An accident isn't a crime unless it involves some level of "carelessness" or "recklessness"

Yes. Outcomes matter though. It's an honest mistake and it's careless. She fired a fatal shot into someone's chest by accident. One of the issues I'm not sure the jury was instructed about was the "reasonable person" standard. This absolutely cannot be properly used to judge the police. Reasonable peoole aren't going to be in that position. She intended to fire a taser into a moving vehicle which could easily be recklessly endangering public safety and showing disregard for the safety of the Wright as tasers are still powerful weapons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549175867.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes. Outcomes matter though.

Right, but I'm not sure how more clearly they can say it than "An accident isn't a crime unless...". It has to be more than an mere accident.

&amp;gt; She intended to fire a taser into a moving vehicle which could easily be recklessly endangering public safety

That is true, but that would only apply if firing the taser wasn't the right call to be made at that moment. None of your original post said anything remotely like, "She shouldn't have even fired her taser in that situation".  This is an argument the prosecution is trying to make, so there is an argument to be made there, but it certainly isn't a clear cut one.  If you want to have that discussion on whether or not she was right to draw a taser in that situation, then we can have that, but that is a much harder target than you seem to be aiming for.  Your original post seems to try to paint her honest mistake as still meeting the bar.  Without her intentional act (the one she intended on doing, drawing the taser) being a reckless one, she just isn't guilty of anything.  You would need to show she shouldn't have drawn any weapon in her situation to do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549211736.0" user="StoopSign" delta="False">
    <text>!Delta The scope of my post was too narrow and simplistic. There's other factors in the case I use to draw my conclusion.

I really wanna stress the inapplicabilty of the "reasonable person" standard as it pertains to cops. It's unprecedented. Our court system predates municipal policing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38549267703.0" user="AnythingApplied" delta="True">
    <text>Thanks for the delta!

Why the focus on the reasonable person standard? The Jury guidance for this case I linked made no mention of leading the jury to use that standard (though it only had excepts from the guidance, its possible it was elsewhere).

Also, other courts have had no issue using a "reasonable officer" standard.  If you want to dig into all the details of how the "reasonable officer" standard is applied, you can see [this document](https://law.lclark.edu/live/files/7237-lcb144art8mandiberg.PDF).  It is literally *precedented* as can be seen by the supreme court cases referenced in that document.  It has quite a rich precedented as a concept.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
