<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38697558521.0" user="Green_Difference2647" delta="False">
    <text>Unlimited subs would make the game more financially heirarchical than it already is. Teams like PSG and Man City, with literally billions in the bank, could just fill up a squad of 22 world class players and essentially play two entire different teams in a single game that can both dismantle any other even moderately good squad. This adaptation to the game would further increase the gap in quality between the top few richest teams and the rest of the world. That's not what football is meant to be.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38698892590.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Not ready to give a delta yet, but I’m definitely curious about the economic implications of such a change.

Could it be possible that the additional subs change the game so much that having superstars becomes less important? And if yes, maybe that’s still a good reason to keep subs as they are 🤔</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38701338617.0" user="FjortoftsAirplane" delta="True">
    <text>A general principle is that anything that removes an element of luck from the game will favour the more skilled player(s).

Limited substitutions means the effects of injuries, fatigue, players being cautious on a yellow card, or just failed choices that aren't changeable are further reduced, and that benefits the team that has more resources.

Having unlimited substitutions would make squad depth that much more important, and that only benefits those who can afford the costs.

It would vastly reduce the efficacy of cards. Often players take yellows to prevent a promising attack, or they use "rotational fouling" where no one player fouls an opponent enough to get a yellow/red for persistent foul play. Unlimited subs would mean you could bring players on for the sole purpose of committing fouls, disrupting the game, and killing attacks.

My other concern is that substitutions take time and are already used to disrupt the flow of a game. Having unlimited subs would slow the game right down. You could always go for roll on/roll off subs but that would involve an overhaul to the way subs are made and require extra refereeing (could make things difficult at lower levels). It would certainly add delays though, as if a coach wants to put out five defensive players for a set piece or corner, that's five on that need to take up positions. Same for attacking plays from corners or long throws. The one thing football doesn't need is people wasting more time.

I also think there's something to be said in favour of limitations. It means that the way the game is initially approached matters much more. How a team sets up for a game isn't a trivial decision. Formations are more rigid as wholesale changes can't be made, and we get to see strategies and tactics play out over 90 minutes rather than be in a state of flux in which the system constantly changes. I also think the level of organisation required in football systems wouldn't lend itself to chopping and changing so much anyway (I suppose that might be a plus to your side as teams wouldn't actually utilise their subs too often). Personally, I don't want to see a constantly shifting game, I want to see whether a team's tactics work over 90 minutes.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
