<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1693263824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/s04iq8/cmv_soccer_would_benefit_from_unlimited/">
    <title>cmv: Soccer would benefit from unlimited substitutions</title>
    <original_poster>cesarsalazar</original_poster>
    <original_post>Soccer (or football) only allows for 3 substitutions and once a player is out, s/he can’t return. 

In my view, this rule is counterproductive. Allowing unlimited substitutions (like in other major sports) would have all or some of the following benefits, without any major downside:

- Increased speed of the game (players would have a chance to rest from sprinting, etc)

- More creative/imaginative gameplay. Coaches can combine different players to achieve different tactics.

- Increased player career span. Players have a better chance to recover from injuries. Less incentive to play while injured.

- Higher play quality. Naturally the players that perform better spend more time on the field.

What am I missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38697404861.0" user="justfukinwitchu" delta="False">
    <text>You forgot to consider a team like man city. They can field 11 star players and still have 11 on the bench. Then you have the likes of brentford who doesn’t have 1 star player let alone 2 teams worth. Until covid hit it was a maximum of 3 including head injuries. Now in every other league bar the prem &amp;amp; championship, I think your now allowed 5 subs and a concussion sub i know thats the case in the champions league.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38697570930.0" user="cesarsalazar" delta="False">
    <text>Unlimited substitutions could also lead to a more competitive sport.

In professional basketball (NBA) some modern teams with less star power can compete with teams with more star power because of the imaginative ways in which they play and the depth of their non-star, yet competitive benches.

In my view, limited changes means more reliance on the 11 starters and less imaginative combinations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38700766337.0" user="fschiltz" delta="True">
    <text>It would be even worse for international competition. A small country like mine (Belgium) is pretty good at the moment because we were lucky to have a few star players in the same generation that we can rely on. But if the depth of the field was more important, small countries could never even compete with large countries such as France, Germany and Brazil and the large countries would be even more dominant than now.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
