<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38865448437.0" user="Traditional_Cup4304" delta="False">
    <text>There is a constitutional injunction against cruel and unusual punishment. This should be sufficient to change your mind. If one chooses not to respect the limits of the constitution, one seeks to usurp the constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865502299.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>The eight amendment of the constitution states: *"Excessive bail shall not be required, nor excessive fines imposed, nor cruel and unusual punishments inflicted."*

I said why I don't think this is cruel and unusual punishment beyond what is already done. Also we deny bail to any risk targets so it's kind of already being mildly violated at reasonable discretion.

Therefore I don't think it violates the constitution.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865564691.0" user="Traditional_Cup4304" delta="False">
    <text>Your logic is faulty because we don’t already do this as a punishment and it is not done specifically because it is cruel. In fact it’s a pretty heinous crime. That’s why people go to jail for it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38867367847.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>Keeping people in a cage or murdering them is also a crime.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38868187148.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>A. It's not specifically done for the purpose of inflicting cruelty

B. Then if that justified your plan, why not go all the way and have things like some being made into Soylent Green or forced into Hunger-Game-esque death games or why not just create a hell if it doesn't already exist and resurrect them after death to be tortured forever, because hey, if "keeping people in a cage or murdering them is also a crime" that can justify any crime</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38869241293.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>But it is cruel by result. Rape as a sentence here would also only be cruel as a result due to trying achieve some good ie. providing free sex as a service.

Turning humans into Soylent doesn't give more benefit than the downsides. Processing people into Soylent would be expensive especially given the supply of death row inmates is not very large. It also wouldn't be very fruitful considering most people would not eat human remains.

Hunger games would be too expensive to try. Also I don't see much point? We already have lots of entertainment, but incel terrorism seems to be growing from a lack of available sex.

Crimes are only justified if they add enough good to offset them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38873499398.0" user="StarChild413" delta="False">
    <text>And you seem to think every incel is not only a mass-shooter waiting to happen but a homosexual male (as you've never mentioned some of these prisoners might be female)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38873678913.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>I'm assuming the majority of incels are straight males. No they're not all mass shooters waiting to happen but many of them sympathize with and encourage mass shooters though they are too scared to do it themselves. 

There would also be female prisoners whose crimes warrant forfeiting their bodily autonomy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38948047169.0" user="StarChild413" delta="True">
    <text>But if you're forcing women into this and basically saying to the straight male incels "fuck this woman or we're going to think you're going to commit a mass shooting", don't you realize the optics would be kinda shitty</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
