<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475259431.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack

If someone is making threats based on something as benign as celebrity gossip, they're really leaning into their animalistic side. So, no, they're not 'dogs' but they are a threatening, human-animal.

And, if someone's type of crazy is celebrity-focused, the celebrity themselves is the *best* person to get them to chill. Especially when it's some BS white-knighting like your case-study here. If something bad is happening in your name, *you're* the one who can stop it, and if you don't, you are consciously perpetuating the threat.

&amp;gt; It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton

Do you *want* violence against gossip bloggers for blogging gossip?

&amp;gt; and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off

They're only seen as bad if they could solve the problem and choose not to. That's textbook bad behavior, isn't it? To have someone causing trouble in our name but you say nothing (literally the least you can do)? 

Lack of condemnation can be seen as support, especially when the de-escalating counter-move is as simple as a tweet or comment.

&amp;gt; celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers

Again, are you *pro-*violence against gossip bloggers? Also, protecting shit-talkers is how free speech works. Are you against free speech?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475964909.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I believe there’s something here called a neutral party in the situations we’re discussing. You seem to rely on a moral binary in situations like this

Would you suggest such a celebrity is liable for these acts if they follow through?

Are you the kind of person to back Good Samaritan laws?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475971621.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Wow, slippery-slope much?

If a celebrity can stop the harassment (and possible assault) of someone else simply by tweeting or making a comment, you don't think they should do so? I never said anything about punishments, so let's calm down with all of that please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476102457.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough.

I’d say they SHOULD for reasons other than moral reasons, not MUST.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476112334.0" user="Deft_one" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, then it's not extremely stupid to request that they use their 'power' as we agree they 'should,' is it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476151115.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I would say “should” over “must”, of course</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476185923.0" user="Deft_one" delta="True">
    <text>So then it's not extremely stupid to ask that they use their 'power' as we agree they 'should,' is it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
