<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39474965164.0" user="LooseBar2222" delta="False">
    <text>What's the alternative? The goal of "calling off fans" is to try and stop the harassment of someone else. There's not a better solution to stop that harassment, is there?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475184213.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that it’s a desperate thing, but they don’t have a duty or responsibility to do so, right?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475210721.0" user="LooseBar2222" delta="False">
    <text>It's really easy to say "Hey fans, stop harassing someone." Given the large impact that this will have, it seems like from a moral standpoint they do have a responsibility to call their fans off.

It's like if you see someone trip and they're clearly injured. Technically you don't "have" to help them by calling 911, but I think it's pretty clear that not doing so would be a dick move.

As a general rule, if you have the power to stop or limit harassment with little effort, you probably should. If you don't, I think it's perfectly justified to wonder why that person didn't do anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475908617.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t agree with the Good Samaritan imperative mindset. I agree with you, however, that it’s socially beneficial to ask fans to stop.

I can’t find any positive obligations for people in nature (nothing that morally compels people to act. Instead, I find what one should refrain from. You can morally ignore a drowning child, but you can’t murder.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39475977062.0" user="LooseBar2222" delta="False">
    <text>If you agree that it's socially beneficial, it wouldn't be stupid to ask a celebrity to call off their fans.

Human society functions on social conventions. I think it's pretty sensible to have social consequences for not doing something that is socially beneficial and that takes no effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476115828.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>For your first part, I agree.

On the second part, I’m talking more about legal ramifications. Social stigmas can go wherever they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476145596.0" user="LooseBar2222" delta="True">
    <text>Is that what your CMV is? It seems like the goalposts have moved from "Asking celebrities to call off their fans is stupid" to "Celebrities shouldn't be on the hook for their fans from a legal perspective."

AFAIK, there's no legal issues with a person's fans harassing someone. There might be legal issues for those specific fans, but the celebrity isn't on the hook. The only way there could be legal repercussions is if the celebrity is being defamatory or actively encouraging harassment.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
