<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755317085.0" user="JayStarr1082" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week. 

I totally agree with this, and I take it you don't, so let me talk about why and how what you said was racist even if you meant no ill will.

Hate crimes happen. You and I have no real control over what individuals decide to do because of racist beliefs they hold. That much is true. But when people make statements like the one above, they're not talking about individual hate crimes - they're talking about patterns.

We have seen patterns of acts of domestic terrorism, committed by white people, against minorities, treated much different in the eyes of the law than if other ethnic groups committed them. Go back just one century, it was the KKK - an organized group of murderers and racists - not even being labeled as a terrorist organization by the US government. One of the most notoriously racist terrorist organizations in American history. And yet, the Black Panthers were swiftly dealt with by that same government. That's the problem we're addressing. One klansman lynching one black teenager is not something you should feel guilty about. A pattern of klansmen getting away with lynch mobs for decades because of an American culture that gives them a pass? Yeah you should feel guilty about that, because that's *your* people, and not only do y'all collectively enable it, a lot of you refuse to acknowledge there's even a problem.

So fast forward to today. It's not klansmen out and about, public and proud like in the era of the civil rights movement. But it is still domestic terrorists, with racist intentions, routinely getting off easier and treated gentler by American culture. A Muslim kills innocents, America blames Islam/the Middle East. But let a white man do the same thing, he's just a "lone wolf" with mental health issues. That double standard is the problem.

And so it *is* racist for you to make yourself the victim of the situation. Because terrorism is treated different in the eyes of the law and the media depending on the race of the terrorist. As white Americans, that's your responsibility to fix, because it's a problem you created. If you don't want to fix it, or even acknowledge it, that's also fine. Shit, I should probably be volunteering at a homeless shelter right now instead of arguing on Reddit. But you don't get to absolve yourself of guilt. Can't eat your cake and have it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755458836.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>So it's kind of funny. I agree with 90% of what you're saying I actually *do* feel guilty about the criminal justice system and how it treats black people differently because I *do* have some control over that and therefore bear some responsibility.

My point was highly specific to the acts of a single individual and how they reflect on people who share their immutable characteristics. If you can somehow tie that in and demonstrate how I am in some way responsible for the Buffalo shooter's actions I'll give you a delta even if I don't necessarily fully agree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755722963.0" user="JayStarr1082" delta="False">
    <text>Sure.

I think you're responsible for the Buffalo shooters actions, yeah, just in an indirect way. White American culture is very tolerant towards acts of racism if it's committed by a white person. And I don't just mean in the court of law, I mean in the court of public opinion. Y'all, collectively, have set the groundwork for political extremism. The specific ways you have set that groundwork is a question a sociologist is better equipped to answer than I am, I can't be an expert on everything - but in short, white American culture resists progress because it makes them feel like the bad guy.

They'd much prefer to turn discussions towards progress into debates about why minority's problems are their own fault. News outlets and political parties have fed this idea that discussions on race relations are basically a game, a source of entertainment where you pick a side and defend it ardently. Should we address police brutality against black people? What if, instead, we countered it with talking about "black on black crime"? That shifts the blame back on them, and if they argue against it, we can broadcast the discussion and profit off of the brewing resentment between the two races.

Everywhere ethnic minorities turn to air their grievances, it turns into an us-vs-them debate, where instead of white people understanding they're in a place of privilege and working on a solution to use that privilege to help, they find a counterargument that absolves them of responsibility. This strategy isn't always intentional, but it is always the more comfortable thing to believe, and it happens almost all the time. And it is absolutely your fault, as individuals and as a culture, for refusing to engage with ethnic minorities in an honest way and take accountability for the problems you have created. Because now, in addition to all of that, you've empowered extremists to think of ethnic minorities as enemies who only exist to pester them for handouts. You've fed the (probably already existing) idea that white people are the "real" victims. And when they go out killing innocents you take yourself out of the picture once again to say it's all the other white peoples' fault and not yours.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756225040.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>This is all interesting but I very much already feel like the bad guy for being a beneficiary of systemic racism (among other forms of discrimination).

I am the bad guy in a very general and broad sense (as are all white people). I feel you have made that point well but I already agree.

Why am I the bad guy as it pertains to the Buffalo shooter though?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39756268498.0" user="JayStarr1082" delta="True">
    <text>I just explained it, in depth. You feed an us-vs-them narrative that directly contributes to radical groups feeling victimized. This pushes them down the path of political extremism and leads to racially-motivated terrorism. If white American culture wasn't so hostile towards ethnic minorities these terrorist attacks against said minorities wouldn't happen - or at least would happen significantly less frequently.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
