<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1886140735.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v6yji7/cmv_public_sector_unions_should_be_abolished/">
    <title>CMV: Public sector unions should be abolished.</title>
    <original_poster>Full-Initiative3926</original_poster>
    <original_post>Despite the support that unions enjoy on Reddit, they are just as corrupt as the corporations they negotiate against. Power corrupts whether that power is in the hands of a CEO commanding a million dollar company or in a union president commanding millions in union dues. Unions are often a necessary evil, not necessarily a force for good. 

For example, Jimmy Hoffa was one of the most corrupt union leaders of all time. It was his explicit goal to bring all logistics workers into the Teamsters Union so he could control the shipping of all goods within the U.S. and charge monopoly rates. This had the secondary effect of raising wages, but really his goal was to increase union dues so he could invest those dues into Las Vegas casinos run by his connections in organized crime. 

Jimmy Hoffa was a bad man, but the damage he could do was ultimately limited because if the organizations his union members worked for went out of business, his party would be over as well. This is where the dangers of public sector unions become apparent. 

Public unions, like police unions and teacher unions, have the same ability to hold their organizations hostage, but because the public sector cannot “go out of business” the damage they can do to their organizations and the tax payer is unlimited. 

Furthermore, unlike private sector unions where workers are unlikely to have any stock or say in governance, all public sector union members are able to vote in the elections governing their organizations like any other citizen. 

Public sector unions should be abolished. Union leaders are susceptible to corruption. Public sector union power is not checked by bankruptcy. Public union members have a governing stake in their organizations so unions are much less necessary.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39877321715.0" user="blackflag415" delta="False">
    <text>Because a guy was corrupt 70 years ago I shouldn't have a union that protects my safety in the workplace? How does that make sense? Jimmy Hoffa died before I was even born bro.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877336376.0" user="Full-Initiative3926" delta="False">
    <text>Jimmy Hoffa is just a famous example to illustrate the point that unions are as self interested as corporations. 

OSHA protects your safety in the work place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39877407904.0" user="Moccus" delta="True">
    <text>OSHA doesn't always cover state and local government employees.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
