<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1888677829.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/v8gx51/cmv_its_stupid_to_care_about_the_environment_in/">
    <title>CMV: It's stupid to care about the environment in space.</title>
    <original_poster>MostRecommendation84</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm a big proponent of space colonization/exploitation and every time I bring it up there's someone who says something along the lines of "Oh we're gonna trash the Moon like we did Earth?" "Oh good more mining!" "Humanity won't rest until we've exploited everything we can!" and other snide comments to that effect. 

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Honestly, it just sounds like the dumbest argument to me and I wouldn't even be bothering with a CMV if I hadn't heard it so many times. *It's rocks. Uninhabitable barren rocks floating through vast chunks of literally* ***nothing****.* There's no space squirrels to worry about, we haven't found any aliens and we really have no reason to assume any are out there, let alone that they give a shit what we do to Mercury. Furthermore, you want to stop desertification or the human rights violations of cobalt mining, you're gonna be hard pressed to find a better solution than the absurd volumes of water and cobalt from here to the asteroid belt.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39891752617.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891864760.0" user="MostRecommendation84" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Interplanetary contamination is also a valid concern.   These barren planets could accidentally be seeded with life by us.  That may sound cool and harmless but the microscopic organisms that can survive in these areas are going to take radically different evolutionary paths from then on.  Remember unlike more complex lifeforms they can evolve rapidly.    We have even observed this on Earth in a lab.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;https://www.newscientist.com/article/dn14094-bacteria-make-major-evolutionary-shift-in-the-lab/  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;There is a real risk that by not being careful when going onto other planets we may accidentally aid in the creation of a microscopic lifeform that could be massively deadly to us and/or other forms of life.     It's not really farfetched to say that humanity could accidentally create galaxywide plagues one day  some of which may even be risks to our very species survival.

I was not aware of this concern, however what specifically makes interplanetary contamination any more of a concern than when say we find sealed pockets underground full of life that hasn't interacted with the outside world since well before humanity existed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39891947886.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
