<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1974133363.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/wncj1v/cmv_westerners_should_be_deeply_worried_by_our/">
    <title>CMV: Westerners should be deeply worried by our nations' inefficiency when building infrastructure</title>
    <original_poster>Real_Carl_Ramirez</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently watching this video: [The £100BN Railway Dividing a Nation](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSD5ps9bLQ0) (it is about extreme delays and cost blowouts with the UK's HSR2 project). Similarly in the USA, the [California High-Speed Rail](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_High-Speed_Rail) also has extreme delays and cost blowouts.

It reminds me of what I've seen here in Australia:

* In Sydney, the [CBD and South East Light Rail](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CBD_and_South_East_Light_Rail) was [delayed by over a year](https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-8102513/Sydneys-light-rail-faces-delay-troubled-project-set-held-back.html) and had [a 1.2 billion AUD cost blowout](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-04-07/light-rail-contractor-sues-nsw-government/9629948).
* In Adelaide, the mere electrification of the [Gawler railway line](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gawler_railway_line) [cost 900 million AUD and was delayed by almost 2 years](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-04-02/free-substitute-buses-for-adelaides-gawler-train-line/100961484).
* Nationwide, the [NBN](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Broadband_Network) had a cost blowout, costing [51 billion AUD](https://archive.ph/jL764) instead of the [original forecast of 29.5 billion AUD](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-06-13/federal-election-nbn-promises-past-and-present/7506714). Keep in mind that this is the cheaper, slower version of the NBN instead of the original version, and thus [Australia ranks #56 in internet speeds](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_Internet_connection_speeds), behind even highly-censored nations like Russia, Saudi Arabia and the PRC.

Before you tell me "*that's because your country is corrupt*", that doesn't make it any less worrying. If western nations constantly face cost blowouts and delays with infrastructure projects, how can we possibly have hope that we can enjoy fast internet in the future? Or clear up transport problems? Or build the infrastructure needed for sustainable development? 

There's a reason why more countries support the PRC's [territorial claims](https://thediplomat.com/2016/07/who-supports-china-in-the-south-china-sea-and-why/) and [policies against Uyghurs](https://archive.ph/wip/8QMbX) than oppose them. Namely, it's because the PRC has been able to buy the loyalty of nations because it's well-known for quickly and cost-effectively building infrastructure for them. I don't want to shill for the PRC here, but Western countries' inefficiency when building infrastructure makes it harder for us to buy the loyalty of nations with this trick.

It's not like western nations are inherently incapable of efficiently building infrastructure (which is another reason why this recent trend of extreme delays and cost blowouts should be worrying):

* Australia's Snowy Mountains Scheme cost the equivalent of [6 billion AUD](https://web.archive.org/web/20060919222034/http://www.ministers.dotars.gov.au/ja/pressconf/2004/APC9_2004.htm)
* The USA's lunar landing effort cost the equivalent of [280 billion USD](https://www.planetary.org/space-policy/cost-of-apollo)
* The Channel Tunnel linking the UK to France cost the equivalent of [12 billion GBP](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/travel/destinations/europe/france/articles/channel-tunnel-facts/)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40401255872.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="False">
    <text>You know, if you looked at the Autobahn and said, “Well, I am willing to overlook all the genocide and repression that the maniacs who built this infrastructure also committed, just so we can enjoy this sweet, sweet highway”, I wouldn’t agree with you but at least I can see your point.  
But if looking at China’s disastrous high-speed rail, housing, and urban development makes you say,  “Well, I am willing to overlook all the genocide and repression that the maniacs who built this infrastructure also committed, just so we can enjoy [dangerous, overpriced, over-leveraged trains](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eLCa6Vl7EeQ), [shoddy, unused apartment buildings](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u7TQz52QmH4), [ghost-cities](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wJ8JBTIVUVw), and a [collapsing banking system](https://youtu.be/YBBnQmRcRI4) ”, I would have to think, you don’t really understand what is going on.

China seems a few months away from total financial collapse, brought on mostly by the reckless and ego-driven way it builds infrastructure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40422054628.0" user="Real_Carl_Ramirez" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But if looking at China’s disastrous high-speed rail, housing, and urban development makes you say, “Well, I am willing to overlook all the genocide and repression that the maniacs who built this infrastructure also committed, just so we can enjoy [dangerous, overpriced, over-leveraged trains](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eLCa6Vl7EeQ), [shoddy, unused apartment buildings](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=u7TQz52QmH4), [ghost-cities](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wJ8JBTIVUVw), and a [collapsing banking system](https://youtu.be/YBBnQmRcRI4) ”, I would have to think, you don’t really understand what is going on.

I am not overlooking their atrocities. As I mentioned in the post details, they managed to make many countries support these atrocities, using infrastructure to buy the loyalty of these countries.

&amp;gt;China seems a few months away from total financial collapse, brought on mostly by the reckless and ego-driven way it builds infrastructure.

People have been saying this for years. Yet it doesn't happen. They've had weird economic issues for years and just shrug it off, so why should I be confident that the collapse will happen this time?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40422643007.0" user="substantial-freud" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;As I mentioned in the post details, they managed to make many countries support these atrocities, using infrastructure to buy the loyalty of these countries.

Countries *love* supporting, or at least overlooking, atrocities.  Everyone tut-tutted the crackdown surrounding the Tiananmen Square massacre, when the Chinese killed thousands of college students on live TV.

My question is, do *you* support those atrocities?

&amp;gt;People have been saying this for years.

Yes, the foolishness of China’s economic policies has been evident for a long time.

&amp;gt;why should I be confident that the collapse will happen this time?

I hope you don’t use that reasoning in your own life.  “I have been smoking for years.  Why should I stop?”  “I have been drinking and driving since college.  Never had an accident.” 

In the case of China, the cracks have begun to show:

* China’s second-largest builders, Evergrande Group, has $300 billion in bad loans — that is about 2% of the total tax-revenues of China; nothing about the loans are particular to Evergrande
* Housing prices have dropped 30% this year, which may cause the GDP to drop by 10%.  This is worse than any drop in US GDP during the Great Depression.
* Homeowners have called mortgage strikes in at least 300 cities.  This has forced regional banks into insolvency.  
* After flatly refusing to pay off on deposit insurance, the Chinese government has claimed it will pay off some depositors of insolvent banks.  It is not clear this is enough to prevent collapse of the banking system.
* The government has promised war with Taiwan over the Pelosi visit: either it will deliver, resulting in the utter destruction of the PRC, or it will back off, causing the government to look weak.

Will the PRC survive to see the Year of the Water Rabbit, six months from now?  _Maybe_.

But everything is very, very bad and there is no appetite for reform anywhere in the CCP.  Xi seems to be doubling down on bad policy in every sector. 

The 20th National Congress is coming up later this year.  Xi will probably try to get himself elected “Chairman” or even “Leader”, titles that have not been used since Mao.  If he succeeds, it will likely mean stasis until a *Downfall*-style final collapse of the PRC government; if he fails and is purged, the government may be able to survive, following a period of chaotic reform.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
