<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1974133363.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/wncj1v/cmv_westerners_should_be_deeply_worried_by_our/">
    <title>CMV: Westerners should be deeply worried by our nations' inefficiency when building infrastructure</title>
    <original_poster>Real_Carl_Ramirez</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently watching this video: [The £100BN Railway Dividing a Nation](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FSD5ps9bLQ0) (it is about extreme delays and cost blowouts with the UK's HSR2 project). Similarly in the USA, the [California High-Speed Rail](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/California_High-Speed_Rail) also has extreme delays and cost blowouts.

It reminds me of what I've seen here in Australia:

* In Sydney, the [CBD and South East Light Rail](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CBD_and_South_East_Light_Rail) was [delayed by over a year](https://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-8102513/Sydneys-light-rail-faces-delay-troubled-project-set-held-back.html) and had [a 1.2 billion AUD cost blowout](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2018-04-07/light-rail-contractor-sues-nsw-government/9629948).
* In Adelaide, the mere electrification of the [Gawler railway line](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gawler_railway_line) [cost 900 million AUD and was delayed by almost 2 years](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-04-02/free-substitute-buses-for-adelaides-gawler-train-line/100961484).
* Nationwide, the [NBN](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Broadband_Network) had a cost blowout, costing [51 billion AUD](https://archive.ph/jL764) instead of the [original forecast of 29.5 billion AUD](https://www.abc.net.au/news/2016-06-13/federal-election-nbn-promises-past-and-present/7506714). Keep in mind that this is the cheaper, slower version of the NBN instead of the original version, and thus [Australia ranks #56 in internet speeds](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_countries_by_Internet_connection_speeds), behind even highly-censored nations like Russia, Saudi Arabia and the PRC.

Before you tell me "*that's because your country is corrupt*", that doesn't make it any less worrying. If western nations constantly face cost blowouts and delays with infrastructure projects, how can we possibly have hope that we can enjoy fast internet in the future? Or clear up transport problems? Or build the infrastructure needed for sustainable development? 

There's a reason why more countries support the PRC's [territorial claims](https://thediplomat.com/2016/07/who-supports-china-in-the-south-china-sea-and-why/) and [policies against Uyghurs](https://archive.ph/wip/8QMbX) than oppose them. Namely, it's because the PRC has been able to buy the loyalty of nations because it's well-known for quickly and cost-effectively building infrastructure for them. I don't want to shill for the PRC here, but Western countries' inefficiency when building infrastructure makes it harder for us to buy the loyalty of nations with this trick.

It's not like western nations are inherently incapable of efficiently building infrastructure (which is another reason why this recent trend of extreme delays and cost blowouts should be worrying):

* Australia's Snowy Mountains Scheme cost the equivalent of [6 billion AUD](https://web.archive.org/web/20060919222034/http://www.ministers.dotars.gov.au/ja/pressconf/2004/APC9_2004.htm)
* The USA's lunar landing effort cost the equivalent of [280 billion USD](https://www.planetary.org/space-policy/cost-of-apollo)
* The Channel Tunnel linking the UK to France cost the equivalent of [12 billion GBP](https://www.telegraph.co.uk/travel/destinations/europe/france/articles/channel-tunnel-facts/)</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40398549175.0" user="barbodelli" delta="False">
    <text>I mean if we had an army of disposable people willing to work for $2 an hour. We'd likely be just as efficient. But we have to deal with these pesky things called safety regulations and worker rights. 

It's not really that much of a concern. If those projects were critical to our survival. We'd get it done with flying colors. We just don't really put that much emphasis on that stuff. 

Also... it's government what do you expect. If you wanted this stuff done right you'd let a few private companies compete on the project.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40398568963.0" user="Real_Carl_Ramirez" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I mean if we had an army of disposable people willing to work for $2 an hour. We'd likely be just as efficient. But we have to deal with these pesky things called safety regulations and worker rights.

I am strongly in support of safety regulations and worker rights. But if our inefficiency in building infrastructure is solely due to safety regulations and worker rights, that's very unfortunate. It would discredit the very concept of safety regulations and worker rights, not to mention give credence to the politicians who oppose these.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40400102635.0" user="Skyy-High" delta="False">
    <text>…what?

No, no it wouldn’t. We know in our own country how often people were maimed or killed before those safety regulations, and none of the news coming out of China indicates that skirting those safety standards can be done without similarly tragic results. 

Why, god why, wouldn’t you look at that information and come to the conclusion that keeping people safe and well-paid simply costs more than not doing that? Why would you think it would be better to live in a society with substandard infrastructure built quickly and at a large health cost, rather than in a society with quality infrastructure built more slowly and with respect for workers’ rights?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40421920121.0" user="Real_Carl_Ramirez" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why, god why, wouldn’t you look at that information and come to the conclusion that keeping people safe and well-paid simply costs more than not doing that? Why would you think it would be better to live in a society with substandard infrastructure built quickly and at a large health cost, rather than in a society with quality infrastructure built more slowly and with respect for workers’ rights?

In Australia, our major right wing party likes finding opportunities to erode workers' rights. Whether it be through finding scandals involving trade unions, or blaming left wing policies for making Australia uncompetitive for manufacturing.

I don't want the concept of workers' rights to be tarnished by association with inefficient construction. If we could construct efficiently, there'd be less opportunity to tarnish the concept of workers' rights.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40422141920.0" user="Skyy-High" delta="True">
    <text>Don’t let perfect be the enemy of good, and don’t believe conservatives when they wring their hands and say they’d agree with you if only XYZ. 

The goalposts will always move. 

You should know from doing any type of home improvement work yourself that doing things correctly, safely, with the right materials, etc will always take longer and be more expensive than doing things fast, cheap, and dangerous. It’s a fundamental property of doing any kind of physical labor. Protecting human beings should **always** be a higher priority than maximizing profits that mostly go to the richest slice of society, otherwise you’re literally allowing them to profit off of the sacrificed health of workers. 

We’ve had that society before, it led to untold suffering and exploitation. All of our labor laws grew out of decades of activism spurred by that suffering. What do you think the men and women who manned those picket lines would say to you, when you claim that you just want to give up those rights for the hope that conservatives will…stop trying to tarnish the concept of workers’ rights?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
