<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1986453802.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/wuolka/cmv_cereals_before_milk/">
    <title>CMV: Cereals before milk</title>
    <original_poster>Big_Committee_3894</original_poster>
    <original_post>It is my opinion that cereals take precedence over milk. I justify this with the fact that in this order, the benefit of correctly measuring the amount of cereal desired is obtained, since otherwise, placing the cereals after the milk, they do not sink and therefore overflow out of the bowl, requiring the help of a spoon to lower the cereals in order to place more on top of them. 
"When you put the cereal first, and you measure the amount of milk wrong, you will have to add more cereal, so you will contradict yourself since you argued to use the cereal first so you don't have to put it more than once" This happens, but only if you measure the quantities wrong 
"But putting the milk on top of the cereals can spill it out making a mess" Only if you are clumsy and you squirt all the milk at once as if it were a torrent. You should be careful to pour it slowly enough so that it doesn't splash out as you pour it over the cereal 
"Yes, but if you add the milk after the cereal, you won't be able to eat all of them crispy yet as the heat of the milk will soften the cereal the longer it is immersed, the cereals on top will be crispy and the ones below will be crunchy more quickly" A valid point, but in this case you must regulate the temperature of the milk. If it boils, it quickly softens the cereal, but if it is lukewarm you can enjoy the pleasure of all the cereal from start to finish being crispy. I personally am not in the habit of drinking hot milk, so all my cereal is crispy and crispy as it should be.
"But I heat the milk in the microwave already in the bowl" What's the problem? Can't it be poured into the cereal bowl? 
"I say Milk with Cereals and not Cereals with Milk, the same way I say Chocolate Milk and Milk of This and Milk of That" Phonetic precedence is not a valid argument? 
"Phonetic precedence makes sense because it means you live in a culture where milk is mostly put first" It's not because something is cultural that it's intrinsically correct.
"Milk has historical precedence over cereal so it must be honored by the primacy of milk in the bowl" And then must the republic also honor the monarchy because it has historical precedence? History is human evolution and evolution implies improvement, so the more in the past we go back worse is the human condition, cereals came like this in the context of historical evolution in improvement of the human condition complemented by milk. 
"Milk is nobler than cereal because it is the first food that we humans, and also mammals animals, take when they are puerile and that makes us grow virile" In fact, milk is fundamental in life almost as much as water, for be the infant's primary source of nutrients, but are you an infant or already a manly man? A man, therefore, why do you treat milk as if you were still a child?

Just my opinion but feel free to change my mind</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40470710817.0" user="Queifjay" delta="False">
    <text>I have come up with the one exception that disproves your rule. While cereal before milk is the ideal order of things when all is right in the universe, consider an instance in which you are dangerously low on milk! In any breakfast scenerio the delight of cereal is hopelessly dependent on the accompaniment of milk. Have you ever poured a full bowl of cereal only to discover that the milk reserves are running bone dry? A splash of milk simply won't make for a satisfying bowl. You may have some cereal and milk at the bottom but soon enough you are left with a dry and almost inedible mound of grains. In these extreme instances it would make more sense to pour your limited supply of milk first. This way you can more accurately gauge the amount of cereal that can be added to the bowl of said milk while achieving an acceptable cereal/milk balance for your dining pleasure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470752929.0" user="Big_Committee_3894" delta="False">
    <text>That is defently a good instance 🤔
But could we not, having limited amounts of milk, reduce the proporcion of cereals as to make them even? Has one would say in my country "Ter fome consoante a fartura" having hunger in proportion to the available food</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40470827069.0" user="Queifjay" delta="False">
    <text>You can certainly try to estimate the amount of cereal you think could adequately handle your rough estimation of available milk in your minds eye...but once you pour all of your milk out, there ceases to be milk. Since milk is the limiting factor here, you are better off putting it in first to see exactly what you are working with. Then you are free to adjust your cereal levels accordingly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40471062876.0" user="Big_Committee_3894" delta="False">
    <text>Indeed, but what if one resorts to measuring equipament to know the correct amount? Tho its more onereous</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40471217454.0" user="Queifjay" delta="True">
    <text>In my specifically laid out scenerio, I will always point back to milk being the limiting factor. You can always add more cereal but when the milk is gone it is gone. Under your method, simple human error inevitably leads you to an excess of dry cereal waste. Surely you would agree that milk first is the more efficient method in this one instance?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
