<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="199744342.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3ax7py/cmv_giving_other_cultures_sht_about_eating_dog/">
    <title>CMV: Giving other cultures sh*t about eating dog meat is hypocritical</title>
    <original_poster>simobk</original_poster>
    <original_post>Hi all,

So someone just posted a video on my FB feed about [the Yulin dog meat festival](https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=yulin+dog+meat+festival). It is horrifying...

For the purpose of this CMV, let's forget about how it's done (the way they get the dogs, they treat them... etc.) and concentrate **only** on the dog meat eating part.

I love dogs, and yes, I find it horrifying that other cultures eat them. However, I also understand that for other cultures, it is horrifying to see us eat beef or pork.

In my opinion, the only situation where you are allowed to complain is if you are talking about eating animal meat in general. But if you enjoy eating a good steak, then it is hypocritical to criticize others for eating what they consider is "just meat".

Again, I am stressing the fact that this is not about the *animal cruelty* part. It's just about the meat eating. For the sake of this CMV, let's suppose that the animals are bred and slaughtered in the most humane possible way.

So... CMV

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27842694537.0" user="Vegandalf_the_Grey" delta="False">
    <text>It's interesting that the animals people tend to get selectively upset about being used for meat are often also meat-eaters.

Eating predators/carnivores means that you have to not only produce the herbivores to feed them, you also have to produce the plants to feed the herbivores.

Unless there's some compelling argument _for_ eating dog over, say, cow, the fact that significantly greater resources are required Calorie-for-Calorie, pound-for-pound, to produce this type of food is a reasonable argument for saying that it's excessively wasteful even with no moral or ethical objection to the food itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842698889.0" user="simobk" delta="False">
    <text>First thing that I read that I actually kinda agree with. However, we also eat hunting game which sometimes is carnivore...

And generally speaking, I was going more into the "ethical" direction with this thread...  :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842707373.0" user="Vegandalf_the_Grey" delta="False">
    <text>Resource management and ecological impact is an "ethical direction", just perhaps not the one you expected.

I'm sure there are ways you could produce (dog) meat in a (more) resource efficient manner, but then you're probably going to run into violating your conditionals about the food being produced in the most humane and cruelty-free manner possible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842757188.0" user="PedanticContrarian" delta="False">
    <text>Also, predation requires more intelligence than grazing does.  Wolves plan attacks and use group tactics, which suggests a level of consciousness that cows don't seem to have.  If capacity for suffering increases as this sort of intelligence increases, which sounds reasonable to me, wolves would therefore be capable of experiencing more suffering than cows.

I think we tend to anthropomorphize carnivores more readily than we do herbivores, which relates to this idea about intelligence and also your observation about which animals we get upset over.  Is our culture just more ethical than Chinese culture on this issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27842818277.0" user="Vegandalf_the_Grey" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Is our culture just more ethical than Chinese culture on this issue?

They presumably operate according to different cultural rules, but that doesn't mean they obey them any less.... in which case I'd assume both would be similarly ethical (though what specifically constituted "ethical" might differ considerably between cultures, of course, due to the differences in the rules being followed).

In a culture where it's commonplace for people to have pets, they probably anthropomorphise them more and ascribe human motivation, emotions, and intelligence to their animal behaviours.   In cultures where this is less common, they're just animals like any other.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
