<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2030191996.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xkq264/cmv_its_fair_to_compare_carnists_people_who_eat/">
    <title>CMV: It's fair to compare carnists (people who eat meat) to nazis.</title>
    <original_poster>Arkenhiem651</original_poster>
    <original_post>1) Carnists think that animals are inferior; Nazis think that jews are inferior
2) Carnists put animals in camps; Nazis put jews in camps
3) Both jews and animals attempt to escape
4) Both are/were normalized. Anyone who goes against these beliefs were/are suppressed and treated as illogical/emotionally driven
5) Both are unnecessary 
6) Both are/were driven long distances and murdered
7) emotional detachment from the victims
8) Both are sentient
Alex Hershaft a holocaust survivor also used this comparison along with other vegan holocaust survivors.
"We're focusing on the victims rather than the cancer of oppression itself",[8] and that "I noted with horror the striking similarities between what the Nazis did to my family and my people, and what we do to animals we raise for food: the branding or tattooing of serial numbers to identify victims, the use of cattle cars to transport victims to their death, the crowded housing of victims in wood crates, the arbitrary designation of who lives and who dies — the Christian lives, the Jew dies; the dog lives, the pig dies."[6

Also Alex Hershshaft looks extremely young considering he's 88 and survived concentration camps. That's irrelevant but I thought it interesting enough to mention considering he claims it's due to his vegan diet.

Edit: I know I say Jews but this also applies to other victims of the concentration camps such as Slavic peoples, gays and communists</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40719510351.0" user="mankindmatt5" delta="False">
    <text>If people who eat meat are Nazis, does that mean vegetarians are anti-Nazis?

They are in effect, direct opposites.

Therefore, Hitler, who famously *was* a vegetarian, was not in fact, a Nazi?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719597248.0" user="BlackHoleHalibut" delta="False">
    <text>“If P then Q” does not give logical support to “If it’s not the case that P, then it is not the case that Q”. 

Consider:

Your argument:

“If a person eats meat, then they are a Nazi. Therefore, if a person doesn’t eat meat, then they must not be a Nazi.”

A different argument with the same form:

“If it is raining, then I brought my umbrella. Therefore, if it isn’t raining, then I must not have brought my umbrella.”

Since it is possible for the premise to be true and the conclusion to be false, the argument is invalid. And since it is invalid, it is unsound.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719834239.0" user="mankindmatt5" delta="False">
    <text>You're right in the umbrella example.

But sometimes an argument formulated like that can work, if the two things are direct opposites.

If a person is a member of a Neo Nazi gang, they're a Nazi.

If a person is a member of (progressive anti racist party), they're probably not a Nazi.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719840610.0" user="BlackHoleHalibut" delta="False">
    <text>It’s not the content of the argument that is problematic, it’s the form. The argument will be invalid regardless of what propositions you plug into it. [That’s what the umbrella example was meant to illustrate.]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719865539.0" user="mankindmatt5" delta="False">
    <text>But sometimes that argument can reach a true conclusion.

If someone is a child, they are not legally allowed to buy alcohol.

Therefore, if someone legally buys alcohol they're not a child.

That argument makes sense. Therefore, in some circumstances it is a rational argument. It depends what it's plugged into the formula.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40719897643.0" user="BlackHoleHalibut" delta="True">
    <text>You have changed the form from:

‘If P then Q, therefore if not P then not Q’

To: 

‘If P then not Q, therefore if Q then not P’

These are not logically equivalent formulations.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
