<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40828627247.0" user="GuRoux_" delta="False">
    <text>The way they act may be the same, but the way they think and experience could very well be different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40828659501.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Couldn’t that be said of all individual humans as well?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40828875316.0" user="GuRoux_" delta="False">
    <text>There's a lot of reason to believe than the human experience is similar.  We have the same hardware, and our software is integrated with out hardware.  Computers are very much different in both hardware and software.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40829330533.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>I see. You mean that the manner in which thought is conducted is similar across humans, if I’m understanding you correctly now. Would that process be so different from an AI’s? Don’t humans respond to the data that is available at any given moment to plot our next moment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40829436966.0" user="GuRoux_" delta="True">
    <text>I agree, humans do take in data, process it, and then act.  Your op wants indistinguishable  ai.  So the actions are by definition the same. How we take in data, that is another difference, if that counts for you because computers will be taking in different data and with much different sensors than humans.  How we process data is definitely different if we are dealing with different input data.  How we think and how we experience should be different than computers given our significant differences.  For example, we experience senses like sight and hearing in two different ways.  Why would a computer experience them like us? Perhaps they see in the way we would call hearing.  Perhaps they experience all senses with sight.  Perhaps they sense in some totally different way we have no intuition for.  Maybe the programmer can control how the ai experiences different things.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
