<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2050475588.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/xwst38/cmv_the_only_difference_between_ai_digital_life/">
    <title>CMV: The only difference between AI (digital) life and human (physical) life is the material which sustains it</title>
    <original_poster>CarpeBedlam</original_poster>
    <original_post>To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal. Also, I don’t necessarily mean an android that is physically equivalent (e.g. Ash from “Alien”), but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior. At that point, I’m struggling to find a difference between the two that isn’t solely about the material required to sustain the life (blood, tissue, etc. for human life, silicon, copper, etc. for AI life).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40828774650.0" user="poprostumort" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;To be clear, I’m talking about a theoretical AI which is designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human, and accomplishes that goal.

So you are creating an hypothetical AI that handwaves any inherent differences between humans and machines that aren't "material that sustains it" and tell us to change your view that there aren't any differences besides "material that sustains it"?

&amp;gt;but just a digital consciousness living in a computer which is capable of replicating human behavior

If it's only a digital consciousness it will not be capable of replicating human behavior. Much of our behavior is directly related to how our bodies work - so an AI will at best replicate the same approximation of human behavior, without inherent variations in how humans are affected by stimuli.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40829567794.0" user="CarpeBedlam" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm… that’s not quite what I mean to propose. I’ve been thinking about what specifically is wholly human and cannot possibly be replicated digitally. I feel sure that there is something more than just blood, tissue, etc. I just haven’t been able to put my finger on anything that would have no digital corollary. So I guess the “view” I’m putting forth is that there’s no reason to think that AI would not be able to replicate human behavior, so consciousness must have physical limitations.

You make an interesting point. That, for example, a digital consciousness couldn’t react to being cold, or dizzy, or hungry. So in order for an AI’s behavior to be indistinguishable from a human’s, it would have to lie. I suppose that leads me to wonder, what if it’s programmed and built to have awareness of the physical components that sustain its life (temperatures, power consumption, etc)? It could then react to stimuli the same as a human would. It would still have to lie about certain things if it was trying to convince someone that it was human, but I think there’s no shortage of examples of humans lying to convince other humans of untruths.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40830987009.0" user="poprostumort" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I’ve been thinking about what specifically is wholly human and cannot possibly be replicated digitally.

Issue is that in theory you can replicate everything, but in reality you would need to know:

\- how exactly human brain works  
\- how exactly it reacts to any stimuli  
\- how emotions are generated and how do they work  
\- how memory works 

So long story short, the whole problem is in whet you handwaved by "designed specifically to be indistinguishable from a human" because it would need a computing power and level of understanding that is currently unfathomable.

And the answer to "what specifically is wholly human and cannot possibly be replicated digitally" cannot be answered without knowing how exactly humans work.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
