<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971170757.0" user="boblobong" delta="False">
    <text>Can you define the floor and ceiling in this context for promiscuity and monogamy?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971293309.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Floor is the worst situation you can have, ceiling is the best situation you can have. 

Floor of monogamy is having a bad relationship, ceiling of monogamy is having a good relationship. Floor of promiscuity is having nothing, ceiling I guess is having a lot of partners. 

I'm not as sure about ceilings as I am about floors</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972850858.0" user="Mafinde" delta="True">
    <text>I’m extremely glad you’re using floor and ceiling correctly, I almost always see it used incorrectly. I’ve even thought about posting a CMV about it but I know I’m correct. 

More seriously, I think you should re-evaluate the ceiling of a monogamous relationship. The ceiling is a life changing partner. Someone who will do everything for you, even at their own expense. Someone who will be there until your last breath. Someone who will literally die for you. Thinking about it strictly analytically and without any sappy emotion - that is an extremely powerful asset to have. 

Really the only other way to get that is immediate family, but if your brothers and sisters find partners like this, then they will be this person for their partner, not you. And you’re likely to outlive your parents. So without a monogamous dedicated relationship, you likely out of luck. 

You might disagree and say you can find such a person, but apply this simple test as a shorthand proxy for closeness - how many people share finances with a non-spouse? Or if you were hospitalized, how many non-spouses would spend literally every night in the hospital room with you? There are many ways to frame this point, but a monogamous partner can (remember we are talking ceiling here) can be a special, unique, and life changing thing</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
