<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="208058488.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3fveyg/cmv_i_dont_like_tipping/">
    <title>CMV: I don't like tipping.</title>
    <original_poster>litle5o</original_poster>
    <original_post>Leaving a tip feels so customary in certain places that it's become an incentive to do your job properly. I understand that it's the service that they provide and not just the food, but isn't that exactly what they're paid for? To give a paying customer a good service? Although I sympathize with their outrageously low wages, but why should I have to fork out more of my money that I'm already spending at a restaurant to subsidize young Jenny here, to get her up to normal living wage? Isn't that a governmental issue of poverty/low wages?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27922389247.0" user="man2010" delta="False">
    <text>They are working for their wages, the only difference is that in some industries those wages come straight from the customer instead of the customer's money going to the business owner and then back to the employees. Tipping essentially cuts out the middle man, and allows you to directly pay the person providing you with a service instead of giving your money to the business, having the business take its cut, and then giving some of that money back to the employees. 

As for why you should have to, well, technically you don't (unless the restaurant/business includes a tip as a part of your bill). If tipping was eliminated then you would probably see an increase in the price of tipped services to make up for the increased wages of servers. In other words, your $10 cheeseburger might go up to $12 to make up for the 20% tip that people don't leave anymore. So instead of paying $10 with a $2 tip for that cheeseburger, you're paying $12 with no tip so the restaurant can pay its servers more than $3/hr. On top of that, the servers don't have as much of an incentive to provide top notch service since they'll be making the same amount regardless. You're drinks might take longer to get refilled, or your food might take longer to be brought to you. You're still paying the same amount, but now you're getting worse service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922441618.0" user="litle5o" delta="False">
    <text>I understand that it cuts out the middle man and gives directly to the employee and in theory that's great. I guess what I fail to understand is why the establishment is not in someway forced to provide a suitable living wage to the employee. Would you say that the increase of the food price be from the restaurant trying to make ends meet, or out of maximisation of profit? 

In regards to the incentive: this is what frustrates me, there shouldn't have to be an incentive of 'extra money' in my opinion. You are paid to provide a service already and that's your wage. If the wage isn't suitable, then perhaps a call for change is in order? On top of that, if you're doing a shitty job 'cause you know you're going to get paid at the end of the day is surely bad service, and should be fired? 

Why isn't the system changed to meet the requirements and produce a solid pay, rather than the wait staff depending on money to determine their wage? 

I hope my naivety doesn't come across conservative.

Note: I'm from the UK where tipping isn't customary. Most UK restaurants are either large chains or independents that are thriving IMO.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27922510893.0" user="FanoTheNoob" delta="True">
    <text>What you are arguing for makes complete sense and should be the way things are, the way I see it, restaurants do this because they are wanting to maximize profits and use the tipped wage to force the customers to hand over the extra cash so they can spend less on payroll.

I would say most servers are happy with this, however. Due to the still-pretty-low minimum wage in the U.S., most servers you come across will actually be opposed to abolishing tipped wages. Even with the criminally low tipped wage of $2.13/hr, a server's tips will, on average, still be much, much higher than the federal minimum wage of $7.25/hr

Servers will be more than happy to take the $2/hr wage because it will actually average out to something more like $15-$20 an hour thanks to the tipping culture that has been established here.

If the federal minimum wage was a livable wage and tipping wages were abolished, I'd say there would be a good chance of eventually moving away from tipping culture.


Until this is the case, however, all you're doing by not tipping at least 10% is taking away the wages of the server who is taking care of you, as income taxes and such often take away 100% of the hourly wage of these employees, if you spend an hour in a restaurant and don't leave a tip, chances are the server had to pay out of his own pocket in order to provide you their service, and that's a pretty shitty feeling.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
