<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="209151241.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3giu4p/cmv_i_have_no_sympathy_towards_violent_criminals/">
    <title>CMV: I have no sympathy towards violent criminals at the point of crime</title>
    <original_poster>feartrich</original_poster>
    <original_post>I can never understand people when they lament about how they feel sorry for someone who just commited a violent crime.

I understand being sympathetic towards a non-violent thief who might be destitute, or a murderer who has done his time and apologized.

But someone who has just done a horrible act of violence towards another person (and hasn't repented yet) doesn't deserve sympathy from anyone, unless they genuinely believe he/she is innocent, or committed the crime in self-defense.

One argument people make is that the guilty crime was committed "in the heat of moment". I see this often being used to defend road ragers and drunk wife-beaters. I can't agree with this argument because it unfairly takes responsibility away from the criminal. If we left every criminal go easy because the crimes were "emotional" or "spur of the moment", we'd have a lot of unstable people out on the streets ready go to off at any moment and hurt others.

Another argument I hear is that the criminal was a "victim of the circumstances", i.e. he was poor or grew up in a dysfunctional family. This is a totally reasonable argument if the crime is non-violent, but being poor or traumatized is not an excuse to kill somebody or even go beat someone up. Anyone who makes a conscious choice to hurt someone physically is simply an asshole.

I oppose the death penalty and am in favor of restorative prison reform, so I hear people giving these criminals moral slack (at more than just a legal or health-based level) all the time, and it drives me crazy. But I want to see the POV they are coming from, so please try to CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27932891167.0" user="elvish_visionary" delta="False">
    <text>What if someone commits a crime out of pure emotion, such as killing someone who previously killed their loved one? It's not ok to take justice into your own hands like that of course, but would you not still have some sympathy toward that person?

Have you heard of the book A Time to Kill by John Grisham?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932903651.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>The way I see it, they have blood on their hands. They made a deliberate choice to commit the horrible act, whether conscious or not.

Just as a drunk man is responsible for his choices while intoxicated, so is someone who commits a crime out of "pure emotion".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932920413.0" user="DAL82" delta="False">
    <text>What about a person with a cognitive disability?  Downs or Alzheimer's?  

They made a deliberate choice to commit a horrible act too.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932942000.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>No sympathy for them, because they purposely decided to make their bad choice. If someone has an IQ of 10, and goes around killing people, he should be kept away for everyone else's safety.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932956755.0" user="DAL82" delta="False">
    <text>A person suffering from a mental illness, a cognitive disability, or even a temporary diminished capacity (emotional state, concussion, drunk/drug) isn't in a position to make good decisions.

___________________


Mens rea...  

A person who unintentionally harms someone is different than a person who intentionally harms someone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932964045.0" user="feartrich" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, but why have sympathy for them? If we go down the whole "mental capacity" ladder, would you have sympathy for a bear that rips someone's legs off? Or a tornado that destroys someone's house?

Evil things deserve no respect, whether it's a conscious person, someone who's mentally ill, or simply an Act of God.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27932979967.0" user="DAL82" delta="True">
    <text>Imagine you have early onset Alzheimer's disease.

You're fine 98% of the time.  But you're having more frequent momentary lapses.  They pass, but they're increasingly more jarring as they occur.

You take early retirement and your husband picks up extra shifts to make up for the loss of income and your treatment expenses.

Tomorrow when he comes home you don't recognize him.  You're having a moment, it will pass, he knows you'll be fine shortly.


You, fearing a burglar, push him down the stairs.  You kill your doting husband.

Then the moment passes and you realize what you've done.

__________________


Should I feel sympathy for you?

You fucking killed your husband.  But you didn't do it on purpose.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
