<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2091734653.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/yld4sd/cmv_companies_accepting_climate_change_is_more/">
    <title>CMV: Companies accepting climate change is more dangerous than companies denying climate change.</title>
    <original_poster>4ofclubs</original_poster>
    <original_post>So I obviously believe in climate change, however I'm more in the camp of "It's too late so we need to act more drastically to prepare" than "we need nuclear power and electric cars to save us."

I see a trend lately that every company ever is advertising "Here at xyz we believe that we all need to do our part in climate change, that's why for every $100 spent we'll plant one tree!" and so on.

You can see it in examples of [greenwashing](https://www.offshore-technology.com/analysis/how-greenwashing-ads-can-be-terrible-for-the-environment/) everywhere.

Companies are realizing they can no longer accept that climate change isn't real, otherwise they will lose customers. They accept climate change is real, do the bare minimum by greenwashing their products, or even making actual efforts such as moving to [solar powered](https://www.cnbc.com/2018/05/28/10-massive-corporations-going-big-on-solar-power.html) production plants, [carbon-neutral plans](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S209580992100429X) for countries like China, or even the a bigger consumer buy-in for [electric cars.](https://www.anl.gov/esia/light-duty-electric-drive-vehicles-monthly-sales-updates)

My point is that all this does is tell us that we can continue to grow and expand our economy and live life as is when there is a lot of [evidence](https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2352550921002931) showing that carbon neutrality by 2050 with business as usual methods of growth in capitalism simply won't work. We need to scale down our production and way of living to even hit 2 degrees warming by [2030.](https://www.ipcc.ch/2022/04/04/ipcc-ar6-wgiii-pressrelease/) 

If these companies continued to deny climate change, most people would start to turn on them, and degrowth ideally would naturally follow. Instead, we follow along blindly because the masses have been told that solar panels will save us and we don't need a larger focus on public transit, less consumption of meat, etc.

TLDR: Companies are greenwashing by saying we can live life as is with electric cars, solar panels, and recycling while continuing to grow under a capitalist system, when in reality the only way to reverse climate change is by reducing our intake, staying local with food production, and overall reducing the way the west consumes.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41052876651.0" user="sawdeanz" delta="False">
    <text>You haven’t explained why the alternative is better… If companies deny climate change won’t that only accelerate economic growth and harmful pollution? You imply that denying climate change is better but you don’t say how or why. 

That being said, I do think significant government initiative is also required…. I don’t see a way for the market to become sustainable by itself so long as the effects of climate change remain externalities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41052907494.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>I wrote it at the bottom, but I'll elaborate.  


Companies pretend to care about the environment, so we go along with their promises that using electric cars will save the environment, ignoring the major issues with mass production of batteries, etc.

We have this situation now where governments are not doing anything so we're turning to the companies for help because they appear as a white knight. If the companies were doing nothing and denying climate change, despite a large percentage of the western world accepting climate change is an issue, I would hope that we would push harder for government intervention, or turn our backs on these companies all together.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053657740.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="False">
    <text>So instead of things getting bad enough for us to turn on capitalism in the future, you want things to get bad enough to turn on capitalism now?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053670183.0" user="4ofclubs" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, because the quicker we act the better chances we have of long term survival.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41053832270.0" user="math2ndperiod" delta="True">
    <text>Here’s the thing though, the damage to cause serious ecological consequences is already done. We’re not suffering from the carbon emitted yesterday, but the carbon emitted a decade or more ago. If we switched to 100% nuclear energy tomorrow, things would continue to worsen for a while anyway. So for the next ~10-20 years until things inevitably get bad enough that widespread change has political support, we can either continue to go full steam ahead pumping carbon and bullshit into our oceans and atmosphere, or we can start to gradually transition so that we don’t have to do a complete 180 to have any chance of survival. 

If we tried to overthrow capitalism all at once we’d probably just end up with a civil war or anarchy or a dictatorship. War is not good for the environment, and we need a functioning, prosperous tech industry to continue to pump out technology that will help us adapt to the coming changes.

Basically, the damage is done. We can either start mitigating damage and transition gradually, or we can continue doing maximum damage until we have to completely overthrow society to change anything.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
