<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="217468142.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3lh3hq/cmv_stubhub_and_other_ticket_resale_sites_should/">
    <title>CMV: StubHub and other ticket resale sites should be illegal and considered scalping.</title>
    <original_poster>aikdaman</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the US, 38 states have laws allowing the reselling of event tickets as long as the sale does not take place at the event site. The other 12 states have varying degrees of regulation, including registration requirements and maximum markups.

Why do we allow this middle man corporation to exist as a loophole for scalping and legally marking tickets up to exorbitant amounts.

At the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups. I understand supply and demand but find it ridiculous that often the re-seller makes the most money per ticket involved in a sold out production for doing essentially nothing. Oh the American way...

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28006402020.0" user="loudnoises461" delta="False">
    <text>I use stubhub primarily to get tickets below face value how do you think that should be treated?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006461644.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>This is why I threw in there should at the very least there should be rules and restrictions in place for maximum markups.

If the ticket is under face I have no issues with that. I'm more concerned about people marking tickets up 3X the face value and who live off the income of doing so. Maybe it's a bit more of a morality issue but it seems to bleed into the gray areas of intellectual property when you're making a profit. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006501753.0" user="RustyRook" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Maybe it's a bit more of a morality issue but it seems to bleed into the gray areas of intellectual property when you're making a profit.

Could you explain this further? The only thing that's being traded is entry to a concert. The intellectual property (i.e. songs) belongs to the musicians, which plays no part in a Stubhub transaction.

&amp;gt; I'm more concerned about people marking tickets up 3X the face value and who live off the income of doing so.

This is what a lot of stockbrokers do too. They buy something, wait for it to appreciate, and then sell it. Sometimes it sells for more, sometimes for less - isn't the same true for Stubhub? Given the alternatives (black market, scalping, etc.) more regulation would work better than making these things illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006525938.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really see tickets as an investment opportunity. When you buy a ticket I think it should be to personally experience said performance. That performance includes intellectual property and that intellectual property is why the person who bought the ticket (to attend) is there, not because they paid entry to a venue. What if there was nothing showing in the venue? There would be no ticket sale. 

EDIT: Spelling
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006535665.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; When you buy a ticket I think it should be to personally experience said performance. 

Do you feel the same way about everything? If I buy a pork belly future, should it only be for personal use?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006546176.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>A ticket isn't generally seen as an investment where gold, pork belly, etc all are. 

I only see the problem in it for people directly making money off an artist performance or sports production that you simply own a ticket to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006570172.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; A ticket isn't generally seen as an investment 

If tickets *were* "generally seen as an investment" would your view be different?

Do you think it should only be legal to invest in things that are generally seen as an investment?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006587899.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>"I only see the problem in it for people directly making money off an artist performance or sports production that you simply own a ticket to."

No, I'm not one for making new laws or over-regulating things. I only have this view for ticket re-sales. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006598784.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>I still don't understand why you think reselling tickets is so much different from reselling anything else.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006628221.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>I just think you should provide a real service to make a profit on a ticket. 

The artist provides the entertainment and the venue provides a place to show it. Then some dude provided you a ticket for 3x the costs because Ticketmaster crashed on your computer when you tried to buy them. It just doesn't seem right for an individual to make more per ticket than both the artist or venue because they got lucky on buying tickets or found a presale you didn't. Heck, for all we know the people buying up these tickets could work very closely and be in bed with these companies. There is no regulation.  

I understand investments and collectibles but tickets to a performance fall into a different category for me and it really takes away from the experience seeing individuals and a corporation like StubHub capitalizing on artists for providing such a minimal service. 

EDIT: Spelling</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006706844.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're wrong in assuming that ticket resellers don't provide a "real service." Take a look at [this paper](http://jimmyatkinson.com/papers/the-economics-of-ticket-scalping/), which has some plausible theories about the services that resellers provide.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006793999.0" user="aikdaman" delta="False">
    <text>Thank you, that's a lot of great information regarding this post. It would be interesting to see what his thoughts are currently, 11 years later. StubHub was only 4 years old at the time of this but it does give a nice look into some of the economics of ticket pricing. It seems to agree that tickets are bit of a different animal than a commodity and also mentioned how the system in 2002 was very inefficient. 

I agree with his conclusion that ticket scalping will always exist. He also addresses my fears of insider trading. I think/hope there will ultimately be an improved system for resale.

At the end of the day Person A who bought their ticket from the original sale and Person B who bought it off StubHub watched the same performance but paid very different amounts. 

I'm a brewer in a state with a three tier system so I regularly deal with distributors, bars, and bartenders all making more money off the product I make than myself. Maybe I just have a thing against the middlemen but I think creators are entitled to a bit more of the pie than they are getting in the current system (don't even get me started on the beer black market, ha). 

If I was an artist and my tickets consistently sold for quite a bit over face value on the secondary market I'd be a bit irked that I'm creating a bunch of extra value for someone that has no involvement in my project or performance. 

When you buy a stock or commodity there is really no way to tell if it will go down or up. If you know enough about concerts you know you're going to win on the "investment" every time. If I did this for a living what would your personal views of my morality be?

I just don't see the necessity of a reseller when the show would go on as planned without them. A show with no artist or venue will not. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28006828121.0" user="stoopydumbut" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; It would be interesting to see what his thoughts are currently, 11 years later. 

Look at the last section entitled "A Futures Market for Ticket Resale," which starts:

&amp;gt;Stephen K. Happel and Marianne M. Jennings (2002) have written a journal article that proposes the creation of a nationally organized futures market for major events tickets. The market for ticket resale today is very inefficient and complicated, with the great deal of fragmentation and information asymmetry that exists. Happel and Jennings (2002) actually argue that the fact that a futures market for tickets has not already been organized is a market failure.

StubHub seems to be fulfilling the role of a futures market.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
