<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28072694915.0" user="bayRumble" delta="False">
    <text>All nutrients (every amino acid, lipid, etc.) exhibit drug-like changes on the body when raised or lowered in the diet. All food and nutrients are drugs in a sense. All are harmful in excess and sugar is not unique in this respect.

Sugar does have powerful drug-like effects, and if used responsibly in an appropriate context it has the potential to massively improve health and quality of life.

For example, sugar powerfully reduces stress (by lowering cortisol, and adrenaline levels, and improves energy metabolism by refilling liver glycogen and increasing thyroid hormone production). When taken after intense exercise, it protects against stress related damage to the body and allows muscles to grow and recover at a rate impossible without sugar supplementation.

It's not right for the government to assume that everyone is stupid and irresponsible, and in the process harm the lives of responsible people that benefit from sugar intake.

I am an active person- I do powerlifting, competitive sailing, and work long hours on scientific research. I fuel this with a sugar intake proportional to the demands I place on my body that prevents stress and fatigue. If sugar was restricted and regulated so I couldn't obtain it, I wouldn't be able to function as well in life. I have a very nutritious diet of mostly natural foods and use sugar as a supplement- usually adding it to coffee or milk before and after strenuous activity. I have experimented with a lot of other diets such as low carb paleo, and none allow me to perform as well or feel as good as I do with a high sugar intake.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072776461.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>One argument that was largely uncontested was - considering the addictive values of sugar and other less healthy ingredients in excess, can you trust an addicted person to make a responsible and smart decision? And why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072785746.0" user="bayRumble" delta="False">
    <text>Pure sugar isn't addictive, it's not even very palatable. It's the unnatural flavors in processed food, not the sugar makes it addictive- and those encourage the over-consumption of any nutrients they're coupled with. People get addicted to processed foods that contain no sugar at all- chips, diet sodas, etc. There is a lot of research into the concept of "food reward" that describes this phenomena. These foods are engineered for unnaturally high food reward specifically to encourage over-consumption.

Like I said, I mostly take sugar mixed into milk or coffee and it tastes good at first but I can't stand too much of it. There are many natural foods with high sugar content (fruit, honey) and they're far from addictive, most people can only enjoy them when truly hungry.

Here is an excellent article on food reward, and how neither fat nor sugar are addictive on there own: http://boingboing.net/2012/03/09/seduced-by-food-obesity-and-t.html

&amp;gt; First described in 1976 by Anthony Sclafani, the cafeteria diet is basically a rat-sized buffet of human junk food, in addition to regular rat chow (9). The menu for a recent cafeteria diet study included such delectable items as Froot Loops, mini hot dogs, peanut butter cookies, Cheez-its, Cocoa Puffs, nacho cheese Doritos, cake, and BBQ pork rinds (10). These are what's known in the business as ‘palatable’, or pleasurable to the taste. On this regimen, rats ignored their regular chow, ate junk food to excess and gained fat at an extraordinary rate, far outpacing two comparison groups fed high-fat or high-sugar pelleted diets. Yes, human junk food happens to be the most effective way to overwhelm the body fat homeostasis system in rats, and neither fat nor sugar alone is able to fully explain why it’s so fattening. Importantly, over time, rats become highly motivated to obtain this diet—so motivated they’ll voluntarily endure extreme cold temperatures and electric shocks to obtain it, even when regular bland rodent pellets are freely available 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072797504.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Could you explain what *exactly* is so addictive about those foods? It feels implied. If not sugar... then what?   
What makes them have such an unnatural "food reward" ?  
Regardless of the source of this, my point still stands(and actually might be more valid now) - can you trust an addicted customer to be responsible for his diet and thus shift the market?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072816853.0" user="bayRumble" delta="False">
    <text>Of course addicts don't make good choices, but you would need to ban most processed foods to have the benefit you're looking for, and not target sugar specifically.

I also do not trust governments to make well informed health policies. Politicians and voting populations don't typically understand biology, or nuanced arguments (sugar is more complex than good or bad but depends on context) and are just as likely to force poor decisions onto people that know better than to help addicts.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072821888.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I can understand that argument; as now I get it is a more nuanced problem than I initially thought.  
I'd really like to know what makes processed/unhealthy foods so addictive. Texture/taste sounds *very* vague.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28072831886.0" user="bayRumble" delta="True">
    <text>Read the work of Stephen Guyenet, who wrote the article I linked above. He is a neuroscientist that studies this issue, and has an excellent blog: http://wholehealthsource.blogspot.com

You might also be interested in reading the work of Ray Peat. He is a very controversial medical theorist and endocrinologist that argues about the health benefits of sugar consumption. His writing can be hard to understand and is full of very unusual ideas- most people dismiss him as crazy but he makes some solid points. http://raypeat.com/

You might also be interested in the "Rat Park" comic that explains research suggesting addiction may have more to do with our overall quality of life than exposure to potentially addictive substances: http://imgur.com/gallery/pI8Nm</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
