<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2238937822.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/11107ha/cmv_the_legal_term_mass_shooting_should_be_broken/">
    <title>CMV: The legal term “mass shooting” should be broken into two categories: ‘mass shooting’ and ‘mass shooting spree’. This will allow there to be much more context in regards to such instances of extreme gun violence.</title>
    <original_poster>SouthrenHill</original_poster>
    <original_post>Note: ALL GUN VIOLENCE IS BAD AND JUST BECAUSE A MASS SHOOTING TOOK PLACE AMONGST GANG MEMBERS DOES NOT MAKE IT ACCEPTABLE TO ANY DEGREE. MURDER IS MURDER, AND VIOLENCE IS VIOLENCE - ITS ALL WRONG. That said, I do believe that there is a lot of context missing when these news stories break out, and the people deserve to be in a position where they are not misled - intentionally or unintentionally. 


In the US, the legal definition of “mass shooting” refers to any instance in which three or more people are shot in a short amount of time. On a surface this may make sense to a lot of people. However, I believe that this terminology is too much of a blanket statement. I say this because due to the media perception and the more extreme cases, many people see this term synonymously with a white, teenage male running into a mall or shopping center and letting loose on random people. In reality, the majority of mass shootings (in the US, at last) are often gang related or due personal disagreements that escalate. 

For example, let’s say there was a gang related drive-by shooting in St. Louis, and for people got shot. That will automatically be considered a mass shooting. Although this would technically the correct terminology, when new outlets post the headlines “mass shooting in St. Louis leaves 4 people wounded”, many viewers would likely imagine another hate crime, terroristic attack, shooting spree, etc. Although 4 people getting shot is HORRIBLE IN ANY CONTEXT excluding self defense, there is a clear difference between a shooting like this and a “Uvalde” type situation.  

This is why I believe there needs to be a new legal term (which would be “mass shooting spree”) in place to differentiate the two. This way, the public - along with legal authority - would be able to avoid any possible confusion on such occurrences. I believe it would also help pinpoint the root causes of these instances of gun violence. “Mass shooting spree”, of course, would refer to situations where multiple random and/or unsuspecting people were shot. 

When you hear “America had x amounts of mass shootings last year”, it’s hard to tell the amount of these that were personal or gang related (in which the victim(s) and perpetrator(s) knew each other) or occurrences which actually involved random, innocent bystanders dying en mass (usually due to hateful or political motivations). By adding the word “spree” at the end when necessary, we would then be able to easily differentiate such cases, and possibly even help ease the public’s hysteria - since it would become clear that it’s not always just random people becoming some lunatic’s target practice.  Meanwhile the term “mass shooting” could continue to be in place for non-shooting spree incidents.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="41863107407.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="True">
    <text>That's not a legal term.

In law enforcement and psych settings, mass killing is the overarching category -- within that are the various subtypes, like spree, serial, mass terrorist, family, workplace, yada yada 

&amp;gt;This is why I believe there needs to be a new legal term (which would be “mass shooting spree”) in place to differentiate the two.

That's not a new term, and again, these are not legal terms to begin with. The law deals in specific crimes and not classification of events like that. Number of murders, attempted murders, etc., not what le categorizes it as.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863148904.0" user="SouthrenHill" delta="False">
    <text>∆ I was under the impression that “mass shooting” was the legal/official term in regards to the shooting of 3 or more people. That said, I still do believe it would be more responsible for media outlets and public officials to enforce the differentiation, at least whenever enough information is out, thus confirming whether or not a mass shooting was a “spree”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863166574.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I still do believe it would be more responsible for media outlets and public officials to enforce the differentiation, at least whenever enough information is out, thus confirming whether or not a mass shooting was a “spree”.

Why? Most people don't understand the categorization rules or why they're used. 

Same as people have no fucking clue what a pedophile is or that most child molesters are not pedophiles. Having the general public understand those differences can have a specific effect (that'd be positive, imo), but I'm not sure what differentiating mass killing type would?

Why do you feel that's important?

eta -- danke. :)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863237820.0" user="SouthrenHill" delta="False">
    <text>Because the public often has a twisted or misconstrued idea of how frequent random mass shootings really are. Due to how general the phrase “mass shooting” is, it’s become easier and easier to - intentionally or unintentionally - convince people living in the nicest of suburbs that even they can’t step outside or they will absolutely be shot (when the likelihood is like &amp;lt;.05% or something, numbers may be a little off). 

Don’t get me wrong, mass shootings (spree or not) and gun violence in general is a terrible epidemic that very much needs to be addressed and ended. However, it is extremely unlikely that anyone living normal, low-drama lives will ever have to endure such situations (specifically in the United States). However, presenting to the public that we have a lot of mass shootings while omitting that fact that the majority of them stem from situations that most citizens wouldn’t even understand (gang violence, etc.) - in which the victims were (unfortunately) often involved - instills extra fear and even confusion into their hearts, and even fuels the flames of division we’re already very much experiencing today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="41863277611.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Because the public often has a twisted or misconstrued idea of how frequent random mass shootings really are. Due to how general the phrase “mass shooting” is, it’s become easier and easier to - intentionally or unintentionally - convince people living in the nicest of suburbs that even they can’t step outside or they will absolutely be shot (when the likelihood is like &amp;lt;.05% or something, numbers may be a little off).

A mass shooting is simply about the number of people. 

I don't get how you think spree killings, which are very rare, btw, would have any effect on perceptions. 

&amp;gt;However, presenting to the public that we have a lot of mass shootings while omitting that fact that the majority of them stem from situations that most citizens wouldn’t even understand (gang violence, etc.) - in which the victims were (unfortunately) often involved - instills extra fear and even confusion into their hearts, and even fuels the flames of division we’re already very much experiencing today.

There are like two mass shootings a day in the US. That's an insane number, and despite FOX's desperation to push the narrative that they're mostly gang related, that's not true.

They are often domestic/familial, which doesn't mean people won't be harmed -- especially in states with lax gun laws (the more strict the gun laws, the less gun violence, and the less strict, the more gun violence). 

[https://www.usatoday.com/in-depth/graphics/2022/08/18/mass-killings-database-us-events-since-2006/9705311002/](https://www.usatoday.com/in-depth/graphics/2022/08/18/mass-killings-database-us-events-since-2006/9705311002/)

I don't, though, get why you;d want to separate out spree killings, which are so small in number.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
