<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223826952.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p9dzc/cmv_college_athletes_are_modern_day_indentured/">
    <title>CMV: College Athletes are modern day indentured servants and deserve to be paid.</title>
    <original_poster>yobittner</original_poster>
    <original_post>It’s about time we start paying student athletes, or at the very least grant all participants full scholarships. Coming from a Division I athlete myself, I never really thought of the subject until undergoing the most stressful past few months of my life. If being a student isn’t enough, try waking up by 8am for your first class, finishing around one, and then going to practice for 4-5 hours. After practice, you grab a bite to eat and by the team you even have a chance of starting your course work, the clock says 8pm. It’s looking like an all-nighter, oh wait that’s every other night, and you are already exhausted from practice.

According to Forbes, the NCAA basketball tournament, also known as “March Madness,” allows for CBS to make more than $1 billion off the games. Athletic conferences receive millions of dollars from the NCAA when their teams make it far in the tournament. It is even estimated that as a whole the NCAA makes $6 billion annually. (It’s registered as a non-profit by the way…) Meanwhile student athletes are either going in debt to pay for school, barely have any spending money, or are just fortunate enough to be one of the few that are financially well off. Quite frankly, I feel as though it’s just not fair that an organization can make so much money off of people who don’t receive any benefits. Its modern day indentured servitude.

You can only look back at the video game dilemma to see how much the NCAA generates off of unpaid workers. NCAA Football and March Madness were discontinued after athletes found players that looked exactly like them. Although names were not able to be used, the NCAA would not only have someone on the cover, but have identical players in the game. There was a settlement in which the game was finally discontinued because of the outrageous greed by a nonprofit organization.

One logical argument that’s often ignored is that an athlete can be compared to a cafeteria worker in a university dining hall. Both represent the school and provide a service that generates money. However, the only one who is paid is the cafeteria worker. Does that make any sense? Why would someone that generates less money for the school receive better treatment? It’s common sense…

At the very least, I believe all NCAA athletes should be eligible for full scholarships. There shouldn’t be any limitations at all. You would be very surprised to realize that actually the majority of NCAA student athletes do not receive any sort of athletic financial aid. A lot of this has to do with the limitation on the number of scholarships per team due to policies such as Title IX. Not only are you paying the school through your hard work, but you also might be literally paying the school…

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28063534408.0" user="weather3003" delta="False">
    <text>I took a quick glance at [this](http://espn.go.com/college-sports/story/_/id/6756472/following-ncaa-money) article and [this](http://www.ncaa.org/health-and-safety/sport-science-institute/ncaa-budget-where-money-goes) article and they seemed to suggest that the NCAA doesn't have nearly as much money as you would think. They're using it all to continue their program, support schools, and support students. I thought it was especially interesting that one article said that the NCAA sponsors research in health and safety for the players' benefit. 

Yes the school is getting money through your hard work, but that money is going back to the students, of which you are one. Someone has to pay for the athletic equipment, the field maintenance, training equipment, etc. They also have to pay for academic enrichment programs too.

Meanwhile, there's no guarantee that the cafeteria worker is even a student at the school. They may need nothing more than money for food for their family, so there's no point putting their pay towards the school.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063550654.0" user="yobittner" delta="False">
    <text>I can see your argument that the NCAA and schools put money back into the program and benefits for student athletes such as research. However, I don't believe that it all adds up correctly. If the NCAA truly has the best interest of the students, then why are their staff some of the highest paid in college sports? Why do coaches at the collegiate level make such a high median salary? You mean Jim Haurbaugh's 7 million dollars from the University of Michigan was just the school putting money back into the program... That 7 million dollars could easily help aid student athletes who are not currently on money. The coaches are making millions while the players are taking out loans... Makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063561003.0" user="ryancarp3" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; You mean Jim Haurbaugh's 7 million dollars from the University of Michigan was just the school putting money back into the program

Indirectly, yes. They pay Harbaugh that money so he recruits the best players to play for Michigan and win games. The more they win, the more money they bring in. This money is then put back into the program. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
