<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="225482448.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3q8vdc/cmv_going_to_the_gym_is_wasteful_and_selfish/">
    <title>CMV: Going to the gym is wasteful and selfish.</title>
    <original_poster>amsteele27</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most people in developed countries, thanks to modern technology, are no longer required to exert themselves physically to earn a living, so they go the gym for various reasons to be able to exert themselves physically. I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy. For thousands of years (at the least) there has been a dearth of physical labor. This gave rise to slavery as a way to force people to do physical work, something most societies did for thousands of years, until very recently, which demonstrates just how incredibly valuable human physical labor is. So why are people squandering this invaluable resource doing completely trivial things? If every person who went to the gym every day volunteered doing something constructive with their energy, they would get the work out they want, but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop. People are wasting their energy to accomplish literally nothing in the world, except for the changes that take place in your own body. If ending hunger and homelessness are more important to people than working out your muscle groups in the exact right order, then this should not be a problem. If the tens of millions of people who went to the gym used all of that energy to a constructive end instead of to literally no end, then we could probably fix many of the problems facing our society today. 



&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28078334095.0" user="noluv4uhoes" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think that the people who do this would serve society far, far better by doing something constructive with this energy.

So isnt your argument actually "*everyone* who doesnt use every last little bit of their energy on something constructive for society  is wasteful and selfish"?

Why are the people who sit at home playing video games and beating their dicks all day being let off?

&amp;gt;but at the end of the day instead of lifting and lowering a piece of metal they would have helped build a house or helped a farmer harvest their crop

I definitely see where you're coming from but is it our fault that there's no actual way for us to do that without becoming professional construction workers or having a friend who owns a farm?

Gyms efficiently allow us to keep healthy which is hard when you dont have a physical job and big food companies pump most things available in the supermarket full of sugar and fat. 

Edit: Also homelessness isnt an issue because we dont have enough homes. In some US cities there are more foreclosed homes than homeless people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078383253.0" user="amsteele27" delta="False">
    <text>A couple people mentioned similar arguments, so I'm just going to reply here. The question about video games is about free time I guess. Simple free time is also an important resource most people have, and it is selfish to spend it doing video games. Everybody seems to be assuming that being selfish is a always bad thing, which isn't true to begin with I don't think. But the real answer for me is that people going to the gym are already motivated and active people. While I think both are selfish, I think it would probably be easier to get people to go to a different location and do a different work out than getting people to put down their video games and go do something constructive. 

Your first question, which others have also asked, is completely distorting my argument. The point of my argument is that if somebody performs action A, but action B satisfies the reason why people perform action A as well as benefiting society, then action B is preferable to action A. What you are suggesting is if action A does not benefit society than it is immoral. So no, that is not actually my argument. The reason sitting at home playing video games is different is also because of this. I am not saying that everybody should change everything they do if it does not benefit society. If there was a very similar activity to video games that did benefit society, than it would be less selfish to do that other activity.

Your third to last paragraph... I'm not trying to suggest everybody could wake up tomorrow and implement what I am saying. There would obviously need to be programs set up to deal with the logistics... maybe the money of a membership would go towards this, and the logistics of this all would replace all the jobs lost to gym membership (addressing a point made in another post). But the fact that there aren't currently programs to allow volunteer workers to work on farms doesn't mean that it is impossible. And for construction, I obviously don't mean going to work on sky scrappers and becoming a professional. You could help build much simpler things, or just forget about construction. It was just an example I randomly used.

The last thing... yes, that is true. But the difference is, the homes that these programs would build wouldn't be owned by banks and huge corporations who would rather see people homeless than lose money on a house. Whatever program oversees the construction would just give the house to somebody who needs it. Property tax would be dealt with. There are already government programs that subsidize low income housing. It would not be a stretch to see them increase funding for such a program. Plus, $20 billion plus that is going into the gym industry could have a hand in this. But again, construction was just an idea. None of this affects my original view.

And in terms of the arguments people are making about it not being accessible in their schedule... why would it be any different than going to the gym? These programs would stay open the same hours as gyms, and would be in the same locations. Instead of doing what is now a normal workout, though, you would do something constructive. There are so many possibilities of what that could be, I did not mean to exclude everything else by mentioning construction and farming only.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28078399630.0" user="jumpup" delta="True">
    <text>working out is more effective, and less strain on back muscles.

basically  if one workout machine generated electricity and the other didn't you might have a point with better use, but people simply chose the thing that gets the best results,</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
