<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477089267.0" user="AlphaQueen3" delta="False">
    <text>Far and wide?  I know at least a half dozen, without searching beyond my local coffee shop.  I'm a lesbian, and while I'm not super femme myself (also not really butch, but ok) plenty of lesbians are.  

Are you only counting people as lesbians if they look lesbian to you? Where are you searching?  Why are you searching?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477101595.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Can you show me some sort of statistic involving femme lesbians to show me they are not in the minority?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477163648.0" user="ItIsICoachCal" delta="True">
    <text>While I couldn't find any studies attempting to create a wide demographic survay, there are studies that compare aspects of butch vs femme lesbian/bi/queer women.

This is the first one I found, and while the thrust of it is about substance abuse, in the process they had to use established techniques to sort their population into "butch" "femme" and neither. In that process they found more femme than butch women, though not to a statistically significant degree. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3189349/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
