<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477089267.0" user="AlphaQueen3" delta="False">
    <text>Far and wide?  I know at least a half dozen, without searching beyond my local coffee shop.  I'm a lesbian, and while I'm not super femme myself (also not really butch, but ok) plenty of lesbians are.  

Are you only counting people as lesbians if they look lesbian to you? Where are you searching?  Why are you searching?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477101595.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Can you show me some sort of statistic involving femme lesbians to show me they are not in the minority?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477163648.0" user="ItIsICoachCal" delta="True">
    <text>While I couldn't find any studies attempting to create a wide demographic survay, there are studies that compare aspects of butch vs femme lesbian/bi/queer women.

This is the first one I found, and while the thrust of it is about substance abuse, in the process they had to use established techniques to sort their population into "butch" "femme" and neither. In that process they found more femme than butch women, though not to a statistically significant degree. 

https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC3189349/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477266891.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Δ Thank you for sharing with me this source. I now know there are more femme lesbians than I had initially thought. Even though the context of the source was about substance abuse, it is still very accurate and shows there is a staggering amount of femme lesbians. I'm not completely changed because it's only a reflection of lesbians who have fallen under drug abuse, I have now acknowledged there are more femme lesbians than I thought.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477323606.0" user="ItIsICoachCal" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; I'm not completely changed because it's only a reflection of lesbians who have fallen under drug abuse

That is not the case. You need to actually read the study before talking about what it does and does not say. Here's what the study says about recruitment: 

&gt;Female and male youths, ages 14 to 21 years, were recruited from three gay-focused community-based organizations (85%) and two college student organizations (15%) in New York City. Meetings were held with the study investigators to introduce the study and invite the adolescents to participate in a study of lesbian, gay, and bisexual youths. In addition, youths were approached individually and invited to participate. These recruitment efforts were conducted by a gender and ethnically diverse study staff who were college educated and trained to follow a common recruitment procedure. Attempts were made to recruit every youth attending the recruitment site. We have estimated that approximately 80% of youths who were invited or attended a meeting participated in the study.

In short, the only criteria was age, meeting in LGBT groups, and willingness to participate, **not** substance use level. 

In fact if you actually look at the data tables, they are not a very substance abuse heavy population.

&gt; Items use a 5-point response scale from “not at all” (1) to “very often” (5). The mean of the items was computed as an index of substance abuse (α = .78 - .92 across all 3 assessment times for the female youths).

Confusingly put since a "1" on all symptoms would mean a 0.00 score.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477543036.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>So in the article, what was the purpose of the survey? Was it to tell how many butch or femme lesbians there were or how many lesbians who are butch or femme are doing drugs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477608675.0" user="ItIsICoachCal" delta="True">
    <text>You know, you can read it if you clink on the link. It's all there. The purpose was to look at a population of young queer people and determine if butch presenting ones were more or less likely to have used drugs or have issues with substance abuse as compared to femme presenting ones. If they only looked at data of lesbians "who have fallen under drug abuse" as you put it, there would be no meaningful difference between them. 

Seriously. Open the link. Look at the data.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
