<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477175505.0" user="GenericUsername19892" delta="False">
    <text>Is this real post? 

https://www.them.us/story/former-miss-puerto-rico-miss-argentina-married

Search google images for lesbian wedding and more than half prove show this is false. 

Now the more complicated matter is how you missed this - search engines try to always give you what they think you like, that is what you engage with. So if you couldn’t find anything, you may want to try a different browser or account for the search engine. Your past uhhh preferences may be contaminating your current queries.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477185485.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;https://www.them.us/story/former-miss-puerto-rico-miss-argentina-married

What if they are in the minority? The photos could be faked too.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477213191.0" user="Rhundan" delta="False">
    <text>Really? First, you say they don't exist, now you're asking if they're in the minority? Who cares, that's not what you said.

And as for the photos being faked... really? Why?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477324307.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;And as for the photos being faked... really? Why?

If you misheard me, I said googling up images of lesbian marriages that could be staged. The actual story of the celebrities is real. However, the couple maybe in the minority though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477340065.0" user="Rhundan" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you didn't say "femme lesbians are in the minority", you said "a lesbian that looks feminine does not exist"

And you haven't answered *why* those pictures would ever be staged. Is there some great conspiracy to convince you that feminine lesbians exist?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477506572.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I know I have mentioned that there is a possibility that femme lesbians don't exist in my post text. I do not believe that and now I believe that there are femme lesbians out there. I simply believe there are a lot of fake images online and they have the potential to be staged: https://www.boredpanda.com/fake-news-photos-viral-photoshop/.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477695877.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="False">
    <text>What motive do you think people would have to fake them?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477707040.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>To gain popularity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477723286.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="True">
    <text>Wait, are you suggesting femme females fake being gay for popularity?

Because I don't know how one would gain popularity from fake images not of them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
