<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2374784829.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/139vvp9/cmv_it_shouldnt_be_illegal_to_speed_it_should_be/">
    <title>CMv: It shouldn't be illegal to speed; it should be impossible.</title>
    <original_poster>CaptainFunktastic</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I'll assume this is for the US only.

To wit. There is no reason for "speeding" to be a finable, or jailable offense, when through the use of common, cheap tech, it could be impossible. Every car with a function on board computer gets a gps tracker installed which connects directly to the tranny, throttle, and speedometer. When the legal speed limit is reached, it cuts fuel, engages a rev limiter, or prevents the tranny from allowing an increase in speed.

A counter to any possible arguments:

* "No one said you have to speed!" I don't have to be punished either.

* "It's not the roll of the government to control my vehicle!" It's not it's roll to punish you either.

* "What if there's an emergency!" Please, any law enforcement or judges in the comments correct me if I'm wrong, but no jurisdiction in the country recognizes "an emergency" as an excuse to speed.

* "What if I'm being chased by a *bad guy*?" Well, if neither of you can go faster than the other, than so what. Also, refer to my previous statement.

* "It's my car!" Sure, but that doesn't matter on public roads.

* "What if I want to take it on the track?" Than you have it classified as a race car, and can never drive it on the road.

* "People will tamper with and disable it!* Sure. If caught, they'll spend a few years in prison for destruction of government property.

* "Speed and horsepower are only marketing gimmicks." So, it's legal to market something I'm not legally allowed to use?

* There are a lot of smaller towns that simply can't survive without ticket revenue". If your city, town, village, community, or municipality can't survive without fucking with it's drivers, maybe it's destined to fail.

* What if I have a [insert classic car here] which doesn't have a computer?" Let's face it, the only time it ever leaves the garage is to go to car shows because you're too afraid of injuring it's potential resale value. Load it on a truck and tow it.

* "I paid half a million for this car!" Well, congrats, you paid half a mil to do 40 mph.

* "My car drives like shit below [X]mph" Well, good job on your shoddy maintenance or your piss poor tune.

* "We should be trusted to operate a motor vehicle responsibly at all times, that what testing and licensing are for." Okay. We're hairless monkies with the the same brains we've had for millennia. Trusting us to operate two tons of explosion powered steel, filled with toxic chemicals, at speeds no living organism was ever meant to travel is a terrible idea.

Please. Change my view.

Edit: View changed. Congrats all!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42514381442.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>What happens when one of those components inevitably breaks or has a bug?  Does the car simply not go?  

What happens when you are in a tunnel or a parking garage when there is no GPS signal?  Does the car simply not go?  

What happens when the speed limit data is wrong for a given road? Or when new roads have opened since the map was updated?

What happens when there is a work zone?

What happens when you have a legitimate reason to speed - like a medical emergency?  Most cops will let it slide if there is a real reason to speed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514417484.0" user="CaptainFunktastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; What happens when one of those components inevitably breaks or has a bug? Does the car simply not go?

If it's an software issue than you call a number and have it reset. If it's a hardware fault, you grab the spare the sent you and follow the instructions.

&gt; What happens when you are in a tunnel or a parking garage when there is no GPS signal? Does the car simply not go?

It uses a cache to save local speeds, and updates when it reconnects.

&gt; What happens when the speed limit data is wrong for a given road? Or when new roads have opened since the map was updated?

Nothing. No one will get hurt, and when enough people complian, it'll get updated.

&gt; What happens when there is a work zone?

Your GPS would be notified in advance.

&gt; What happens when you have a legitimate reason to speed - like a medical emergency?

There have been countless cases of people being pulled over while hauling ass mid birth or heart attack, and the cop will say "no excuse." Spend 45 minutes giving you a ticket - because it *needs* to take that long apparently - and drive away while your dad dies in the passenger seat.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42514446768.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
