<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2454551757.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/14ldk99/cmv_most_communities_are_echo_chambers_its_not/">
    <title>CMV: Most communities are echo chambers. It's not echo chambers that are inherently harmful, it's echo chambers that echo world-shaping ideas that are.</title>
    <original_poster>ivyinthewait</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most communities are echo chambers in order to create a civil environment. Racism, homophobia, ableism etc. tend to be filtered out of communities in order to protect the mental health of community members who are apart of these marginalised groups while also upholding a civil and non-toxic environment. This is an echo chamber because it causes a lack of exposure to alternative viewpoints. This specific type of echo chamber is the most popular form of echo chamber we see on the internet today and can be seen in places like music communities, gaming communities, art communities etc. I classify this form of echo chamber as harmless. An etiquette is required to form a community which considers the mental health of the members within it.  


The actual issue we have with "echo chambers" are the ideas they are echoing. Political echo chambers, conspiracy echo chambers, hate groups, pseudo-science or anti-science echo chambers, etc. These echo chambers are harmful due to the inherent world-shaping views that come with them. There is a difference between an echo chamber with a focus on creating a civil environment and an echo chamber that tries to pull you into a specific way to view the world and how the world should work. Forming one's perspective on how to view the world and how the world should work is a process that requires exposure to various ideas and constant willingness to hear out other perspectives.   


&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42923426821.0" user="Poetic_Mind_Unhinged" delta="False">
    <text>Censorship does not inherently create an echo chamber. A community can remove/disallow hateful speech without becoming an echo chamber. Exposure to different ideas can still happen while limiting exposure to toxic, hateful, or blatantly false ideas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42923542125.0" user="ivyinthewait" delta="False">
    <text>how would you define an echo chamber?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42923646310.0" user="Poetic_Mind_Unhinged" delta="False">
    <text>Oxford Languages defines it as:

"an environment in which a person encounters only beliefs or opinions that coincide with their own, so that their existing views are reinforced and alternative ideas are not considered."

In this community (CMV) you aren't allowed to be "rude" (overtly racist, sexist, etc.) or personally attack people. There is censorship happening constantly, yet the whole premise of the sub is based around exposure to contradictory or alternative views/ideas. By the standards you've laid out this is an echo chamber, when it clearly is not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42923738461.0" user="ivyinthewait" delta="False">
    <text>Racist and sexist sentiments are still allowed on this subreddit on the conditions that it's expressed in a refined manner. While it does filter out posts that express them in hostile ways, the ideas aren't necessarily prohibited, the rhetorical methods are prohibited. I don't think this subreddit is an echo chamber really. I guess it's echoing a degree of anti-hostility lol?

In regards to the first example mentioned in my original post: These echo chambers from what I've observed tend to exile people with racist and sexist ideas. But I will say that there is a possibility that because it's uncommon to see racism and sexism expressed in a non-hostile matter online, i may have made a faulty observation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42923905206.0" user="Poetic_Mind_Unhinged" delta="True">
    <text>&gt;the ideas aren't necessarily prohibited

That's why I specified *overtly* and mentioned personal attacks.

I think your definition of echo chamber is simply far too broad. Most communities, even ones which have limited censorship rules in place, have a diverse community of individuals with varying world views. For example the exclusion of racist people doesn't mean all non-racist people remaining will agree on everything, especially if the community in question is based around something very different like economics, video games, or whatever else.

The only time banning racists would create an echo chamber is in the context of a community who's primary engagement is the discussion of racism. In this context all members would constantly be exposed to anti-racist views which reinforce their beliefs. 

However, in the context of a community based around discussing economics, banning racist people has very little effect on the dialogue. It isn't necessary to have racist opinions expressed in that context in order to avoid constant exposure to one set of ideas/ideals. The remaining members who aren't racist will never (or rarely) share those views and will still disagree about many other things related to economics.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
