<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="246358818.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/42oboi/cmv_tom_cruise_is_an_awful_actor/">
    <title>CMV: Tom Cruise is an awful actor.</title>
    <original_poster>kslidz</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not think that Tom Cruise makes any movie he is in bad or that his performances are not enjoyable. I just think that he is incapable of imitating any role but Tom Cruise. People seem to love him and I just cannot get it. What is the point of watching the same thing over and over again, I feel like it could be a good reality show though. "Watch Tom Cruise this week being a marine/computer hacker/nazi/super hero/etc" I guess I am more dumbfounded by people that like him who don't like Michael Bay. He is dumb entertainment. Nothing wrong with that but insinuating that he isn't the most 1 dimensional actor on the face of the earth just boggles my mind. 

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28257577585.0" user="McKoijion" delta="False">
    <text>[Do you know what's the hardest thing you can do on guitar?](http://imgur.com/gallery/kJGKDl0)

Just because Tom Cruise mostly chooses to make one dimensional blockbuster hits instead of story driven Oscar bait doesn't mean he can't. [Tom Cruise hasn't had a real flop in over 30 years.](http://www.forbes.com/sites/scottmendelson/2015/07/30/box-office-tom-cruise-is-still-a-man-of-few-flops/#424fba2318ee) He has chosen his roles perfectly because even a few flops can mean the end of your career in Hollywood. Despite all his craziness and all the popularity he lost with his Scientology connections, he still made $40 million last year. That's fifth place. He has had three of the top 20 [highest paid roles of all time,](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_highest_paid_film_actors) which is more than any other actor in history. Criticizing him for not being a good actor is like criticizing the best offensive player in the NBA for not being good at defense too. It's not that can't be good at character roles (check out Born on the Fourth of July, Magnolia, Rain Man, etc.) but he actively chooses not to do them. Criticizing him for this is like criticizing Daniel Day-Lewis for not making more money. It's a different skill set, but generally speaking if you are good at one, you can translate it into being good at the other if you want to. The hardest skill is combining both critical and popular appeal into one. Very few people can do it any field.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257646189.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>I have not seen Born on the Fourth of July and Magnolia has been a while although I do not remember being impressed. 

The rest of your point just reaffirms my opinion. 

The thing is I don't see people praising Michael Bay as a great director I see people hating on him as completely focused on money. It is the same thing as Tom Cruise but I hear praise for Cruise all the time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257809058.0" user="shehulk111" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The thing is I don't see people praising Michael Bay as a great director I see people hating on him as completely focused on money. 

Its not the same at all. Tom's movies are critically acclaimed. 'Edge of tomorrow' and' Mission impossible 5' both have more than +90% on rotten tomatoes, and are well regarded by audiences. Plus I can't see how someone can change your mind about something as  subjective as acting abilities. I find Cruise excellent in all his films and others may find him horrible while others may feel neutral about it. The thing is none of us have the right answer because acting is an art form, and some of us will like things others don't, so I don't know why ask people to change your mind. If you don't like his acting, then don't. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257903880.0" user="kslidz" delta="False">
    <text>fair point about it being subjective, I guess I was just hoping there was more to it than some people just enjoy him. I did get some roles to check out which I definitely will. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28257923699.0" user="TagaKain" delta="True">
    <text>I disagree a bit with this. First off, acting is not that subjective, and I don't think you're denying the fact that Cruise fits well into most of his roles. That's good acting, no matter how repetitive you think it is.

Second, Tom Cruise is a *movie star* as well as an actor. His onscreen charisma is part of his talent on display in these blockbusters (in fact, it's the major part). Think back to the NBA analogy. Think back to RDJ as Iron Man, to Jennifer Lawrence, to Harrison Ford. They are hired just as much for their charisma as their ability to blend into roles.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
