<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2491044503.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1573q8n/cmv_the_us_is_on_the_brink_of_civil_war_2/">
    <title>CMV: The US is on the brink of Civil War 2: Electric Boogaloo.</title>
    <original_poster>Nailyou866</original_poster>
    <original_post>A bit of a doomer post, I know, but this is why I am here.

I think the trends in the US are terrifying and will have a catastrophic climax in the near future. Civil unrest seems to be at an all-time high due to a variety of factors. I am very left/libertarian leaning and I see right wing and liberal outlets promoting highly charged news, racial tensions on the rise, police brutality, class warfare, and identity politics taking center stage as major contributors.

The news. Headlines are what news outlets thrive on, and the more extreme or outrage-y drive traffic to the articles, meaning that positive and uplifting stories are either left in the dust or not written in favor of something more likely to increase engagement. This means that context and nuance are buried in favor of opinion pieces that cause people to be irritable or in despair. Reporting biases gear audiences to a place of discontent. I know this isn't necessarily a bad thing on its own, as this can be a catalyst for change, but given some sources and motivations, such as right wing media trying to cause change against "wokeness", this can ruin interpersonal relations as people begin to hate their fellow person. I know that politics has a massive presense in society, but when people see humans just existing as "political" or "woke", they can easily otherize humans into something not themselves, making it easier to hate.

Racial tensions. This is relatively self explanatory as white supremacists are pouring out of the woodworks to attack movements like BLM and policies like Affirmative Action. It makes it difficult to be a person like me, cis, white, male, and working in security. I know I make black people uncomfortable because without knowing me, they might be quick to assume I have white supremacist ideals or biases. Anecdotally, I had to pull aside a group of black kids at one of my posts because they were causing problems at the establishment, and I kept having to get onto them about what they were doing. I pulled them aside to explain how the actions they were engaging in were problematic for the establishment and why management kept having me get onto them. Basically a "look, people are paying for a certain experience, and are complaining because you are getting in the way and being disruptive. If you want to be here, that is fine, but you have to follow the rules." As I was talking to them, an older black gentleman walked by and stopped to listen to what I was telling them. He told me after they left that he appreciated the way I talked to them and handled the situation maturely, and he stuck by because he was a little nervous because he saw "a white rent-a-cop talking to a group of black kids" and he wanted to make sure that everything was on the up and up, which I totally get. We talked for a while about the state of police and race issues, and largely agreed on several positions.

Which brings me to my next point, police brutality. It is no secret that Law Enforcement is... problematic in the US. I know it isn't just the US, but my focus is here right now. Connecticut just had several hundred police busted for over 20,000 fake and falsified tickets over a several year time span. As phone footage and body cam footage is released we see a really dark reality for minorities in the US. People being murdered or beaten for a variety of reasons, dogs being released on people and uncontrolled, and militarization of the police force given budgets that far outweigh things like parks and recreation or mental health. These issues are felt nation-wide and the average citizen can do nothing to redress their grievances, or it further hurts them because the State backs the cops. Qualified Immunity has been abused to the point where cops can just violate your rights and get away with it because "they couldn't have known they were violating your rights". The average citizen is powerless against the police, which is by design. If a cop draws on me and I were to shoot in self-defense, I would have a greater degree of a burden of proof than a cop would if it were the other way around, or even if I didn't draw. We saw that with kids being murdered by police for toy guys or adults being murdered for a hairbrush that was assumed to be a weapon.

Class warfare. People are being kicked out of house and home due to wage stagnation and supression, while the rich just get richer. We can see a direct example of that concept with the Hollywood debacle. Streaming services are massively profitable, requiring next to no cost compared to the older ways of distribution, and yet shareholders are raking in profits while actors and writers are being paid less overall due to the elimination of residuals through the streaming model. Massive shifts in technological advancements result in more money being accumulated by those already at the top. While I can go on about the inherant flaws of a profit-driven economy, the real facts are that CEOs and investors are gaining net worth and value while every day citizens are struggling to get by. More and more Americans are living paycheck to paycheck because of these things.

Identity politics. For whatever reason, LGBT+ issues are now taking the forefront of the GOP's platform. "Wokeness" is something that they are now dedicated to fighting, with baseless accusations being thrown against these minority groups of grooming and pedophilia, with the rise of acceptance and more people feeling comfortable enough about coming out being used as evidence of a conspiracy to turn everyone trans and gay. Children taught that it is OK to be different are somehow being indoctrinated in to this cult of degenerate behavior. The falsified outrage against the minority groups is being used to motivate hate crimes against anyone who supports them. Are there discussions that can be had about the type of information and when it is appropriate? Sure, but this isn't their goal. It was not and never has been about "protecting children" evidenced by the anti-trans bills being passed nation-wide that are trying to ban or raise the age to 25.

There are other issues at play, like rising mass violence and conspiracy theories, but these are kind of my main focuses. I am terrified that we are going to see an unresolvable schism in American society that will lead to a civil war with a death toll higher than any war to date. The lines won't be as clean this time, since before, people were mostly aligned with their state. In this time period, I would be more likely to catch a bullet from my neighbor than someone from another state, as was the case in the Civil War we know from history. Please, restore my faith in our ability to avert this catastrophy and come to a better solution. Some of my positions, such as my ideology or views on minorities and trans, you will not be able to change, those aren't the focus of this CMV. I just don't want to be worried I wake up and hearing about the new Fort Sumter.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43117263481.0" user="Quentanimobay" delta="False">
    <text>From my viewpoint none of these things are radically worse than they have been in the past. There have been times where things were worse than they are now and it didn't escalate to a civil war. If you think back to during the civil rights movement when things were really tense with mass civil unrest across the country how things are today doesn't look so bad. 

I think with the advent of social media we can quickly fall into the trap of listening to the loud minority. The 24 hour news cycle has adapted to thrive off of adversity so social issues are pushed to the forefront but reality is quite different. If you look for different types of a news you will find it. I've spent a lot of time curating the type of news I consume to make sure that at least half is non-political. The less doomsday media you consume the less of it you'll see.

It's easy to forget that near 40% of the country doesn't even vote. Out of the 60% that do vote I am willing to bet that at least half are moderate one way or another which only leaves 30% or less have strong enough views that they're actually willing to physically fight over them. 

I also don't want to downplay the very real threat of radicals. I know they exist and unfortunately some of them are armed and ready to militarize but that would be less of a civil war and more of the government stepping in to stop what basically amounts to terrorist. I don't think there's nothing to worry about but overly worrying about it by thinking were on the brink of war is counterproductive. 

Not really important to my main point but I did want to bring up your experience with racial tensions. You would have likely garnered the same reaction anytime over the last 100 years. The only difference is that you're aware of how you're perceived.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117392945.0" user="Nailyou866" delta="False">
    <text>I largely agree with the point about social media, and I meant to lean more into that in my media section of my post.

It could just be my location, but I am relatively consistantly inundated in real life with people parading around Trump bumper stickers, making crude comments about Democrats or wokeness,  and generally public demonstrations of political affiliation. I just have the general vibe in my area that people are politically aware, and thus might be inclined to stick to their positions. I also meant to address the Jason Aldean's small town song, and general public perception, which in my area, again, generally supported. That song is unquestionably about political vigilante-ism.

I don't think voting metrics on their own serve as a concrete example of political leanings, as I am well aware of the tendancy to refuse to vote because of a lack of faith in the candidates most in line with ideology. Leftists are particularly bad in this area, refusing to vote for centrist liberals because they aren't going to do Universal Healthcare or something else. I don't know if it judt an issue for leftists, but I imagine the right might also suffer slightly from it too.


The part I am most interested in further discussing is about the government dealing with radical's militarization. Would Jan 6th not be evidence enough of the potential problem with relying on the government to step in? I meant to speak more on Jan 6th as well, but we see state legislators and governors either tacitly endorse or downplay the issues with Jan 6th, as Republican officials seem to be more permissive of right wing radical action. There seems to be a running theme of right wing radicals being stochastically encouraged by Republicans. What we would likely see, in my estimation, is red states backing their radicals, which could further devolve into blue states backing the federal government and fighting the red states. Florida is rescinding their full faith and credit from blue states, which would indicate a potential for interstate conflict.

I acknowledge that racial tensions have always been a problem, and my perception is a real factor in my position. It just seems to be exacerbated by white supremacists being far more comfortable with being open about theirs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43117549379.0" user="Quentanimobay" delta="True">
    <text>&gt;It could just be my location, but I am relatively consistantly inundated in real life with people parading around Trump bumper stickers, making crude comments about Democrats or wokeness, and generally public demonstrations of political affiliation.

I live in a state where urban changes to corn fields in less than mile. And while I hate to stereotype and say that it turns into "Trump Country" it would mean ignoring all of the flags and billboards announcing it as such. I can't help but to think of it as a bandwagon thing. Lots of people show public support and repeat the things they hear to simply not be ostracized by their community. Im not naive enough to think that none of them believe it but hear enough of it at the local bar and people start saying the same things to not stick out. It gets hard to gauge how many people actually believe it but not everyone who says those things would actually fight for it.

&gt;I don't think voting metrics on their own serve as a concrete example of political leanings, as I am well aware of the tendancy to refuse to vote because of a lack of faith in the candidates most in line with ideology.

There will always be a certain amount of people that don't vote because of lack of faith but those same people also wouldn't fight hard for their opinions either. The point I was trying to make is that they don't view people with opposing views as harshly as someone who voted specifically so the "other side" doesn't win. That type of mindset is necessary to actually start a civil war.

&gt;The part I am most interested in further discussing is about the government dealing with radical's militarization. Would Jan 6th not be evidence enough of the potential problem with relying on the government to step in?

I actually don't think that Jan 6th was a big deal all things considered. Was it bad? Yes but aside from the loss of life it was relatively harmless and that harmlessness it what allows the GOP to be neutral enough to look like they condone it. The problem that the GOP is facing is that Trump has essentially created a large rift in the party. They can not secure elections without at least some of the Trump vote and that's what's keeping the GOP from speaking out against it. Most of the people who did speak out against it didn't win their elections. However, none of them have intervened against the FBI investigating or sentencing the participants. The GOP's silent condoning of it only goes far enough to maintain their voting base. 

The real concern is paramilitary groups that have been silently growing. They're actively seek disenfranchised young white men and radicalizing them and providing them with military training. Some of these groups are already on FBI watch lists which is both reassuring and scary because that means the government is taking them seriously. I think if any of them acted in a meaningful way the GOP would be forced to make a choice, either they continue to stay silent and risk losing their more moderate base or speak out against it and lose the support of the radicals that they don't actually want to admit they need.

&gt;I acknowledge that racial tensions have always been a problem, and my perception is a real factor in my position. It just seems to be exacerbated by white supremacists being far more comfortable with being open about theirs.

I still think it's a matter of perception. Once you know the signs it's just way easier to pick out. Maybe some of the subtly is gone but the amount of racists haven't grown.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
