<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="250195022.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/44yjpq/cmv_nuclear_power_should_be_widely_adopted/">
    <title>CMV: Nuclear power should be widely adopted until/unless renewable energy sources can catch up</title>
    <original_poster>LostInRiverview</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've had numerous debates with other self-described liberals (in the American sense of the word) regarding nuclear power's place in energy production and in combating climate change. During these discussions, I've held that nuclear power plants should be aggressively built in order to meet current and future electricity needs. We have agreed that non-renewable energy is a detriment to the planet, and that an ideal solution would be non-nuclear as well (e.g. solar, wind, and other as-yet-unknown methods of power generation), but they have argued that nuclear power in itself is inherently dangerous, devastating, and should not be part of our "energy portfolio" moving forward. I feel this view is based mostly on an emotional reaction to the idea of nuclear power, rather than one based in science and reason. I have pointed out that modern methods of nuclear power generation are much safer and more efficient than those developed in the mid-20th century, and many times safer than continuing to burn fossil fuels for energy. Additionally, while we are making strides towards improving our power generation through renewables, there's no guarantee that we'll ever be able to provide all the energy we need through those methods, especially if/when we transition from gas-powered to electric vehicles. Transitioning to modern nuclear reactors for electricity seems the most level-headed long-term solution to our energy problems, at least until such time as we can find better ways to generate green electricity. 

Change my view.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28287825465.0" user="teddyssplinter" delta="False">
    <text>There is only so much capital available for investing in non-fossil fuel sources of energy. If we spend significantly more on Nuclear sources of energy, then we'll have that much less capital to advance non-nuclear renewable sources and the development and adoption rates of those non-nuclear renewable sources will be that much slower. And, in a similar vein, if we do ramp up nuclear investment, and those sources of energy come online and begin providing a growing fraction of our energy, that industry will become competitive and defend itself from energy competition much like the fossil fuel industry has with lobbying, marketing, etc. They will fund "think tanks" to function as research mills for how great nuclear is, how nuclear waste isn't such a problem, why solar is not feasible, etc., and all this will further impede development and adoption rates in those safer renewables.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287855523.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>I don't disagree with what you're saying, but I'm curious as to what your "counter-proposal" would be. The current system is not sustainable in the long-term, so *some* form of change does seem necessary. The big sticking point here is the question of whether renewable energy really can meet 100% of our energy needs; I'm not convinced that it can, even if we invest all our capital into developing that technology further.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28287962276.0" user="teddyssplinter" delta="False">
    <text>Why couldn't it meet 100%, or very near 100%, of our energy needs? Germany's renewable energy production went from 6.3% in 2000 to 30% in 2014, and their aim is 80% by 2050, which, at the pace they're going, is quite feasible. And they are accomplishing that *while* having a law on the books requiring the country to *phase out ALL nuclear energy production by 2022*. Isn't that convincing?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28288119234.0" user="LostInRiverview" delta="False">
    <text>Having an aim is different from making actual progress. They might hope to achieve 80%, and they may even be on pace currently, but that doesn't mean that output will continue to grow at the same pace heading into the future. With present-day technology I don't think they'd be able to transition to 100% use of renewables, or anything close to that. In order to hit 80% or higher you have to assume that new technology will help bridge the gap, but that's not a safe assumption. And, even if more efficient methods of green energy production could be developed, there's no guarantee that they would be cost-effective compared to nuclear. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28288171155.0" user="teddyssplinter" delta="True">
    <text>New technology is not a safe assumption? Hmm. I believe our entire civilization is predicated on that assumption. *Nothing* is a guarantee. That isn't the standard by which we judge what the most "level headed long term" course is. Heck, nuclear is no guarantee. There could be another major Fukishima type disaster that causes public sentiment to turn rapidly against nuclear precisely at the time when we become reliant on it *most*. If you consider that the countries with the most advanced and sophisticated nuclear industries are now leading the charge away from nuclear (see [here](http://www.reuters.com/article/us-energy-nuclear-idUSBRE88D1DR20120914) and [here](http://www.smh.com.au/business/taking-stock-of-nuclear-renaissance-that-never-was-20100817-128ky.html), just for example), how can pursuing what they are abandoning be "the most level headed long term solution"? From the latter linked article, *"[T]he hard facts...point towards a continuing slow phase out of civilian nuclear energy in most of the large OECD countries."*</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
