<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2503391384.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15egd5k/cmv_either_every_recognized_genocide_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Either every recognized genocide should be illegal to deny, or none of them should be.</title>
    <original_poster>Tibbenator</original_poster>
    <original_post>This IS NOT about whether some genocide took place or not, nor is it an argument about freedom of speech on the matter. This is simply about application of law.

A country should not pick and choose which horrible atrocity is illegal to deny and which ones aren't. Every act of genocide recognized as such by that nation's government should be illegal to deny or none of them should be. The law should be applied evenly to every genocide.

What sense does it make to decide which atrocities are illegal to deny and which aren't? It seems to be giving a message that "We recognize all these terrible crimes against humanity for what they are, but some of them are worthy of more protection than the others".

Making only select genocides illegal to deny just adds fuel to fires of conspiracy. Racists, nazis, bigots, all of the above, and so on, tend to see these laws as some sort of warped justification for their views; they believe they must be right because it's only illegal to deny the specific genocide that they are focused on and not others.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43185083424.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>Generally speaking, certain countries have specific issues with certain kinds of ideologies that are more likely to deny a specific genocide, hence the prohibition of the denial of that genocides helps keep that ideology from using that denial as a way to pursue their ideological (and harmful in the view of that government) goals. 

For giving some specific examples, Ukraine allowing the denial of Holomodor as a genocide helps fight against the russophilic ideology that directly harms the whole country's (and also culture's) survival, hence focusing in preventing that kind of speech helps the government keep that ideology that directly threatens the government in check. And the same goes in Armenia but replacing Russia with Turkey and Holomodor with the Armenian Genocide.

Countries that do not have any special issue with any specific genocide being denied have no special interest in keeping specific ideologies in check. Russophilia does not threaten the existence of the country of Armenia, so no reason why Armenia should have a special law against the denial of Holomodor and vice versa with Ukraine and Turkey (in fact, having those laws would directly harm those countries as Armenia depends on Russia for protection and Ukraine buys Turkish arms for their war, so passing those laws would not only not help them but also harm them as it would anger their allies).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185128544.0" user="Mysterious-Bear215" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;For giving some specific examples, Ukraine forbidding the denial of Holomodor as a genocide helps fight against the russophilic ideology that directly harms the whole country's 

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;Countries that do not have any special issue with any specific genocide being denied have no special interest in keeping specific ideologies in check. 

So... Is more about politics than denying a genocide? Then there is no reason to change OP view, correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185142376.0" user="smcarre" delta="False">
    <text>How are you surpised that politics influence laws? That's literally how they are formed.

And OP's view is that every genocide should be equally illegal to deny and I'm showing examples of how doing that would be harmful to some countries/cultures/populations, directly against OP's view.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185259369.0" user="Mysterious-Bear215" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;How are you surpised that politics influence laws?

Not sorprised. I should have say: It just about politics.

&amp;#x200B;

&gt;I'm showing examples of how doing that would be harmful to some countries/cultures/population

If a country ban to deny certain genocide, how is hurmful to ban also any other genocide? It's just consistency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43185267366.0" user="smcarre" delta="True">
    <text>&gt; If a country ban to deny certain genocide, how is hurmful to ban also any other genocide? It's just consistency

You can read that in the first comment I made where I placed two different examples.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
