<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428035001.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>What's your point? Some experiments from the past were unethical? Yeah we know that, that's why we don't do them anymore.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428047636.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>My point is progress in innovation in that department has reduced significantly after the morality of experiments increased.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428059928.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>Well no not really. Most of those studies apart from being deeply unethical were also just deeply flawed and aren't good examples of innovation anyway. 

There's innovation everyday, new studies out all the time, new therapies, new understandings. You just need to pay attention.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428079832.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Innovation exists I never disagreed with that statement in my post. I said about how people talk less about such good experiments and do extensive research on the bad ones. Countless videos on YouTube and articles have been published on older expirements cross-analyzing it and talking about it.


Discussion on such taboo experiments led to even more innovation and understanding of psychology, unlike the better and more morally ethical experiments which stagnate at a single point  as most don't talk about them   AS MUCH and reduce the rate at which innovation happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428125637.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I said about how people talk less about such good experiments and do extensive research on the bad ones

OK but how is that psychology's problem? Seems more like an issue with the people talking about psychology, not the field of psychology itself.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428182803.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>But the people talking are the researchers themselves, they make extensively researched countless articles on those topics and quite few in comparison for the good expirements.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428232861.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>Where are you reading these things?

Yeah those experiments are still taught and talked about, largely as a cautionary tale on what not to do. It's important to learn from mistakes of the past. But countless other things are also taught and spoken about. Attention grabbing things will always grab attention, that's the way of the world dude. 

Do you want them to never be spoken of again? I'm still finding it hard to see what the view you want changed here is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428246042.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>I want my view that immorality in experiments leads to more discussion and innovation to be proven false.

I want to make my view that more ethical experiments and big inventions in this feild to be talked about more by laymen like me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428407381.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>You should have been more explicit about that in your op.

Well what do you want psychologists to do? 

The research you're talking about is out there, it's just that laymen aren't talking about it because we'll they're laymen. Why would they want to if its not as attention grabbing as the shocking stuff? Surely this is the same as any other science, the public will talk about cool super colliders or gene editing. But all the other stuff doesn't sound as catchy. 

Unless you want psychology researchers to double as marketing experts, you need to look for this stuff yourself if its something you want to know more about.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428568631.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>The main reason I want it to be more marketed is due to the taboo and lack of awareness in this deparment.

Unlike other medical feilds, pshycology and mental health has been quite taboo and very less awareness is them and most in my surroundings simply talk about the bad expirements that happened giving the sentiment that the bad expirements gave the most innovation.


I apologise for being less coherent in the post, I hadn't given it the thought it required for posting but I wanted clarification and understanding in this department.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428668824.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>It would be nice yeah if psychology got more positive attention.

But I think you've picked the wrong target of the post. What you want is for the media to pay more attention. Which can't be forced and tbh comes with its own pitfalls.

We already have to deal with "pop psychology". You see it all over twitter or other social media. Random posts with "psychology says..." followed by some random nonsense that gets spread and believed. Like the whole 10% of your brain thing that everyone believed for a while. If you really want to know the actual research you need to go to the reputable sources, which just aren't as flashy. 

The real nitty gritty research is always going to go on beyond the publics eye with the interesting stuff filtering through. That's pretty much the way of all things.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428779087.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Yet as far as I have seen , the lack of awareness in mental health and excess fear seemed to stem from lack of awareness.


You are right that those twitter bullshit is quite annoying and wrong side of it. I just hope that after giving it time, the excess fear in my community reduces with more positive sides and factual stuff come to light and unfortunately, only media seems to be the way.

I want psychology to be treated like any other medical feild and not to be feared either because of lack of awareness or stigmam</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428862334.0" user="vote4bort" delta="False">
    <text>And that's an admirable goal. I doubt it'll be achieved by declaring "psychology is fucked" though. 

Directing your efforts to spreading positive mental health awareness would be a much better use of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428871000.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Yes it was definitely a clickbaity mistake and I apologise for being ignorant and overgeneralising it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428973704.0" user="vote4bort" delta="True">
    <text>I think if you'd have stated your view as "there should be more awareness of psychology and mental health" not many people here would disagree with you. Its not perfect but awareness is certainly on the rise in a lot of places. But you can't expect it to just happen, people need to put in the worm. And if it's something you feel passionate about, there's plenty of ways you can help out yourself.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
