<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428051323.0" user="olidus" delta="False">
    <text>Science is an attempt to understand the world around us.

Most science experiments go by without crossing ethical/moral lines. The scientists who do get to live in infamy forever.

Think about other medical professions and how they got to where they are today. Psychology isn't inherently in the business of being unethical.

To condemn a field of study because of a handful of terrible researchers is heavy handed.

Scientists crossing lines is fucked up, not necessarily the field of study.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428096578.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Yes I condemned the entire field which was a clickbaity error and I apologise but I wanted to highlight how most stuff about experiments and psychology tends to talk about the older experiments rather than the new ethical ones.


And most importantly as far as I have seen, the most progress in research has been done only when they pass the ethical standards, at least that's what's popular.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428134224.0" user="olidus" delta="False">
    <text>Sure, some of the worst examples of scientific exploration are taught, mainly because it serves as both an example of ethical misconduct and how they formed the basis for a lot of current practice and theory. 

But in order to really say psychology is currently "fucked up", it would have to still be gaining on and forming the basis for the field.

Surgical techniques evolved from some pretty brutal practices, especially before anesthesia was widely used, and informs a lot of the current practices. 

Professional standards evolve and peoples expectations of ethical conduct along with it. People used to shrug when people with mental illness were experimented on, now we find that pretty abhorrent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428174988.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>My post wants to highlight that it's important to have lax ethics for innovation to happen.

Many ethics committees tend to stop experiments involving humans extremely quickly which halts innovation.


I should have given more context when I said psychology, I meant the experimentation department of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428209509.0" user="olidus" delta="False">
    <text>So you are suggesting that innovation cannot happen, or happen fast enough,  without crossing moral or ethical boundaries?

To which I would reply, fast enough for whom? The problem with modern researchers (and a good number of past ones), is that they refuse to acknowledge, or even undertake, generational work. They want the credit for a discovery and will do whatever it takes to get there.

Innovation is not inherently bad, but psychology as a field of study can continue to evolve its understanding without crossing moral or ethical lines. 

For example, if we could get around the moral conundrum of "personhood" and the ethical complications of cloning, we could make huge advances in medicine in a very short time period. But can we get there without it? Probably.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428262264.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>If possible can you explain your example a bit easily I am quite a bystander in this feild.

Fast enough to cause sensationalization and awareness to keep more and more experiments happening.

I know it's cynical to think, but I wish for more well-known and talked about research in this feild even if it's somewhat morally questionable  but not until it cause irreversible damage</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428413228.0" user="olidus" delta="False">
    <text>Walter Mischel's Experiment on delayed gratification 

Latane and Darley's bystander effect experiment 

Asch's Paradigm experiment (Conformity study)

Bandura's social learning experiment (Bobo Doll Experiment )

Festinger and Carlsmith Cognitive Dissonance experiments 

All of those examples are pretty classical experiments without moral or ethical implications that are some of the most cited and form the basis for a lot of derivative research and can be found is most PSYC 101/102 curriculums.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428541897.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, I have read up on a few of these and am aware of them on a surface level.

You are right that these are basics and well-cited no doubt and have quite a lot of importance. 

And I want such experiments to be more common and well known and more widespread unlike the earlier ones which seemed to me ( before this post) to have a much wider impact and cause of rapid innovation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428643865.0" user="olidus" delta="True">
    <text>I think it you view it as rapid expansion simply because not much was known in the field back then.

Think about the technological revolution or the Information Age. New things innovate quickly and then plateau until the next great breakthrough. There has not been any major innovation in the handheld device field since the smart phone. Does that mean no impactful innovating is going on? certainly not, it is just not leaps and bounds beyond what we already know.

Think about the battery, a simple chemical storage of energy that has remained largely unchanged. The next evolution will be solid state and that will change everything we think about stored energy.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
