<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43441371523.0" user="Rainbwned" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.  

I strongly believe that if a person cannot afford the 15 seconds to tally up the total cost of something, they are not actually interested in shopping around for price comparisons.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441485127.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>Are you against companies making it as easy as possible for consumers to compare?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441498363.0" user="Rainbwned" delta="False">
    <text>Not at all.   
The argument OP has is making it legally mandatory.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441528461.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>And the problem with that is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441573941.0" user="Rainbwned" delta="False">
    <text>I don't feel the need for the government to require that kroger list lettuce as 1.08 instead of .99. I don't feel like it's worth the massive overhaul, and I don't think that people keen on price matching lose anything more than a few seconds of their time.   
Personally I don't mind knowing that ticketmaster adds $50 to each $30 ticket, instead of just seeing an $80 price.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441606802.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I don't feel the need for the government to require that kroger list lettuce as 1.08 instead of .99.

Like every other country in the world does? You know the reason Kroger does that is precisely to fuck you, right? They want you to have the illusion it's cheaper so you'll buy it, even when it costs you more. In any other country that would rightly be seen as greedy dirty manipulation. 

Absolutely nothing wrong with the government saying that you can't try to trick your customers into spending more money. 

&gt;Personally I don't mind knowing that ticketmaster adds $50 to each $30 ticket, instead of just seeing an $80 price.

Same as above. They do this to fuck you and squeeze more money from you than you otherwise might if they had to show the full price. 

If you're okay with getting subtly shafted each time you go buy groceries then that's great, but others don't.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441797207.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Like every other country in the world does? You know the reason Kroger does that is precisely to fuck you, right? They want you to have the illusion it's cheaper so you'll buy it, even when it costs you more. In any other country that would rightly be seen as greedy dirty manipulation. 

This topic came up in Congress with gasoline and ability to advertise 'taxes included'. 

There was a very significant portion of the electorate who was completely against the idea. They wanted citizens to *know* what was added to the price of the product by government in taxation. 

Kroger is charging you 99 cents for that lettuce. They have zero say in any taxes collected on it. They don't keep anything from those taxes. If it it a 1.08 total, it tells the customer that they have to pay 10% tax rate to the government for buying that lettuce. 

I personally think this is very important. It makes people cognizant of the costs of taxation. 

&gt;If you're okay with getting subtly shafted each time you go buy groceries then that's great, but others don't.

Except you are not getting shafted. You are seeing the prices *Kroger* has for its products. The total you have to pay is that total from Kroger *plus the Federal, State, and Local taxes*.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441868376.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Except you are not getting shafted. You are seeing the prices Kroger has for its products.

You're missing the point. The price advertised on the shelf should be the price paid at the register. Doesn't matter if some of that money doesn't go to the store, because it's *the consumer* that matters most. 

"I'm gonna give you an inaccurate sense of how much you're going to pay because that extra bit doesn't come to me" is not an excuse. They're not gonna let you walk out of the store with your turkey if you only pay the "Kroger price". You are entitled, as a consumer, to know in real time exactly how much any item will cost you at checkout, period.

This is pretty much an exclusively American phenomenon. I spend a lot of time in the UK, many items in UK supermarkets carry VAT tax, but that's included in their shelf price. Your average Brit would be fucking furious to get to the till and pay more than what it said on the shelf. It's false advertising, pure and simple, just normalized here because that's all we've ever known.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441894641.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; You're missing the point. The price advertised on the shelf should be the price paid at the register. 

No. I get that. 

The problem is, it is fraught with problems when you have literally thousands of different taxing districts. What you pay is a combination of what the store is asking and what the government wants in taxation.

&gt;because it's the consumer that matters most. 

Not really. You just want this to be the case.

Frankly speaking, I *like* the transparency in the costs of taxation. 

If you buy a TV, you know the government's cut because it is the difference in the advertised price and what you just paid. 

Now tell me how much tax you paid on Gasoline....

&gt;This is pretty much an exclusively American phenomenon.

So? There are lot of uniquely American things. That is not a *bad thing*. 

&gt; I spend a lot of time in the UK, many items in UK supermarkets carry VAT tax, but that's included in their shelf price. 

And they don't have literally thousands of taxing districts either.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442011312.0" user="BrokkenArrow" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Not really. You just want this to be the case.

? Why would it not be the case? 

&gt;If you buy a TV, you know the government's cut because it is the difference in the advertised price and what you just paid. 

I don't give a shit what the government's cut is, what I give a shit about is being able to make a good decision with all the information available. That means knowing the full price that *I'm* gonna have to pay for something. 

It's pretty impressive to try to frame dishonesty about pricing as "transparency" about taxation. Feel free to point out what the taxes are on my receipt, but I want to know what I'll need to fucking pay to buy this item right now.

&gt;So? There are lot of uniquely American things. That is not a bad thing.

It's not bad because it's uniquely American, its uniquely American because every other country rightly decided that it was bad. 

If you think that taxes are missing from the shelf price here for *any other reason* than the fact that the retail industry groups lobbied for it, then they've done an incredible job with their PR.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442123629.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; ? Why would it not be the case?

Because a lot of regulations are written to ensure it is easy for business to comply. 

Being exactly what a 'consumer' wants is not always the best answer.

&gt;I don't give a shit what the government's cut is, 

Others do.

&gt;what I give a shit about is being able to make a good decision with all the information available.

Then you should know the local tax rates. 

&gt;It's pretty impressive to try to frame dishonesty about pricing 

There is absolutely nothing *dishonest* about this pricing. Claiming this does not make it true.

The prices are all advertised as XXX plus taxes. There is not one thing dishonest about that statement. 

&gt;It's not bad because it's uniquely American, its uniquely American because every other country rightly decided that it was bad. 

That is not an argument. It's an opinion.

I have repeatably told you *why* it is done this way. When you have literally thousands of different taxing districts in a country, it is impossible to clearly, properly, and accurately advertise the 'price' paid when you have chain stores located in *different* taxing districts. 

&gt;If you think that taxes are missing from the shelf price here for any other reason than the fact that the retail industry groups lobbied for it, then they've done an incredible job with their PR.

Spoken like a person who has never had to consider compliance with tax laws or how to operate a business. This is actually something that was discussed in a recent SCOTUS case. South Dakota vs Wayfair overturned past case law requiring sales tax collection for sales in a state without a physical presence in the state. It specifically discussed issues in Quill that technology had alleviated.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442140509.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>Would you agree that all fees that aren’t mandatory taxes be included in the base price?  Stuff like non optional “resort fees” for example?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442188903.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="False">
    <text>&gt; Would you agree that all fees that aren’t mandatory taxes be included in the base price? Stuff like non optional “resort fees” for example?

Yes - fees for the facility that are not 'optional' should be disclosed up front and clearly. That in my mind is a deceptive business practice.

They typically get away with it by stating only *some* clients have to pay these. If you are a 'member' of some club, those are not required. Places that rent timeshares don't charge the resort fees to owners for instance. 

The other way they get around it is stating there is a resort fee plus a per-night charge. You only pay the resort fee once and not 'per night'. This also complicates the pricing immensely. In total cost calculations, the 'per night' rate depends on how many nights you stay. 

Right now on VRBO, there are some obnoxious and deceptive fees added on to prices. These are typically called 'cleaning fees'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442233701.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>This is basically my view, but esp for hotels, I think taxes should be included too, because many towns with lots of hotels like to pass special hotel room taxes that are above and beyond traditional sales tax.

Also, towns with concert venues like to pass “entertainment taxes” which are similar to sales tax, but unique to the specific purchase.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442297520.0" user="Full-Professional246" delta="True">
    <text>I could readily see Hotels being required to disclose total rates. These, even as chains, have unique specific locations you go to. Different locations already have different rates. Requiring the nightly rate plus what taxes are isn't a significant burden. 

It's not like a Kroger grocery store or a Lowes home improvement store that carries the same item for the same price all over a state.

If you want more transparency on a concert ticket/hotel room, that is quite reasonable to me. If you want to play games with prices at commodity stores like Lowes - that is a fundamentally different situation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
