<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2560674926.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16ck5f2/cmv_focusing_on_ideological_purity_does_not_win/">
    <title>CMV: Focusing on ideological purity does not win elections</title>
    <original_poster>LaserWerewolf</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have encountered many people who openly say that they hate centrists more than they hate their actual political opponents. Fair enough, because ideologically they often have more in common with their opponents than with a genuine centrist, but when the election comes around the same people often ask why more centrists don't vote for their candidates. I don't know about you, but I think voting for people who hate me seems like a questionable idea. 

I have also noticed that in certain echo chambers (possibly this is a general feature of echo chambers) people are often insulted, verbally abused, or even excluded if they do not share every single belief common to the people in that echo chamber. Often this person then leaves and joins a different echo chamber where they are more welcome. 

Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity.

Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

I think this person would most likely start agreeing with Party B more and with Party A less after switching to the Party B echo chamber. I also think this person would be less likely to vote for a Party A candidate and more likely to vote for a Party B candidate after switching to a Party B echo chamber. 

To change my view, you would have to persuade me that focusing on ideological purity causes a greater number of people to vote for one's party. Bonus points if you can back this up with some kind of statistical data, but a purely logical argument could also be convincing.

&amp;#x200B;

&amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43508508186.0" user="kneeco28" delta="False">
    <text>I'm going to ignore the hate part of it, cause that's a whole different discussion.

Let's focus on this:

&gt; Let's say that a person starts out in a Party A echo chamber. They agree with 9 out of 10 of the main Party A viewpoints. But because they disagree with Party A one one single viewpoint, they are pushed out of the echo chamber by people who demand ideological purity. Now let's imagine that Party B says, "It is enough for us that you agree with us about this one viewpoint. We accept you." The person now joins a Party B echo chamber.

What does accept mean in this context? Does it mean simply welcoming and accepting support? No one has a problem with that. Or does it mean changing the position to align and engage this person? That's the rub.

Cause let's imagine the current US landscape.

If there's a Republican who agrees with Republicans on guns, taxes, climate change, trans people, "wokeness", etc... but completely opposes the Republican anti-abortion positions and that person therefore registered, donates, and votes Democratic, then great! Democrats will do nothing but pump their first.

But that's not actually how it plays out. How it plays out is the person leaves Team R because of abortion and suddenly there are people, on the periphery of Team D, that say "Hey! We can get them on our team, we just need to slow down on all the policies about climate change, guns, and trans people and focus on abortion!" 

And that is where people on Team D resist. 

No one on team D will say we don't want your vote for our agenda. What they do say is we don't want your vote *over* our agenda. Or, at least, they say so so long as they believe (right or wrong) that they don't need that vote to win. 

It sounds like you're arguing for people to be more welcoming, but you're actually arguing for people to be more conservative. Don't rock the boat and get more votes. And that is where you lose people.

It's absolutely true that there has to be some calibration. The center of a party should never embrace policies that the country as a whole mostly rejects. That is a road to electoral ruin. But you can't take that lesson to heart to the point that you just sell-out your principles and do whatever it takes to align with the center of the country, cause that's also a road to ruin - maybe not electorally, but in every single other way.

Your problem is your conflating demands on the party members with demands on the party itself. Democrats would be stupid to demand that every single Dem voter care about addressing climate change. But Democrats would also be stupid to do anything less than demand that every single Dem leader and elected official care about addressing climate change.

And, therefore, you have to balance. You can't have so many voters that don't such that the party doesn't. And it's not just like you know when that threshold has been crossed. And it's certainly not easy to undo once it has. So a degree of vigilance in protecting your notion of justice is necessary.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43509111918.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;It sounds like you're arguing for people to be more welcoming, but you're actually arguing for people to be more conservative. Don't rock the boat and get more votes. And that is where you lose people.

It applies to any faction, not specifically Democrats. 

Every political party is at least something of a big tent, and must appeal to a broad enough coalition to get representation. This inherently involves compromise. This isn't in any way exclusive to the left, the right, or anything else. 

You \*could\* have more, smaller parties and less compromise within each of them, but that requires a somewhat different system, and will require coalition building to get laws passed anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510058251.0" user="LaserWerewolf" delta="False">
    <text>I would so love for the USA to have a system which required coalition building. It would incentivize electing people who know how to cooperate.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43510133654.0" user="TheAzureMage" delta="True">
    <text>It'd be a better system. A proportional aspect to the system similar to what many countries in Europe use might be superior.

The two party system tends to boil things down to exactly two options for the general election, and for the primaries, candidates like to try to appear more radical than the other candidates to gain as many party voters as they can. 

In this respect, ideological purity \*can\* win elections right now, but in doing so, it creates an unhealthy environment in the long term.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
