<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742861216.0" user="marketMAWNster" delta="False">
    <text>As a conservative (Trump skeptical) involved in electoral politics there is really just such a large amount of people who resent the changing tides socially/culturally/economically etc. 

Socially - basically wokism. The destruction of civic religion, socialist tendencies, gender obsession, DEI etc

Culturally - celebration of effeminate men and masculine women, transgressiveism, modern art and a destruction of classical beauty in nearly every sense

Economically - the US is stagnating and lacking in dynamism (really since the 70s) and manufacturing is dying. Nobody is going to be able to fix this problem so conservatives really are just "mad" that the 1950s or 1980s/90s economies will not be returning. 

The biggest reason of all is that the government is so fundamentally untrustworthy at every turn 
Afghan wars
Covid response
Ukraine
Mismanagement of resources
Unequal application of DOJ (Obama irs scandal, Trump indictments, catholic attacks etc)
Degrading institutional trust across most metrics

Trump supporting populist are much different than old-school mainline GOPers. Many MAGA republicans are not really conservative in any sense except socially.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742923083.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>Right, so are you arguing that the composition of "conservative" has just significantly changed? What happened to the old mainline GOP people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742983349.0" user="marketMAWNster" delta="True">
    <text>They wre still there but I woukd say are dwindling (or at least not growing)

Roughly 50% of the party is pro Trump and the other 50% is some mix of antipathy or resentment to Trump. The growing part of the party is younger minorities (populist), Midwest white collar workers (populist) and gen z conservatives (populist). The base of the party (neocon GOP and old social security + social conservatism people) historically are dying off to age or are very suspicious of Trump or are moderate dems these days. 

They are still there - they are just being pulled along much like Bernie has pulled along some democrats (not to the same extent). If you look at the polls Trump has like 50% locked up and the other 50% is split amongst 7 people. The real issue is nobody in the GOP agrees on next steps.

Some want to moderate and become "more appealing" which usually means sacrificing values 
Some feel that the GOP has done nothing but "moderate" since Reagan and it has resulted in 2 Mediocre presidents and a long march to economic and social leftist
Some want to rejuvenate historical America (at least the ideal of the 50s or 80s) and think somebody like Trump can do it
Some simply want no change to anything in society and basically believe America is working just fine
Some really want the government to be radically reduced and turn more into a pre 1930s government.

That is alot of wildly different opinions all under 1 roof and the party really doesn't have a good grasp on what direction they should go (so it appears that the party is disunified)

Democrats - on the other hand - appear to all be headed in the dame direction and it is more of a matter of degree. Nearly all dems (except Manchin tester sinema) want more leftist ideas both socially and economically, so they all unify pretty easily (see Pelosi speakership). It's not like Biden or Bernie disagree much in principle, but rather to the extent 

Eg - Biden forgives some student debt, Bernie forgives all student debt etc. These are directionally the same but differing extents</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
