<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742860663.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="False">
    <text>I can't agree with this. Firstly, ignore all the personal stuff. Most people who actually have political values don't care about that, or at least don't care about it more than having a president who agrees with their agenda.

And when you look at policies, the first thing you gotta see is the Supreme Court. Trump guaranteed conservative dominance in the court for likely decades to come. His justices struck down Roe V. Wade, a conservative goal ever since the case was first decided.

And the rest of his governing was pretty good for conservatives as well. He passed a tax bill that was what they were all asking for. He reduced environmental regulations. The republican healthcare plan failed, but that lost out in Congress, hard to directly blame Trump.

Basically if you ignore the personal stuff, he was a standard republican. Could have been Jeb Bush in office. The one thing Trump has that the other republicans don't have is he proved he can win. DeSantis will not beat Biden, nor will Nikki Haley or Mike Pence or anyone else in the GOP. Trump probably won't either, but he wasn't supposed to win in 2016 and still did. So if conservatives want a win in 2024, he's likely the best they have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742913477.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK, so anti abortion, tax cuts, reducing regulation. The thing is, these policies are not actually particularly popular. But maybe they are popular with a section of the hard right, and that's what's behind this. In which case, how did the hard right get in the driving seat?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743006006.0" user="DuhChappers" delta="True">
    <text>Do you have any data showing those policies are not popular among republicans? Because the polling I've seen definitely disagrees.

https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2020/06/18/three-in-ten-or-more-democrats-and-republicans-dont-agree-with-their-party-on-abortion/

64% of Republicans agree with their party's abortion policy, as do 7% of dems for some reason.

https://news.gallup.com/poll/225137/americans-remain-negative-tax-bill-passage.aspx

Overall Americans disliked the tax bill, but 78% of Republicans liked it.

https://news.gallup.com/poll/355838/americans-revert-favoring-reduced-government-role.aspx#:

This shows that 72% of Republicans and 43% of independants think there is too much regulation right now. This is the only issue where the majority of Americans actually agree with them, it's definitely popular.

I think you underestimate the amount of Republicans that you would classify as "far right", to be honest, or you just need to shift the definition of what is extreme for them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
