<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43744085377.0" user="friendlywhitewitch" delta="False">
    <text>I think it’s a misinformed idea that these people don’t believe in anything. They do believe in things, and rather strongly, but those beliefs are not the kinds of things they want to advertise openly. Primarily; people, regardless of their color, who support Trump are racist. You mentioned family, personal religion, and a number of other categories, but the biggest lie even he has conjured up is “I am the least racist person ever”. When Trump makes attacks on minorities and says “make america great again” he really means “make white people unilaterally powerful with no accountability like it used to be where the lower races know their place and don’t talk back”. 

He evokes the fundamental idea of what conservatism is and means; to “go back” to the traditions and systems of the nation before modernity and to reject progressive ideals for a more conventional or conservative society. In America that is, definitionally, defined by white supremacy and racism. To “go back”, to “make America great AGAIN” would require us to fully embrace the racism that formed us and even if it didn’t I don’t think Trump voters would actually want that. 

The racism is the point; many Americans will not say it but fundamentally they believe the white race is superior and should have power over the entire world but America most especially. It’s the reason Barack Obama constantly fielded racist attacks: cartoons of him as a monkey telling whites what to do, insults that his wife was a gorilla or a man in a dress because she is a black woman who doesn’t look like Beyoncé, that he was a Kenyan Muslim secret immigrant; it was all to let him and his voters know “we don’t take orders from black people and we don’t elect them to power.”

I grew up with these attacks and seeing the proto trump party, the Tea party, promoting the most racist and openly, hatefully white supremacist ideas and being mostly embraced by the voters on the right even if people like John McCain and Steven Schmidt and other establishment conservatives didn’t like it. I’ve debated a lot with right-wing voters and conservatives and trump voters; consistently the result I find is that whether eloquently or clumsily, they try to hide their racism and become offended when they know you have found them out. Whether consciously or unconsciously, they know they are racist, and they don’t like you or I knowing it. So they will tell you to your face they want state’s rights and family values and whatever else the new line is, while quietly voting for people they know are racist like themselves. I genuinely think that John McCain lost the presidential race when he corrected some racist white lady at his campaign who came to the stage and started calling Obama a secret Muslim, an Arab, a terrorist sympathizer etc, and McCain said “No he is not, he is a good man and we just disagree on policy points”. He made a line in the sand and said “Republicans who want racism, white supremacy, and racist conspiracy theories can go over there, ones who don’t can come with me” and the entire party went over that line and formed the modern GOP we see today, putting Trump on the throne and being willing to destroy democracy to get him there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745008088.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>You've really majored on racism here. Why do you think that's the most important issue?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43745339725.0" user="friendlywhitewitch" delta="False">
    <text>Because it is. I have talked to people who voted for trump back in 2016 and their answers, some more obvious than others, were clearly race based. Some said their issue was about abortion, but even that is race related as many conservative and right-wing political groups have expressed fears about the “browning of America” as Ann Coulter (right political ideologue and author of popular right-wing books) once put it. The more common name for it is “white genocide” and “white replacement theory” and rightwing news pundits like Tucker Carlson of Fox News talk about it constantly.

When I say their answers were race based, what I mean is that while they USUALLY didn’t (but sometimes did) say outright they don’t want non-white people “taking over” or “browning America “. Instead they will say “illegals are overrunning the country and changing the demographics to suit democrats, someone has to stand up to that”. For me, as a Mexican Indigenous person who is also European in ancestry, this struck me as insane because the “illegals” they were talking about originally come from this country, where the majority of those excluding them are from other countries originally. When I brought this up, their answer UNILATERALLY was “well this is our country now and we aren’t giving it to anyone, and if your people (mexicans) want it back, they can take it!”

It became clear to me both from talking to these people, and from looking at what they were saying online, on tv, and from their hero’s books and popular manifestos, that all the talking points about “family values” and “christian principles” are outright lies. They couldn’t give two shits about those things. The real goal is singular and supersedes all other goals or values: the white race must have dominion over the world and over all lower (non-white) races and anyone who tries to stop that needs to be gotten rid of permanently, non lethally or otherwise. The elite Republicans in congress have ousted Lizz Cheney (whose voting record is more conservative than Trump’s or anyone else’s), Adam Kinzinger, and any other republicans who wont go along with Trump who were already few in number. Why are they doing that? Because low taxes, family values, and conservative principles are not their primary concern, making a white dominant ethno-state where Christianity is the state religion and the law is essentially Evangelical Shariah Law. They openly advocate for Christian Nationalism, no more separation of church and state, and for any book pertaining to racism or slavery or civil rights to be banned in schools and burned at public book burnings. That is why I focused on race; because it alongside Evangelical Christianity is the main motivating animus behind their politics even if they are too cowardly to openly admit their fascist and white supremacist beliefs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43748711561.0" user="l_t_10" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Some said their issue was about abortion, but even that is race related as many conservative and right-wing political groups have expressed fears about the “browning of America” as Ann Coulter (right political ideologue and author of popular right-wing books) once put it

Black women have the most abortions though, if its about white supremacy why seek to limit or ban it?
How does those square with eachother

"In the District of Columbia and 29 states that reported racial and ethnic data on abortion to the CDC, 39% of all women who had abortions in 2020 were non-Hispanic Black, while 33% were non-Hispanic White, 21% were Hispanic, and 7% were of other races or ethnicities."

https://www.pewresearch.org/short-reads/2023/01/11/what-the-data-says-about-abortion-in-the-u-s-2/

That runs counter to the goal of racism doesnt it?
Unless they are courting groups like Hebrew Israelites, Black Hammer i suppose</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43749003735.0" user="friendlywhitewitch" delta="True">
    <text>It squares because what black women are doing is not relevant to the reproduction of the white race and the birth rates that determine whether white people are replacing themselves, lowering in number, or having higher birth rates and therefore more white children. White women are the gatekeepers of existence regeneration for the white race on a fundamental and physical level. 

It is white mothers who are their primary target, because by preventing or banning abortion, they ensure more white mothers are producing children for the white race. So what if more black women have more children as a result? Black people have been a labor engine in America and have been since the advent of transatlantic African slavery and the seeding of the first plantations in the New World, and this is true whether they are working class or incarcerated as both provide their labor to enrich the country. 

Black women having lots of unplanned or unwanted pregnancies was not a threat to the white supremacy of yesteryear during slavery or pre-Roe V Wade, why would it be a threat to a white supremacy supplemented by modern technology, science, and military force?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
