<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2599419093.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/16zmklx/cmv_the_way_that_conservatives_have_got_in_line/">
    <title>CMV: the way that conservatives have got in line behind Trump shows that they never really believed in anything in the first place, apart from belonging to a tribe and beating the other tribe.</title>
    <original_poster>Kavafy</original_poster>
    <original_post>As things stand, Trump has already been chosen as a presidential candidate once and is massively in the lead to be chosen again. Yet he seems to go against traditional conservative values in so many respects. 

* Family values: he's a known adulterer, "grab 'em by the pussy" etc.
* Religion: clownishly ignorant about the Bible
* Managerial competence: ignorant of basic facts about world and US affairs
* Honest dealing: on his own admission he's exploited bankruptcy rules several times to get out of debts. And where are the tax returns?
* Promises kept: where's the money from Mexico for the wall? Where's the "beautiful" healthcare plan that we were promised?
* Decorum: I don't think I need to say much about this one. Belittling, name-calling, tantrums, the list goes on.
* Democracy: "if I lose then it was rigged". This is probably the biggest of them all. 

I understand that some conservatives have distanced themselves. But the majority of the GOP seems to be behind him. What explains this, except for wanting to feel like you're in the in-group, and wanting to own the stupid libs?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43742846515.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="False">
    <text>My dad, who is almost 70, often recalls how he was able to pay for college without debt by working a part time job.  Can you imagine college being so cheap and wages being so high that student loan debt didn't exist?  It sounds like a fantasy but it used to be a reality.

Trump campaigned on make America great again.  Suppose your a blue color worker in America whose seen their wages stagnate or decline in the last 20 or 30 years.  all you hear about from the democratic party is LGTBQ and DEI and then alone comes Trump blaming outsources of jobs, moving manufacturing to Mexico, and reducing low income migrant workers.  

I think just blaming support on Tribalism doesn't capture the whole story.  Trump is a lair and a con artist and he conned a lot of people.  Make America great again was a powerful slogan and there was probably some truth behind it.

And as you say, a lot of conservatives don't support him.  Some love him, and others sort of dislike him but still buy the maga story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43742883975.0" user="Kavafy" delta="False">
    <text>OK, so the deteriorating economic situation provided fertile ground for Trump. And he's selling a story about making things better. And I guess he was a disruptor and not a career politician. 

So the issue would be what? We need to make the country better? What confuses me abotu this is, doesn't every politician kind of have the same message? Why haven't conservatives turned away from Trump in disgust at his complete repudiation of 90% of what they're supposed to stand for?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43743033950.0" user="jatjqtjat" delta="True">
    <text>&gt;What confuses me about this is, doesn't every politician kind of have the same message?

I guess the obvious answer is that is message was more convincing.

His message had clear antagonists: China, Immigrants, and the concepts of outsourcing and offshoring.  I don't think he's wrong about these things.   An increase in the supply of labor, according to econ 101 should drive wages down.  Off shoring jobs reduces the local demand for labor which should also drives wages down.

I think there was and still are not a lot of politicians trying to court working class white people.  Trump was able to identify that group felt politically alienated.  Its a HUGE group of people, and he crafted a message that appealed to him.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
