<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2660036271.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/17zpt4f/cmv_rape_victims_have_a_harder_time_processing/">
    <title>CMV: Rape Victims Have a Harder Time Processing Their Rape Because Society Expects Them To Have the Expected Feeling of Being Raped.</title>
    <original_poster>DayOk2</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the main reason why rape victims have a harder time processing their rape is because society expects them to feel like how a rape victim is supposed to view. For example, society expects rape victims to have a particular reaction to being raped like they should cry, be numb, be scared, or be embarrassed, which makes it harder for rape victims to process their rape because they will feel like they are an exception to rape victims.

My conclusion is that rape victims would have an easier time processing their rape if society explicitly tells them to feel whatever they want to feel like. Change my view about why society does not necessarily make it harder for rape victims to process their rape.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44141571944.0" user="reginald-aka-bubbles" delta="False">
    <text>How are they supposed to feel? Rape victims by definition have been violated in the most intimate way. Rape is a physically violent and emotionally brutal experience, so I really wouldn't expect myself to respond any other way if I were assaulted. 

  
All of those emotions/actions  you listed (crying, fear, embarrassment) could also be felt after other traumatic experiences too, not just rape. Do you think it is more likely that this is society's expectation or just how human beings generally respond to trauma?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44141585749.0" user="DayOk2" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Do you think it is more likely that this is society's expectation or just how human beings generally respond to trauma?

I think society might have conditioned people to feel something rather than these people feeling what their mind wants to feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44141613191.0" user="reginald-aka-bubbles" delta="False">
    <text>OK lets assume you have someone who has never been a part of our society, they're just dropped in Adam and Eve style, fully formed and cognizant but without our societal conditioning. If this person were raped, how would you expect them to feel?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44141659910.0" user="DayOk2" delta="False">
    <text>Mild to high chance of being traumatized. Society intensifies the confusion and denial that rape victims feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44141710519.0" user="reginald-aka-bubbles" delta="True">
    <text>Because at its core, it is a traumatic event. So these responses would then be natural, not societal. The societal response is following the natural one, not causing it - I guess that's what I'm trying to get at, because society doesn't happen in a vacuum. If you remove society, they will still have a hard time processing a rape because a rape is a hard thing to process.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
