<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="285265861.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4pu8jp/cmv_paytowin_games_are_not_unfair_or_unethical/">
    <title>CMV: Pay-to-win games are not unfair or unethical</title>
    <original_poster>pocketMAD</original_poster>
    <original_post>Pay-to-win games are not unethical.

	After frequenting /r/clashroyale, a subreddit dedicated to Supercell’s new multiplayer strategy game, one notices a vast amount of complaints on the immorality that exists in Supercell’s business model. I agree the game designed to be pay-to-win: purchasing certain options grants one a greater advantage. Regardless, a company offering paid advantages for their video game service is not unethical or evil.
	This method is fair. If one decides their gaming experience is fine as it already stands and that purchasing advantages simply is not worth the cost, then refrain from paying. Heck, go and create your own game with your own business model.
	There’s nothing wrong with complain about a video game. I think complaining is healthy for a community as the company can view the complaints and better their game. I just think complaining about pay-to-win in general is wrong because companies need to make money. 
	Another counter to my argument is pay-to-win games often construct an elitist top-200 filled with players known as “whales.” They put in tons of money to stay at the top, making it impossible for players who pay nothing to ever reach that high. But these people spend most of their day sustaining their high ranks. These people are Youtubers and twitchers. It’s their job to be at the top to sustain their audience. If you wish to be at the top, make your free youtube or twitch account, learn how to gain followers, do it, and then you too can be at the top. This seems perfectly fair to me.


_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28580229698.0" user="GenderNeutralLanguag" delta="False">
    <text>Pay-to-win games are not unethical, but they are unfair.

Any competitive game SHOULD be based on the skill and ability of the player, not how large her bank account is.  To say I'm better at Game A because I've spent 1,000 on lots of pay-to-win items is simply wrong.  I'm not better, I have more money.  This is unfair.

They are not unethical.  Games are made by companies.  Companies exist to make money.  That companies offer "feel like a winner" for cash money isn't unethical.

Let's take this out of the virtual world and look at it in terms of a real world competition.  There is a foot race where you need to drag a 300 pound sled 1 mile.  This is a fair race.  It's got the same set of rules and same difficulty for every one.  Now, if the race orginizers started offering special promotions where for enough money you could reduce the weight on the sled all the way down to zero, and move your starting position up all the way to the finish line.  This would no longer be a fair race.  There are different difficulties and different starting positions.

We don't see basket ball games where one team has paid for 15 players on the court and the other could only afford to pay for 4 players on the court.

This wouldn't be unethical though.  Everyone knows the game is rigged.  Every one knows that it's unfair.  The people with no sleds starting at the finish line are just paying for an "I'm a winner" trophy that doesn't actually mean anything.  I can go down to the trophy shop and buy myself trophies.  No one considers stores that sell trophies unethical, even if you can buy them without doing anything to earn them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580289460.0" user="pocketMAD" delta="False">
    <text>I rarely pay money in Clash Royale, and I think the game is fair for non-paying players. There are enough non-paying players to sustain a fair environment insomuch you stay below a certain rank. However, above that rank, one must pay money to thrive. Yet I don't really view this as unfair because there's already a great deal of leg room for non-paying players to compete. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28580591781.0" user="EmporioIvankov" delta="True">
    <text>That's a direct contradiction. Clash Royale imbalances the playerbase. It gives clear advantages based on factors irrelevant to the game. Those things are unequal. They are unfair, by definition.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
