<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="299317869.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4y7f59/cmvit_is_unreasonable_to_hold_black_people_to_the/">
    <title>CMV:It is unreasonable to hold black people to the same intellectual standards as the general population.</title>
    <original_poster>Sky-Jellyfish</original_poster>
    <original_post>[IQ is strongly correlated with school performance, years of education, and job performance.](http://psych.colorado.edu/~carey/pdfFiles/IQ_Neisser2.pdf) IQ tests (along with other tests such as the SAT) consistently show African people to be less intelligent. 

["8. The bell curve for whites is centered
roughly around IQ 100; the bell curve for
American blacks roughly around 85;"](https://www1.udel.edu/educ/gottfredson/reprints/1997mainstream.pdf)

["The four data sets can be averaged to give an IQ of 68 as the best reading of the IQ in sub-Saharan Africa."](http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0160289609001275)

If attending university or working in upper management in a business requires a high IQ (say one standard deviation above the average or 115) then we should accept that a smaller portion of black people are capable than the general population.
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28697279444.0" user="nikoberg" delta="False">
    <text>Hey OP, this is a topic that comes up a lot. I found [this](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/48usgx/cmv_i_believe_black_people_have_a_lower_average/d0mpy0w) was a pretty good comment that covers most points that come up. (Credit to /u/Doppleganger07)

The tl;dr of this is two things: 

1) IQ is an imperfect measure of intelligence, which doesn't actually have a unified, commonly accepted definition by all the experts. IQ tests show *something*, but it's not equivalent to "intelligence."

2) Many, *many* factors other than genetics influence intelligence. It's impossible to eliminate all these factors when trying to find out whether a demographic group as broad as "all black people" has lower IQ, and we know in the past that groups with lower IQs and actual genetic differences based on demographics didn't have lower IQs because of genetics but because of environmental factors, which are very much at play with the black population. It therefore seems quite likely that there's no genetically based difference to intelligence at work.

For convenience, I've quoted the whole thing below. The original post has links to sources that are not included in the quote, so please go there if you'd like them.

&amp;gt;This statistic of course, doesn't take into account anything other than race. Let's go through why most of the academic community isn't concerned about this.

&amp;gt;1) The gap we see here is not at all unique. There have been many instances of populations of people with lower than average IQ that have closed the gap entirely.

&amp;gt;For example, women used to score far lower than men on IQ tests. This is no longer the case since women have gotten more educated. In this case, we are starting to see the IQs of women surpass those of men (in general)].

&amp;gt;Another example is the IQ data gathered from East and West Germany prior to unification. East and West Germans were / are genetically indistinguishable, but there was a gap between the two reaching 17 points in some areas. If you take IQ as being mostly genetic, these results are highly problematic.

&amp;gt;A third example (and I could go on for longer but this is already long enough) is the Flynn effect. This is the well documented phenomenon that observes populations IQs rising as they develop economically. The average black person today gets the same score as the average white person did in the US in the year 1950. The average black person's score is 15 points higher than the average white person just 100 short years ago. Unless you think there was a major genetic change in whites in the past 50-100 years, the rise in scores (for both races) was due to environmental changes. Whites have simply enjoyed a higher standard of living (then and now) which leads to them having environments more conducive to learning.

&amp;gt;I know I said that was the last example I'd give, but let me do one more because I think it illustrates my point. Another big difference in IQ scores can be seen between northern Americans and Americans in the South. In fact, there have been studies done where blacks in the north scored higher on IQ tests than whites in the south. Are northerners different genetically than southerners? If not, then why the difference? If we accept whatever that difference is, why are you not using that to explain the black - white difference?

&amp;gt;The above examples give pause to the idea that IQs for groups are set in stone (they 100% are not and that's a fact), and that genetics are the primary determination of a persons cognitive ability.

&amp;gt;2) IQ scores only measure one type of intelligence (poorly)

&amp;gt;IQ scores can only measure one type of intelligence, and it doesn't even do that as well as we'd like. IQ tests don't accurately measure strategic intelligence, or even creative intelligence. 

&amp;gt;This is a huge problem since these forms of intelligence that the IQ tests cannot measure are some of the most important. Creativity lies at the soul of every major invention. It lies in the soul of every song, movie or play. Similar things can be said of strategic thinking.

&amp;gt;Would we think worse of people like Jimi Hendrix and Ghengis Khan if we found out they scored low on an IQ test. If we would, we probably shouldn't.

&amp;gt;3) IQ scores cannot measure potential

&amp;gt;There are certain types of questions asked on IQ tests that you can get better at with practice. For example, pattern recognition and memorization are two things you can improve on drastically throughout your life (if you practice). This has two problems. One, it gives advantages to people who do similar kinds of thinking activities daily (this explains some of the Flynn effect we discussed earlier). Two, we may mistake someone had a low genetic limit based on someone not normally having to perform those kinds of activities, or not having as good of tools throughout their lives. Here is someone discussing this here.

&amp;gt;4) At this point people will often say that when you control for certain variables the differences don't entirely disappear. For one, the differences fall away quite rapidly once you start controlling for things (income and neighborhoods mostly). Second, we have no way of controlling for other things that effect IQ testing scores.

&amp;gt;One such example is Stereotype Threat. This is a phenomena that we've seen in not only IQ scores, but in math, reading, sports and (essentially) any other area where a stereotype exists. Stereotype threat is the phenomena that shows people perform worse if there is a fear that they will further a certain stereotype about themselves. The presence of this cannot be totally corrected for (although it can be manipulated somewhat).

&amp;gt;Another example is cultural differences. We know that there are many ways that different races raise their children that influence their cognitive development. I really want to wrap this up, but one such example is the word gap.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697343428.0" user="Sky-Jellyfish" delta="False">
    <text>That's a strong argument, but I'm going to add onto an argument /u/FreakyCheeseMan made in that thread.

If human populations have been seperate enough for long enough (I understand that there is some gene flow, but humans are obviously aren't homogenous.) wouldn't you expect to see differences in intelligence?  I'm kind of talking out of my ass for this next part so please correct me if I'm wrong. In East Asia for example Rice Paddies were a major source of food for thousands of years.  Rice Paddies are difficult to cultivate.  Many Sub-Saharan African tribes never took to building complex farms but instead continued hunting and gathering.  Could this difference in lifestyle for millennia affect intelligence of the people?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28697392869.0" user="nikoberg" delta="True">
    <text>In theory, yes. In practice, we don't meet those conditions. First of all, there's a *lot* of gene flow between human populations. As far as population barriers go, we are basically leaky sieves. There's been some debate back and forth, but the general consensus today [is that "race" as we understand it doesn't really exist biologically.](http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/ajpa.22899/abstract)

Does that mean there are zero genetic differences between "races?" Well, there are always genetic differences between demographic groups. There just aren't that many, and the likelihood they can have such a large magnitude in effect on IQ seems remote. 

Second, why would rice farming be so much more difficult than tribalism? A random tribesman from the Amazon rain forest will know hundreds of plants on sight, their use as food or medicine, the animals that like to feed on them or use them for shelter, the behavior and use of the *animals*, and so on. The farmer isn't stupid- he will, of course, know in great detail the process of farming rice, raising *his* animals, the weather and the best time to plant crops, local political conditions, and so on. Farming isn't easy. But why would you assume being a hunter-gatherer is any easier? Surely intelligence is an adaptive trait in both circumstances?

(By the way, lots of Africans were farmers too. So it's not even the case that there's a huge divide between Africans and the rest of the world in how they lived.)
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
