<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="323449689.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ckndl/cmv_i_should_give_up_trying_to_stop_climate_change/">
    <title>CMV: I should give up trying to stop Climate Change</title>
    <original_poster>FifthDragon</original_poster>
    <original_post>We made some small progress here in America during the last presidential term, but despite that, we've already passed the point of no return with regards to Climate Change. No matter how hard we try, we can't fully reverse it. Now we (will shortly) have Donald Trump in the Oval Office, a man who has promised to repeal all Climate Changes acts, while the House and Senate are filled with a majority who likely agrees with him. The way I see it, the only way we can even stop Climate Change, not to mention reverse it, is to have someone in office as radical as Bernie Sanders with a House/Senate majority on his side. And that's just *my* country, don't get me started on China. I don't want to drown, please CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28898147130.0" user="nanonan" delta="False">
    <text>You should give it up, and concentrate your efforts on local, practical, actual environmental positivity like planting trees. As far as climate armageddon, you should definitely relax. Nature is incredibly resilient, versatile and adaptable, if we can survive ice ages we can handle a little warming.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898210141.0" user="FifthDragon" delta="False">
    <text>I'll be honest, I hadn't thought of your first point. Is there anything else I can do locally?

&amp;gt; Nature is incredibly resilient, versatile and adaptable, if we can survive ice ages we can handle a little warming.

I'm less worried about nature than I am about us humans.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28898238598.0" user="nanonan" delta="True">
    <text>Humans are even more adaptable and resourceful, we'll be perfectly fine. I'm sure you can find somewhere to volunteer your time for environmental projects, just try to find ones that are actually doing things apart from revenue raising.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
