<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="337048102.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5ko3za/cmv_some_people_want_companies_to_pay_a_carbon/">
    <title>CMV: Some people want companies to pay a carbon tax, others do not. I believe the best compromise is an optional carbon tax.</title>
    <original_poster>antilisterine</original_poster>
    <original_post>There are people who care about climate change who want companies to pay a carbon tax - well they can pressure companies to prove that they're environmentally friendly and they can do that by paying the optional carbon tax. It's like they're saying, hey, we care so much about the environment, that we're willing to pay a tax that we don't even have to pay.

However those who don't care about climate change can remain unaffected by it - they can buy products and use services from companies that refused to pay the optional carbon tax. Also, as I've mentioned before, I don't believe that disadvantaged people should be forced to thank society for treating them like shit or be forced to help people with good lives whilst their lives are miserable - in this scenario, they have a choice. These people can choose not to support companies that pay the optional carbon tax so that way they're not thanking society, they're not helping people with good lives and they can remain completely unaffected by it.

It just seems like a win-win situation to me. So why can't we fight for an optional carbon tax instead? I see literally no problems with it.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29005904980.0" user="ElysiX" delta="False">
    <text>The whole point of a carbon tax is to take away or at least shift that choice from the complacent and slow market.

It and similar schemes can only work of the damage to the environment is factored in as a unavoidable cost and tradeoff that raises prices. Desperate or greedy people won't care if its optional, so you don't give them that choice.

All the optional tax will achieve is to give piece of mind to the people that buy alternate more expensive products or lessen their consumption. But thats not the objective of the tax, the objective is to lessen the environmental effects.
So it has to affect everyone in order to force the companies to either change or make the product more expensive so people buy less of it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29005953994.0" user="antilisterine" delta="False">
    <text>My point is that if companies have a choice, then we will still have the same outcome anyway. Desperate and greedy people will care once their profits are hurt which will happen when more people care about climate change and decide to support renewables. This will help to protect the environment.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29005966665.0" user="FlyingFoxOfTheYard_" delta="True">
    <text>This depends. Will this honestly hurt their profits more than a hefty carbon tax? Especially in the industries that would lose the most such as resource companies? It will take a whole lot of profit loss for a coal company to compare to the loss they'd get from a carbon tax. And honestly, most people truly don't care enough. They still buy products made in sweatshops, products made using slavery, products that destroy the environment. They know, and don't care. Why would this honestly change in the slightest? You assume people care far more than most of them actually do.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
