<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="352222222.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5tpcem/cmv_privacy_is_actually_a_bad_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Privacy is actually a bad thing</title>
    <original_poster>Wagawaga2401</original_poster>
    <original_post>Around the XIX century, the concept of privacy was very different than the current one. Your personal data and identity would travel with great difficulty to a different state, and someone in a different country would find nearly impossible to know personal details about you, much less interact with you in a threatening enough way. That does not mean information was safe either; gossiping and the such were as rampant then as they are now; but thanks to how slow information travels, they were much less dangerous. You could start a new life by traveling in horse with enough money to a different part of the country, where nobody knows you.

Right now, thanks to the modernization of identity documents and such, that's nearly impossible; but I don't think that's a problem.

In the modern age, there are many problems where a person of public interest and/or hate has their privacy breached; death threats, harassment, violence and all sorts of things can happen. The usual approach is to try to disappear; to go back to a state of privacy; change names, appearance, address, and online identities. But all of this could be avoided if the assailants didn't have privacy either. 

It would probably be impossible to implement, but I think that if law enforcement agencies had the ability to minutely track people's activity, both online and in real life, many, many instances of harassment, crime, rape and similar things could be prosecuted, if not prevented. It would certainly be much more difficult to effectively plan a terrorist attack or mass shooting.

And to most of the citizens who (I assume) will see this, whose worst crime will probably be online piracy or drug possession/use, this won't be as much of a problem as it will be an increase in safety, not only from terror attacks but from common everyday thefts.

This argument seems so obvious and intuitive to me that I find it hard to believe that it's not the mainstream opinion. What is it about privacy that people fight so hard to defend? Is there a basic principle of social relationships that is passing right above my head, or is everybody else in the world a dirty criminal with horrible things to hide? Occam's razor points to the first one, and that's why I'm here. Please change my view.




EDIT: what I've learned so far:
&amp;gt;the government isn't flawless and unbiased, and privacy allows you to retaliate with much more strength than information about it. also people suck.

I'm going to sleep, so see you in a couple of hours, pals. ^I ^stayed ^here ^for ^the ^first ^4 ^hours ^so ^I ^think ^I'm ^good ^to ^go

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29125252025.0" user="hayhen14" delta="False">
    <text>This is objectively wrong on multiple levels and this is why. 

Firstly, allowing government absolute access to everyone's privacy for the reason of stopping bullying and harassment is extremely dangerous; in the same way that violating free speech is dangerous. Free speech and right to privacy exist to check state tyranny. If opposition to the government is disallowed, the state because tyrannous and violates the rights and good of the citizens. If citizens are able to write and talk about the evils of the government they are able to organize and oppose the beginnings of an evil government and thus perpetuate a just government. Privacy is the same. Arguing that no one should have a right to privacy would be the same as saying that I don't need free speech because I have nothing to say. Without privacy any opposition to a government would be impossible and thus a check by the citizens to the beginnings of an evil government would be impossible. An absolute right to privacy is just as essential to an absolute gurantee of free speech. Disallowing it is a surefire way to despotism. 

Secondly, the argument that "all of this could be avoided if the assailants didn't have privacy either" is extremely dangerous. You argue that this would be helpful because many crimes would be able to be prevented. This is very similar to the Patriot Act that allows government spying in order to prevent terrorism. Sacrificing human rights for national security is always dangerous. Would you want to live in a society in which human rights are systematically violated in order to save a few thousand lives? No, saving lives isn't worth it if it results in the gross violation of rights. 

The prevention of terrorism or rape or anything else you mention is not worth the violation of human rights. I am more likely to die by lightning than have those happen to me. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29126116154.0" user="Wagawaga2401" delta="False">
    <text>My question is, is privacy really a human right? I believe my life would have developed just fine even if I didn't have the ability to hide it. I don't think I'm actively hiding anything from my friends or a loved one right now. My basic argument is the "nothing to fear, nothing to hide" mentality, and I think most of the fear comes from being alone and exposed, if that makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29127230711.0" user="hayhen14" delta="True">
    <text>Privacy is intrinsically related to property. It is a truism that rational beings have a right to property. I have the right to decide whether or not to share my belongings, and I have sole ownership of things that I have acquired.  If I purchase a book, I am allowed to do what I want with it because it is mine. This includes my right to keep it private and/or secret. If I have information such as personal emails I have a right to ownership of those. Spying on me and violating my privacy violates my ownership of digital objects and thus violates my right to property.

The nothing to fear nothing to hide mentality is the same as saying  I don't need free speech because I have nothing to say. How is opposition to an evil government possible without privacy? How are citizens allowed to have ownership of everything if they are forcibly shared? Privacy is an absolute, any violation is immoral. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
