<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="352222222.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/5tpcem/cmv_privacy_is_actually_a_bad_thing/">
    <title>CMV: Privacy is actually a bad thing</title>
    <original_poster>Wagawaga2401</original_poster>
    <original_post>Around the XIX century, the concept of privacy was very different than the current one. Your personal data and identity would travel with great difficulty to a different state, and someone in a different country would find nearly impossible to know personal details about you, much less interact with you in a threatening enough way. That does not mean information was safe either; gossiping and the such were as rampant then as they are now; but thanks to how slow information travels, they were much less dangerous. You could start a new life by traveling in horse with enough money to a different part of the country, where nobody knows you.

Right now, thanks to the modernization of identity documents and such, that's nearly impossible; but I don't think that's a problem.

In the modern age, there are many problems where a person of public interest and/or hate has their privacy breached; death threats, harassment, violence and all sorts of things can happen. The usual approach is to try to disappear; to go back to a state of privacy; change names, appearance, address, and online identities. But all of this could be avoided if the assailants didn't have privacy either. 

It would probably be impossible to implement, but I think that if law enforcement agencies had the ability to minutely track people's activity, both online and in real life, many, many instances of harassment, crime, rape and similar things could be prosecuted, if not prevented. It would certainly be much more difficult to effectively plan a terrorist attack or mass shooting.

And to most of the citizens who (I assume) will see this, whose worst crime will probably be online piracy or drug possession/use, this won't be as much of a problem as it will be an increase in safety, not only from terror attacks but from common everyday thefts.

This argument seems so obvious and intuitive to me that I find it hard to believe that it's not the mainstream opinion. What is it about privacy that people fight so hard to defend? Is there a basic principle of social relationships that is passing right above my head, or is everybody else in the world a dirty criminal with horrible things to hide? Occam's razor points to the first one, and that's why I'm here. Please change my view.




EDIT: what I've learned so far:
&amp;gt;the government isn't flawless and unbiased, and privacy allows you to retaliate with much more strength than information about it. also people suck.

I'm going to sleep, so see you in a couple of hours, pals. ^I ^stayed ^here ^for ^the ^first ^4 ^hours ^so ^I ^think ^I'm ^good ^to ^go

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29124920605.0" user="choobe" delta="True">
    <text>Your whole argument hinges on the governments doing what's right, but the government is not this morally just, static entity that we should blindly trust. How easily would it for instance be to "accidentally" leak some private information about political opponents and (lawful) opposition to your regime? 

Most people don't want people around them to know everything about them, even if it's all perfectly legal, so it's essentially blackmail waiting to happen (this would be things like porn preferences, if they cheat on their partner, if they've had an abortion, and stuff like that), you might say "well, those people *should* be exposed!", but personally I don't want the government playing moral judge about things that should concern noone but the person themself. 

The other issue is implementation, this stream of data would be so big, it's essentially impossible to gather and store, but since you already admitted that in the OP, I won't say anymore about that. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29124966230.0" user="Wagawaga2401" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the government is not this morally just, static entity that we should blindly trust. 

I do admit that it was a fairly idealistic version of the government; but you must also take into account that the current politicians got where they are by keeping many, many secrets; if every aspect of the candidates' lives were pried over the magnifying glass of the press, it would be difficult for someone with bad intentions to get into power. This is a really good argument, thought, so I think you deserve a ∆.

&amp;gt;Most people don't want people around me to know everything about them, even if it's all perfectly legal

This is more of an issue about education. People who are used to wearing shoes indoors might be shocked when asked to take their shoes off when entering a house, and vice versa. We are used to hiding information because everyone else does the same, and being the only exposed one in front of people who hide information is really unfair. I think this would also promote a more healthy relationship between people and porn/polygamy, since those are usually taboo topics that are frowned upon despite their (apparent?) ubiquity and normality. The abortion issue is much more delicate, though, but I can only put a delta per comment. I think.

As a footnote, yes, I said polygamy is seemingly normal, but if you do it when your partner expect fidelity, you're a jerk. I think, however, that in a world without privacy, people would be more open to talk about it and/or to commit seriously to monogamy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29125014980.0" user="choobe" delta="True">
    <text>How about "unacceptable" opinions? Take weed for instance, it's fairly accepted now (relatively speaking at least), but just a few short years ago many people saw weed as basically the same as heroin, and anyone advocating for legalizing it was a druggie who wants children to have easier access to drugs. I don't think that would have changed if people didn't get to state their opinion and discuss the issue anonymously without fear of it blowing up in their face in real life the next day. 

To your education point: 

A lot could be solved with more education, but not all, and some problems would be much worse. It would be so easy to discriminate based on things *you* found morally repugnant, but weren't technically illegal to discriminate on. Even if you yourself did stuff "they" found morally repugnant, you could just surround yourself with like-minded people. I think this would incite more fear of doing things out of the norm than acceptance, simply because we humans love to feel superior to others, and we also love like-minded people. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
