<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29214935314.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>People still use drugs in the Philippines right?

There are still drug addicts there correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214941349.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Duterte is not as able to effectively enforce policy due to the Philippines being a third world country with corruption and he still made drug usage go down. The United States would have much better outcomes due to a better police force.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214951848.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>Do you think the American public would tolerate public executions or corporal punishment for something as simple a smoking a joint? Or helping others to smoke a joint. 

Or the idea that the American Constitution forbids cruel and unusual punishment so your idea would be impossible anyway. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214969244.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you think the American public would tolerate public executions or corporal punishment for something as simple a smoking a joint? Or helping others to smoke a joint.

This is not about usage, it is about distribution, and I was mostly talking about harder drugs such as heroin.

&amp;gt;Or the idea that the American Constitution forbids cruel and unusual punishment so your idea would be impossible anyway.

Cruel and unusual punishment is a social construct and its interpretation differs according to time and culture. Placing such a reverence towards the constitution constitutes the bibliolatry that the founding fathers wanted to prevent hence why they considered it to be a living and breathing document.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215027970.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>Cruel and unusual punishment is part of the Bill of rights. 

Which is a very important part of the Constitution. 

We can't have public beatings and killings because people have a right against those practices. 

A pesky thing that Constitution is. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215039166.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>You just responded to my argument against your position by restating it. This is the exact thing that Christian fundamentalists do when they are challenged. The only difference is that your bible is the constitution and it doesn't even say it is infalliable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215046147.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>You didn't make a meritorious argument. 

If we win the war on Drugs by ripping up the Constitution then we really didn't win anything. We just became a country that got rid of a bunch of human rights. 

Sure it would a lot easier to target crime if we removed all human rights, but we wouldn't have a county.

Let me know what rights would you let me strip from you. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215054366.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you care so much about human rights that you see it as being some sort of god? I don't care about severe punishments for crime since I am not a criminal and only criminals should care about that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215061163.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>The better question is why you care so little about them. 

I asked you a simple question. 

What rights could I take from you. I'm still waiting my answer. 

To speak, assemble, due process before the law. 

You have a lot to pick from. And you still have to justify your case. And you haven't done that yet. 

Sure we could murder every single person that we even thought did drugs. That would solve things as well. 

Or we start to look at drugs as a medical problem and not a criminal one like other countries have done. Because that seems to work a lot better. 

At least it works a lot better then trying to justify taking rights away from people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215071720.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>I already said that I am perfectly OK with forgoing my right to not be subject to cruel and unusual punishment since I will never need that right. I guess Freedom of Assembly is another one I am willing to give up since I don't intend on overthrowing the government any time soon.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29216557920.0" user="Bruggenbrander" delta="False">
    <text>Imagine they suspect you of distributing drugs, wrongly ofcourse. Now imagine they indeed disregarded human rights and torture a confession out of you. Would you feel society improved because drug use would drastically decrease? If so how many innocent people can the government kill and or torture before you feel it would not be worth it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217293379.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If so how many innocent people can the government kill and or torture before you feel it would not be worth it?

A greater rate than the rate of violent crime as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217793074.0" user="Bruggenbrander" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah and that is impossible to account for. So in practice it can't work</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217842405.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yeah and that is impossible to account for.

It is very easy to figure this out. Just look at crime statistics and compare them to the rate of false convictions. If you can't gather statistics on false convictions then there is no point in caring about them since abolishing the criminal justice system will cause too much chaos. 

Or are you just saying that you don't like what I said? I can't tell.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217859451.0" user="Bruggenbrander" delta="True">
    <text>No when one throws out human rights it becomes even more likely false convictions will go up, which cannot be accounted for. For a real world example look at the Philippines. And the way one uncovers false convictions now takes time and relies on interviews with the presumed perpetrator. Kill the presumed perpetrator and you won't easily uncover the false conviction. 

You can stop crime, pretty easily even by giving up rights. You already said you have no problem giving up Human rights so why not fix the problem instead of this retarted bloodlust thing? Chip all people to now their location at all times. Outlaw cash money and monitor all currency movements. Implement blood tests on a nationwide level on regular but unannounced moments. This would solve the problem mostly.

Now you can go even further to weed out crimes
Start a eugenics program and only people deemed fit (no disposition for addictions, high iq and eq intelligence) get to breed. Kids are brought up in education camps and be taken away from their parents as soon as they are born. Within a generation or 3 they won't even know what drugs is.



Now don't get me wrong I'm not advocating this because I kinda like my human rights and free will, even if some people do horrible things with it. It just seems to me that you just want to kill people which fixes nothing as past examples have learned. Either you control the environment or accept that crimes will happen and need to be handled with respect for human rights.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
