<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29214978811.0" user="swearrengen" delta="False">
    <text>If corporal punishment and public executions gone ahead and successfully deterred distribution, then the War on Drugs would still have been a failure, because it would have been *unjust* - a violation of human rights, a betrayal of the values of personal freedom, and a destruction of American identity. America would become a fascist tyranny with moral standing no better than the Phillipines. That would be like winning a battle to lose the war, or cutting off your nose to spite your face, or draining the baby out with the bathwater.

But it wouldn't have worked anyway - precisely because America is such a rich honeypot of buyers and such a large market, and the the values of capitalism are so entrenched in the American psyche that a higher government penalty would simply mean a higher black market price and financial reward to the distributor/seller. In America (and not so much in other countries perhaps) as risk increases, so does reward/incentive - and the world is full of very poor people willing to take that risk.

Switzerland won the war on drugs - by giving them away for free! That's how you destroy the production/distribution incentive, you nationalize it and offer it at zero cost. What drug seller wants to sell into a market where the government has reduced the price to zero?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214995958.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If corporal punishment and public executions gone ahead and successfully deterred distribution, then the War on Drugs would still have been a failure, because it would have been unjust - a violation of human rights, a betrayal of the values of personal freedom, and a destruction of American identity. America would become a fascist tyranny with moral standing no better than the Phillipines. That would be like winning a battle to lose the war, or cutting off your nose to spite your face, or draining the baby out with the bathwater.

Human rights are a human construct and one that isn't benefiting American society at the moment unless you consider massive drug use to be a contribution to humanity. A self identity based on a dysfunctional social construct isn't one worthy of being preserved.

&amp;gt;But it wouldn't have worked anyway - precisely because America is such a rich honeypot of buyers and such a large market, and the the values of capitalism are so entrenched in the American psyche that a higher government penalty would simply mean a higher black market price and financial reward to the distributor/seller. In America (and not so much in other countries perhaps) as risk increases, so does reward/incentive - and the world is full of very poor people willing to take that risk.

Increasing risk does not inherently increase incentive. There reaches a point especially when the risk is risk of bodily harm as opposed to financial problems that nobody will be willing to be a drug dealer due to the expected outcome being negative.

&amp;gt;Switzerland won the war on drugs - by giving them away for free! That's how you destroy the production/distribution incentive, you nationalize it and offer it at zero cost. What drug seller wants to sell into a market where the government has reduced the price to zero?

Methadone subsitution for rehabilitation is not the same thing as giving away drugs for free to undercut dealers. Plus why would you want to undercut dealers since that would just mean that you have the same problem but it is government subsidized.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215016142.0" user="750lucklord" delta="False">
    <text>Are you honestly suggesting that we get rid of or seriously scale back human rights? You said human rights aren't doing America any good but the way I see it, human rights are the reason it's called the land of the free.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215026120.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Human rights might be the reason why America is called the land of the free but does that means that they are good for America? I think that China will overtake America due to not having human rights holding it back from progress.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215032626.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think that human rights are a good thing?

Great. There is a reason then why we can simply ignore what you have to say. 

Sure we can have anything if we control and restrict and ignore all human rights but we are left with a society that most wouldn't like to live in. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215054314.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>What would you not like about a society like Singapore's?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215079927.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="True">
    <text>Singapore is a small island nation-state with a population of just over 5 million people.

It can only stop the influx of drugs because they heavily monitor their borders.

The USA simply cannot do that. Aside from the fact that the US population is more than 60x the size of Singapore with 120 miles of coastline as compared to the continental USA's approximate 9000 miles of border.

As for their society?

They have no free press or freedom of speech and the government often censors any politically, racially or religiously sensitive material.

Homosexuality between men is outlawed, human trafficking is a serious issue, and there are no rights for foreign workers. Meaning migrants are not given a minimum wage, limited hours, safety protections, or employment benefits leading to approximately 1 in 4 people in Singapore being a migrant as opposed to the approximate 12% in the USA.

And on the topic of caning, caning is never used as the sole punishment in Singapore. It is only ever used in conjunction with a minimum of 3 months in prison. People aren't "caned and sent on their way" they are caned and then thrown in prison.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
