<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="368037533.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/634bkt/cmv_in_the_future_when_the_average_age_of_death/">
    <title>CMV: In the future when the average age of death is significantly higher than today, the age of adulthood will also be significantly higher.</title>
    <original_poster>synergistali</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is just something that popped into my head and I thought about it for a few minutes. 

The reason I think that if the average age of death is higher that the age that a person is considered an adult will be higher is because that is how our society has functioned so far. Long ago children were considered adults at maybe 13 or so. Now it's 18. I think this is because the age of death being greater now then long ago. So I'm just extending this reasoning to the future. 

Really I made this post so that I can hear some better reasoning as to why this would happen or why it wouldn't. 

Cheers!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29250954486.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29250978419.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>Really good points! But I think my arguments still hold even though you may not think they are strong factors. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251000140.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251009031.0" user="synergistali" delta="False">
    <text>Not being able to get pregnant is something which occurs due to your body aging. If you can live longer then your body will be healthier for longer. So you should be able to get pregnant at a much later age if you will also die at a much later age. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29251021378.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
