<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="370308710.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/64h012/cmv_it_is_not_necessary_to_prove_that_gays_are/">
    <title>CMV: It is not necessary to prove that gays are "born this way" in order to advance gay rights.</title>
    <original_poster>poolerboy0077</original_poster>
    <original_post>Perhaps in response to people who claim that being gay is a "lifestyle choice," there has been a push by gays and gay allies to prove that gay people are born this way. Even Lady Gaga decided to make it an anthem for the LGBT community. Many people make this assertion in the context of gay rights, including many well-educated and smart people like Judge Richard Poser did in his concurrence for the latest federal appeals Title VII discrimination case. I hold the position that, while it may be true, this is unnecessary in the context of advancing gay rights. Insisting as much, in my opinion, is a kind of naturalistic fallacy. You are welcome to change my view.

**EDIT:** Thanks everyone for posting. You are free to continue to post here and I'll hopefully get around to them if time permits, but I have to go to bed. To sum up what's occurred below, I remain unconvinced by the arguments presented. I was hopeful that there would be some kind of rationale or perspective I hadn't yet come across but a lot of these arguments I've already encountered (for several years now), and needless to say I don't find them to be very persuasive. :( I'm hopeful someone will come to this thread with something I haven't yet thought of before.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29269787874.0" user="clickstation" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it's necessary. 

Why is racism wrong? Because it's treating people differently *because of things that are out of their choice, things they're born with.*

A restaurant for example can reject a potential customer because they stink. Or because they dress inappropriately. Or because of their behavior. But not because of things they can't control: their race, age, gender (in most cases), etc. 

It's okay to say "patrons must wear suit and tie. If you won't wear them, more power to you, but don't come here." Why is that okay? Because it's preference vs preference. We prefer this kind of outfit, you prefer that kind of outfit, then we're just not a good fit. There's no discrimination here; the only thing keeping them from coming here is **their own choice.**

If we think being gay is a choice, then the same thing can happen: "you sir can like men, but you're not welcome here. You're welcome anytime, as soon you choose to like women."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29270180508.0" user="hotbowlofsoup" delta="False">
    <text>Not being born that way, isn't the same as it being a choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29271489112.0" user="clickstation" delta="False">
    <text>That's an interesting point, shame you stopped there. Can you elaborate? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29272818934.0" user="hotbowlofsoup" delta="True">
    <text>Sure. I think more of what we are as individuals is nurture than we like to admit. When we're young we experience all kinds of stuff, that shapes us into the persons we are. That doesn't mean it's a choice what kind of person we became, or what things we prefer.

It's difficult to explain this without it seeming like a negative thing though. Because the most apparent and commonly accepted examples are trauma related. 

I started wondering about this, because I'm gay myself, and I've noticed a very common family situation with a lot of gay guys I know: The lack of a strong father figure. Either they have single mothers, or very overbearing mothers and "weak" fathers. That's anecdotal, I know, but it seems like in this conversation it's completely ignored.

On the other hand when a girl has daddy issues, it's commonly accepted she had a rough relationship with her father, if one at all. A girl like that isn't born that way, but it's not a choice for her to be like that either. Maybe the problem with that scenario is, people think it *is* a choice.

I don't know if gays are born that way. But it's like a taboo to even talk about it. And it really shouldn't matter.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
