<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="376661722.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/68961m/cmvfreedom_of_speech_should_not_be_limited/">
    <title>CMV:Freedom of speech should not be limited</title>
    <original_poster>shad0w-fax</original_poster>
    <original_post>I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits. Even in case if the speech is offensive to people. One can choose not to listen but not to take away my right to say it. Before someone suggest the "fire in a theatre",I recently came across with this speech of Christopher Hitchens and would recommend you to watch it (https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=4Z2uzEM0ugY)
One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? Who would you give authority to decide for you what is and isn't right to think and say?
Obviously, it is not an ideal case. Of course the best way is to have a perfect individual to make these decisions but, have we not seen that at last it always ends badly. That kind of authority would be tyrannical.
I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly. No one person should be given so much power. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29321430520.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I strongly believe that freedom of speech and expression must have no limits.

Eh no. This applies only to governmental institutions. And institution who have big influence, reach and obligation to public (news, movies, literature, radio, TV, etc...) . That is specifically what Christopher Hitchens is talking about. Every one of his remarks are made in regards to governments and regimes. Since that is his area of interest and framework he is talking about.

However Free Speech doesnt apply to private institution. Or at least not as much. They are dictating the rules, because they are paying for the platforms they give you. Take reddit for example. Any admin can censor anyone's opinion as they wish. And rightfully so. Moderated discussion is the most productive.

Airlines have a strict rules what you can or cannot say in plane or airport. Or even how you can or cannot behave. If you start shouting on plane in air about bomb. Then other people can get angst, can freak out, which can be incredibly damaging in plane. Which is why a personal is perfectly in rights to "shut you up".

Theatre is basically a metaphore about the government. Indeed Christopher says that the official said this quote, just a he was locking up the Yiddish speaking socialists.

&amp;gt;One big question is-who will be the one deciding that what is and isn't right to say? 

Ultimately its at the discression of the private companies. And current government. Altho I agree that public / free speech should be given incredible weight. I do not think it should be infallable 100% of the time. There are genuenly times where reducing your right for free speech can greatly benefit the situation. Simply because you filter in only the relevant information. 

A lot of people do not like this view. Because it can mean that this can be missused. But then again, everything can. Its not really argument to say it can be used for bad purposes.

&amp;gt;. That kind of authority would be tyrannical. I would like to give analogy of democracy being imperfect as compared to a benevolent dictator BUT we know dictatorship always end badly.

IF there is a catastrophe. The government will forcibly override the private institution ability to broadcast TV, because they want to get the news about the catastrophe across. Likewise with public broadcasts, etc...

The difference is that the situation is important. And government genuenly works to benefit the people. But is still tyranical after a fashion.



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29322576081.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks,i realied it after some reply that what I intended to post was about hate speech but I was late.Also I was too naive to draw B/W pictures and forming binary opinions.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29322729599.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Changing your mind is here awarded by delta. If this comment changed your mind, give it delta please.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29322755514.0" user="shad0w-fax" delta="True">
    <text>Can i give any number of delta?Because i framed my opinion so incorrectly that almost every comment makes me realize my mistake.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
