<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390098992.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6g96b4/cmv_i_believe_in_death_of_the_author_but_only_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe in Death of the Author, but only for some forms of art</title>
    <original_poster>PeptideBond007</original_poster>
    <original_post>If you're not familiar with the Death of the Author concept, [here](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/DeathOfTheAuthor) is a link that explains it (warning: TVTropes).

I have had many discussions with people about this theory in the past, and although none of them have convinced me to change my mind I am still open to the possibility. 

_____


**Where I believe Death of the Author applies:** physical art (sculpture/painting/drawing) and literature (poetry/prose). Since these forms of art are inherently more subjective, I think it makes a lot of sense to argue that the creator may be unconsciously channeling things outside of their original intention. Since all of these forms of art rely entirely on the creative vision of one person, any number of things in that person's personal history or life experiences can influence their work in ways they don't realize. I also think that works of art like these are distanced from their creators in ways that other art is not, and this distance allows for greater freedom of interpretation.

To give an example, Mary Shelley's *Frankenstein* is often analyzed using the context of Shelley's own issues with her father. Shelley probably did not intend for this to influence her work and might not have agreed with some interpretations of the main character's oedipal tendencies. In my opinion, this does not make those interpretations wrong.

**Where I believe Death of the Author does not apply:** performance art (films/TV/theater). These forms of art are less subjective. They also function by a creative consensus between performers, directors, producers, etc., meaning that their vision and motivation has to be much more clearly defined. Performance art even comes with *documentation* of these motivations in the way of stage or script direction. In a book, if a character says "I'm sorry," it is up to the reader to interpret that character's motivations based on the rest of the text. In a performance, the line "I'm sorry" is often accompanied by directions in the script to indicate those motivations for the performers' benefit. Performance art is also much "closer" to the artist than physical art or literature is, so it cannot be decontextualized in the same way that those art forms can.

To give an example, television followings in the modern era of internet fandom are very eager to "ship" characters outside of the intentions of the director/screenwriter/performers. This sometimes goes as far as fans arguing that a character's sexuality is actually different than the creators say it is (e.g. that a straight character is actually gay or bisexual based on their own interpretation of the show). In my opinion, these interpretations are objectively wrong.

_____

I suppose this CMV has two potential deltas – either convince me that Death of the author applies to performance art or that it doesn't apply to physical art/literature. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29427616221.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>The death of the author is a concept that describes the power imbalance when it comes to art. An artist (or group of artists) may very well develop a performance with a clear intention, vision, and motivation - but the audience is still going to have their own personal interpretation independent of authorial intent. That intent (if it is known) may inform the audience but the fact of the matter is that once your art is out there in the world you no longer own the message.

This applies to all forms of art, no matter how "subjective" they may or my not be. Anything can come with clear and documented visions and motivations, from abstract sculpture to Christmas pagents. But the existence of clear authorial intent doesn't impact the power the audience has over the message.

It's like in the Mel Brooks movie *The Producers*, the main characters funded a play written by a neo-Nazi with the intent of creating a bomb and scamming an insurance company. The author of the play created the play to pay homage to Adolf Hitler. Yet the audience decided it was a comedic satire and a hit, annoying the author to no end and putting our main characters in jail. Who had the power? Was it the producers? The author? The director? The actors? Or the audience?

Edit: Another example might be a group of cooks for an event. They all documented an intent to provide satisfying and tasty food for the event, right? But does that intent impact the audience's taste at all? Nope. No amount of cooking an apple pie with the intention of it tasting good is going to impact an audience member who just plain doesn't like apple pies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427653250.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like food is separate from art because "taste" in that case is a lot more universally agreed upon. Intent doesn't really factor in at all in that case.

*The Producers* is a really interesting example and one case I haven't considered as thoroughly. However, when I referred to theater I meant it in terms of the sum total of the production. Probably the majority of the people involved in *Springtime for Hitler* saw the production as satire in the same way the audience did. If you're just talking about the author's vision (i.e. the script), I think that would fall under literature instead. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427670501.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>My food example was to show how intent is unimportant when it comes to personal taste, it's just an illustrative example that I figured we would both quickly understand.

Like let me give you a second example - I wrote out my post with the clear and documented intention of changing your view, yet you did not award me with a delta and your view was not changed. My message was not conveyed as I had wanted it to be.

You can't speculate on how the majority of the people involved in Springtime for Hitler saw the play, since we're not privy to their experiences. But I'm not sure why having more people with a more unified intent means anything to the audience.

I think you're confusing the ability for a larger group to develop a message more likely to be recieved in that way with the notion that the audience still doesn't hold all of the cards when it comes to the message.

The other people involved with Springtime for Hitler weren't interviewed by the audience ahead of time. It was the audience who controlled the entire message after the show was put on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427699774.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>In the case of *Springtime for Hitler,* I think the only reason that they got anyone to agree to do it was because they assumed it was satire. It would be a hard argument to make that *all* of them were Nazis. The way the actor playing Hitler portrayed him makes this pretty clear, I think.

However, following that train of thought to its logical conclusion does bring up a potential flaw in my viewpoint. Are there any cases of films/TV/plays that were an earnest effort by the entire production to impart one message but were interpreted by the audience as something entirely different? I don't know of any, but if you do then I think I'll have to give you a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427793095.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I feel like we're talking past each other - it doesn't matter what the production of Springtime for Hitler intended, the audience received a message wholly separate from that.

And as for an example I'll use skinheads glorifying American History X - if that's not a clear case of the message being muddled by the audience I don't know what is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427825368.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>I think maybe I haven't articulated my viewpoint clearly enough? What I'm trying to say is that for performance art, an audience member interpreting a performance in a different way than was intended by the production is "wrong." I don't *literally* mean "wrong" because ultimately it's art, not fact. I just mean that it's invalidated by being able to ask the cast/crew/etc specific character motivations and meanings behind gestures or other subtleties.

In the case of American History X, I'm not sure that really counts because the general consensus still agrees with the viewpoint of the creators. I was thinking more along the lines of people trying to make a propaganda film and accidentally making something that went down in history as a poignant anti-government satire. Or maybe people trying to make a serious, issue-driven artistic film and instead making something that is widely agreed upon to be a hilarious comedy. The more I think about this, the more sure I am that something like this exists but I still can't think of any specific examples....</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427852393.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I don't literally mean "wrong" because ultimately it's art, not fact.

It's art, not fact. So the death of the author applies just as much to performance as anything else. I think this sentence perfectly encapsulates my point.

You can claim that their interpretation is more "wrong" for all sorts of reasons. But personally I find authorial intent (regardless of how many authors) to be the weakest justification for an interpretation. Textual justifications are much more compelling.

&amp;gt; I just mean that it's invalidated by being able to ask the cast/crew/etc specific character motivations and meanings behind gestures or other subtleties.

No more than anything else is invalidated by the opinions or the author or authors. The text must stand on its own. If you're doing a large production of an interpretive dance meant to represent the changing of the seasons and the audience comes out discussing how your dance beautifully conveyed the stages of life then you can sit there and scream, "it's about the seasons you dolts!!" until you and every other dancer is blue in the face. But the fact remains that the audience read it differently than you intended.

&amp;gt; In the case of American History X, I'm not sure that really counts because the general consensus still agrees with the viewpoint of the creators.

General consensus is, like the intent of the author, a moot point. The text stands on its own, that's what the death of the author means.

If you watch American History X and you walk out of the experience thinking that neo-Nazis are cool because of it then you've gone against both intent and general consensus - yet your interpretion is just as valid if based off of the text.

I'm not saying that an individual can't take things like general consensus or authorial intent into account when trying to figure out how they personally interpret something - just that others are perfectly able to throw all of that away.

Interpretation is itself subjective. That's why when doing an alaysis of a work you might very well come to different conclusions than the person sitting next to you.

The fact that two people can see the same work and come to different interpretations of that work is compelling enough for me to consider the author(s) good and dead. The audience decides for themselves what the message of a work is.

Believe me, as an artist I *wish* I could literally force people to see things the way I want them to see it.

&amp;gt; I was thinking more along the lines of people trying to make a propaganda film and accidentally making something that went down in history as a poignant anti-government satire. Or maybe people trying to make a serious, issue-driven artistic film and instead making something that is widely agreed upon to be a hilarious comedy. The more I think about this, the more sure I am that something like this exists but I still can't think of any specific examples....

Maybe duck and cover? If I recall correctly it was intended to make people feel safer in the face of certain death. But it was largely treated like a dumb joke because everyone knew what was up.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427885603.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>I think we are talking past each other. You're saying that because performance art is still art, death of the author automatically applies and the creator's intentions are automatically invalid. I'm saying that I don't think it should apply in the same way because of the extra depth of information/motivation involved.

If a character in a play has a stage direction telling him to act sad and he doesn't act sad (even though he's trying to), that just means he's a bad actor. If an author intends to write a character as acting sad but it doesn't come off that way, it changes the meaning of the piece.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427901269.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying they're invalid, just that I think the art stands on its own, always. There's no way around it. You can construct a very well crafted argument for why you should receive X message incorporating intent, stage directions, anything you want.

I'm just saying that the death of the author concept means that the work stands on its own when it comes to analysis. I can sit here and hem and haw about how people should be reading my play but I have no control over them *or* the message once the work is out there.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427930860.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>This is just coming down to a fundamental difference of opinion. You're telling me what you believe, but you're not telling me why.

Here's a counterexample to your assertion that you have no control over the message once it's out there: sometimes, when I'm watching TV, I can't understand what a character is saying due to sound effects or unclear enunciation. There have even been a few times when I've misunderstood what was said badly enough that I actually took the opposite meaning from what was intended (ex: they said "did" but I heard "didn't"). Would you argue that my interpretation of the dialogue is just as valid as the "correct" version?

In my opinion, a misinterpretation like that is wrong, and it can be corrected by consulting official scripts/transcripts released by the production team. I argue that this is the same as if I were to consult the stage directions in these scripts because I couldn't tell what emotion an actor was trying to portray, or the meaning of some gesture that was made.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427958090.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; This is just coming down to a fundamental difference of opinion. You're telling me what you believe, but you're not telling me why.

Well yeah, we're discussing a subjective concept in how you analyze art. If you think authorial intent is important more power to you.

My position comes from a consideration of what is important to me as part of analysis. I find art analysis to me much more enriching and engaging when forcing the text to stand on it's own.

&amp;gt; Here's a counterexample to your assertion that you have no control over the message once it's out there: sometimes, when I'm watching TV, I can't understand what a character is saying due to sound effects or unclear enunciation. There have even been a few times when I've misunderstood what was said badly enough that I actually took the opposite meaning from what was intended (ex: they said "did" but I heard "didn't"). Would you argue that my interpretation of the dialogue is just as valid as the "correct" version?

The message was impacted by the sound, and this impacted the audience. Had you not bothered to look up what the original line was you might never had known, yet you would have formed an opinion.

That said, I don't think mishearing a line is the same thing as misinterpreting it. You say that the death of the author does come into play in literature, right? But would you consider a typo in the edition you're reading to be a misinterpretation or not?

&amp;gt; In my opinion, a misinterpretation like that is wrong, and it can be corrected by consulting official scripts/transcripts released by the production team. I argue that this is the same as if I were to consult the stage directions in these scripts because I couldn't tell what emotion an actor was trying to portray, or the meaning of some gesture that was made.

There's something about your steadfast adherence to intent when it comes to plays that's been amusing me for a while now, because you keep bringing up stage directions from the script.

Plays aren't *intended* to be read, they are intended to be watched. You're not supposed to sit there and read along with the cast.

The script informs the performance, it isn't some kind of ultimate authority on the play. If, for example, an actor changes a line for a specific audience (like by making a local reference) that changes how the audience might react to it. Are you arguing that in this case the audience should not pay attention to the performance or something?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
