<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390098992.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6g96b4/cmv_i_believe_in_death_of_the_author_but_only_for/">
    <title>CMV: I believe in Death of the Author, but only for some forms of art</title>
    <original_poster>PeptideBond007</original_poster>
    <original_post>If you're not familiar with the Death of the Author concept, [here](http://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/DeathOfTheAuthor) is a link that explains it (warning: TVTropes).

I have had many discussions with people about this theory in the past, and although none of them have convinced me to change my mind I am still open to the possibility. 

_____


**Where I believe Death of the Author applies:** physical art (sculpture/painting/drawing) and literature (poetry/prose). Since these forms of art are inherently more subjective, I think it makes a lot of sense to argue that the creator may be unconsciously channeling things outside of their original intention. Since all of these forms of art rely entirely on the creative vision of one person, any number of things in that person's personal history or life experiences can influence their work in ways they don't realize. I also think that works of art like these are distanced from their creators in ways that other art is not, and this distance allows for greater freedom of interpretation.

To give an example, Mary Shelley's *Frankenstein* is often analyzed using the context of Shelley's own issues with her father. Shelley probably did not intend for this to influence her work and might not have agreed with some interpretations of the main character's oedipal tendencies. In my opinion, this does not make those interpretations wrong.

**Where I believe Death of the Author does not apply:** performance art (films/TV/theater). These forms of art are less subjective. They also function by a creative consensus between performers, directors, producers, etc., meaning that their vision and motivation has to be much more clearly defined. Performance art even comes with *documentation* of these motivations in the way of stage or script direction. In a book, if a character says "I'm sorry," it is up to the reader to interpret that character's motivations based on the rest of the text. In a performance, the line "I'm sorry" is often accompanied by directions in the script to indicate those motivations for the performers' benefit. Performance art is also much "closer" to the artist than physical art or literature is, so it cannot be decontextualized in the same way that those art forms can.

To give an example, television followings in the modern era of internet fandom are very eager to "ship" characters outside of the intentions of the director/screenwriter/performers. This sometimes goes as far as fans arguing that a character's sexuality is actually different than the creators say it is (e.g. that a straight character is actually gay or bisexual based on their own interpretation of the show). In my opinion, these interpretations are objectively wrong.

_____

I suppose this CMV has two potential deltas – either convince me that Death of the author applies to performance art or that it doesn't apply to physical art/literature. Change my view!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29427622502.0" user="Mitoza" delta="False">
    <text>You're slightly misunderstanding the scope of the claim. A sculpture's form can be analyzed as individual geometric curves as well as materiality. The choices of the form and the materiality can be seen as a script of sorts. For example, it is clear that Damien Hirst had to construct a tank around the shark to keep the formaldehyde from escaping in *The Physical Impossibility of Death in the Mind of Someone Living*. The individual component pieces are not subjective, those choices had to be made for it to be what it is. What is subjective is the final object or the constructed phenomenon, or rather, the meaning is subjective.

To your example of film, you must expand the scope of the work to encompass the whole of the finished product. A character may say "sorry" and there may be narrative or artistic reasons why that may be, but that's just one curve of the film's form. What is really being interpreted is the whole context. The question you're trying to answer isn't "why is this character apologizing" it's "why am I being shown an apology" or "what are my views about this apology". To that end, film and performance is just as subjective.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29427671960.0" user="PeptideBond007" delta="False">
    <text>I'm really intrigued by your first paragraph – do you think you could elaborate a bit more? I like the idea of being able to differentiate between practical vs creative choices, but in practice I'm not sure how that can be reliably achieved.

As for questioning character motivations in film, some people do actually create their own motivations and insist that they're just as valid as the actual intended ones. For example, an actor can say "I'm not playing this character as gay – his relationship with this other character is just a friendship" and I think that's really the only valid interpretation of that performance. Meanwhile, the nature of literature means that characters' motivations are more ambiguous and open to interpretation. One semi-popular interpretation of *The Great Gatsby* argues that Nick Carraway is actually gay, and I think that's a valid interpretation based on the available text.

Edit: I guess my thought is that in performance art, what's going on inside a character's head is much less subjective than in literature because there are multiple people dedicated to explicitly defining it. No one can ask Nick Carraway what he was thinking when he gazed admiringly at Jay Gatsby, but they can ask Tobey Maguire what his character was thinking when he gazed admiringly at Leonardo Dicaprio.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29428338295.0" user="kaijyuu" delta="True">
    <text>you're giving an actor the privilege of objectively defining the performance when you don't give a writer the same benefit? i know writers (especially of series) who have notes, pages and pages of character backstories, timelines, etc; the *documentation* exists, but isn't necessarily accessible by the audience (movie/tv "bibles" are not commonly made accessible either) - so why is an actor who is interpreting the written word of another person(s) given more weight than the one who wrote it, presumably with motivation and intent for the character in mind? and the actor can have unintended influences as much as a writer can - how can they not?

as well, there are many people with input on a tv show/movie, which i feel muddies the waters as to whom is granted ultimate authority anyway - in the case of the new star wars, oscar isaac had mentioned that he was portraying poe dameron and finn's relationship as a romance, but john boyega later commented that it was "all in oscar's head". so was poe gay and flirting, but finn was entirely uninterested? if boyega didn't know about isaac's intention during filming, can boyega comment after the fact that he was uninterested despite not having the knowledge to have specifically used that in his performance? does it matter that it doesn't seem as though the three guys who wrote the script would likely have intended isaac to portray poe dameron in that way?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
