<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="390778824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6gnqvc/cmvstate_atheism_is_the_only_way_to_provide/">
    <title>CMV:State atheism is the only way to provide secular institutions.</title>
    <original_poster>gingermarxist13</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____
State atheism is the belief that the state should maintain the official position that there is no god. I believe that simply not endorsing one religion or the other is doomed to fail because of the personal religious preferences of civil servants. A good example of this is when evangelical christians refuse service to gays/lesbians in public services. If the official position of the state prohibits all public endorsements of religion (by civil servants), religious discrimination becomes far easier to deal with.

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29433056358.0" user="activatedalmondz" delta="False">
    <text>Britain has an established church, but in practice the state is very secular. Homosexual marriage is permitted, and has been for a long time. Inclusion of people of all religious faiths is the norm. Clearly, Britain can have both an establish church and secular institutions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433084194.0" user="gingermarxist13" delta="False">
    <text>thats something I hadn't considered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29433097574.0" user="activatedalmondz" delta="True">
    <text>Well, did it change your view at all? </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
