<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="398392859.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6l6xwb/cmv_i_dont_understand_why_everyone_loves_wonder/">
    <title>CMV: I don't understand why everyone loves Wonder Woman</title>
    <original_poster>LilYonsan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Could someone help a cis-gendered white male understand why critics and people alike are raving about the new Wonder Woman movie? Having seen the movie myself, I really just don't understand what all the hype is about and when I think about this movie I seem to think about three main points that I just can't get around: the movie felt formulaic, the music was sub-par and predictable, and finally the movie's role in relation to my current ideas of gender.

**Wonder Woman felt formulaic:** 
This is one of my main criticisms of the movie, and I think it has come from the movie market being over-saturated with superhero movies as of late. Other than the first two batman movies (and maybe the third), I laugh at the relative quality of DC's live-action movies compared to their Animated Universe counterpart. Wonder Woman does what every other superhero movie has already done, the only difference was that it was a female lead (which I'll get more into later), my complaint was the result to me felt uninspired and the execution of the scenes was unoriginal (When viewing many of the fight scenes in this movie, I was reminded of 300)

**The Music Felt Bland:**
As a musician myself, I feel the music also played a large role in my lack of interest. I'd like to start off this point but suggesting readers watch this video [here](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7vfqkvwW2fs) to get a better understanding of where I'm coming from on this point. You don't have to, but it might help. If not, basically the point of the video is that, due to many factors, the music in movies and what composers are actually allowed to compose has been limited, resulting in a more neutral and uninspired soundtrack as a whole. There are only two sections in the movie featuring a cello playing a leading-tone into a tonic with loud drums behind it that stood out, and honestly I think the only reason it stood out was because they turned the music up slightly louder than they did the sound effects. 

**With regard to Gender:**

Which brings me to the point of this movie that I'm really trying to wrap my head around. "Maybe", I thought, "that is the point. That it's just like all of the superhero movies that feature men, but shows that a woman can do it just as well". Before I go on this topic, I'm glad to see more movies that feature female leads (this and ghostbusters I think do some good in a societal level, especially given some of the political turmoil this country has been in as of late), but if that is the entire point then, like my other complaints, movies like Kill Bill and Alien did it better because they weren't so preachy about it. To me, Wonder Woman took the approach "she does this despite the fact that she's a woman because she's powerful, rooooaaaar!!", whereas Ripley in Alien and **bleep** in Kill Bill were just badasses because they were and that was the end of discussion. 

In summary, it's not that I thought that Wonder Woman was a terrible movie, but I don't think it deserves nearly the praise and hype that it received, and I felt like I could have spent the time watching that movie doing something more meaningful. But, as I mentioned at the beginning of this topic, I'm a guy, so maybe I'm just not getting something here. Please, change my view reddit because I would really like to understand better what I don't already! 

Thanks for reading! 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29493316164.0" user="Anki_gamer" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not going to convince you that the film is good, but instead try to change your posted view that you don't "understand" why everyone love Wonder Woman". I was actually listening to NPR review this film on the radio yesterday, and while it began with an actual discussion about the quality of the movie as if it were any other, it quickly shifted to discussing only feminism, the lead, and the director. 

Now, first off I agree 100% about your points regarding the Alien movies and how we should view female lead films as a whole. I view it as a discredit to women in the industry when we don't talk about their actual work, and instead focus on the irrelevant fact that they are women. If a female lead film is bad, we should critique it just as harshly as we would any other film, it's disrespectful to do otherwise.

However, many people disagree. One of the big points from NPR regarded  the female director. In the modern movie industry, all a male director typically needs to do to be able to direct in the lucrative blockbuster arena, is one really good smaller film. Patty Jenkins (the director) had previously directed Monster in 2003 to massive critical acclaim, but had to wait 14 years before being trusted with such a big film like WW. If a male director had been at the helm of monster they probably would have been given a much higher budget film way sooner. 

Now, regarding the leads. Obviously there's the group of people who will love a film for having a female lead regardless of how it's handled. But WW supporters also point to Chris Pines character as an example of what feminism should be. Pines masculinity isn't affected by being around WW, and they are both able to look at each other as being equals instead of dominating one another. It's this acceptance of differences, and ability to combine their different strengths which people love.

Again, I'm not trying to convince you that the movie is good, but I'm trying to change your view that you don't understand why the movie gets such praise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493367783.0" user="LilYonsan" delta="False">
    <text>And this is exactly the sort of discussion that I was looking forward to, so I appreciate your response! 

I was aware that it was a female director at the helm, and in my opinion I don't think that this movie should in any way impede her in terms of her career. She's obviously capable of making a decent superhero movie and the fact that she had more success than male directors doing the same thing does speak volumes. 

What bothers me, though, is that the patriarchy only seemed to use her to create a movie about women because she's a woman, and I think that only speaks counter to the progress that society might make if the publishers and producers take this movie as a "one-off". Until I start seeing more female directors at the helm without any questions really being asked, I remain a little skeptical at the progress that people are claiming this movie will have made. 

I did like how Chris Pines seemed to understand concepts such as equality, and even consent better than most male characters (or male perspectives, really), but (and maybe I'm seeing this wrong), but it still seems to me with that logic that the movie was still ultimately about the man and not about the female lead. On that criticism, I don't know how far I should go because the stories have already been written, there's really only so much that they can do, but then it goes back to the formula problem so I guess I've just reached full circle lol. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29493401402.0" user="Anki_gamer" delta="True">
    <text>Hey, I personally couldn't agree with you more. I couldn't care less what sex or race the lead in a film has, as long as it's good. However, it's clear by the reviews that many people do care. 

I think for a lot of women specifically, the movie represents their struggle to be viewed as equals in the entertainment industry. We have been pumping out super hero movies by the truck load, and they consistently tell the same stories and showcase strong male leads with females always being assigned a supporting role. 

WW may follow the general formula for it's plot and action, but it's the behind the scenes progress that really have people lauding it so heavily. Just like how Pine and Gadot learn to view one another as equal partners, females want to be viewed as equals in the movie industry. Is WW woman a fantastic film that should make you cry due to how powerful it is? Definitely not, but it broke convention regarding it's director and lead (and unlike Ghost Busters, it actually performed very well). People love this film not just because of it's casting and direction, but because it represents female lead productions finally being viewed as equal to the current standard of film-making. 

As a result, the director now has more political capital to produce more big budget films, and whether or not WW is good when viewed in a vacuum, it sold enough tickets to show the industry that people are craving more female lead and directed projects. So the industry will stop viewing female lead films as being such a gamble. The ultimate goal being that we stop viewing films as being "normal" or "female lead" and instead just as films.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
