<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="401821196.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6n8f7w/cmv_lord_of_the_rings_are_great_films_but_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: Lord of the Rings are great films, but it is not a good trilogy</title>
    <original_poster>This_The_Last_Time</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is inspired by a recent Movie Fight debate about what is the best movie trilogy (check it out from YouTube). 

I'd argue, that even though I LOVE Lord of the Rings movies, and have seen them dozens of times, it is not a good movie trilogy. For one simple reason: the movies do not work separately. 

I think for a movie trilogy to be good or better than most, the parts of the trilogy have to work both individually as single movies and as pieces of a greater whole. 

LOTR does not work as individual films. None of the themes or storylines are resolved within a single film, with the exception of characters who are both introduced and killed within one film (Boromir, Shelob). 

LOTR films are individual films only in technical sense: they all have their separate release dates, each one ends with ending credits, etc. But the story contained in these films does not work when viewed as a single piece, because you do not get to see the big picture. LOTR films are really a single film, single story, released in three separate parts. 

I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. Story cannot be truly great if it does not end. Imagine if Fellowship of the Ring was a box-office bomb, and the two others films were never released. Who would call Fellowship a self-contained, resolved film? It would still be a good film, just without resolution. Audiences would think, what then, only to be answered, nothing. A good story does not ask questions it does not try to answer. 

Then look at Godfather. If Godfather Part 2 was never released, Godfather 1 would still work perfectly on its own. Part 2 enchances the first one, and vice versa, but neither requires the other.  And no one needs the third one. 

Lord of the Rings films are great. But in reality they are a trilogy only in technical terms, as the story within is one single story, not three complementing ones. If you only watch one of the films, but not the others, story is flawed and incomplete. If you watch the films out of chronological order, nothing makes sense. All the plot threads and all the character archs in the trilogy take multiple films to reach their conclusions, with the aforementioned exception of characters who are introduced and killed within a single movie. 

An exceptional trilogy of films should work both individually, where you only see one of them (not necessarily even the first one), and still feel like you got everything you needed and wanted, and as parts of a bigger whole. Lord of the Rings films do not work without the other parts of the trilogy. Without them, story is incomplete, unresolved, and the character archs unfinished. 

CMV. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29520150941.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. 

This seems like a questionable requirement for "good." You're pretty much saying that movie trilogies must be conceived episodically to work as trilogies - that the story needs to be conceived and executed as three separate and relatively independent chapters. That's an oddly specific structural requirement that wouldn't seem to have any bearing on whether the story being told, or the individual movies themselves, are actually good - as you yourself say, the LOTR movies *are* good.

Three good movies = a good trilogy, it would seem; anything else is just a matter of how one chooses to structure and execute a story over those three movies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520166797.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>To clarify I think there can be three good movies, that are not a good trilogy. For example Cornetto trilogy, where each individual movie works fine, but experiencing any of the other films does not bring anything of value to the audience. They are too separate. They are three individual stories, branded as a loose trilogy. 

LOTR is one story, branded in three parts. None of the parts work without the others. 

Dark Knight Trilogy works individually and as a whole. It is a good trilogy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520175949.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>But the only reason you think there can be three good movies that aren't a good trilogy is that you begin from the arbitrary place of "they have to work well individually and as a whole." My whole point is there's no reason to think that this, on its face, is what makes a trilogy "good," any more than there's reason to think that being structured in a particular way is what makes an individual movie good.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520309477.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;But the only reason you think there can be three good movies that aren't a good trilogy is that you begin from the arbitrary place of "they have to work well individually and as a whole."

I don't think that's arbitary at all. A good three-piece meal has to work as three pieces and as a whole. 

&amp;gt;being structured in a particular way is what makes an individual movie good.

I'm not saying the movies are bad. They are good, regardless of structure. But they do not serve all the functions of a trilogy, so it cannot be a good trilogy. Like having a separate handle and head don't make a good hammer, regardless how good the parts are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520326754.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think that's arbitary at all. A good three-piece meal has to work as three pieces and as a whole. 

So you're saying if you ate a great three-piece meal, but then looked back at it and said, "Well, I don't think I'd eat those three things individually," then it wasn't a good meal?

&amp;gt;the functions of a trilogy

This is what I take issue with. There *are* no "functions of a trilogy." A trilogy, by its nature, doesn't *have* to do anything. All "trilogy" denotes is that there are three related movies. How they relate to each other is a function of structure and storytelling choices and a variety of approaches would seem to be valid. To assume one approach is the only way to properly be a trilogy and then judge all trilogies on that basis seems bizarre to me.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
