<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="401821196.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6n8f7w/cmv_lord_of_the_rings_are_great_films_but_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: Lord of the Rings are great films, but it is not a good trilogy</title>
    <original_poster>This_The_Last_Time</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is inspired by a recent Movie Fight debate about what is the best movie trilogy (check it out from YouTube). 

I'd argue, that even though I LOVE Lord of the Rings movies, and have seen them dozens of times, it is not a good movie trilogy. For one simple reason: the movies do not work separately. 

I think for a movie trilogy to be good or better than most, the parts of the trilogy have to work both individually as single movies and as pieces of a greater whole. 

LOTR does not work as individual films. None of the themes or storylines are resolved within a single film, with the exception of characters who are both introduced and killed within one film (Boromir, Shelob). 

LOTR films are individual films only in technical sense: they all have their separate release dates, each one ends with ending credits, etc. But the story contained in these films does not work when viewed as a single piece, because you do not get to see the big picture. LOTR films are really a single film, single story, released in three separate parts. 

I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. Story cannot be truly great if it does not end. Imagine if Fellowship of the Ring was a box-office bomb, and the two others films were never released. Who would call Fellowship a self-contained, resolved film? It would still be a good film, just without resolution. Audiences would think, what then, only to be answered, nothing. A good story does not ask questions it does not try to answer. 

Then look at Godfather. If Godfather Part 2 was never released, Godfather 1 would still work perfectly on its own. Part 2 enchances the first one, and vice versa, but neither requires the other.  And no one needs the third one. 

Lord of the Rings films are great. But in reality they are a trilogy only in technical terms, as the story within is one single story, not three complementing ones. If you only watch one of the films, but not the others, story is flawed and incomplete. If you watch the films out of chronological order, nothing makes sense. All the plot threads and all the character archs in the trilogy take multiple films to reach their conclusions, with the aforementioned exception of characters who are introduced and killed within a single movie. 

An exceptional trilogy of films should work both individually, where you only see one of them (not necessarily even the first one), and still feel like you got everything you needed and wanted, and as parts of a bigger whole. Lord of the Rings films do not work without the other parts of the trilogy. Without them, story is incomplete, unresolved, and the character archs unfinished. 

CMV. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29520111329.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>I think this is more of a conversation concerning structure, rather than quality. I'm not sure why the structure of a trilogy means it is good or bad necessarily.

There are a lot of ways to tell a story, and LOTR is more like an epic than it is a movie. The books themselves are actually broken up into six parts, and it tells the story of Frodo and the Ring in more of an episodic sort of way. It's about the whole journey.

If you enjoy the thing as a whole, then I think it's fair to say its a good trilogy. Do you think the only good television shows are ones where each episode works on its own? Trilogies are a whole, to be judged as a whole. We already have a name for individual works that we judge them by - movies.

Can you provide more examples of good trilogies?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520149746.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this is more of a conversation concerning structure, rather than quality. 

Yes, it is indeed a question of structure, because movies themselves are good, and whether the structure matches the story. Because as a story, it is one story, not three separate, complemeting stories. 

&amp;gt;Do you think the only good television shows are ones where each episode works on its own?

Not at all. The story structure is inherently different in those two mediums. But any good trilogy, whether movie or album, has to work in both the state it was released in (separately) and in retrospect (all together). 

&amp;gt;Trilogies are a whole, to be judged as a whole. 

And separately. If it's only one whole thing, then it's also only one story, and may only be consider a trilogy due to technical or promotional structure choices. I think there is a difference between a story released in three parts, and a story in trilogy format. Trilogy has both sides, and when we evaluate any trilogy we evaluate both the big picture and all the individual films. 

Let's say we have a three-course meal. By its definition, this meal consists of three parts, and when we evaluate the meal, we evaluate the three parts it consists of. You cannot evaluate the meal without its parts. 

But if we get one piece of the meal now, the other one a year from now, and the last one two years from now, and they all need the other two parts work, I cannot say that the meal was good. I can say that individual pieces of the meal were tasty, but because each part of the meal depended so much on the other parts, I cannot say the meal was good. 

&amp;gt;Can you provide more examples of good trilogies?

Frankly, there ain't that many, but for the argument's sake I'll say the Dark Knight trilogy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520164625.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Yes, it is indeed a question of structure, because movies themselves are good, and whether the structure matches the story. Because as a story, it is one story, not three separate, complemeting stories.

I suppose my point here is a resounding, "so what?" What does it matter if something you enjoy has one structure over another?

&amp;gt; Not at all. The story structure is inherently different in those two mediums. But any good trilogy, whether movie or album, has to work in both the state it was released in (separately) and in retrospect (all together).

Do they have to work separately to be good, though?

&amp;gt; And separately. If it's only one whole thing, then it's also only one story, and may only be consider a trilogy due to technical or promotional structure choices. I think there is a difference between a story released in three parts, and a story in trilogy format. Trilogy has both sides, and when we evaluate any trilogy we evaluate both the big picture and all the individual films.

A trilogy is just a series of three movies. They might have any number of structures. From very loosely-related like the [Cornetto Trilogy](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Three_Flavours_Cornetto_trilogy) to very much interlaced like LOTR. I'm not seeing why one is inherently better than the other.

Sometimes a story requires a longer format, even if that story is told through movies.

&amp;gt; Let's say we have a three-course meal. By its definition, this meal consists of three parts, and when we evaluate the meal, we evaluate the three parts it consists of. You cannot evaluate the meal without its parts.

&amp;gt; But if we get one piece of the meal now, the other one a year from now, and the last one two years from now, and they all need the other two parts work, I cannot say that the meal was good. I can say that individual parts of the meal were tasty, but because each part of the meal depends so much on other parts, I cannot say the meal was good.

See, now you're talking about release dates. Do you think LOTR would have been better if all three movies were released at the same time?

I'm also not following your analogy. We'll wait for continuing stories, as evidenced both by television and by LOTR. Serialized entertainment has been around forever.

&amp;gt; Frankly, there ain't that many, but for arguments sake I'll say Dark Knight trilogy.

There are very few. In fact, *most* trilogies follow a structure closer to LOTR than The Dark Knight or the aforementioned Cornetto trilogy. I would argue that they're exceptions to the typical trilogy structure, rather than the standard by which to judge all other trilogies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520190630.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I suppose my point here is a resounding, "so what?" What does it matter if something you enjoy has one structure over another?

Well, that's the point of this CMV. Debate about structure. I think you can answer any CMV with, so what, what does it matter?, but that's not very fruitful approach, is it? 

&amp;gt;Do they have to work separately to be good, though?

For TV-series to be good? No. But like I said, different mediums, inherently different rules. 

&amp;gt;A trilogy is just a series of three movies. They might have any number of structures. From very loosely-related like the Cornetto Trilogy to very much interlaced like LOTR. I'm not seeing why one is inherently better than the other.

I disagree. I don't think Cornetto trilogy is a good trilogy. It's a series of three good films. Watching more than one, or all three, does not give you any additional value or appreciation for the trilogy, except, well I liked the films themselves. From my view, watching all parts of the trilogy gives you more appreciation or understanding of the story, but you can still enjoy each film on its own, as they work on their own. No one knows if you ever get to finish your story. 

&amp;gt;See, now you're talking about release dates. Do you think LOTR would have been better if all three movies were released at the same time?

As a story, if we would have had one complete story for the get-go, hmmm, from story perspective, it would have made the most sense. Because it is one story. 

Another good trilogy (presumedly, haven't seen the third one yet): Planet of the Apes. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520203612.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well, that's the point of this CMV. Debate about structure. I think you can answer any CMV with, so what, what does it matter?, but that's not very fruitful approach, is it?

It's a question. I'd like to know why you think the structure is wrong for trilogies.

&amp;gt; For TV-series to be good? No. But like I said, different mediums, inherently different rules.

A movie trilogy has but one rule: be three movies.

&amp;gt; I disagree. I don't think Cornetto trilogy is a good trilogy. It's a series of three good films. Watching more than one, or all three, does not give you any additional value or appreciation for the trilogy, except, well I liked the films themselves. From my view, watching all parts of the trilogy gives you more appreciation or understanding of the story, but you can still enjoy each film on its own, as they work on their own. No one knows if you ever get to finish your story.

Let me put it another way. What is bad about this type of structure of the LOTR structure? Why does a trilogy have to perfectly balance both its long arc and its three shorter arcs to be considered good? Why can't we consider trilogies that have different structures to also be good?

&amp;gt; As a story, if we would have had one complete story for the get-go, hmmm, from story perspective, it would have made the most sense. Because it is one story.

So right now you do have access to all three at once. Why do the release dates matter?

The books were released slowly in six parts.

The crux of my argument is that using the movie trilogy structure of three movies to tell a long story is perfectly acceptable. It's a medium that even allows for long-form story telling. They're three movies that total out to about 12 hours worth of content (extended cuts). 12 hours of good and compelling content. I see no reason to consider it a "bad trilogy" based on arbitrary metrics like structure.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520298672.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;A movie trilogy has but one rule: be three movies.

Here we disagree. Three movies =/= trilogy. Or to be more specific, three good movies =/= good trilogy. 

If I take random three books from a book store, is it a book trilogy? No. If they are written by the same author? Still no. What if it's one story, with same characters, in three physical parts? Then it's one book in three volumes. 

If Quentin Tarantino had died in 2000, I wouldn't call his first three movies a trilogy. They share actors and director, but they are not related in any substantial way (fan theories aside). 

&amp;gt;Let me put it another way. What is bad about this type of structure of the LOTR structure? Why does a trilogy have to perfectly balance both its long arc and its three shorter arcs to be considered good? Why can't we consider trilogies that have different structures to also be good?

Well, it's not inherently bad. Just like having a cone with three balls of ice cream is not inherently worse than having three cones with each having one ball of ice cream. Different structures that work for different purposes and needs. 

&amp;gt;So right now you do have access to all three at once. Why do the release dates matter?

Because people consider it to be good trilogy, when it is one good movie in three volumes, basically. It's not a big thing, I admit, but I like to argue semantics. 

&amp;gt;The books were released slowly in six parts.

Gonna correct you here: Three parts, three volumes, with each one containing two "books". And Tolkien wanted it to be released all at once, because that's how he wrote it to be read. The books are not a good trilogy either. They are a good book, good story released in three volumes. 

&amp;gt;The crux of my argument is that using the movie trilogy structure of three movies to tell a long story is perfectly acceptable. It's a medium that even allows for long-form story telling. They're three movies that total out to about 12 hours worth of content (extended cuts). 12 hours of good and compelling content. I see no reason to consider it a "bad trilogy" based on arbitrary metrics like structure.

It's not a bad series of movies. Movies are good. It is a good epic. And it is 100% acceptable to split your movie in three parts. But it doesn't work as a trilogy, because it is a single story, split into three and doesn't serve all the functions of the trilogy, as I see them (mainly working both as separate films and as a larger whole. LOTR works only as a larger whole). </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520322126.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; If I take random three books from a book store, is it a book trilogy? No. If they are written by the same author? Still no. What if it's one story, with same characters, in three physical parts? Then it's one book in three volumes.

This is not how books work, it is not how movies work, it is not how trilogies work.

&amp;gt; If Quentin Tarantino had died in 2000, I wouldn't call his first three movies a trilogy. They share actors and director, but they are not related in any substantial way (fan theories aside).

First off, it's well established that there are a few links between Tarantino movies. Secondly, you could very well describe his first three movies as a "trilogy" because trilogy is an arbitrary term referring to a group of three related things. Be that relation directors, actors, stories, authors, whatever.

&amp;gt; Well, it's not inherently bad. Just like having a cone with three balls of ice cream is not inherently worse than having three cones with each having one ball of ice cream. Different structures that work for different purposes and needs.

You're saying it inherently means it is a bad trilogy. That the movie trilogy structure doesn't work for this type of story. But I think its existence and popularity tells a different story.

&amp;gt; Because people consider it to be good trilogy, when it is one good movie in three volumes, basically. It's not a big thing, I admit, but I like to argue semantics.

They are very clearly three distinct movies all telling one overarching story.

&amp;gt; Gonna correct you here: Three parts, three volumes, with each one containing two "books". And Tolkien wanted it to be released all at once, because that's how he wrote it to be read. The books are not a good trilogy either. They are a good book, good story released in three volumes.

They are a good trilogy of volumes.

&amp;gt; It's not a bad series of movies. Movies are good. It is a good epic. And it is 100% acceptable to split your movie in three parts. But it doesn't work as a trilogy, because it is a single story, split into three and doesn't serve all the functions of the trilogy, as I see them.

But it isn't one movie in three parts. It's three movies telling one over arching story.

I'm not sure what you're not getting at this point. Three movies are a trilogy. That's just how that word works. You say you like to argue semantics, well lets see it! Semantics is more than just making up definitions for things.

Does that mean the Pirates of the Caribbean trilogy is actually just two movies? Are Terminator one and two actually one movie as well?

Is Pulp Fiction actually not a movie because of its structure?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520398981.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;This is not how books work, it is not how movies work, it is not how trilogies work.

This is what you argued. You said: 

&amp;gt;A movie trilogy has but one rule: be three movies.

You are conflicting with yourself. So apparently there is more rules? Being three something is not enough?

&amp;gt;First off, it's well established that there are a few links between Tarantino movies. Secondly, you could very well describe his first three movies as a "trilogy" because trilogy is an arbitrary term referring to a group of three related things. Be that relation directors, actors, stories, authors, whatever.

I disagree (or used to, check other posts). Trilogy is not simply three things by same author. 

Is 1941, Raiders of the Lost Ark and E.T. = Spielberg trilogy? No. Same author, released consecutively, not a trilogy. 

&amp;gt;You're saying it inherently means it is a bad trilogy. That the movie trilogy structure doesn't work for this type of story. But I think its existence and popularity tells a different story.

I didn't say it doesn't work. I said it doesn't serve the function of being trilogy, which I defined earlier, therefore it's a bad trilogy. Just like shoe is a bad hammer. 

&amp;gt;They are very clearly three **distinct** movies all telling one overarching story.

That's my point! They are not distinct. They are clearly one whole, and only one whole. Feel free to argue otherwise. This is what I wanted to hear. 

&amp;gt;They are a good trilogy of volumes. 

Trilogy of volumes? Please. Or, you know, a good story released in three volumes. 

&amp;gt;But it isn't one movie in three parts. It's three movies telling one over arching story.

It is exactly that! One story, three parts/volumes/movies. 

&amp;gt;Is Pulp Fiction actually not a movie because of its structure?

It is. Many movies have multiple storylines and archs. 

&amp;gt;Are Terminator one and two actually one movie as well?

Nope, two movies, two stories, each with their own distinct beginning, middle and end. If T2 never came out, T1 would have been fine on its own. 

&amp;gt;Does that mean the Pirates of the Caribbean trilogy is actually just two movies?

Well well well! This is much more interesting question. First movie is clearly it's own thing. Hmm. I'd argue that yeah, under my terms, the 2nd and 3rd Pirate-movies are actually just one movie in two parts. Is it silly? Yes. Logical? I'd say so. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520420350.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You are conflicting with yourself. So apparently there is more rules? Being three something is not enough?

Nope. You can call any set of three movies a trilogy.

&amp;gt; I disagree (or used to, check other posts). Trilogy is not simply three things by same author.

A trilogy is a word that has many uses. In this case, LOTR is literally a movie trilogy.

&amp;gt; I didn't say it doesn't work. I said it doesn't serve the function of being trilogy, which I defined earlier, therefore it's a bad trilogy. Just like shoe is a bad hammer.

It serves the function of a trilogy just fine.

&amp;gt; Trilogy of volumes? Please. Or, you know, a good story released in three volumes.

Please what? Why are you king of the word "trilogy" all of a sudden?

&amp;gt; It is exactly that! One story, three parts/volumes/movies.

Yes, three movies. A movie trilogy.

&amp;gt; Well well well! This is much more interesting question. First movie is clearly it's own thing. Hmm. I'd argue that yeah, under my terms, the 2nd and 3rd Pirate-movies are actually just one movie in two parts. Is it silly? Yes. Logical? I'd say so.

It's ridiculous. Define a movie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520444485.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Nope. You can call any set of three movies a trilogy.

So 1941, Raiders and E.T. are a trilogy? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520456688.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>Alright, so pretend you're writing an academic paper about these three movies. And at some point in your paper, you say something like, "the trilogy of films discussed here..."

Do you think that's improper English? Do you think the point is lost? I think the audience would recognize that the term refers to the three movies the person is writing about.

Trilogy, as colloquially used for movies, refers to three movies that usually take place in the same shared universe. Star Wars is comprised of two trilogies, soon to be three, and now at least one standalone movie. Or you could say it's one sextilogy. Or whatever. It's arbitrary.

LOTR is commonly understood as a movie trilogy because it's three movies, and yes they are separate and independent movies that even have their own beginnings, middles, and ends, and it all takes place along the same journey. It's a movie trilogy. Three movies = trilogy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520483549.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>You are right about other stuff. Three movies that take in place universe are usually a trilogy. Not gonna argue that. Trilogy is a term many people use and understand. Not gonna argue with that either, though it only means that is widely know term, not that it's the correct term. 

&amp;gt;LOTR is commonly understood as a movie trilogy because it's three movies, and yes they are separate and independent movies that even have their own beginnings, middles, and ends, and it all takes place along the same journey. It's a movie trilogy. Three movies = trilogy.

But care to elaborate here. Like I said, I fail to see how three movies in LOTR are distinct, separate or independent story-wise. This is the argument I wanted to hear, tbh. I don't think any storyline or character arch reaches a conclusion within any single movie, except if the character dies. To me, they all tell 1/3 of one story. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520518466.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>They're not independent *story-wise*. They're independent in that they contain rising action, climaxes, and falling action. There's also a series of smaller stories throughout. The entire sequence of the Mines of Moria is rising action as they explore the mines, a climax with a big battle, and falling action when Gandalf is killed and they make it to Lothlorien. That's one story within the larger, overarching one of Bilbo's quest. And these smaller adventures are all over the place.

It is correct to use the term trilogy, because the story is presented to us in three movies. Fellowship, Two Towers, Return. It's really not that hard to find the beginning, middles, and ends of these movies.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520539396.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, they are scenes. Scenes that begin, have middles and ends in those movies. Storylines and character arcs really don't. The central questions are unanswered until the end of the last movie. Even some very big plotlines (like Battle for Rohan) spill to other movies. The fate of the Fellowship is the only big storyline I can think of that ends when a movie ends. 

Anyway, thanks for the debate. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520540887.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="False">
    <text>You don't think the fate of Rohan is a storyline that ends?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520553403.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>Not really. Saruman is defeated, but still alive, so is Wormtongue. The original mission of Aragorn and Co. (reach Merri and Pippin) is still unsolved by the end of the movie. King Theoden's story is still very much unfinished, and he dies in the next movie, and Eowyn's arc that started in Two Towers doesn't reach its conclusion until Pelennor fields. Biggest battle ends, but we do not know what came of it, until the next movie begins. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520557436.0" user="BenIncognito" delta="True">
    <text>Right, but Helms Deep is defended and the people of Rohan are saved. Aragorn and co's entire plotline in the Two Towers is about saving the people of Rohan from the imminent attack by the Uruk-hai.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
