<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="403343304.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6o51oo/cmv_retard_is_not_an_offensive_or_ableist_word/">
    <title>CMV: "Retard" is not an offensive or ableist word because the connotation has changed from referring to mentally handicapped people to referring to stupid people, much like how the meaning of other words like "dumb" and "lame" have also changed meanings dramatically.</title>
    <original_poster>Dillon-psm</original_poster>
    <original_post>So a lot of people find the word "Retard" used as an insult to be incredibly offensive, akin to saying the n-word to a black person. They say that this is because historically the word means mentally handicapped person and it was used in a patronizing and derogatory way during a time when there was a massive cultural stigma and disgust with mental disabilities. 

Yet, many words over the course of history change. Hell, a lot of the words we use today to refer to someone as an idiot - including the word idiot - were historically used to describe mentally ill/handicapped people. 

To this day, words like Imbecile, Moron and Cretin are used to describe stupid people (or troublemakers, in the case of cretin), yet these words actually mean the exact same thing as "retard". 

So why is retard singled out as "ableist"? Are people who take offence to the word simply being resistant to the natural evolution of language, or does their anger have merit? 

EDIT: Everyone made very good points. I'm considering them, but based on the fact that for the most part I had *nothing* to fire back with, I'd say my views have been thoroughly changed and I'm going to phase this word out of my vocabulary. I'm guilty of frequent use - it's easy to just turn to a buddy and say that in good fun without even thinking, but I'll be mindful in the future. 

Thanks people. Also You get a delta, you get a delta, and you get a delta, everyone gets a delta!!!!!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29532109850.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="True">
    <text>Is the word "retard" still regularly used to refer to the mentally handicapped? If you called a mentally handicapped person "retarded" would they (or anyone else around) know exactly what that means? 

The answer to both of those questions would seem to be "Yes." The force and power of the word "retard" as an insult still demonstrably derives from a force of comparison to the mentally handicapped - *everyone* knows what you mean when you use "retard" to mean stupid; there is no confusion here, and the original meaning of the world has not been lost, as is the case with "idiot" or even arguably "lame."

Using "retarded" to mean "stupid" is akin to using "gay" to mean bad or "Jewish" to mean cheap; the only reason we even know what someone means when they say these things is because of a comparison it makes to a marginalized group.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532129501.0" user="Dillon-psm" delta="False">
    <text>This is an interesting and valuable counter-point, I appreciate it. So you think the word has not yet separated enough from it's roots to be as inane and unoffensive as the other words I brought up? It's still deeply ingrained in our minds and in recent history that this means "mentally disabled", hence using it is bigoted? 

Two questions on this front then - is it ok to use this word in circles made up of people who have no knowledge of it's roots/history? 

And whether it is or not, do you think that there will eventually come a point where this word loses it's offensive edge and becomes like the other aforementioned words?

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532141825.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So you think the word has not yet separated enough from it's roots to be as inane and unoffensive as the other words I brought up? It's still deeply ingrained in our minds and in recent history that this means "mentally disabled", hence using it is bigoted?

More than just this - I think it's used because it has a certain amount of force behind it, and it has that force because of a consciousness of the kind of comparison you're making when you call someone a "retard." It's precisely why it's a more "effective" insult than "idiot."

&amp;gt;Two questions on this front then - is it ok to use this word in circles made up of people who have no knowledge of it's roots/history? 

Again, I think it gets used *because* of its history. And in any case, I'm not sure either the intent of the person using a given word or the relation of the person hearing the word to that word has anything to do with whether using it is "okay" or not. If you know what "retard" means and you say it, then that would seem to me to be problematic. 

&amp;gt;Two questions on this front then - is it ok to use this word in circles made up of people who have no knowledge of it's roots/history? 

I'm not sure. I think the word has been the subject of a more conscious and widespread scrutiny/condemnation than words like "idiot" ever were, so I imagine it's going to linger a lot longer as a taboo word. I could be wrong though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532158997.0" user="Dillon-psm" delta="False">
    <text>Someone else suggested that "retard" is a much harsher term than it's predecessors, even compared to their historical usage (in other words retard is harsher that idiot was when it meant the same thing). Do you think that's accurate or not? I do submit that your are correct in stating: 

&amp;gt;It's precisely why it's a more "effective" insult than "idiot."

In my circle of friends at least, there is a progression - "Dumbass" to "Moron" to "Idiot" to "Retard". So I'll concede that there certainly is an internalized association in society that hierarchically denotes "retard" as the most potent and insulting way to call someone stupid. 

I've held the argument that the word is powerful because of how it sounds, aesthetically. From a purely auditory stance, it's a harsh word. It ends on a firm D, it's got a T in it which is a somewhat curt sound as well. But this could also just be rationalization on my part - a common thing people do to avoid being wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532163872.0" user="Literally_Herodotus" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Someone else suggested that "retard" is a much harsher term than it's predecessors.

It's certainly harsher *now*. Whether it always was or not, I don't know, but that seems kind of beside the point. Your view is in regard to whether the word, right now, is offensive and ableist, and it is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
