<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="403343304.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6o51oo/cmv_retard_is_not_an_offensive_or_ableist_word/">
    <title>CMV: "Retard" is not an offensive or ableist word because the connotation has changed from referring to mentally handicapped people to referring to stupid people, much like how the meaning of other words like "dumb" and "lame" have also changed meanings dramatically.</title>
    <original_poster>Dillon-psm</original_poster>
    <original_post>So a lot of people find the word "Retard" used as an insult to be incredibly offensive, akin to saying the n-word to a black person. They say that this is because historically the word means mentally handicapped person and it was used in a patronizing and derogatory way during a time when there was a massive cultural stigma and disgust with mental disabilities. 

Yet, many words over the course of history change. Hell, a lot of the words we use today to refer to someone as an idiot - including the word idiot - were historically used to describe mentally ill/handicapped people. 

To this day, words like Imbecile, Moron and Cretin are used to describe stupid people (or troublemakers, in the case of cretin), yet these words actually mean the exact same thing as "retard". 

So why is retard singled out as "ableist"? Are people who take offence to the word simply being resistant to the natural evolution of language, or does their anger have merit? 

EDIT: Everyone made very good points. I'm considering them, but based on the fact that for the most part I had *nothing* to fire back with, I'd say my views have been thoroughly changed and I'm going to phase this word out of my vocabulary. I'm guilty of frequent use - it's easy to just turn to a buddy and say that in good fun without even thinking, but I'll be mindful in the future. 

Thanks people. Also You get a delta, you get a delta, and you get a delta, everyone gets a delta!!!!!

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29532128332.0" user="cacheflow" delta="False">
    <text>I think the difference is timescale.  In my lifetime, I know it was common when people used  "retarded" to describe mentally handicapped people.

It's not ancient history.  To many people, it was still prevalent in our lifetimes.   Other terms, like "lame" to mean crippled weren't common in my lifetime.  Similarly, using "dumb" to mean unable to speak.

Thus to me, those words don't have identical meanings, they carry very different connotations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532143251.0" user="Dillon-psm" delta="False">
    <text>In essence - it'll take a few generations before it's far removed enough to be ok? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29532189380.0" user="openforum2011" delta="True">
    <text>That's an interesting question, but to be honest I think the answer is "no" in this case, and the reason is the widespread and immensely successful globalization effect of the Internet on the world and language. 

Due to the fact that "retard" is presently known to be an epithet against the mentally handicapped worldwide, and there are countless articles, dictionary definitions, TV shows, movies, and even online videos of people protesting/propagating use of the word, it will remain pejorative for much longer than the antecedent terms such as "idiot" and "moron" did in referring to a mentally handicapped person. When those older terms fell by the wayside, there was nothing there in the public consciousness to persistently remind us of those words' connotations with insulting the handicapped. With "retard" in the 21st century, there is. And our society is far more politically correct now than it was in the 1950s, as well.

So in essence, I think the Internet has helped to stall the euphemism treadmill, so to speak.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
