<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410977978.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6soomy/cmv_i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_we_all/">
    <title>CMV: I have no faith in humanity and we all deserve to go extinct.</title>
    <original_poster>rfreymuth</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't even know exactly what to say about anything in relation to this topic. Now, I have no experience of any actual human beings physically hurting me or anything else that would typically make someone lose faith in humanity, but what they did collectively was enough to make ME do so!

First, and most importantly, the election of Donald Trump. Ever since the beginning of his campaign, my parents had been constantly talking about how Trump was so stupid that there would be absolutely no chance that he would win the election based on how people really do think, and based on that, I made a vow to myself that I would lose faith in humanity if he won. I did. I now believe that humanity needs and deserves to go extinct because of this.

But that's not the only reason why I believe we all need and deserve to go extinct. The other reason is the inevitable box office success of The Emoji Movie. Ever since its ANNOUNCEMENT, I thought that it was the worst idea in the history of movies and even the greatest amount of care put into it would still make me never want to watch it. Well, obviously the movie did not have any effort at all, and nearly nobody liked it. I was really very happy about that. But the thing that made me double down on my belief of humanity's extinction being deserved was the fact that it will become a box office hit!

I can't think of any other examples I have gone through right now, but I hope you get what I'm saying! I actually don't care if the World War I Christmas Truce makes someone else restore faith in humanity, or any of the other "being kind to your enemies" scenarios in big-name wars did the same, or anything else that would restore faith in humanity. The fact still remains...

How could humanity be so goddamn STUPID!!! First, the election of a bully, troll, and CRIMINAL as President of the United States, and now the inevitable box office success of the worst idea in the history of movies, which will result in other equally bad ideas like "Damn Daniel: The Movie"!

As a result, we DESPERATELY need to go extinct! We fucking deserve it!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29592230544.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>I don't necessarily disagree, but I don't follow your reasoning. What exactly makes humans worse than other animals? It can't be stupidity, because most animals are pretty fucking dumb.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592243610.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>I wanted to say something like "We are destroying our planet" or something like that, but my view on that was changed when I saw this: https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/1kuacg/i_believe_mankind_is_wrong_and_repugnant_and_not/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592281937.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="True">
    <text>If humans go extinct, evolution would keep chugging along until:
A) Some other human like master species rises to the top, possibly a species even worse than humans
B) The sun explodes, everything is snuffed out

So I'd rather we work out the flaws in our species now, rather than risk evolution putting the planet through this all over again. Maybe the planet would benefit from a megadeath scenario, where a large portion of humanity is wiped out, but the extinction of humans will just set everything back by eons.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
