<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410977978.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6soomy/cmv_i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_we_all/">
    <title>CMV: I have no faith in humanity and we all deserve to go extinct.</title>
    <original_poster>rfreymuth</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't even know exactly what to say about anything in relation to this topic. Now, I have no experience of any actual human beings physically hurting me or anything else that would typically make someone lose faith in humanity, but what they did collectively was enough to make ME do so!

First, and most importantly, the election of Donald Trump. Ever since the beginning of his campaign, my parents had been constantly talking about how Trump was so stupid that there would be absolutely no chance that he would win the election based on how people really do think, and based on that, I made a vow to myself that I would lose faith in humanity if he won. I did. I now believe that humanity needs and deserves to go extinct because of this.

But that's not the only reason why I believe we all need and deserve to go extinct. The other reason is the inevitable box office success of The Emoji Movie. Ever since its ANNOUNCEMENT, I thought that it was the worst idea in the history of movies and even the greatest amount of care put into it would still make me never want to watch it. Well, obviously the movie did not have any effort at all, and nearly nobody liked it. I was really very happy about that. But the thing that made me double down on my belief of humanity's extinction being deserved was the fact that it will become a box office hit!

I can't think of any other examples I have gone through right now, but I hope you get what I'm saying! I actually don't care if the World War I Christmas Truce makes someone else restore faith in humanity, or any of the other "being kind to your enemies" scenarios in big-name wars did the same, or anything else that would restore faith in humanity. The fact still remains...

How could humanity be so goddamn STUPID!!! First, the election of a bully, troll, and CRIMINAL as President of the United States, and now the inevitable box office success of the worst idea in the history of movies, which will result in other equally bad ideas like "Damn Daniel: The Movie"!

As a result, we DESPERATELY need to go extinct! We fucking deserve it!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29592160271.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>You've listed  examples that are specifically American. 

Shouldn't your view be that you have no faith in Americans and they all deserve to go extinct?

Edit: removed "to" between "listed" and "examples"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592162596.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if that's the case, then I think that America is completely broken and that I should move out and live in another country as soon as possible!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592168841.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>Sounds like a change of view. Is there anything about works affairs to show all humans deserve to die?

Edit: world affairs</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592180627.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>At first, I didn't know what you mean by "work affairs". I think you mean "cheating on spouse at work".
In that case... not that I could think of. I have never heard of any personal experience about people having an affair at work. I don't even have a significant other at all!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592200224.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>It should be world affairs, like how because if Trump, leaders like Angela Merkle are stepping up and thinking more globally

Edit: stupid autocorrect</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592226204.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>I don't what to respond with. I guess it's somewhat nice that something like this is happening (I don't know much about the current German chancellor, but...) but I think that more epically bad things similar to what I'm talking about are going to happen, which would further prove my hatred for all humanity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592247388.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>That could be confirmation bias, if you look for bad things, you'll only see bad things. 

Trump's only going to be president for at most 8 more years, and it's unlikely that truly epic bad things will happen in such a short time (I'm thinking "fall of the Roman empire" epically bad)

Sure, his "America first" plan seems to decrease the role of America in the world, but the role America has been playing as a global superpower is unprecedented. Maybe this withdraw is what the world needs to let countries work together to solve problems.

Less people die of hunger every year, we progress towards eradication of more diseases like polio and malaria (only 37 cases of polio in 2016!). China is moving green, and rural India is skipping fossil and going straight to solar.

So sure, some things look bad, but lots if things look good too!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592297746.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That could be confirmation bias, if you look for bad things, you'll only see bad things.

I think the only reason I get bad things was that something told me about them. For example, the reason why I was obsessing over Trump was because my parents kept talking about his negative potential all the time.

And the reason why I was so angry about The Emoji Movie was because I've seen in a YouTuber (by jacksfilms as part of YIAY) video called "Hollywood in 4 words", one of the answers submitted by viewers was "This is happening now" with a picture of The Emoji Movie announcement. Since then, he was constantly hyping up the movie all until release, and going so far as to say it's the greatest thing that ever happened to cinema! I seriously considered unsubscribing him for that reason.

Those are the only reasons why I was ranting about it and why humanity was the worst species in history.

By the way, I forgot to mention that in my original post! Humanity being the worst species in history!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592299452.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>So has your view been changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592306052.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>I don't really know. But I need to know how to stop UNINTENTIONALLY look at bad things! Because I feel as if the only way for me to solve that issue is to just disconnect from the internet for the rest of my life!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592322141.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="True">
    <text>Firstly, if you no longer think all humans should die, you should award a Delta.

If you want to curate your media, you should probably do a few things: 1) consume more than just American national news, look at local news or international news, 2) specifically encourage your parents to donate money or time to fix problems they see, and not complain about it 3) encourage your parents to talk about positive stuff too.

The numbers show you are better off living now than at any point in human history. On average you get better healthcare, nutrition, education, etc than any other time period. 

Plus, YouTube has cats, and there's always /r/dogberg</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
