<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="415345595.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6vaapn/cmv_the_accepted_morality_of_today_should_not_be/">
    <title>CMV: The accepted morality of today should not be applied to different historical time periods when addressing the issues we face in today's society.</title>
    <original_poster>carter1984</original_poster>
    <original_post>In my opinion, history is virtually being rewritten right in front of our eyes and those with opposing views are too easily labeled racists and bigots. Regarding the current debate over confederate statues and/or monuments, The claims all seem to be centered around the morals (or lack thereof) of the confederacy in general and the people of that time, and the times the sculptures or monuments were erected and I think this is the wrong approach.

Virtually everyone in modern western society agrees that slavery is immoral, however this was not always the case. Slavery was practiced by civilizations all over the world for 5000 years, and indeed still tales place in some parts of the world today. Turning the civil war
into a debate over the morality of slavery through a modern lens is dangerously close to rewriting history and using it as a tool in modern political warfare. The civil war was largely about slavery, but more about economics (admitted the economics of the slave labor pool) and self governance than any moral crusade. By turning the debate into a "black and white" issue about slavery, we overlook the nuance and history of the tumultuous period and potentially damage our own abilities as a modern society to properly analyze, debate, and improve from what the period may have to teach. 

For more context, dueling was considering an acceptable way of settling debates even up to the early 20th century, a practice we no doubt condemned in a modern moral world. Age of consent laws across the country varied, but average somewhere around 12 years old until well after the civil war, and in some states was as low as 7 years old until almost the turn of the 20th century. 

Historical context is extremely important and is being forsaken in a modern political game as evidenced by the removal of not only statues  confederate generals but even of [supreme court justices](https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/md-politics/md-senate-president-slams-hogan-for-fast-vote-to-remove-taney-statue/2017/08/17/41833b12-8390-11e7-ab27-1a21a8e006ab_story.html?utm_term=.0237b3cedaa9), and removing our ability as a society to have debates about history in the proper historical context.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29626467577.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="False">
    <text>Once more right guys? 

Okay here are the reasonable but incorrect assumptions you're making:

- the statues are old and represent the thinking of a simpler time when mankind didn't know better. 

They aren't. The statues are from the 20s 60s and 70s and coincide with Jim Crow laws, the height of lynchings, and the civil rights movement. They were put up recently to try to intimidate southern blacks. 

- removing the statues is about punishing people who are evil because of slavery. What about Washington, will we remove his statues?

Removing the statues is not about slave owners. It is about not honoring people who literal fought a war trying to kill the soldiers of this country in order to sustain a system that the [whole western world had already figured out was wrong at the time](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Anti-Slavery_Convention) 

- removing the statues erases history. 

Statues are not history. They are memorials that honor legacies, people, and causes. Historical artifacts of value are being left in place or moved to museums like the national archives and Smithsonian where everyone can see them in their historical context. Most of these statues are not historical artifacts of history and *are* monuments to racism created by racists and attended in their construction and removal by racists. There were no history nerds protesting their removal because history nerds know that these statues do not in historic value. There were Nazis and white supremacist attending their removal because nazis and white supremacist know that they have racial oppression value. 

- confederate heroes aren't defined by their bad actions

Even General Lee thought confederate statues were a bad idea. Memorializing them encourages nostalgia for a wound that should have long since healed. Confederates are traitors to this country as defined by their legacy. Name one other country with statues of the heroes of a failed rebellion. There aren't any because it would undermine unity and social cohesion. Healing is more important. And even General Lee himself knew that. 

When asked to attend the dedication of a statue to confederate soldiers, General Lee replied:

&amp;gt;“I think it wiser moreover not to keep open the sores of war, but to follow the examples of those nations who endeavored to obliterate the marks of civil strife &amp;amp; to commit to oblivion the feelings it engendered.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29630713737.0" user="GinsbergsPeacock" delta="False">
    <text>I mostly agree with you, but you are mischaracterizing a central point which I think represents a huge blind spot in the liberal position on this issue. And, consequently, why I'm a bit more conflicted about the removal of these memorials.

&amp;gt; Statues are not history.

Neither is much of history, if we're looking for comprehensive factual accuracy. Our understanding of human history is only as complete as the record of art that has survived to modernity. And that necessarily includes monuments to evil people and publications of lies.

Put another way, human civilization is crucially dependent on the mechanisms by which we evolved into civilizations--the ability to pass on information in fixed media across generations. It is so far the only way we have been able to overcome the generational reset button when it comes to collective knowledge. But, as even recent history has shown, if history is sequestered in libraries and databases, whitewashed by new media, or eliminated altogether, people forget. Extremely quickly. Just look at vaccines. The Clean Air and Water Acts. Trickle-down economics. Allowing people to forget how bad things were--because, we *know* 90% of them will never research these things independently--is almost guaranteed to pull us back into the same problems given enough temporal distance.

To be sure, part of my conflict comes from the fact that, you're right, most of these statues were primarily in recognition of people and are otherwise devoid of express historical significance. And that, by letting these statues remain, it creates the impression that these men were important, when they were in fact just the product of small, ideologically motivated cults of personality.

But they do still say something important: that the South, even as recently as fifty years ago and by all accounts through today, is still a hotbed of crazy racist fanaticism. Crazy enough to build statues in honor of militant, racist shitstains. That is an incredibly important fact that, to my mind, should not be swept under the rug or forgotten.

Like many other historically wrong ideologies, I would rather some public records be preserved. I don't even see why there needs to be such an all-or-nothing approach to these statues, either. We could select a few statues of substantial historical significance to keep and destroy the rest. We could recontextualize the statues by erecting additional sculptures or buildings around them. Or even by outright defacing them and making them into mockeries.

I mean, I enjoy the catharsis of shitting on neo-nazis as much as the next guy. But I can't help but think that all of this is a bit shortsighted. Can we at least create a national "Statue Toppling Day" to memorialize this event as the progressive move everyone wants it to be, rather than the regressive move it might otherwise end up being?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29631068419.0" user="fox-mcleod" delta="True">
    <text>Cool. This is a good convo. I agree with you in sentiment. 

However, we obviously can't live in a constat state of preservation. If you live next to a run down rats nest of an abandoned factory, that is a **perfect** example of 90s post industrial grunge inspiration, should we keep it? Should we carefully remove *new* rust to preserve it as it was when it inspired Thurston Moore? Well, there is some merit. It really is something that we will be lost. It has an impact. 

Okay, well what if your daughter is at risk of getting tetanus and the runoff is lowering neighborhood values? Well now we have a decision to make. Maybe some things need to move on. 

In this case, we should ask, "does it do more harm or good?"

As a biracial person, I think I have a more nuanced perpective. I've seen racism. I look white enough that I've been friends with racists. My family members are the kind of people who are affected by the sentiment engendered by a walk in a park *named* for a man who fought for the right to *own* your family. 

These statues matter to racists - look at who protested their removal. They matter to southern blacks - look at who elected officials to get them removed. 

They don't matter to artists or lettered historians. Look at who was absent from the debate. There is a system for lobbying for historical status. *That* isn't what we're talking about is it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
