<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="419002642.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6xgoia/cmv_american_cities_are_terribly_designed_and/">
    <title>CMV: American cities are terribly designed and administered compared with European cities.</title>
    <original_poster>bostoninwinston</original_poster>
    <original_post>Most American cities are terrible compared to European ones. I'm not talking about big cities like NYC or SF- I mean the typical- the average- American city- is just awful by any objective comparison. You can go to out of the way cities in Italy or France, Germany or Belgium, and they build places as though their great-grandchildren would be proud to live there. Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history. In the US. there are few places to gather. The social life of American cities is incomparably lifeless compared to European cities. Our Cities are heavily segregated by race and economic class in the way European cities aren't. The architecture here is mostly corporatist modernism, and looks cookie-cutter. It quickly gets dated in the way the art of European cities don't. People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity. The average European city is vastly more productive than the average American one – despite Europeans having dramatically more benefits, time off, vacations in, and shorter work hours on average. We damage our environment far more readily than European cities do. Our cities are designed often in conflict with the rule areas that surround them, whereas many European cities are built integrated into their environment. We spend more money on useless junk thank Europeans do. Our food isn't as good quality. Our water is often poisoned with lead and arsenic, and our storm drainage systems are easily overrun compared to European water management systems.  European cities are managing rising seas and the problems related to smog far better than American cities are. 

I can't think of a single way in which American cities are broadly speaking superior to European ones. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29654935591.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="True">
    <text>Most of the things you note, the use of cars for transportation, building materials, etc., seem to relate to the lower population density in America. If there is more space, why build up or down, when you can build sideways? That, plus the fact that the automobile was developed alongside several American cities, means they were designed to be more car accessible and less public transportation. 

&amp;gt; People here have to get around by car, and as a result are fatter and live shorter lives than the average European. Our unhealthiness contributes to our under-productivity.

It’s not that simple. You have to figure in the choices America made regarding a social safety net, and the effects of wealth inequality in America. Japan for example, has much lower productivity per hour, but has a better average public health. And it can’t be because of driving vs. not driving, because most people in Japan use trains, cars, or non-walking/biking forms of transportation to commute. You are leaving out the factor of diet, which somewhat relates again to the geography. It’s hard to have healthy fish dishes for example, when you are far from a large body of water. 

&amp;gt; Here, the average city has no city center, major monuments, or sense of history.

This is the last one of your comments that struck me, and where I’m going to disagree the most. The reason why the average European city has more history, is because they’ve existed for hundreds of years longer. By the time America started getting settled, Europe was steeped in history. You can’t artificially add history into a city, and I think comparing a city with a 400 year history, and one with a 100 year history, is a bit of an exercise in futility. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29654985401.0" user="bostoninwinston" delta="False">
    <text>1) You're entirely right that much of what I find wrong with American cities is due to their lack of density. However, I don't think American cities had to build sideways, just as European cities didn't have to build densely. In fact, most American cities have laws that require that the city be built in a sub-urban manner. Almost no cities have a density minimum, almost all cities have a density maximum for various zones across the city. Why build up when you can build sideways? By building up and down, we dramatically increase the economic productivity of the land, reduce environmental impacts, and allow more space for agricultural production. This is why the tiny country of the Netherlands can the second to the USA in gross worldwide agricultural production. 

2) You may be right about japan, but I'm not comparing US and Asian cities. Yes- diet, etc, all matter. I don't think they demonstrably matter more than the urban environment. The French have been well known for eating much more saturated fat than Americans, and yet have fewer heart issues than we do per capita. Why? It seems to me the #1 feature is cityscape, which allows for people to bike and walk, not drive. This leads to more passive exercise and less anxiety. 

3) I'll give you a partial  ∆ for this one- You're right that we're young. But even so- when looking around American cities, you're lucky if you see 1 historical monument, and it seems like it's always to the Confederate Dead or some general from the Civil War. There are disproportionately few monuments to the dead of the Revolutionary war, war of 1812, Spanish-American War, any of the Indian Wars, the Mexican-American war, WW1, WW2, Korean War, Vietnam, etc. And that's just war-related monuments! Where are the monuments commemorating escaped slaves, great entrepreneurs, inspiring preachers, challenging artists, and any other notable individuals?  While Europeans seem to put up plaques, monuments, statues, arches, etc, everywhere, where are America's?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29655067258.0" user="shinkouhyou" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;The French have been well known for eating much more saturated fat than Americans, and yet have fewer heart issues than we do per capita. Why?

Current research has been pointing to sugar consumption as the major dietary contributor to heart disease, not saturated fat... and Americans eat a *lot* more sugar than almost anyone else in the world.  Medical conditions (chronic inflammation, dental disease, etc.) can also contribute to heart disease, and our lower level of access to affordable health care means that people are forced to let these conditions go untreated for decades.  

Americans are certainly less active on average than their European counterparts, but the walkability of cities isn't the *only* factor.  Americans tend to work more (500 hours more each year than the average German!) and take far fewer vacations.  More work means more time sitting (both at work and while commuting), less recreational exercise, more stress and a greater reliance on processed food and fast food. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
