<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424649670.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70tps6/cmv_compulsory_national_service_is_bad/">
    <title>CMV: compulsory national service is bad</title>
    <original_poster>advicemonkey69</original_poster>
    <original_post>I debate at school, and the topic is similar to this. While researching, I have come to strongly agree with the negative side and really can't see any justification to affirm the following: In the US, national service ought to be compulsory. By the way, this isn't a homework question or anything, I just really would like to hear others' opinions.

Essentially, national service isn't confined to military service, so if you would like to CMV using examples other than military, feel free.

I believe that making service compulsory defeats the purpose.  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.  Additionally, when looking at national service in terms of a draft, why? The US military already has plenty of people willing to go to war voluntarily.  

A draft would only bring citizens to resent their government.  Using utilitarian calculus is not necessary if the outcomes could be produced similarly in a way that doesn't violate peoples' autonomy, such as with voluntary service.  </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29698705022.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  People are more driven to do well and be effective in things they choose to do out of intrinsic motivation.

Hahaha. I honestly agree with this on a deep level, but at the same time it is not what's actually going on in the military. Intrinsic motivation is doing something you enjoy for its own sake. Now, some of the people in the military may fall into such a category, but I'm pretty sure the majority are in it for the perks, which have to be really good to get people to join such a godawful bureaucratic mess full of incompetent people in leadership positions. 

Note that this isn't from personal experience, but reports and complaints from my brother who is in the navy as a nuke. He's also an example of "in it for the perks". They pay for education, pay six figure money for reenlistment, and you get all sorts of benefits for having military service history - looks good on resumes, preferential hiring, discounts, etc. etc. 


The argument I'd make for compulsory national service - which would include non-military service - is that if you want to have a functional democracy you should want an informed public, and one thing you want the public informed about is what their government is doing, how it's being run, what it's like to actually be part of it. We have many anti-government people in the US who haven't the faintest idea, but we also have very pro-government people who also haven't the faintest idea. Those people can debate intensely but they're talking past eachother. This isn't a good situation for a society to be in because it's never going to settle on the truth, you'll get no positive synthesis from the discourse.

It also can give people a certain shared experience, something many of us I think lack and which may be important culturally.

Potentially it also takes people who are dumped into real world from a fairly inadequate education system that doesn't teach them shit about being a person in the real world, and puts them in a safer situation than where they'd have ended up otherwise.

It's also meritocratic and fair, in a way, with serious potential to reduce poverty. Everybody has to do it, and if you do well it may allow people who otherwise wouldn't have been given the opportunity some upward mobility. 



There are clearly a variety of logistical problems to solve to achieve such, but I don't think that "people should operate on intrinsic motivation" should be your argument unless you're also prepared to argue for a restructure of almost everything about a capitalist society, because that's simply not what most people are doing right now. I am a warehouse manager, do I want to do what I do 5x8hours every week? Fuck no, there is *no* intrinsic motivation. It's only to get money to fund things I actually care about - like drinking and talking, art and music, etc. etc.
  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698854752.0" user="advicemonkey69" delta="False">
    <text>I really like your intrinsic motivation argument. What about the people that wouldn't be capable of doing national service, like disabled people? Would they just be excluded? How would that work?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698876035.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="False">
    <text>Depends on the disability. There are things that physically disabled people can do just fine. Of course you wouldn't give a mentally disabled person any jobs where that could be a problem. Some might be excluded if they're too dysfunctional. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698879998.0" user="advicemonkey69" delta="False">
    <text>How would we be able to draw an objective line between those who are disabled and those who aren't? Couldn't that result in anger if some people don't see something as a disability and thus those people get off but they don't? Would the people who don't do their service go to jail? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29698890475.0" user="Havenkeld" delta="True">
    <text>We already draw lines, they may never be perfectly objective(whatever that means) but they just have to be better than nothing, which they clearly are. If a person cannot perform any sort of job without being a liability due to disability, don't give them a job. Very few people fall into such a category, usually it's pretty obvious - severely mentally challenged people - and they're already exempted from many things more functional people are expected to do anyway. 

And sure, people will find reasons to be upset over anything so this would be no exception, but managing the emotions of the entire population isn't feasible. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
