<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="424733549.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/70vii5/cmv_very_high_rent_prices_are_not_immoral/">
    <title>CMV Very high rent prices are not immoral</title>
    <original_poster>Cooldude638</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've just read this comment, and the ensuing thread: https://www.reddit.com/r/LateStageCapitalism/comments/70mzv9/housing_mission_impossible_xpost_runitedkingdom/dn4lx1v

I've seen the sentiment quite a bit lately that "rich people" acting in their self-interests directly screws over "poor people", and that this is wrong.

Economic theory dictates that this is not immoral. If nobody could afford the ridiculously high rent prices, nobody would have rents that high. Nobody would build luxury housing if nobody could afford it. Poor people have just as much a right to live in a city as rich people, but the reciprocate is true as well. It just so happens that the rich can afford to jump in line to get into the city. 

If it could be proven that these housing practices are some strange offshoot of redlining or something, i.e deliberately screwing over poor people for no economic reason, that would be sufficient to change my view. As it stands, I believe the evidence shows that this is simple supply and demand at work.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29699216307.0" user="goroboldo" delta="False">
    <text>Since when does economic theory or cause and effect dictate the morality of a thing? You're confusing "is" and "ought". </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699251249.0" user="Cooldude638" delta="False">
    <text>No, I don't think rent prices *should* be high; I think it would be great if everyone could afford housing anywhere they want. It would certainly make it easier on me.

This is not the case.

I've said that these actions are not immoral because the intentions are purely economic.

Here's an analogy:

A kitten is stuck in a tree. A fireman attempts to save the kitten but it falls and dies (the kitten, not the fireman). Is that action immoral based on its outcome? I say no.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29699259903.0" user="Super_Duper_Mann" delta="True">
    <text>~~You've contradicted yourself with your analogy.~~ 

~~&amp;gt;I've said that these actions are not immoral because the intentions are purely economic.~~

~~Here, you're saying that *intent* is the deciding factor of whether an action is moral.~~ 

~~&amp;gt;A kitten is stuck in a tree. A fireman attempts to save the kitten but it falls and dies (the kitten, not the fireman). Is that action immoral based on its outcome? I say no.~~

~~Here, you say that *outcome* is the deciding factor of whether or not an action is moral.~~

~~Which is it?~~

EDIT: Reread your comment and realized it is in fact consistent - my point above is moot. 

My reply in that case would be that if the fireman had a small army of economists telling him that all evidence points towards the fact that his climbing the tree will result in the kitten's death, but the fireman did so anyway for his own benefit (getting that hero story in the paper or whatever) then yes, it would be immoral. Such is the situation with current urban housing practices - developers and realtors ignore vouchsafed, long-term economics in favor of short-term profits, to the detriment of the local population. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
