<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="431133293.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/74ookt/cmv_i_should_turn_my_car_off_at_stop_lights/">
    <title>CMV: I should turn my car off at stop lights</title>
    <original_poster>Sleeper_in_the_code</original_poster>
    <original_post>I currently do not have a job, and will not be able to get a good one for a few years (I am in school and a bad student, so I need as few distractions as I can afford), and want to save money where I can. My commute has two (sometimes three) lights where I might have to wait for up to about two and a half minutes to get moving again, idling for that whole time. Seems to me that that is wasted gas, since I am not going anywhere but my engine is running. 

However, I have never seen anyone do this, so I can not help but feel like I am missing something obvious as to why I should not do this. 

I want to save gas, and therefore money, but I also want to avoid doing anything dangerous or illegal. 

Maybe this is a question for a different sub, but I have no idea where else I should go, and this seems like something that could be discussed. 

Edit: yep, I’m convinced. Saving money by not idling isn’t really worth the drawbacks, and if I’m really concerned, I should look into a car that is supposed to do this (a few years from now when I hopefully have more money). </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29749272428.0" user="bguy74" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly, you're adding wear and tear to your starting system - a lot of it.

Secondly, according to GM, this is only wise if your were to be stopped by at least one minute, and better 2 minutes.  Since you can't predict the duration of a stop then this pretty hard to pull off.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29749280327.0" user="Sleeper_in_the_code" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t think of the wear and tear, but you do say that its viable for a minute or two? My drive does have two lights that routinely take about that long. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29749309285.0" user="bguy74" delta="True">
    <text>Yup, that's the conventional wisdom best I can tell.  They do make cars that are _optimized_ for this, and they are built to handle both the wear and tear and to get the most gas savings - but, those do this automatically.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
