<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="444945722.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7cwqbe/cmv_eas_current_feature_of_buying_heroes_with/">
    <title>CMV: EA's current feature of buying heroes with credits in Battlefront is not outrageous or even out of the ordinary.</title>
    <original_poster>PeterPorky</original_poster>
    <original_post>EDIT: I've changed my view partially because I think BF2's situation is indeed unique, though I think the option of a grind that is comparable to many other games makes it not worthy of outrage.

So the situation is that in EA's new Battlefront game, the internet as a whole is outraged that players must play 40 hours to unlock Darth Vader, or to pay money to unlock that character.

I think this outrage is ridiculous, since paying for the ability to play as characters or to have other abilities is standard in other games, and that playing dozens of hours to unlock characters and abilities in other games is also standard, and has been for a long time.

Examples of pay-for-character/pay-for-ability games:

1. CoD (unlock the level 65 weapon day 1 with pre-order)
2. Most MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2 (very comparable loot crate system)
4. Age of Empires 2
5. Newer fighting games with other characters as DLC

Examples of play-for-character/play-for-ability games:

1. CoD (you must level up for a wider selection of weapons, perks, killstreaks, etc)
2. All MOBA's
3. Team Fortress 2
4. Super Smash Bros. series
5. Older fighting games
6. Goldeneye

Unlocking characters after long lengths of play has been a part of games since forever. In Super Smash Bros. Melee you'd have to complete 1,000 online matches to unlock Mr. Game and Watch (or spend dozens of hours completing difficult challenges). Mortal Kombat's Crypt system also had players playing for dozens of hours to accumulate credits to spend to unlock characters at the Crypt. Age of Empires and MOBA's have some characters/civilizations on free rotation, but you must pay money or grind countless hours in order to unlock characters/civilizations.

Unlocking characters or weapons by paying money instead of grinding to get them has been part of games since microtransactions have been a thing. The combination of the two has been a thing for just as long.

The outrage against EA is just part of another gaming echochamber source of outrage against another industry standard being blown out of proportion by an ignorance of looking at how things have been. CMV.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29858923812.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>The reason people are outraged is becuse of the use of the flawed loot box system. There are many things wrong with the the game and it is barely out. The reaction that is formed is a culmination of a lot of things for a game that people have been looking forward to for year. We feel betrayed that EA would try and pull something like this after promising no pay wall this and free this no day one dlc that.

For me and a lot of people it was the final straw. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29858970501.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The reason people are outraged is becuse of the use of the flawed loot box system. 

What's flawed about it? It doesn't seem any different than the loot box system in other games.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859089941.0" user="fenderkruse" delta="False">
    <text>Well the loot box system in general is a flawed way to handle unlocks in a game. There has been multiple good examples of systems that don't use loot boxes, which to be honest, is only relevant today because it enacts microtractions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859106389.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>Can you explain the difference between the loot box system here and why it differs from things like CS: GO, TF2, etc.?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859129604.0" user="Tino_" delta="False">
    <text>TF2/CS are skins and skins only. What you get from the boxes do not change the dynamics of the game, nor are they required to unlock core aspects of the game. CS has everything unlocked for you from day 1, and you can get every single weapon in TF2 for less then 2.50 from automated trade bots.

BF2 forces you to use the loot boxes to unlock parts of the game to increase the power of a class, or unlock an entirely new class.

The boxes in TF2/CS or Dota 2 are very different then they are in BF2.

Edit: To add to this, in the OP you said that TF2 has a very comparable model to the current BF2 one, and you could not be more wrong. TF2 is free to play, not a full $60-$80, anyone with steam can boot it at anytime and none of the characters or abilities are locked behind a paywall, they are locked behind skill and game knowledge. Weapons are "locked" behind a playtime wall sure just due to how random drops work, but the weapons are so cheap you can literally get all 156 of them for a single trade of less then 2.50 from the multiple trade bots that the community has set up. Yes if you are ignorant you can buy the weapons from the store, but other, much cheaper, options do exist and are advertised on a frequent basis. Saying that BF2 has a comparable system to TF2 could not be further from reality.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859194006.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; TF2/CS are skins and skins only

In TF2 you can buy weapons that are otherwise unlocked through playing hours of games. This is not applicable to just skins. Each character has their basic 3-5 stock weapons/abilities and each character has dozens others that are "found", or unlocked through achievements. Or you could buy them directly from the store.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859221914.0" user="Tino_" delta="False">
    <text>I have put over 7K hours into TF2. I am aware of the system and it is NOT comparable to the BF2 one, especially because like I said you can get ALL of the weapons in the game for less then a single key. The game is also a free to play game and not a full paid game, and stock is the best option 90% of the time excluding a single unlock in the crossbow for medic.

Even IF you want to push the idea that TF2 and BF2 are similar in the micro system, you don't get these weapons from unboxing, you buy them directly from the store. At best you get a chance at strange weapons from the older (5 or 6 year old crates) and at worst you can only unlock skins or cosmetics for the classes. This is unlike BF2, because you cannot directly buy the unlocks you want, you have to pray to RNG.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859245448.0" user="PeterPorky" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I have put over 7K hours into TF2. I am aware of the system and it is NOT comparable to the BF2 one, especially because like I said you can get ALL of the weapons in the game for less then a single key.

Fair enough. Is there a trade system in BF2 where I can either pay $9.99 for a Cow Mangler from Valve or $0.03 from someone on the market?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29859254065.0" user="Tino_" delta="True">
    <text>BF2 items / cards are locked to the account, no trades and no way to get them from a 3rd party.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
