<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="456163249.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7jl5td/cmv_the_current_state_of_sexual_harassment/">
    <title>CMV: The current state of sexual harassment allegations can have a devastating affect on social relationships and employee/employer trust.</title>
    <original_poster>totally_bamboozled</original_poster>
    <original_post>In the past 2-3 months, we've seen dozens of high profile men step down from positions of authority due to sexual harassment allegations. In many cases, it looks like these allegations are backed by credible evidence, but on the other hand, it seems like this culture of "Fire First, Investigate Later" could gradually turn into a kind of corporate witch hunt. 

I truly believe that rape culture is a real and scary phenomenon on college campuses and corporate workplaces alike, but it seems like this has the potential to spiral out of control. In a nutshell, we're promoting a culture where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email. With a few paragraphs of false, though believable information about a suspected incident of workplace groping, my personal career could come to an end. With it, my source of income and social/professional relationships take a permanent hit. When I've asked my wife about this, she has said, "Sorry, it's men's faults for creating this culture of insecurity and harassment for so many women in the first place."

I don't know how to explain it, but this seems like a scary path to go down. I'm a millennial that didn't grow up in the 1950's to help create decades of complicity in workplace harassment. Sexual harassment against women is a real problem, but it seems like there's no buffer between legitimate claims and claims that have the potential for abuse. Worse, sexual harassment allegations have included claims of "unwanted attention" and "unsolicited gifts" as credible allegations that could contribute to someone's firing. See [here](https://www.npr.org/sections/thetwo-way/2017/11/28/567026934/npr-chief-news-editor-departs-in-wake-of-harassment-allegationshere). Knowing that the line for sexual harassment in the workplace has been blurred to fairly commonplace social interactions means that *any* male employee/employer is at risk of losing their job. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29942832985.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;where any male's life could come crashing to the ground with a single email.

What makes you think this? Has it been a single e-mail that "did in" any of the people who have resigned?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29942869818.0" user="totally_bamboozled" delta="False">
    <text>Well I think that's part of the problem. There is no minimum threshold for assessing when an allegation is credible. One email? Two emails? Multiple emails? One really long email with screenshots of text messages? 

The real question is: are companies conducting thorough investigations? Are they looking through security footage from the alleged dates? Are they speaking with witnesses? Are they conducting interviews? Are they calling previous employers? 

Part of the problem is that many of these people are being fired 1-2 days after allegations come out, so it difficult to assume what, if any, level of investigation is conducted. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29943230345.0" user="stink3rbelle" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; There is no minimum threshold for assessing when an allegation is credible.

Is this how folks have *actually dealt with allegations*? Or is this just something you're afraid of?

I would urge you to reflect on a few things: Did Louis CK respond to a few rumors? Did Harvey Weinstein get ousted from his position after one or two allegations, or did it take more than that? Did Al Franken step down after one story, or several corroborating stories? Did Roy Moore drop out after one story, did anyone in his party call him out after the single story?
&amp;gt;Part of the problem is that many of these people are being fired 1-2 days after allegations come out

Really? I haven't seen *anything* of the kind. I have seen slow, almost deadly-slow action taken after several allegations come out. From your OP:
&amp;gt;this seems like a scary path to go down.

Frankly, I'm not seeing this, and I haven't seen any rational analysis that would support this. I don't even think we can say with certainty that the spate of recent allegations-and-repercussions are anything but a media trend. I wish we could. I believe that *if* we could, we could also begin to talk about some of what you're pointing to here: what kind of accountability we want to see; what kinds of allegations should be taken most seriously; how best to corroborate allegations like this. But right now, most of what's coming out is serial harassers who have gone ~~unnoticed~~ unnaccountable *for years or decades*.

Institutions are fairly resilient against change. They have permitted (or encouraged) sexual harassment within their structures *for decades*. There is no reason to believe that the current attention focused on the issue will change this state of affairs in the slightest. That is, I think your fears here are misplaced, and/or mis-timed. *If* national attention remains focused on this stuff, *if* we can institute some lasting changes to the ways we have encouraged and permitted this shit, *then* we can talk about how best to deal with the stuff. But unless your greatest ambition is to be a serial rapist CEO, I highly doubt you're at any real risk right now.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
