<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="464135371.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7oc157/cmv_people_who_hang_around_in_a_group_are_all/">
    <title>CMV: People who hang around in a group are all similar to each other and people who prefer being alone are too different from the them (the former)</title>
    <original_poster>zer0_snot</original_poster>
    <original_post>**Background:**

I've seen that we have two kinds of people in life. Those who prefer to hang out in groups - no matter where they go they end up being part of a group (almost always). And those that are always alone. They tend to be alone most of the time (most of the time).

**Belief 1 that needs to be changed:**

Let me elaborate on these points. For example, in the workplace your whole department might be divided into 5 groups. Then in each of those 5 groups the people are all similar to each other. You could say that group 1 has people of type A qualities, group 2 has people of type B qualities. If group 1 has 5 people then those 5 people are more or less similar to each other. I would say 70% similar in terms of life opinions, behaviors, attitudes etc.

CMV1: This is the reason why the group people get along with each other. It's because they're all similar to each other. They're just lucky that they were born with/absorbed such common behaviors that they always find similar people, no matter where they go.

**Belief 2 that needs to be changed:**

People who prefer being alone are very different from these group-guys. Such people usually end up being alone because they are too different. Their sense of humor is different, behaviors, perceptions, opinions, tastes are all too unique. So when they hang out in a group of people they cannot relate to the conversation or behaviors - because they are too different.

CMV2: No matter how much they try, the people who prefer hanging out alone can never be part of a group. It's because they're too different to fit in. The group-guys will never understand, appreciate or respect the loner-guys. Even when they're all hanging out together. It's only a matter of time before the group-guys start belittling the loner-guys for their lack of group-socializing-skills and making judgements on their whole personalities. It's just unfortunate that the loner-guys were born/developed into tastes that were just way too unique. Group-guys will never accept loner-guys.

**In other words:** 

We all fit into 2 kinds of people. 

The group-guys - who get similar people like them no matter where they go. I'm not saying a 100% similar, but like 70% similar. You all share the same tastes across movies, songs, discussions of the workplace, attitudes towards friends and acquaintances, mannerism of talking, eating/drinking/smoking preferences, hangout location preferences. They understand each other very well and become quick-friends.

The loner-guys - who are way too unique. There's like 1 in 30 guys who are similar to them. They mostly remain alone because they cannot fit in with the group guys. They will never get to be part of any group because of this. The group guys are all similar and loner-guys are way too different.

Please help me CMV!


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30005203689.0" user="ThatSpencerGuy" delta="False">
    <text>It seems to me that you're describing [extroversion/introversion](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraversion_and_introversion), which has been a useful concept in personality theory for a long time. In reality, of course, people fall along a spectrum, and most people will be more or less introverted in different settings or at different points in their lives. So it doesn't quite feel right to say, simply, that there are "two kinds" of people, though it may be helpful to roughly sort people into "extroverted leaning" and "introverted leaning" or something like that. 

In any case, introversion isn't uncommon, so people are not introverted because they are unique. 

It's also only [*one* part of a person's personality](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Big_Five_personality_traits), and it isn't the case that extroverted people are simply alike in all other ways. Some extroverted people are highly conscientious, others not at all. Some are highly neurotic, others have low neuroticism. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30005243352.0" user="zer0_snot" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; it isn't the case that extroverted people are simply alike in all other ways

I still feel that extrovert people are all alike. It would be great if you could point out a few examples to explain how you mean this. In my eyes, currently, I feel that all extroverts are all the same more or less.

Highly conscientious might mean in an ambitious way, right? Some people have a strong drive for life and some have lesser. I agree with them having a variation on the neurotic scale but they still have the same *tastes* and opinions, isn't it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30005262225.0" user="palacesofparagraphs" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Highly conscientious might mean in an ambitious way, right?

'Conscientious' means "meticulous, careful, governed by or conforming to the dictates of conscience." Basically, someone who actively tries to do the right thing. It's often used to refer to people who think about others' needs and wants. I suppose you can be conscientious in an ambitious way, that is, you try hard to do the right thing because you believe it will help you succeed, but ambition isn't a necessary quality of conscientious people or of extroverts in general.

I guess my main question would be what you think the qualities of extroverts are. 'Extrovert' just means someone who draws energy from being with others. But the personalities of such people can vary greatly. The personality of an actor is probably very different from the personality of a football star, but both might be extroverts with a lot of friends.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
