<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="468395254.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7qvc3a/cmv_congress_should_change_congressional/">
    <title>CMV: Congress should change Congressional elections to Mixed Member Proportional to end gerrymandering.</title>
    <original_poster>huadpe</original_poster>
    <original_post>Congress has the power to regulate and alter the "times, places and manner of holding elections for Senators and Representatives" under Article I, Section 4 of the Constitution.

Currently, under this power, the Congress [has mandated that all members of the House of Representatives be elected from single-member geographic districts.](https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/2/2c)

I propose that Congress repeal this provision and replace it with one requiring that members of the House be elected under a mixed member proportional system, with a bare majority of the seats apportioned to a state being divided into geographic districts, and the remainder being used to fill in based on party vote in those seats using the D'Hondt method.

For states with only 1 seat, this would mean no change.

For states with 2 seats, this would mean both districts were "at large."  The party who won the normal "at large" seat would also win the second at large seat if they had 2/3 of the two-party vote in the state, or in the event of a three+ party split, if they had achieved twice as many votes as the next-most-vote-getting party.  Otherwise, the next most successful party would get the second seat.

For states with 3 seats, 2 would be geographic and 1 would be at-large.

For states with 4 seats, 2 would be geographic and 2 would be at-large.  

For states with 5 seats, 3 would be geographic and 2 would be at-large.

And so on.

I don't have a firm threshold for party qualification for at large seats, but I'd be fine with anything from 5-15%.  Members running as independents would be able to run in geographic districts only, and I'd allow that any party winning a geographic district be allowed to get proportional seats regardless of the threshold.



This would effectively end gerrymandering, while still allowing local representation of regions of states with sufficient population to have 3 or more representatives.  The boundaries of those districts would become far less important, because the at-large seats would ensure that packing and cracking have little if any effect on overall partisan makeup.

This would also not require a constitutional amendment, since it would be able to be enacted under the Article I Section 4 power.

I think that at least one party (probably the Democrats) should run on this platform, and if elected, pass it into law.

*edit* fixed an error when I inserted a paragraph at the wrong spot when composing this.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30038552535.0" user="BrotherItsInTheDrum" delta="False">
    <text>I think this would be a positive change, but it wouldn't "end" gerrymandering. It reduces the importance somewhat, but people will still try to draw ridiculous boundaries around the geographic districts to gain an advantage.

I've argued for a related system -- for smaller states we just use proportional representation. For larger states, we split them into geographic regions of somewhere between 5-10 members, and use proportional representation within each region.

I think this does a better job of reducing the importance of gerrymandering -- because there are *no* single-member districts -- while still ensuring that geographic interests are represented in large, diverse states.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038588782.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think this would be a positive change, but it wouldn't "end" gerrymandering. It reduces the importance somewhat, but people will still try to draw ridiculous boundaries around the geographic districts to gain an advantage.

How?  What advantage could be gained?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038602722.0" user="BrotherItsInTheDrum" delta="False">
    <text>... maybe I misunderstood your proposal.

Under your system, aren't half the seats given to the winners of geographic districts whose lines are drawn using the same process that we use today?

Those districts will still be gerrymandered, just like they are today.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038611729.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The other half are given out though in a manner specifically designed to ameliorate gerrymandering.  So if you pack all the Democrats into 1 district and you win the other 5, say, but the state is 50/50 evenly split on popular vote, then the 6 at large seats will be apportioned 5 democrats / 1 republican to make up for it.

You can gerrymander your heart out for the geographic seats.  Then the at large seats smack you upside the head with a 2x4 that says "every vote matters."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038654206.0" user="BrotherItsInTheDrum" delta="False">
    <text>Ah, I did misunderstand.

Is there a detailed description of the exact system you'd propose that you can link? I don't think I've seen a system like this before.

Does an individual cast a single vote, which is used for both the geographic and at-large districts? Or do they cast two separate votes?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038669684.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>It's a well known proposal.  New Zealand and Germany it for their national government.  

https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mixed-member_proportional_representation

As I proposed it, one vote.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038697952.0" user="BrotherItsInTheDrum" delta="False">
    <text>In that case I'm struggling to see the point of this.

My understanding is that the allocation of seats is always the same as with proportional representation. If you win 60% of the votes, you get 60% of the seats, regardless of how the geographic districts are drawn or who wins them. So what's the point of the geographic districts?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038708635.0" user="huadpe" delta="False">
    <text>The idea is to retain the benefits of local representation.  So for a really big state like New York, you would want politicians who represent Buffalo to speak to the local issues Buffalo has that New York City does not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30038737792.0" user="BrotherItsInTheDrum" delta="True">
    <text>So there are a couple things I can't quite get past:

First, you make a reference to independents in your post. But anyone who votes for an independent is abstaining from the at-large election, right? If a popular independent runs, they would be essentially playing spoiler for the at-large election.

Second, I worry that people will "feel" like they're voting for an individual, when really they're *primarily* voting for a party. For example, Republicans could run someone really moderate in a safe Democratic district. People voting for him will feel like they're voting for a moderate, when really the effect of their vote is to elect a much more conservative Republican from the at-large list.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
