<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="476947007.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7vymnz/cmv_either_political_beliefs_should_be_a/">
    <title>CMV: Either political beliefs should be a protected class, or religious beliefs should not be a protected class</title>
    <original_poster>IJerkOffToSlutwalks</original_poster>
    <original_post>I am doing this CMV because I believe there is an ideological inconsistency in America when it comes to the concept of a protected class. The core of my view is that political affiliation and religious affiliation should be treated in the same when it comes to protected classes, regardless of what the classification actually is. In other words, I don’t really care if they are protected classes or they aren’t, but they at least should be the same. 

Here is a list of all the protected classes in America. 

- Race
- Color
- Religion or creed
- National origin or ancestry
- Sex
- Age
- Physical or mental disability
- Veteran status
- Genetic information
- Citizenship

Most of these classes have something in common - they are things that you are unable to change about yourself. For example, no one chooses where they were born, you’re just stuck with what you got. However, there is one notable exception in this list; religion. 

A person can choose their religion. They can switch religions or abandon religion altogether. It is my belief that the reason that religion is a protected class is because religious beliefs, while changeable, tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity and changing religions isn’t something that people do on a whim. 

I believe that political beliefs are just like this. They tend to be a very fundamental part of a person’s identity, and they tend to not change on a whim.

I believe that this is a double standard that should be corrected. What I’m saying specifically is this: if I can’t hang a sign on my business that says “no Muslims” then I also shouldn’t be allowed to hang a sign that says “no Republicans”. Similarly, if I am allowed to hang a “no Republicans” sign, I should also be allowed to hang a “no Muslims” sign. 

To change my view, you must convince me that there is a fundamental difference between political and religious beliefs that warrants the apparent double standard in our protected class system. If you can draw a convincing distinction between the two, that will change my view. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30105652162.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>

You make a good point that political beliefs and religious beliefs should be treated similarly, which is why I think the word “creed” is included with religion.  A “creed” is not necessarily religious, but instead can be broadly defined as “a set of beliefs or aims that guide someone’s actions”.  A political ideology can be considered a “creed” and can be protected accordingly. 

This mostly happens at the state level; most states have laws that protect people from being fired from jobs or otherwise discriminated against on the basis of political affiliation.  Most of the legislation seems to be concerned with protecting the rights of workers to organize unions or advocate for better working conditions.  There doesn’t seem to be much protection for other forms of discrimination, like being refused service at a restaurant, and I think the obvious reason is that it’s just difficult to even discriminate in that manner. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105680896.0" user="IJerkOffToSlutwalks" delta="False">
    <text>I hadn’t heard that creed is synonymous with political beliefs. If that’s the case, then how are companies able to fire people for their beliefs? For example, the famous Google memo.

I would also argue that it’s just as hard to discriminate based on religion as it is to discriminate based on politics in, say, a restaurant. You can’t tell someone’s beliefs based only on what they look like. However, we still have laws that say you can’t hang a sign up saying “no Muslims”.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30105746959.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="True">
    <text>

Did a bit of reading on the issue just now, and two points arose immediately in my mind:

First, the issue is being litigated.  California law does prohibit being fired for political discrimination, and political discrimination is being invoked in the lawsuit, alongside racial and gender discrimination against white men (snort).  The lawsuit is going to hinge on the factual matter of whether or not the employee was actually fired for his politics, his race, or his gender, or whether Google fired him for more legitimate and legally acceptable reasons.  In any case, the letter of the law in California still holds that firing someone for their political affiliations would be illegal.

Secondly, there is an interesting crossfire of issues going on in this case.  If the political affiliation being discriminated against is one which itself is accused of being discriminatory, what happens then?  This is what Google is going to argue: they fired an employee who himself was circulating memos that were discriminatory in nature.  If discrimination is a part of someone’s political creed, does discrimination against that political creed become acceptable?  And if so, how far do we need to go down somebody’s political rabbit-hole to determine whether they are actually discriminatory?  Hypothetically, you could have some weird Neo-Nazi who says, “I’m not discriminatory, I think all races should be included in my ideal political structure; it’s just that they should all be subsumed under the control of the master race for their own good, but I still believe that they have rights that should be protected and that they should not be completely discriminated out of the picture” – would this wacky viewpoint contain discriminatory elements that would justify an employer firing them?  How far would we have to indulge their views to reach that conclusion?  (Note: definitely not saying that I have any answers, I just think the questions are very interesting)


</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
