<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106518683.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106574965.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Well, this argument doesn't work for me. An omnipotent God could make us understand what's behind the door without us having to open the door in the first place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107204132.0" user="hamletswords" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't that make us omnipotent as well?  Life, meaning and even just happiness is all only possible because of our ignorance and the suffering it causes.  It's overcoming ignorance and difficulty that makes success meaningful.

I tend to agree with you, btw, that if there is a God he's got to be a kind of a fuckhead to put us all through this shit.  But I've also overcome some things and that sense of accomplishment and meaning would not be possible otherwise.

It's why I have a real hard time going to church even though I was raised Roman Catholic.  It's all about praising God, but if you think about all the pain and suffering in this world he created, why the hell would anyone praise him, let alone thank him?  The only answer is that you have a very broad and wise view of life, and I do not think the majority of people that go to church are capable of that, nor do I find much insight into that view in church services.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107350958.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>We attribute meaning to overcome struggles, but I think that's ultimately a human value, not a Godly one. It's difficult, probably by definition impossible, to attribute value to anything outside of our own human perceptions. 

But I think an omnipotent God should and would be able to overcome that barrier.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107382872.0" user="hamletswords" delta="True">
    <text>I'm not so sure.  Meanings by definition exist in part because they are not their opposites.  Happiness exists in part because it is not suffering.

A truly omnipotent God would not know suffering nor happiness, and maybe that is the gift we are given.

Think of it like a parent giving Christmas gifts to their child.  Santa isn't real, the gifts are actually bought via exchange, and there is no real proof Jesus existed.  But despite that, parents keep giving their kids gifts on Christmas, because their ignorance of reality allows them to feel some joy.

Parents do this year after year, and it exemplifies in part the motivation an omnipotent God may feel when prescribing ignorance for the human race.

The main point being that although an omnipotent God may not want humans to be sad, he may know that they must be sometimes to feel happiness.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
