<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106513514.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>

Have you ever heard of Leibniz’s “best of all possible worlds” argument?  Check this out:

https://www.britannica.com/topic/best-of-all-possible-worlds

The real fulcrum of the argument is the idea that human beings are incapable of actually imagining a world with less evil and suffering because of our limited perspective.  We erroneously assume that better worlds are possible, but when we imagine those better possible worlds we must be blind to how they would yield an even greater evil and more suffering than what currently exists. 


</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106578055.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>If the best world that God could create still includes suffering, does that not make it so they are no longer omnipotent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106611477.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>No, it means human suffering is inevitable - no exercise of power could eliminate it.  Even if God could eliminate it, God might not want to. Leibniz uses the word "omnibenevolent" to indicate that it's not just humans that God expresses benevolence towards.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106631075.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I'm trying to understand this.

I don't understand how this would no longer make them omnipotent? If they HAVE to make a world with suffering, how are they still omnipotent?

Apologies if I'm misunderstanding.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106949640.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="False">
    <text>Your misunderstanding is rooted in the human perspective that less suffering or no suffering is 1) a possibility, and 2) would be something that God would want.  

Even the omnipotent can't do something impossible, like making a four-sided triangle - omnipotence just means that one is capable of doing everything within the realm of possibility.  If we think we can imagine a world with less suffering, it's probably a delusion.  We don't have God's perspective on things so we don't see how what we imagine might actually create more suffering.

We also don't know whether God's benevolence necessarily means an elimination of human suffering.  It might be that God's benevolence extends to all of his creations, not just human beings, and to focus solely on eliminating our suffering would cause greater suffering across the universe.

We don't know these things, but it's important to note that Leibniz was working with the *axioms*, or presumed truths, that God actually exists, that he is omnipotent, omniscient, and omnibenevolent.  He starts with assuming these are true and logically deduces that this must be "the best of all possible worlds", even if it seems imperfect from our limited perspective </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107018185.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>"Even the omnipotent can't do the impossible." 

Then they're not omnipotent imo.

Yeah, if you decided those three things to be your criteria, then the best possible world theory makes sense.
But the issue with that  is you decided on gods nature before you had any actual evidence of it.
WHY do you think god is omnibenevolent? WHY is he omniscient? WHY is he omnipotent? 
These things are assumed because of how religious literature described God, not because of how God was actually observed to be.
I don't like theodicy because it's not attempting to define god based on how god actually is, rather the way we're told god is supposed to be.
The entirety of theodicy rides on those three assumptions, assumptions we have no proof of.

That's my opinion on it, anyways.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30107386294.0" user="DrinkyDrank" delta="True">
    <text>Of course you are right that the axioms themselves aren't infallible.  Leibniz was an 18th century philosopher, thinking in a time when Christianity was far more pervasive.  But in your post, you were really conceding those axioms and attacking the next stage of the argument.  You were saying that if God was omnipotent, then there should be no suffering, which isn't necessarily the case.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
