<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106442429.0" user="KevinWester" delta="False">
    <text>What if earth is just a training ground, as many religions believe? You live, you learn, you die. Then you start over (ie Buddhism, etc).

Suffering - although might seem very significant here and now - is ultimately just a tool to help is grow and learn. Might suck that your kid died, but in the grand scheme that kid's soul is just starting over in a new body and regenerating  and you probably went through some sort of growth in the process. 

Nothing really matters except for our continued growth and experience, guided by an omnipotent god.


Think of it like high school (earth). 14 year olds might think events that take place there are earth shattering and pivotal, while adults looking in from the outside (ie "god") know that all the drama really means nothing at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106464896.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>I guess the issue i have with this is what purpose would there even be for such a training ground? I have trouble comprehending why a god would "beat around the bush." Why put us through those trials in the first place if the omnipotent god already knows how it will turn out?

I think your response would work for a benevolent god, but not an omnipotent one.

Thanks for your response!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106481027.0" user="KevinWester" delta="True">
    <text>I mean, in such a complex setting - we're talking about endless possibilities, I imagine there could be many explanations. Maybe god is the collective conscious of all souls that and can basically "see and understand" everything simultaneously, but there is still room for overall evolution and growth that needs to come from experience. God doesn't have to be a guy in a robe or whatever, it could be something vastly more complicated. 

Perhaps god is the gatekeeper for this realm/dimension, but there are many levels beyond. 

A god can be omnipotent when it comes to this universe/dimension, but not necessarily the next. 

Lots and lots of possibilities. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
