<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="477042548.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7w0odw/cmv_god_could_be_either_benevolent_or_omnipotent/">
    <title>CMV: God could be either benevolent or omnipotent, but not both.</title>
    <original_poster>TaterTotsBandit</original_poster>
    <original_post>I have yet to see an argument that adequately explains the existence of suffering in the face of a benevolent, omnipotent God.

Provided God were both of these things, it wouldn't have created suffering in the first place. There wouldn't have been a need. To say that a God had to necessarily do something makes it no longer omnipotent.

I often see people say that suffering serves a purpose, such as bringing us closer to God or giving life meaning.

But once again, if the God were both benevolent and omnipotent, suffering wouldn't have had to be created in the first place. An emotion humans perceive as positive could just as easily take its place. If you claim otherwise, then that God is either no longer omnipotent or no longer benevolent.

No longer omnipotent because it can't get rid of a negative emotion, no longer benevolent because it can and chooses not to.


Edit 1: my opinion hasn't been changed but I've learned new concepts and been introduced to some novel ones, so the thread was still a success!!!

I decided to stop answer as most responses are currently bringing up free will, but the concept of that is for another thread entirely. 

I respect what others are saying, but i feel like ones conclusions about free will and the benevolence of creation is completely experience based. As such, I don't see a point in arguing over it as you can't change someone's life experience.

I'm still reading the responses, and will answer any that I feel I didn't address elsewhere in the thread.

Thank you all for your responses!

Edit 2: upon answering (I hope) every comment so far, it seems free will is more closely tied to benevolence than I'd originally realized. So I'll make a separate thread about that once I make my thoughts up on it (free will is one of those things that scare me, lol, so give me time pls).</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30106651710.0" user="EggcelentBacon" delta="False">
    <text>benevolence is subjective....so totally could. If God thinks he's benebolent, he is. God's subjective opinion of benevolence surely outways any other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106680683.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Well is that God really still benevolent if it doesn't even take into account the feeling, emotions, opinions, etc of its creations? I'd call that a tyrant.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106710233.0" user="EggcelentBacon" delta="False">
    <text>God wouldn't though and by merrit of being God he's righter than you. Basically God is whatvere he says he is by merrit of being God. that's sort of the problem with the God argument. much like arguing with infinte possibilities that I may date a supermodel with laserbeam titties...It's possible because of the infinite nature of infinite possibilities. So God being all powerful and all knowing and all... well everything, he/she may cause you pain as it is better for you in the end. thereby fulfilling the benevolence. or maybe recognises you are safest when you're depressed and hibernating in front of netflix and thus makes sure your life goes to shit...point is if you adhere to the notion of an allknowing allpowerfull God, you gotta accept he knows what's best and is thus benevolent. And yes most tyrants think they're being benevolent, but when the two conflicting opinions on benevolence are you vs God it makes sense to claim God is correct, because he would know...he's ALLknowing...he's God.  So it really bares no weight whatsoever if you would call him a tyrant....God's opinion outweighs yours. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106752933.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>But the only reason gods opinion is outweighing mine is because he isn't even considering it in this case. Once again, making it so he is no longer benevolent.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106770051.0" user="EggcelentBacon" delta="False">
    <text>if god is all knowing and omnipotent it stands to reason that every thought or feeling past present and future would be considered in every decison he makes. thus if consderation of your opinion (although i wouldn't even agree that, that is necessary for bevolence) is a criteria he fulfills this by the merrit of knowing and considering any information possibly availabe to him...which is literally everything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106785078.0" user="TaterTotsBandit" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so he considers any and all. But there is still suffering.  Sometimes completely unmitigated. I still don't see how that is justified, especially if his omnipotence could just get rid of the need for it in the first place.

And if you say that suffering is necessary, NO MATTER THE REASON, then God is no longer omnipotent. There's no such thing as true omnipotence if it is limited or restricted in any way.

That's my definition of the words, anyways. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30106821640.0" user="EggcelentBacon" delta="True">
    <text>Peiple onky sufder in their minds though, if one can even call it that. God may hot agree with this conception of suffering...and God would be right, because God is right. For examlle Death isn't suffering when the afterlife is considered. How could a mere mortal make a judgement on what contitutes suffering when a benevolent God may believe otherwise. And unlike the reverse if God believes something it makes it so...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
