<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="483439173.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7zts1x/cmv_an_econ_phd_program_is_the_best_decision_for/">
    <title>CMV: An econ PhD program is the best decision for me</title>
    <original_poster>GrandHomework</original_poster>
    <original_post>Background: I am 26, male, have no responsibilities outside of my full-time job, and have an undergraduate degree in finance. Currently, I make $68,000 a year and will consistently receive industry average raises, bonuses, and promotions. I’m happy with my current position and can imagine myself happy here for a long time. On a scale of 1-10, 1 being pig trough cleaner and 10 being dream job, I’d put myself at a 6.5 right now.

My reasoning for why I believe a PhD makes sense:

1.	There are very few things constant in my life, but one of them has been a lifelong passion for learning. I don’t play video games, watch Netflix, rarely hang out with friends like the average person, but rather spend all my leisure learning. As a result, I’ve amassed a great deal of knowledge over the years, and I find it unfulfilling if I don’t put it to good use. Aside from using it to play devil’s advocate on this sub with my actual account, of course.  From what I know about academia, a genuine interest in perpetual learning is a key to success.

2.	The general advice is to not get PhDs for the money. Maybe less so for econ, but I do it as a safety measure for employment, not as a foot in the door to private equity. I don’t care about money as long as my basic needs are met. More money is nice, yes, but I could live with my current salary for the rest of my life perfectly fine. I come from a pretty poor family, and have no desire for conspicuous consumption. While in undergrad, I once subsisted off of less than $2 a day for food and drink. Money is not more important to me than spending 40 (or more) hours a week doing something that I find meaningful.

3.	I have a life goal of being at least being remembered, somewhat. I can’t be an actor, or a singer, or a hockey player, but I have a chance of being remembered as an econ professor that students enjoyed learning from, or a researcher who helped publish a groundbreaking study. I'd die satisfied in these scenarios. Not to say that I’m using a PhD as a prop for an ego boost, but as a secondary function (to teaching and furthering research) that makes my career more fulfilling. This is something that I can’t do at my current position, as I’ll probably only ever be remembered by that guy in the company, which is very unfulfilling to me.

Possible avenues to change my view:

a.	Although I mentioned economic PhD program in particular in the title, I am open to entertaining other ideas. Though I’m not sure what transfers just as well from a finance undergrad. Keep in mind it's generally regarded that econ PhDs are very employable relative to other PhDs.

b.	Although my ability to reason is pretty good, my skill at math is quite low. I’d consider myself slightly below average for a STEM student. Competing students that are naturally gifted at such (which economic PhD programs tend to attract) will inherently have the upper hand on me throughout grad school.

c.	Any other opportunity costs of doing a PhD, which is 5-7 years. Keep in mind I don’t really care for money, not more than doing something with my life that is meaningful to me.

d.	The possibility that I will hate research. If most of research in grad school consists of reading and writing, which I have done happily for most of my life leisurely (sometimes on the topic of econ), I have very little reason to believe the same won’t hold true in the future.

e.	That I should get a master’s degree first. Theoretically if all goes well I will start my PhD at 27 or 28, which is pretty good timing. If I spend two years receiving a master’s degree first, I will be forced to complete a PhD program at a much later age.

f.	Anything else about being a PhD student I don’t know.


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30157273210.0" user="professorsheepkitty" delta="False">
    <text>I am well-versed in higher ed, but not up-to-date about your specific degree. There are many programs that allow either a) masters credits to count towards PhD or b) allow you to complete both a masters and PhD within ~5 years, like an accelerated program. I realize that the latter option would still have the end goal of having a PhD. However, if you are able to partake in option A, it is worth pursuing before you consider pursuing PhD. The market is becoming over saturated with advanced degrees; such degrees do not guarantee better employment. In fact, many colleges will opt to hire those with a masters degree. You can still get tenure with a masters degree too. Now you may not want to work in academia, but this is still a good indicator of employment in general. 
The advantage to obtaining a masters degree is that it isn’t as time consuming, still makes you more competitive, and will give you an idea of what a doctorate program will be like. If credits can apply to PhD anyway, then it would be like a bridge. 
Good luck! </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30157407239.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;There are many programs that allow either a) masters credits to count towards PhD or b) allow you to complete both a masters and PhD within ~5 years, like an accelerated program.

My current understanding is that the process of transferring credits between graduate courses is not as simple and streamlined as how you have it laid out. There are complications from school to school, across different states and across different countries. 

Regarding option a, there will eventually be some dead weight between the process of an initial master's program and then a separate PhD program after. Applying for programs, waiting for semesters to start, etc. it is less efficient than simply enrolling in a PhD program from the get go. The longer a PhD program is put off into the future, the less the ROI. Even if I start a PhD at my current age right now, when I finish, it's estimated I'll be several years older than the average age of a newly PhD grad.

&amp;gt;Good luck!

Wait... are you trying to change my view, or strengthen it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158129067.0" user="professorsheepkitty" delta="False">
    <text>I’m more so encouraging you to think of other options. Why does age matter so much? Just out of curiosity. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30158893810.0" user="GrandHomework" delta="False">
    <text>I spent a good amount of time thinking about your question. 

My answer is that it's not my age, but my intuitive feeling of how seamlessly a transition it will be from my current position (career wise, life wise, opportunistic wise) into a PhD program and forward. Currently I work at a tech startup as a technical writer and what I do has many extremely applicable elements. I'm currently single and have little to no other responsibilities outside of my job. Every other option simply seems distraught with chaotic, superfluous inefficiencies and I will not be successful as if I jumped straight into a PhD program.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30159431590.0" user="professorsheepkitty" delta="True">
    <text>I see what you’re saying, and that makes sense and helps me understand your position a little better. 
As a follow up, would you be okay living anywhere in the country? One thing to consider is that after you earn the degree, if you choose to be a professor like you mentioned above, jobs are highly competitive in academia; the institution chooses you instead of vice versa. There are many more PhD candidates than there are jobs as professors for many reasons now more than ever. Researching the job outlook would be a good idea. If you’re willing to live anywhere, single, and willing to take the risk that you might not land a job in academia, then PhD might work out. 
One risk of obtaining the PhD is the word “overqualified.” If you don’t get a job right away in academia, many employers will turn you away simply for the fact that you have an advanced degree and they don’t want to pay you more. Even if you tell them you’ll settle for a lower salary, they fear that you will leave them later on in pursuit of something like ... a job in academia. 
The above reasoning is what convinced me not to pursue it. I wasn’t necessarily willing to live anywhere, I wasn’t willing to take the risk of not landing a job in academia, and I didn’t want to hear “overqualified” especially given the fact that I already heard it after I earned my masters degree. 
I worked for a recruiting company for several years, and many employers told us to essentially toss any applications that had advanced degrees listed for the reason above. They valued skills and experience over degrees 
Here’s something to consider instead: go for a masters degree. 
Reasons: 
1. Two years is less time to commit. If you hate it, then it’s a short time.
2. You can have time to research and see if you enjoy it. I bet you would, given your self-description. You can learn research skills via writing a thesis and get yourself published. 
3. You can most definitely get a job in academia. Sure, you likely won’t be working for a place like MIT, but a masters degree can mean everything at a community college: tenure, department chair, or even just teaching. You would have the chance to be more picky on geographical location, and still do everything in academia. No, comm colleges aren’t as prestigious as universities. But you could use the community college to really make an impact in your field through teaching AND having an institution to help fund research and conferences. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
