<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495162519.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/86t1uf/cmv_euthanasia_should_be_legal_in_all/">
    <title>CMV: Euthanasia should be legal in all jurisdictions to be performed on humans.</title>
    <original_poster>SirenitoDelFrio</original_poster>
    <original_post>Euthanasia is the practice of painlessly killing someone due to terminal illness or extreme pain. If this is allowed to be performed on animals, then why are humans any different?

Since this is a messy political and ethical question, I’ll try to state my side of the problem only.

-

When a person is suffering, either do to cancer, life threatening injuries, a vegetative state, or any other factor that reduces their quality of life to nearly nothing, I whole heartedly believe that the execution of euthanasia should be allowed legally.

What joy from life does a person get if they are trapped in a hospital bed, with no chance of getting better? If they have no hope of living their life, then why should we continue to force their hearts to beat via machines? All the machines do is keep the heart beating, and drain the families bank accounts. They don’t keep the brain active, they don’t allow for communication. It’s simply a way for a hospital to earn money from a grieving family.

What is ethical about forcing someone to keep living, when they don’t receive the actual benefits of life? I just don’t see the moral responsibility of keeping someone alive when they receive no quality of life. I don’t get why someone should be kept alive if they have no chance of getting better.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30246712403.0" user="bobbybrixton" delta="False">
    <text>What could possibly go wrong when you give people the right to kill others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30246779379.0" user="SirenitoDelFrio" delta="False">
    <text>The thing with euthanasia is that the patient or family must consent, or it will be considered murder</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30247408805.0" user="briskyfresh" delta="True">
    <text>Patients can consent in the moment, but people's outlook on life can change drastically in a matter of weeks to months. It's just a matter of timing, and I don't believe that someone should be able to make the decision to kill themselves because of how they temporarily feel, even if their illness is forever.  

Have you seen the movie called "Me Before You?" I know it's just a Hollywood depiction, but I think watching it might change your mind. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
