<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="495807671.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/876vnb/cmv_social_classes_are_pointless_things_like/">
    <title>CMV: Social classes are pointless. Things like feminism and racism end up becoming about power, instead of equality.</title>
    <original_poster>obkunu</original_poster>
    <original_post>I’ve seen so many people get their panties in a bunch over men’s rights or women’s rights or Black Pride or White Pride. 

I get the idea. To make the dominant class take themselves less seriously and make the oppressed class take themselves more seriously, until the playing field is even. 

So when Katy Perry basically forces a guy to kiss her, it’s okay because men are to take themselves less seriously. But if a man forces a girl to kiss him, it’s not okay because women are already taken too lightly. 

I get the idea I really do. But lately it seems as though women won’t stop until men are basically jokes and women are deities. 

Same goes for Blacks and Whites. Has there ever been, or is there currently any social class based issue that isn’t about reverse dominance in the name of evening the playing field?

Seems to me like social classes are just insecurities being raised to art forms until there is something else to band together and complain about. 

Edit - Someone brought my attention to the actual numbers and they basically make the idea of reverse-dominance moot. So topic closed folks. I’ve changed my view.  (Don’t know if I’m doing this right.)


</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30251029889.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think this? What examples have you seen about women 'not stopping until men are basically jokes and women are deities'? Why do you think black people want dominance instead of pride?

For the record, I didn't like Katy Perry kissing that guy either. It had nothing to do with feminism, it was just the old double standard of 'of course men always want sex'.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251051897.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>This guy from work had a sexual harassment charge for saying a girl looked nice that day. He was just paying her a compliment. Ultimately, she lobbied so hard that the guy had to vacate his position. This is a gross show of dominance. She knew the courts would take your side. She knew the man can’t fight back, and she painted him as a fool and a pervert, and cost him his job because she was offended. 

This also happened with my father. Thankfully, he is known to be squeaky clean around the office and they laughed at the girl for even suggesting he had sexually harassed her. 

These stories routinely come up in my circle. Why? Why do these women want to run such a tight ship and basically be worshipped? They now work for the same pay and they are able to give more aggressive compliments to guys all the time.

Similarly, I’ve seen Black people who were dismissed for lack of merit use the race card. Why this show of reverse dominance? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251058496.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>Your two stories contradict each other, though. The first guy has to vacate his position because men can't fight back, but your father had a good reputation and therefore no one believed the accuser. Either the first person did not have a good reputation or something doesn't add up.

&amp;gt;These stories routinely come up in my circle.

And 'my circle' regularly has stories about how men harass women and people refuse to believe her. 

&amp;gt;Why? Why do these women want to run such a tight ship and basically be worshipped? 

See, it's statements like these that makes it hard to have these conversations. Women don't want to be complimented, but they want to be worshiped? That doesn't make sense. 

&amp;gt;Similarly, I’ve seen Black people who were dismissed for lack of merit use the race card. Why this show of reverse dominance?

Misusing the race card isn't 'a show of reverse dominance', it's a black person being an idiot. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251077231.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>My stories do not contradict each other. The first guy had no reputation. He kept to himself. But my dad has a reputation for being clean, so it was harder (impossible) for his accuser to take him down. 
  Should a man have a reputation to stand a chance against a woman? Shouldn’t the particular incident be analyzed before you ruin the man’s life? 


&amp;gt;And 'my circle' regularly has stories about how men harass women and people refuse to believe her. 

  I thought I wouldn’t mention the possibility of your being insincere regarding this debate when you brought up that “contradiction”. I thought maybe you misunderstood. But this makes me really reconsider my position. If you want to continue debate, do it without assuming I’m a liar. Ask if you need examples. But don’t be arrogant and demeaning. 


&amp;gt;See, it's statements like these that makes it hard to have these conversations. Women don't want to be complimented, but they want to be worshiped? That doesn't make sense. 

It doesn’t make sense, or you don’t want it to make sense? It’s pretty clear in that incident what I meant by “worship” — Say anything I don’t like and I’ll take you to task for it. 

&amp;gt; Misusing the race card isn't 'a show of reverse dominance', it's a black person being an idiot. 

A show of dominance is when you knowingly abuse your power. When a Black person knows everybody will take their side, and they know they’ve got the White Employer on the back foot, they are abusing their power. 





</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251082732.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I thought I wouldn’t mention the possibility of your being insincere regarding this debate when you brought up that “contradiction”. I thought maybe you misunderstood. But this makes me really reconsider my position. If you want to continue debate, do it without assuming I’m a liar. Ask if you need examples. But don’t be arrogant and demeaning.

You read a lot into something I intended as 'my experience is different, so I don't see how this is relevant'. My bad, I should have been more clear.

&amp;gt;It doesn’t make sense, or you don’t want it to make sense? 

Yeah, okay. I'm done here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251093193.0" user="obkunu" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;&amp;gt;It doesn’t make sense, or you don’t want it to make sense? 

&amp;gt;Yeah, okay. I'm done here.

I’m sorry. I was pissed when I thought you were being arrogant and demeaning. I’d like to hear it, if you have more to add regarding the subject. But I understand if you don’t want to. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30251104928.0" user="Hellioning" delta="True">
    <text>Thank you for your apology. 

Basically, the issue I see here is that I simply don't see anyone losing very much just from a sexual harassment claim. I'm sure it happens, but I have far more experience with people being harassed and not being believed. Plus, [only somewhere between 2 and 10% of rape claims are false.](https://icdv.idaho.gov/conference/handouts/False-Allegations.pdf)

Obviously, this doesn't mean that false rape claims do not happen, but it's not as much of an issue as actual rape. I can't find a study on false sexual harassment allegations, unfortunately.

Incidentally, I'd also like to see an example of a black person, dismissed for lack of merit, using the race card and having everyone actually take their side. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
