<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="496153887.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/87easf/cmv_most_modern_medical_advances_have_come_from/">
    <title>CMV most modern medical advances have come from companies looking to profit in the American medical system, and if America were to switch to a European style system then progress would slow worldwide</title>
    <original_poster>Extratydoncbicbslleb</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this without a ton of knowledge about the recent history of medical advances, but it seems to me that most modern medical companies don’t see much money to be made in socialist systems. While they will take the profits they can get there, if America were to switch as well medical advancement would stall (with the advantage that the current top quality of care would be widely available)

I am fully aware that there are numerous inefficiencies in our healthcare system unrelated to capitalist/socialist systems but that isn’t the subject here


Thanks </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30253766739.0" user="SurprisedPotato" delta="False">
    <text>There are different kinds of medical advances, and the most important kinds don't bring large profits. 

One fantastically important advance that's happening now is the eradication of polio. There used to be hundreds of thousands of cases annually, with high fatality rates, and many victims left permanently disabled. 

Last year, there were 27 cases worldwide. 

The Big Bucks response to Polio would have been expensive interventions in hospitals, and expensive patented medication. The actual response - eliminating polio via a thorough vaccination programme - has been much more effective, but involved *spending* money. There's no cash in eliminating disease. 

Malaria cases have dropped by 67% in the past two decades, from 1.5 million annually to 500,000 annually. The Big Bucks response would have been experimentation with expensive medication - but since Malaria is almost unknown in the wealthy parts of the world, there was no money in that. Instead, astounding progress has been made by distributing insecticide-treated mosquito nets to affected areas. There's no cash for wealthy health companies in that.

In the developed world, perhaps the biggest health crises now is obesity. The Big Bucks solution would be new cholesterol medications, or surgical treatments. However, the most effective treatement for obesity is diet and exercise, which also reduces your chance of a huge number of expensive and dangerous illnesses. There's no money to be made in educating the public about the need to eat healthy and walk 30 minutes a day.

An upcoming health crisis is antibiotic resistance. My mother-in-law passed away in January, when a wound on her knee got infected by a normal skin bacterium that happened to be resistant to all the antibiotics they tried. There are already strains of tuberculosis which are resistant to all known antibiotics. Google tuberculosis. It's a very unpleasant illness, and we may soon have no way to treat it. 

The world urgently needs research to discover new antibiotics. And, when new antibiotics are discovered, and found to be effective and safe, they need to be *not used*, but kept in reserve to fight the strains of disease that are immune to all the others - because if the new antibiotics get used, the bacteria become immune to them as well, and we're back to square one. 

There's no money to be made in investing hundreds of millions of dollars to discover new medication that is then only sparingly used. 

In all these cases, keeping the American Healthcare system only promotes certain types of innovation - specifically, innovations that discover expensive treatments, where a market for the treatment exists. In many important cases, there are cheaper treatments that are more effective. Either medical advancement is rolling along just fine without Big Pharma, or medical advancement has stalled anyway, because Big Pharma can't see a way to make money there.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30253841262.0" user="Extratydoncbicbslleb" delta="False">
    <text>The polio example is a strange counter to the argument- on the one hand it’s vastly outside of the normal way American healthcare works true, but it was still made in America.

Regardless that isn’t what I’m asking, I’m asking if there have been great advances outside of the American system (and not including foreign companies that are funded in the hopes of American profits)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30254319480.0" user="SurprisedPotato" delta="True">
    <text>The US is the leader in health research, as measured by the sheer number of papers published. 

I grabbed [data from here](http://www.scimagojr.com/countryrank.php)

However, the US has a huge population. If you account for population, then US drops all the way down to number 24 in the world. 

I grabbed [population data from here](http://www.worldometers.info/world-population/population-by-country/), and put it with the publication data into [this spreadsheet](https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1p-Hmk9IVM1nj2Eoq75uquEUqR5akzFj_Pied-xyRJTg/edit?usp=sharing)

If you believe that the type of healthcare system a country adopts has an effect on the amount of health research output, then you should encourage the US to adopt a healthcare system similar to Switzerland, Denmark or Sweden. 

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
