<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="503594194.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8btrrm/cmv_america_doesnt_need_more_stem_majors/">
    <title>CMV: America doesn't need more STEM majors.</title>
    <original_poster>brotherhood4232</original_poster>
    <original_post>I used to follow the Reddit consensus that STEM = good and "basket weaving" majors = bad. I graduated with an electrical engineering degree myself. But after looking for a job myself, it doesn't seem like the job market could support a ton of more STEM majors.

I've seem very few job postings that said Entry Level. Most want 3\-5 years of experience and a host of qualifications that no new graduate will have. This means you are not only competing against other new graduates, but you are also competing against Mid\-Level STEM professionals. I think a flood of new STEM graduates would exacerbate this problem and a lot of those new engineers would be working at Starbucks. Change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30309645691.0" user="limbodog" delta="False">
    <text>Just so you know, those '3-5 years experience' postings are often the ideal candidate, but not the only potential candidate.  Apply for those anyway unless they literally say "applicants with less than 3 years experience will not be considered."

Employers want the best they can possibly get just like employees.  Someone's usually got to settle.

I mean, I got my job with a HS diploma and no direct experience when they wanted a degree and several years of specific experience.  They clearly settled for me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309668530.0" user="brotherhood4232" delta="False">
    <text>I do apply anyway. But clearly, these employers want more. I might see 10\+ years experience even more than I see 3\-5. Should I apply for these as well? How can an new grad compete with all of that experience? It seems like what employers really really want is a bunch more experienced engineers in their late thirties to exist. Or more STEM Masters and PhD graduates.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30309748348.0" user="limbodog" delta="True">
    <text>Yes, that's what they want - for the ideal candidate to be available and not want to get paid much.  We're currently in a bad situation in the USA.  We have near full employment, but salaries have not increased much.  If salaries catch up, people will move around more and those positions will become more available.

But the only real part that I wanted to CYV on was that a job posting saying 3-5 years experience is ideal doesn't mean that those are the only people they'll consider.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
