<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="505621166.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8d17se/cmv_activists_should_abandon_the_phrase_white/">
    <title>CMV: Activists should abandon the phrase "white privilege" because it alienates white people who didn't grow up wealthy</title>
    <original_poster>ShiningConcepts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Blacks are [more than twice as likely to grow up in poverty](https://www.kff.org/other/state-indicator/poverty-rate-by-raceethnicity/?currentTimeframe=0&amp;amp;sortModel=%7B"colId":"Location","sort":"asc"%7D), [disproportionately sentenced for the same crimes](https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2017/11/16/black-men-sentenced-to-more-time-for-committing-the-exact-same-crime-as-a-white-person-study-finds/?utm_term=.b0e81ca325dc), [several percentage points ahead in terms of unemployment statistics](https://www.bls.gov/web/empsit/cpsee_e16.htm), prone disproportionately to police arrests incl. for nonviolent drug usage, and the list goes on. There are a wide variety of issues minority rights activists bring up that are legitimate - I'm not here to dispute those. I fully support that fight.

My view here is that the usage of the phrase "white privilege" is wrong and should be retired. Many upper class white people are privileged as they are immune to the ripple effects of a racist history (and the modern day effects of racist police departments and shitty schools in minority neighborhoods). But for the poor white ones, which there are many, the phrase white privilege should be abandoned. Because it minimizes and implies less importance for the suffering countless poor white people had to go through - while blacks are disproportionately victims of all the things i mentioned, some whites are the victims of them to.

I understand why a white person who suffered hardship in their life would feel alienated by hearing someone throw around the term "white privilege" - the term asserts there is a privilege in being white. There is privilege in being rich, but not solely in being white. So, the term should be abandoned in the interest of not alienating poor white people from a legitimate movement that has legitimate concerns.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30326208961.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="False">
    <text>But those poor white people still do have advantages that they didn't earn simply based on the color of their skin. Just because someone can't see the benefits of being white doesn't mean that they don't exist. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326308772.0" user="ShiningConcepts" delta="False">
    <text>What advantages does a white person born into an underfunded foster home, attending a useless and underfunded school, who is harassed by police officers and thrown in jail over nonviolent drug usage have? I'm sure there exist lots of poor white people whose quality of life and income falls below that of even the average/median black person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30326328678.0" user="Iswallowedafly" delta="True">
    <text>All the ones that come with being white. 

A white person in that situation will have advantages over a person of color in that same situation.

That the only type of comparisons you should be looking at.  All things being equal it pays to be white in this country. Society does give an easier path if you are white. Now I didn't say easy. I just said easier. 

WE can't forget that racial bias still exists. We can't forget that this racial bias does affect people in everything from getting a job to renting a place. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
