<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="514822279.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8iifev/cmv_history_would_have_largely_gone_better_if_the/">
    <title>CMV: History Would Have Largely Gone Better if the Nationalists had Won the Chinese Civil War</title>
    <original_poster>Kasunex</original_poster>
    <original_post>I'm aware that this is a tricky topic, so I'm sure the responses to this will be very interesting. Basically, I contend that, based on what we can assume, if the Nationalist Government of the Republic of China had put down the Communist Revolution, history would have gone better. Now "better" is a relative term, but I'll explain why I believe so.

First, the obvious. Mao Zedong's government killed around 45 million people. Some people put that number as high as 78 million, but either way, he's up there with Hitler and Stalin as one of the most brutal dictators and mass murderers in history. Chiang Kai\-Shek, on the other hand, was not exactly a benevolent ruler either; but the most excessive count I can find puts him as responsible for 18 million deaths. Still far too high, but far cry from Zedong. Let's also not forget that only about 2.8 million of those deaths were from corruption or political repression. The rest were the result of war. So; even if Chiang had continued corrupt and repressive policies in peacetime, that's still millions of lives saved right off the bat.

Secondly, there's the likelihood that the Republic of China would have reformed into a democracy. That's what it did on Taiwan after all, on top of becoming one of the "Four Asian Tigers". Let's not forget that, ideologically speaking, the Republic was only supposed to follow authoritarian policies until the country was stable and educated enough for democracy. Of course, there's no way of knowing whether or not the Kuomintang officials would have honored their pledge, and this also doesn't mean that the transition would have been smooth. But, it still seems likely that it would have happened eventually. Communist China is still a dictatorship today. I doubt the shallow, corrupt system that the Kuomintang perpetuated would have been so stable to the democratic wave of the late 80s and early 90s.

Third, there's the benefit for the rest of the world. With China an anti\-Communist ally, the Korean War would have gone much differently. North Korea would have been surrounded by American allies, and thus less likely to attack South Korea. But even if it had decided to do so, the only chance of victory it would have is if the West just didn't care enough to stop them. I'm aware that the only way America was able to get a coalition together from the UN was thanks to the Soviet Union boycotting over Taiwan, but let's be honest, it's not like America and South Korea couldn't have defeated North Korea on their own, especially if China was on their side. So, either no Korean War or a decisive Western victory. In a Western victory, Korea is united, all those killed by Kim Il\-Sung survive, and the united Korean Republic likely would be democratic as it became in our timeline. The Vietnam War is a lot more difficult to predict, but it's also very possible that it would either not occur; or be a Western victory.

So there you have it. At the very worst case scenario, a few million would have survived. In the best case, millions would survive on top of two wars being prevented and China, Vietnam, and Korea becoming democratic. I am not saying that Chiang Kai\-shek was a good guy, or that he deserved to win, or that his wining would have suddenly turned Asia into a utopia. Just that, based on what evidence I have seen, a Nationalist China would have saved millions of lives and possibly spread democracy as well.

If you want a delta, remain respectful. Don't be condescending, don't try to claim that your argument is "just so obvious" or that anyone who disagrees is stupid, uneducated, etc etc. It annoys me enough when people do that in other arguments, and this is a very opinionated and complicated topic. Also, giving credit where credit is due and solid, concrete examples are huge pluses. That said; don't be upset if I don't give you delta; I don't always give them even when I like the points made.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30401177468.0" user="Carbon_Hack" delta="False">
    <text>It may have lead to a war with Russia, which would have been the sole remaining communist power if this happened. America is known to be a little, er, overbearing at times, and this could have lead to them feeling that they had enough power to pressure Russia to change to a democracy... and if they decided to not switch, it might have lead to nuclear war. Whilst the world isn’t perfect, it’s it a lot better than a nuclear wasteland</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401217546.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>That's possible, but I don't really know why the USA would be in such a rush. I mean, communism is surrounded and blocked on all fronts, why would there be a willingness to risk nuclear war? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401233640.0" user="Carbon_Hack" delta="False">
    <text>The USA has always moved fast, and it would also see Russia as the only threat remaining in the world. If Russia did cave, a New Democratic Russia, China, and USA would basically rule the world with uncontested. The US, knowing this to be true, would likely get a little too aggressive. Another possibility  is that a democratic revolution starts and the dying Communist government gives shoot to kill orders on protesters. This would almost guarantee a war as Chinese citizens would feel like their northern brothers had just been slaughtered. The US, which would probably be good buds with China, would come in to help. Any war with dying Russia is a nuclear war with dying Russia.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401263106.0" user="Kasunex" delta="False">
    <text>Hmm...your argument digs pretty deep into hypothetical territory, but also brings up an interesting point about the world balance of power. Today, China is the biggest check on America's power; only doomed Russia would remain in this timeline. Would the western world having that much unilateral authority be good or bad in the end? I'd like to say good, but that sort of concentrated and unchecked power can lead to some pretty bad results. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30401284582.0" user="Carbon_Hack" delta="True">
    <text>It would definitely be good for a while, but would likely lead to massive corruption later on. Or we might see the development of new alliances. If the new trifecta of superpowers got a little bit to overbearing, Europe or the Middle East might begin to to take major steps to resist their influence.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
