<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440305098.0" user="TheManWhoWasNotShort" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, the Michael Brown case is one of the most important cases out there for the issue of police brutality. You know and I know and everybody's dad knows that Laquan McDonald shouldn't have been killed.  That case is obvious and egregious. 

It's the borderline cases like Michael Brown that help to define what is and what is not acceptable use of force.  Michael Brown struck the officer, but appeared to be running away.  Is it okay for an officer to shoot a fleeing suspect not currently attacking? There is conflicting evidence of whether Brown was facing officer Wilson or not when gunned down.  Is it acceptable for an officer to shoot a suspect not even facing him?  Michael Brown was approximately 30 feet away from Darron Wilson.  Was that close enough to warrant firing or is that far enough away to react with non-deadly force? 

If we want police to engage with the public in a reliable manner which the public can trust, these are just some of the questions we need to iron out.  Cases like Michael Brown give us the questions we need answers to.  How far is too far for deadly force on an unarmed suspect? When can you shoot a fleeing suspect? When are other methods of force usable and preferable? All these questions need clear answers, and these cases give us those answers and tell us if we need to reform police policy.

The law is made with the fringe cases, not the obvious</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440334256.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>That would be an excellent use of this case, but I rarely hear it detailed in that manner. It's usually used in the same manner that clear cases of police brutality are. TIME, for example, ran a cover page showing him linking arms with MLK. There is no entertaining the possibility that the shooting might have been justified for many people. 

As for your middle bit, yes, he did strike an officer and attempt to gain control of his weapon. That right there, full stop, should say something. If anyone, of any race, manhandles, strikes, and attempts to take the weapon from a police officer, they should be *very* thankful if they survive the encounter... but they shouldn't expect to. On the long list of things you *shouldn't* do if you're not trying to get killed by a cop, assaulting them and trying to disarm them are probably things 1 and 2. 

There really isn't much conflicting evidence on which way Brown was facing or moving when he was shot. He did attempt to flee, yes, and Wilson pursued him, which only makes sense. Brown (who had just demonstrated ample ability to violently manhandle Wilson and a desire to take Wilson's gun) then charged Wilson. There were no entry wounds on Brown's back. ["Brown’s blood in the roadway demonstrates that Brown came forward at least 21.6 feet from the time he turned around toward Wilson."](https://www.justice.gov/sites/default/files/opa/press-releases/attachments/2015/03/04/doj_report_on_shooting_of_michael_brown_1.pdf). And most disinterested eyewitnesses corroborate Wilson's story, forensic evidence, and the autopsy. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440410399.0" user="TheManWhoWasNotShort" delta="True">
    <text>This case drew battle lines specifically because it is so controversial. What you saw were people strongly advocating for this to be considered lethal use of force, many on the Left, and people strongly advocating that it was not, many on the Right.  The media and political figures aren't really where you're going to find a nuanced discussion of the law and specific policy.  That happens in courtrooms through precedent and in police stations through political pressure. 

What did happen, though?  [Missouri updated their Use-of-force statute] (https://themissouritimes.com/31453/nixon-signs-bill-to-update-missouris-use-of-force-statute/) to include language which states that a police officer may not use lethal force on a fleeing suspect unless they have probable cause to believe the individual may be a lethal danger to others.  This is a direct result of the issues that the Michael Brown case brought up.

So while the media has been a warzone of people advocating strongly one way or the other on these issues, clear rules are being created to address the questions being presented.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
