<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="519757161.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8lg76x/cmv_michael_brown_doesnt_deserve_a_place_in/">
    <title>CMV: Michael Brown doesn't deserve a place in discussions about police brutality.</title>
    <original_poster>chadonsunday</original_poster>
    <original_post>So obviously the [Michael Brown shooting](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shooting_of_Michael_Brown) happened quite a long time ago, and at the time it was seen (incorrectly, in my view), as just another in a long string incidents where racist cops gunned down innocent, unarmed black men. This view was espoused by lots of people, including Al Sharpton and then President Obama. And, given the not-so-low-level hysteria surrounding this alleged epidemic of racist cops murdering black folks, I suppose I can forgive people for jumping to conclusions *when it happened.* But the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now, and I'm *still* seeing people (twice on Reddit just today - prompting this CMV) listing him among other, *real* victims of (possibly racist) police brutality. 

I believe this damages the BLM or BLM-type cause - Brown, more than perhaps any other person killed in a controversial shooting, deserved every bullet he got, and Wilson, the officer who shot him, showed a fair amount of restraint before opting to shoot him. If you list a real criminal who was practically begging for death-by-cop alongside *real* victims of police brutality, you diminish your credibility, and tarnish the victimhood of those who didn't deserve to die: if your bar for what constitutes police brutality/racism is as low as the shooting of Michael Brown, one would have reason to doubt your credibility, knowledge, or sincerity. 

Look, the one and only reason the Brown shooting is even controversial in the first place was because it sparked months and months of intermittent riots and protests *before* the facts came out, and then more once the facts *were* out. It's notoriety was further boosted by prominent figures like those I mentioned commenting on it as a case of police brutality, and even moreso since it was the genesis of the "hands up, don't shoot" chant. But it is *not* controversial because Brown didn't deserve to get shot. Including Brown in the list of black men victimized by the police is, in effect, saying it doesn't matter if any given shooting was actually justified or not so long as facets of the public get sufficiently outraged about it. 

This post is, to some extent, contingent on your agreement that police should *ever* be able to use deadly force. If you disagree with that that's fine, but I really feel it's another discussion entirely. Assuming we *do* agree police should be allowed to shoot people in certain circumstances, the Brown case is a great example of what a justified shooting looks like. 

Y'all know what to do. Cheers. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30440326382.0" user="BolshevikMuppet" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the facts of the shooting (most importantly, that cops only made contact with Brown since he just assaulted and robbed a convenience store worker, that he evaded arrest, that he assaulted a police officer, that he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again) have been out for many years now

By "the facts" you're referring to facts which were established by multiple witnesses (or a witness and forensic evidence) and were not contradicted by anyone else?

Or are you referring to the facts as stated by the police themselves in defending their conduct?

If it's the latter, I'd really encourage you to at least consider the possibility that a police officer under investigation by both his own department and the FBI might have an incentive to "remember" circumstances justifying the shooting.

In particular:

&amp;gt;he tried to take a cop's weapon, and that he attempted to charge said officer after attempting to evade arrest again

From where do you find this uncontested "fact"?

And how do you explain the officer's conduct in washing his hands (you know, like how you would get rid of evidence) and bagging his own gun into evidence (you know, like no other suspect gets to do because they might tamper with it)?

And how would you like to approach the prosecution's handling of the grand jury?  Wherein the prosecution acted much more like a defense attorney for the accused (with harsh questioning of witness accounts and attempts to discredit prosecution witnesses) rather than following the standard practice of a prosecutor putting on the best evidence to support indictment?

Doesn't that sound an awful lot like bending procedure to help out a police officer accused of killing someone?  But...  Why would the prosecutor bend over backwards to help ensure the officer wasn't indicted if everything was as clean and tidy as you seem to believe?

That last bit isn't just me (I am a lawyer, but I don't work in a grand jury state).  To wit:

["The officer’s testimony, delivered without the cross-examination of a trial in the earliest phase of the three-month inquiry, was the only direct account of the fatal encounter."](https://www.nytimes.com/2014/11/26/us/ferguson-grand-jury-weighed-mass-of-evidence-much-of-it-conflicting.html?smid=pl-share)

Why didn't the prosecutor cross-examine the person accused of the crime?

(same source) "the sharp challenges prosecutors made to witnesses whose accounts seemed to contradict his narrative"

Why did they cross-examine other witnesses?  Are police officers just more reliable?

"the prosecutors did not press Officer Wilson and other law enforcement officials about some contradictions in their testimony."

That seem legit to you?

[Sunny Hostin, a former federal prosecutor, believes the state wanted to avoid presenting a clear-cut case that would have led to an indictment. "Prosecutors generally present very streamlined cases to the grand jury," she says. "**As a prosecutor you should not present witnesses in front of the grand jury that you wouldn't present at trial**."](http://www.cnn.com/2014/12/14/justice/ferguson-witnesses-credibility/)

I'd imagine she'd include "or refuse to cross-examine witnesses you would cross-examine at trial."

If you really think the facts are so clearly on the officer's side (and I assume are aware of all of these criticisms of the lack of any real pushback against his account), why do you think the prosecutor went so far out of his way to make sure the result went this way?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30440409039.0" user="chadonsunday" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;By "the facts" you're referring to facts which were established by multiple witnesses (or a witness and forensic evidence) and were not contradicted by anyone else?

Not at all. Most of the "facts" I presented (and I'm realizing now I probably should have gone with a more wordy but more accurate "what we can best tell happened based on the evidence" or something like that) are contradicted by someone at some point or another. Eyewitness testimony isn't exactly bulletproof. Witness 105, for instance, corroborated Wilson and forensics, but also said Wilson was driving a car, not a SUV, which he was in fact driving. So yes, of course some witnesses deviate from the statements of other witnesses, Wilson's account, forensic evidence, or the autopsy report (and even hard facts, like car vs SUV). 

But in general I'm leaning not just on Wilson's account but the compilation of other forms of evidence, most of which *do* seem to corroborate his account. 

&amp;gt;If it's the latter, I'd really encourage you to at least consider the possibility that a police officer under investigation by both his own department and the FBI might have an incentive to "remember" circumstances justifying the shooting.

Well of course. Maybe he was really just some racist Neo-Nazi scumbag who only joined the force to unjustifiably kill back people, and lied his ass off at every turn. But that doesn't seem to be the case. 

&amp;gt;From where do you find this uncontested "fact"?

The DOJ report would be one. And again, not "uncontested." But if you have, say, 10 witnesses, Wilson's account, forensic evidence, autopsy evidence, and DOJ findings that all pretty much agree on what happened and on the other side you have 2 witnesses who hate the cops and keep offering wildly different accounts of how Wilson is a cold-blooded murderer, I'm going to tend to agree with the former group. 

&amp;gt;And how do you explain the officer's conduct in washing his hands (you know, like how you would get rid of evidence) and bagging his own gun into evidence (you know, like no other suspect gets to do because they might tamper with it)?

I can't. I'm not Wilson. I don't know. IIRC he said it was because he was quite shaken up after the incident and wasn't thinking clearly. And I don't exactly find that too hard to believe. We all have our fields of expertise: you're a lawyer, I was a first responder for many years. Trauma and shock can really fuck with your head. Even hardened, well trained veterans make mistakes when shit hits the fan, and Wilson was a 28 year old kid and, AFAIK, this was the first time he ever killed anybody. Again, unless we're asserting he's a racist piece of shit who revels in killing black people, the dude was probably operating in an adrenaline-educed haze for several hours after the event, and probably fucked up over it for months or years. Maybe he washed his hands as part of some malicious coverup for a race-based murder. Maybe he was in a heavy state of shock, saw his hands, and thought "oh, blood, I should wash that off." I don't know. But what's that saying about not attributing to malice what can be blamed on incompetence? That concept has to apply even more when the person is in shock. 

As for the rest of your comment, I'm a bit out of my league as to why it's significant. Obviously as a lawyer you're probably seeing some glaring issues with this stuff that I'm not. Could you do an ELI5 summary on the latter bits? And I hope you don't begrudge a layperson from holding an opinion about this stuff. 

Cheers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30441388461.0" user="BolshevikMuppet" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Eyewitness testimony isn't exactly bulletproof. 

That cuts both ways.

You can’t say “we know from the evidence” when the evidence is witness testimony, and then claim that witness testimony is unreliable. The primary source of the officer’s version is what he said (and was never properly questioned about), which is also witness testimony.

&amp;gt;the compilation of other forms of evidence, most of which do seem to corroborate his account.

*Many* of which corroborate *parts* of his account.

To wit: the witness who said that he *did* see the victim moving slowly towards the shooter, but with his hands held at chest-height and away from his body in what the witness described as communicating “see, you got me, I’m hurt”.

It corroborates some of Wilson’s account, but contradicts big parts of it.

&amp;gt;Well of course. Maybe he was really just some racist Neo-Nazi scumbag who only joined the force to unjustifiably kill back people, and lied his ass off at every turn. But that doesn't seem to be the case.

It’s odd that you felt the need to jump from “his story might not be accurate and he has an incentive to have a story that justifies his actions” straight to “well it doesn’t seem like his entire career was a sham, so...”

If I can speculate just a bit, it seems like you’re uncomfortable directly addressing the possibility that the shooter (while not a snidely whiplash kind of villain) didn’t have a good reason for the shooting, and altered events to be able to keep his job, livelihood, and reputation. 

Instead your response here amounts to “oh, sure, it could be something completely ridiculous, but it doesn’t seem like this ridiculous scenario I made up, so that’s it.”

&amp;gt;But if you have, say, 10 witnesses, Wilson's account, forensic evidence, autopsy evidence, and DOJ findings that all pretty much agree on what happened and on the other side you have 2 witnesses who hate the cops and keep offering wildly different accounts of how Wilson is a cold-blooded murderer, I'm going to tend to agree with the former group.

And if that was how the evidence stacked up, you’d be justified.

But the DOJ didn’t find that the shooting was justified or that Wilson was telling the truth, only that it would be difficult to prove in court.

“Difficult to prove him guilty” and “actually didn’t do it” aren’t the same thing. And that’s even as someone who worked as a public defender for a spell.

More than two witnesses (including a number who were credible) corroborated the account that the victim had been shot while surrendering and/or while posing no immediate threat to the shooter. And of those witnesses who unambiguously supported the shooter, some indicated that they felt pressured to support him due to to his position as a police officer.

I don’t know from where you read that the DOJ investigation cleared Wilson. It didn’t.

&amp;gt;I can't. I'm not Wilson. I don't know. IIRC he said it was because he was quite shaken up after the incident and wasn't thinking clearly

So he might have tampered with evidence, but only accidentally?

I don’t mean to be glib, but I can only hope that if I shoot someone my “shaken up” reaction is to destroy evidence and circumvent chain of custody in such a way as makes it more difficult to find evidence about the shooting. That’s just damned good luck.

&amp;gt;Maybe he washed his hands as part of some malicious coverup for a race-based murder. Maybe he was in a heavy state of shock, saw his hands, and thought "oh, blood, I should wash that off." I don't know. But what's that saying about not attributing to malice what can be blamed on incompetence? 

You keep going back to “either it was a race-based murder or it’s fine”. Why would the only way for the cop’s actions to be suspect be if he began with the intent to shoot a black suspect? As opposed to that implicit biases influenced his decisionmaking subconsciously, and then the system which is skewed heavily towards police officers protected him?

&amp;gt;Could you do an ELI5 summary on the latter bits? And I hope you don't begrudge a layperson from holding an opinion about this stuff.

I can give it a go. And, no, I wouldn’t begrudge laypeople from having an opinion. Though I would caution a bit more restraint in how strident a lay opinion should be.

So, let’s talk grand juries!

Typicallt, a prosecutor in front of a grand jury presents their best possible case for indictment. There’s no right for the accused to give testimony, no right for the accused to have witnesses who support their defense, and no right to cross-examine prosecution witnesses.

So, in essence, the case presented to the grand jury is in almost every case: what if you took every prosecution witness at face value, heard do no other testimony, and saw only the evidence that supports the prosecution’s case?

One of the huge complaints about the grand jury system is that a thing meant to protect against unjust prosecution ends up being a rubber stamp for indictment.

Which makes it downright *odd* that in this case the prosecutor presented not only a whole lot of evidence against indictment, but impeached (it’s a term of art, basically “questioned the reliability of”) his own witnesses. 

In particular, he both allowed the accused (who has no right, remember, to give evidence at *all*) to give his side of the story, he didn’t question the accused at all. Which is weird, since that would imply to the jury that there’s nothing to question in the shooter’s own statement.

And, perhaps worse, he allowed the accused’s unquestioned account of the events to be the first thing the jury hears. This gets more into trial practice theory, but there’s a lot of research into concepts around how juries interpret facts. Once you give them a narrative, they will typically treat that as the frame through which they view all of the evidence. It’s very difficult to actually move a jury away from a settled script.

So if the first thing they hear is the version of events from the accused, and no part of it is questioned...</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
