<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="525177041.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8ood75/cmv_pride_parades_should_have_less_nsfw_content/">
    <title>CMV: Pride parades should have less NSFW content</title>
    <original_poster>punmaster29</original_poster>
    <original_post>To preface, I'm bisexual and I love pride month and pride parades. However, I think that the amount of inappropriate content impedes some of the intent behind pride. 

To me, pride is about celebrating the LGBT+ community and promoting acceptance and understanding. It's about not being ashamed of who we love and what we identify as, and being able to share that with the world. 

I think the parade would ideally be a great place to bring our families, to show parents and children how incredible and talented the community is. I'm not out to my family, but bringing them to Pride would be a great start towards warming them up to accept me. But generally given the amount of public nudity and sexual inappropriateness at Pride, this is pretty much out of the question. 

In order to be more inclusive and celebrate love with as many people as possible, I think pride parades should tone down the sexual undertones and focus more on the concepts of love, pride, celebration, and acceptance. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30483232796.0" user="ProtoMoleculeFart" delta="False">
    <text>But how else are people gonna taunt the homophobes and bigots?  It's gotta be so cathartic for people who've been hurt deeply by this.

On a more serious note, it probably feels even more safe and it's about being yourself to the max. It tends to drive the abusers away and/or draw them out in to the open, which is doubly nice.

Also, as a straight man - why do women always get to have all the fun?  It's ok for a woman to show all her bits at family events, even breast feed in front of everyone?  Yet as soon as a guy's junk isn't behind 2+ layers of suffocating material.. It's inappropriate?

I think you aren't looking at the big picture my friend.  Men need to stop treating women like special snowflakes, and start celebrating men who are sexually secure and healthy, regardless of their sexual orientation.  I believe strongly that we are doing not only the LGBT community a great disservice by thinking the way you are, but we are also hurting all males.

Let it all hang out.  Educate kids earlier on, stop letting fear rule our culture.  It is a sickness.  IMHO.

Edit: TL;DR letting insecurity rule is not a driver of prosperity or a strong society.  We should be celebrating all human forms and learning from them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483240535.0" user="punmaster29" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what exactly you're trying to say or how it pertains to my post. Men and women at Pride show public nudity, and I was referring to any type of nudity. I'm not going to comment on your breastfeeding remark because it's not relevant to the discussion. 

Why do you want homophobes/abusers as you call them to come out in the open? I'd personally prefer if homophobic people stayed away from pride. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30483308187.0" user="redheadredshirt" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; I'd personally prefer if homophobic people stayed away from pride.

That's... kind of the point. It's pride in one's self in the face of adversity. 

Every once in a while a thread comes up about 'being proud to be white' and the consensus is 'Why? What have white people fought through, what big challenge have they tackled?' Pride makes sense only in the face of those challenges. 

So being who you are and turning it up to 11, and then having people come and protest or bring on the adversity, is the very point of Pride. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
