<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="537285091.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/8vvvtv/cmv_not_all_gay_people_are_born_that_way/">
    <title>CMV: Not all gay people are born that way.</title>
    <original_poster>eltonjohnelway</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, I should make it known that I am not anti-LGBT and I believe that everyone should have equal rights and be treated fairly. I am straight but I do have a few gay and lesbian friends, coworkers, and family members. 

The common belief nowadays is that gay people are "born this way" and I can't find myself to completely believe this. I want to, as I want to be fully supportive of my gay friends. However, I am under the belief that who we are as people is almost completely defined by how we are raised and the experiences we have as children and through our entire life. IE- "we are the sum total of our experiences". I think that this expands to sexuality. I don't think there is anything wrong with this or that it is some sort of a mistake if you end up being gay. However, I do believe there is some alternate timeline/universe/ course of events ( whatever you want to call it) where certain people end up with different sexualities. In my opinion, my life could have been drastically different and I could have ended up being gay, but my cousin could have ended up straight. 

I am not trying to offend here, and I hope that it doesn't come off that way. I would truly like to have my view changed. Thank you!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30580321283.0" user="spacegecko" delta="False">
    <text>“Born this way” is usually used in contrast to “homosexuality is a choice.” 

I think that the idea of “born this way” is in essence the idea of “I didn’t actively choose who I am attracted to.” What you are saying is basically the same thing: that you are the product of things you don’t really have control over. I think you’re getting hung up on the semantics of “born this way” when what folks are generally communicating is “I’m not actively choosing to feel this way.”

Pretty hard to pinpoint the degree to which genetic predisposition vs external influence has on sexuality, and people aren’t really choosing either factor...thus the simplification of “born this way.”</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580398682.0" user="eltonjohnelway" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with and like your answer. And it does make me feel better about my opinion. I don't think (most) gay people are actively trying to feel that way. I'm not sure if a delta is deserved, as you didn't change my view, but explained and restated it. Thank you!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30580447500.0" user="spacegecko" delta="True">
    <text>Realistically, I have a hard time imagining anyone would be able to change this particular view...I just don't think that the idea you're wanting to hear from this CMV (Homosexuality is 100% always genetically determined?) is reflective of science. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
