<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="548728073.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/92p5ah/cmv_there_is_no_reasonable_or_practical_way_to/">
    <title>CMV: There is no reasonable or practical way to actually enforce an abortion ban</title>
    <original_poster>captainporcupine3</original_poster>
    <original_post>My apologies if I'm hopelessly naive about U.S. law. A better title for this post might be, "I can't think of any reasonable or practical way to enforce an abortion ban, please enlighten me."

I often hear people arguing the merits of an abortion ban without grappling with the real and practical challenges of actually enforcing the ban. It seems to me that there are some pretty glaring issues that would arise if we tried to actually enforce a ban. I'm starting from the premise that we all agree that it's permissible to terminate a pregnancy if necessary to save the life of the mother. So here are some potential issues I am wondering about:

1) How does the state determine that you had an abortion in the first place? It's my understanding that the government can legally subpoena your medical records by obtaining a search warrant if necessary for a criminal investigation. But on what grounds could the state receive such a warrant in the first place? How would the state know that you as an individual were ever pregnant in the first place, let alone suspect that the pregnancy was terminated? I'm not aware of any registry of individual pregnant women that could be checked over. 

2) If the state did have some suspicion that a specific pregnancy was terminated, on what grounds would it suspect that the termination was unlawful? Particularly if abortion is lawful when necessary to save the life of the mother. Not to mention the fact that pregnancies are terminated when the fetus has died in the womb. Assuming the state had some mechanism for determining what pregnancies were terminated, would it be given carte blanche to review to the medical records of any individual who fell into that category in order to determine if each individual case was legal? Is it reasonable or practical for the state to launch an investigation into the private medical history of every woman whose pregnancy is lawfully terminated to root out the individuals whose pregnancies were terminated unlawfully? 

3) Assuming you granted the state those rights and were willing to support the bureaucracy necessary to enact them, what next? When reviewing individual medical histories, what criteria does the state use to determine that an individual termination was unlawful? Surely there are plenty of borderline decisions where the mother's life is at substantial and even imminent risk but she still has the right to continue the pregnancy if she chooses? What metric does the state use to determine that a specific pregnancy was risky enough that termination is deemed legal or illegal in that instance? Isn't it true that in many cases different doctors would reasonably disagree on the risk to the mother's life?

4) Once the state determines that a particular termination is deemed unlawful, how do you prosecute? Does the state pursue murder charges in a jury trial? Are the individual's private medical records made available to a jury so that they can make the ultimate ruling on whether the termination was indeed unlawful? And based on what -- the reasonable person metric? Can non experts make a reasonable determination on the merits of a medical diagnosis like the need to terminate a pregnancy?

Again, my apologies if some of these questions are naive. From my humble position these seem like reasonable questions, but if I am wrong that they are serious or noteworthy issues then please change my view.

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30668623772.0" user="GnosticGnome" delta="True">
    <text>Pro life people want to stop abortion, not to punish women who have them.  So the most effective way to do this is with sting operations against Ob-gyns who perform the abortions.  Have a pregnant woman without a legal reason for an abortion try to convince doctors to perform one on her.  If they agree to schedule one, arrest them. 

Not calling it right, but you could make it a lot harder to get a surgical abortion that way.  Likewise selling abortifacients on the dark web or word of mouth, you could make much harder for people who aren't the most tech savvy or socially connected.  Obviously you couldn't get the number to zero but you could drop it a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30669891479.0" user="JNiggins" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Pro life people want to stop abortion, not to punish women who have them

The President briefly talked about punishing women for abortion &amp;amp; when everyone rightly freaked out, he recanted. But I think his remarks showed his inner thought process. [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](https://www.nytimes.com/2016/03/31/us/politics/donald-trump-abortion.html). 

In addition, Republican representatives have often called for the punishment of women, in addition to their doctors, for abortion. 

An ID rep. called for their execution, but then similarly walked it back. [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](https://www.washingtontimes.com/news/2018/apr/3/bob-nonini-idaho-gop-candidate-suggests-punishment/)

Another ID rep. tried to introduce legislation that would charge women for 1st degree murder just last year [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](http://www.ncsl.org/research/health/fetal-homicide-state-laws.aspx).

A number of OH representatives have introduced a bill that, while currently under revision, would currently criminally punish women &amp;amp; doctors with the same crime [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](https://www.legislature.ohio.gov/legislation/legislation-summary?id=GA132-HB-565).

I would posit that the politicians who say that they would not punish a women for an abortion, but only punish their doctor, are playing a politically expedient game. It is the reason they "accidentally" tell the truth &amp;amp; then have to walk it back. The party's actions as a whole in other avenues of this question seem to show that they would change their hand if the political wind blew differently, or if they had more power. 

Indeed, since Planned Parenthood v. Casey sets the state's right to ban abortion at "viability of the fetus," and due to advancements in medical science, viability is therefore a moving target that is always waxing backward (from 24 weeks at the start of the millennia to around 20 weeks now). Because of this women are being prosecuted as we speak [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](https://www.nbcnews.com/news/asian-america/indiana-has-now-charged-two-asian-american-women-feticide-n332761) &amp;amp; that is likely to continue &amp;amp; increase. 

Furthermore, pro-life individuals often frame the argument as one of a binary choice between if a fetus is a "human life" or not (ignoring the spectrum of viability in Planned Parenthood v. Casey). This is almost always to focus the argument in such a way to quantify "abortion as murder." The logical conclusion to that construction of thought is that murderers should be punished. This is a shocking, but logically consistent framework for those self-identifying as "pro-life" &amp;amp; is likely the reason why their representatives do what they do &amp;amp; will likely punish women &amp;amp; feel justified in doing so. 

Finally, before 1973 laws banning abortion almost always had provisions for the punishment of the women for their abortions. [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Abortion_in_the_United_States#History). Women were not "protected" by anti-abortion laws, they were pursued by the state for violating these laws. If the supreme court were to invalidate their own previous abortion rulings, chiefly Roe v. Wade &amp;amp; Planned Parenthood v. Casey, the status quo ante would prevail &amp;amp; abortion would be illegal, in admittedly various forms, in 38 of 50 states immediately [&amp;lt;Source&amp;gt;](http://www.ncsl.org/research/health/fetal-homicide-state-laws.aspx).

I could actually go on, but to say that those who self-identify as pro-life don't want to punish women is to admit that you simply don't fully understand the history of the topic in which you speak. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
