<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="564888063.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cbif3/cmv_the_current_national_us_gun_control_laws_are/">
    <title>CMV: The current national US gun control laws are all that’s needed right now.</title>
    <original_poster>ElderAcorn</original_poster>
    <original_post>While I won’t go into all National US gun laws, I will point out the ones that I think need pointing out because they pretty much sum up the gun control debate.

According to http://lawcenter.giffords.org/gun-laws/policy-areas/who-can-have-a-gun/categories-of-prohibited-people/#federal

“The federal Gun Control Act of 1968, codified at 18 U.S.C. § 922, generally prohibits the sale of firearms to any person who:

Has been convicted of, or is under indictment for, a crime punishable by imprisonment for more than one year;

Is a fugitive from justice;

Is an unlawful user of or addicted to a controlled substance;

Is underage;

Has been adjudicated as a mental defective or committed to a mental institution;

Is unlawfully in the United States or has been admitted to the U.S. under a nonimmigrant visa;

Has been dishonorably discharged from the military;

Has renounced his or her U.S. citizenship;

Is subject to a court order restraining him or her from harassing, stalking or threatening an intimate partner, his or her child or a child of a partner, or engaging in other conduct that would place an intimate partner in reasonable fear of bodily injury to the partner or child; 
or
Has been convicted of a misdemeanor offense of domestic violence.”

I think that these address the people that no one wants getting a gun to the best of anyone’s capabilities to find out about someone. If you want to know what crimes have a mandatory minimum of 1 year or more here’s a list that I think you’ll find reassuring https://famm.org/wp-content/uploads/Chart-All-Fed-MMs.pdf

As for background checks, the only people required by law to do a background check are private sellers ( http://lawcenter.giffords.org/gun-laws/policy-areas/background-checks/universal-background-checks/#federal ) 

“Federal law imposes various duties on federally licensed firearms dealers. Firearms dealers must, among other things:

Perform background checks on prospective firearm purchasers.

Maintain records of all gun sales.

Make those records available to law enforcement for inspection.

Report certain multiple sales.

Report the theft or loss of a firearm from the licensee’s inventory.

Federal law imposes none of these requirements on unlicensed sellers, however.”

As stated in the quote, unlicensed sellers do not have to do any of these things by law, but they actually do have to if they don’t want to go to jail. The people not allowed to be sold gun from the top cannot be sold guns by anyone licensed or not. That means that a licensed dealer would be forced find out about the person while an unlicensed would do it because if they did give a gun to someone who fits one of those conditions, they’d get the same punishment as if the licensed dealer were to do the same. They are both equally punished if they sell to a person fitting the list, licensed dealers are only forced to check by law. 

All in all, this adds up to mean that people that we don’t want to have guns will either not have guns, or we have no laws being proposed that could any further not give guns to those people without restricting regular citizens from getting guns

Edit: This statement sums up my deltas “To clarify my new clause: The current national gun laws along with the requirement to properly store guns and background checks required for all buyers regardless of seller are all we need.”</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30793174141.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>Actually, according to ATF, only liscensed sellers have to perform background checks.

&amp;gt; Federal Firearm Liscenses are critical in public safety because... they help keep direarms out of hands of prohibited persons by running comprehensive background checks.

This same report also makes it clear that an unliscensed dealer (anyone "not engaged in the business of dealing firearms", ie a person selling at a flea market, gun show, online, etc. for a limited period only) do not *have* to oerform background checks. They are entirely optional, and between inexperience with the business and the fee that is reuired for a check, many do not partake in back fround checks.

Sources:

https://www.atf.gov/file/100871/download

https://www.csgv.org/issues-archive/gun-show-loophole-faq/

https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2017/jan/02/guns-state-background-checks-study</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793187020.0" user="ElderAcorn" delta="False">
    <text>I mentioned how only licensed dealers legally have to perform background checks, but my point is that the unlicensed ones get punished the same if they sold to the bad people. I’ve got a history of explaining things poorly so I’ll use an example: A bad guy who went to jail for 2 years goes to a gun shop and tries to get a gun. They do a background check and find out that he is not legally allowed to be sold a gun. He leaves and goes to an unlicensed seller. The seller gives him the gun, and the man walks off with a new gun. He is later found by the police to be in possession of said gun, and the police track it back to the unlicensed seller. He is arrested for selling a gun to someone who went to jail for a year or more. This is why it isn’t illegal for unlicensed dealers to not do background checks, but it is in their best interest to do so because they will be punished if they sell to someone who would fail a background check.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793207254.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>Your argument is that no change at all is nexessary for US gun laws, but wouldnt it be better to be preventative and not let unliscensed gun dealers sell without a background check in the first place? Which scenario is better: someone who shouldnt have a gun never gets a gun, OR they do, shoot their ex-wife (or whoever) with it, and their seller gets punished. One scenario has a dead body, the other doesnt.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793222926.0" user="ElderAcorn" delta="False">
    <text>But the fact that the seller gets punished is what would prevent that from happening. None of them would take the risk unless they were uninformed on the law, but if they were uninformed on the law then they wouldn’t be informed enough to know to do a background check assuming that a law was passed forcing them to do so. No seller is going to think, “I will either possibly go to jail and not to a background check or avoid all legal consequences and do a background check. Let’s go with the first one,” because prison is a very dangerous place that has been reinforced as the closest thing you can get to hell culturally. The only people willing to take that chance are criminals who wouldn’t be affected by background check laws</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793238720.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have a source that that many unliscensed gun sellers always go for background checks?

Because I have sources that prove requiring universal background checks from all dealers show lower rates of gun violence (https://cdn.americanprogress.org/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/BackgroundChecks-factsheet3.pdf)

&amp;gt; States that require background checks for all handgun sales have lower levels of gun violence compared with states that do no require background checks</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793290538.0" user="ElderAcorn" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t mean to be cliche here, but correlation does not equal causation. The states that don’t have the laws could be bigger gun use states than those that do. As for the Missouri statistic said in your source, nothing says anything about illegal gun sales just that more murders and fire-arm homicides were committed. There is an infinite amount of reasons for those homicides to be committed and the fact that they had separate uses of murder and fire-arm homicides for the same argument is a bit suspicious for lack of a better word</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793306784.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="False">
    <text>I didnt mention the Missouri statistic directly.

Yes, correlation does not always equal causation. But numerous similar studies have found a heavy relation between universal background checks and gun violence. Heck, even first implementing background checks in general lowered gun rates throughout the country.

Plus, you cant really believe that having more background checks wouldnt result in less people who shouldn't have guns getting them. Of course it isnt perfect 100%, so dont argue that. Because no law is ever 100% at stopping crime. But it can certainly lower it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793337497.0" user="ElderAcorn" delta="False">
    <text>I decided to go through your entire source and found the Missouri statistic. Should I not look thoroughly? You mention numerous studies that show a direct relation, but you didn’t cite any of them. If I see a direct relation between forcing background checks for private sellers and having  significantly less illegal gun ownership (I’d say  minus 500 or more is a reasonable number to call significant) then I’ll give the delta, but all I see now is murder rates fluctuating. If they were done with illegal guns, it should’ve been mentioned. And yes background checks initially lowered gun crime rates because they had no incentive to do them before, but now they do both for licensed sellers through the background check laws and private sellers through the prohibited buyers list.

Also, I’ll never make the argument that laws don’t stop criminals. That’s a stupid argument. It’s so annoying to hear people say that argument because it’s just advocating for no laws because people’ll break them anyway</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30793387853.0" user="begonetoxicpeople" delta="True">
    <text>https://everytownresearch.org/background-checks-loophole/

https://www.rand.org/research/gun-policy/analysis/background-checks.html

https://www.americanprogress.org/issues/guns-crime/reports/2018/03/15/447964/require-background-checks-gun-sales/

http://www.center4research.org/does-gun-control-really-work/
(First part only really deals with the argument about background checks)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
