<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="565121219.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9cgibn/cmv_it_is_a_jerk_move_to_play_music_while_camping/">
    <title>CMV: it is a jerk move to play music while camping within earshot of other campers.</title>
    <original_poster>estheredna</original_poster>
    <original_post>We put a tent up in a state park campground for about 4 weeks out of the summer. Most of the time you can just hear nature, people talking, kids playing, lots of birds and squirrels  . Every 5th day or so, there is someone who brings some Bluetooth speakers so they can listen to music , but loud  enough  that people in a half dozen sites nearby get to ‘enjoy’ whatever they are playing. 

Right now I’m cooking dinner and the guys next to me are playing U2, Dave Matthew Band and similar inoffensive crap.

This would be entirely normal in a backyard gathering, but once you reserve to be in a public campground, it becomes selfish, intrusive,  rude.

Am I wrong?

(I know it’s a known risk of car camping. I’m not really  mad. More rolling my eyes. I wish they’d shut that crap off.  )

</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30795194655.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="False">
    <text>So, you are in a *public* campground surrounded by a whole host of people who likely have paid to be there, and give tax dollars as well to fund this place for all.  People will have differing views of how to enjoy this space, yours is to sit and listen to nature, some will be to meet with friends in an outdoor setting and socialize (often including music), some will be to bring their children and let them explore nature.  

That is the thing with public parks and campgrounds, their usage is not defined.  Beyond this, why the heck are you sitting at the campgrounds to experience nature?  If you want to experience nature the campgrounds are almost never the place to do it (which is why music is normally socially acceptable outside of quite hours), get on the trails, beaches, lakes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795206621.0" user="estheredna" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough . They are not breaking any rules. But: It is night time. I did spend the past 12 hours hiking and swimming in a pond and enjoying nature. Now I am camping. There are about 35 sites here. 34 of us are chilling out. Most of the week all the sites were pretty quiet . Tonight , ONE has made the choice to play music. But since were all outside and pretty close to each other we all have to listen to their lousy tunes. Again, it’s allowed. I just think it’s a jerk thing to do. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30795323668.0" user="Doodoointhepeepants" delta="True">
    <text>I think your issue is expectations, I’m also a bit surprised by this being something you aren’t used to, as I’ve been spending 4-8 weekends a year in a public campground for the last 30 years from Ohio to Washington (mostly WI, MN, MI, SD, ND) and  Friday/Saturday night, especially on Labor Day/Memorial Day there is almost always music, and groups who aren’t there to do much else than drink outside with a fire.  I literally got back a few hours ago from camping in a state park here and there were multiple sites that were playing music until around 10, with fires and talking/laughing until even later.

Basically comparing a Tuesday to a Saturday is like comparing what a bar restaurant is like on a Tuesday night vs a Saturday.  Again, this is public land, not yours, the rules are determined by the public, not just the enthusiasts.

Consider people like this being there a good thing, and them enjoying the park being a good thing, basically if parks aren’t accessible to all, they will cease to exist (since they exist purely due to the will of the public).  That may mean you have to deal with other people’s sound waves impeding into your space, however sound waves have never been seen as an impediment on the “your freedoms ends where mine begins” dichotomy.  Basically, don’t allow yourself to be so affected by others, and don’t have expectations of others to adjust their behavior, while within rules, on public land.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
