<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889283247.0" user="Midnight_Lightning" delta="False">
    <text>Why can't both good intentions and good actions be required in order to get into The Good Place? It's not like the two contradict each other, it's possible to have good intentions and to act morally.

Also, I think Chidi's main problem isn't the fact that he did harm, but more the fact that he was cowardly, he often didn't do the right thing even when he knew what it was, due of fear. Like the time when he lied to his coworker about liking his new boots.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889322721.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>Intent and actions could both be a prerequisite to getting in to the good place, however that would mean that the system would be somewhat unfair and the show asserts that only bad people should be deserving of an eternity of punishment in the bad place. If someone did not intend to do harm, or simply failed at being good, then such a system would penalise those that did not try to be good *and* succeed at doing so.  
If I remember correctly, the medium place was real (and not just a fabrication for the sake of causing and elaborate problem like most other stuff in the bad place), but it was very rarely used and so those that tried to do good but didn't succeed wouldn't end up there despite being more of a morally grey person. 

I don't really remember any other instances of cowardice other than the boots incident, which was still a case of him trying to spare the other person embarrassment by telling a lie to make them feel better, but it spiraled so he was caught in a dilemma where he tried to do what he thought was right and be kind. Eventually he did tell the truth, but that incident shows how he tried to do good but it didn't work for reasons beyond his control. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889332779.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; however that would mean that the system would be somewhat unfair and the show asserts that only bad people should be deserving of an eternity of punishment in the bad place.

This is more of a meta-problem with the show, TBH. It is very difficult to mesh "these people were so bad they deserve an eternity of punishment" with "these people are sympathetic protagonists we could initially conclude deserved to be in The Good Place."</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
