<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="577631717.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9jwnhh/cmv_in_the_show_the_good_place_the_presence_of/">
    <title>CMV: In the show "The Good Place", the presence of both Tahani and Chidi contradict the rules presented of who ends up there</title>
    <original_poster>SirApatosaurus</original_poster>
    <original_post>#Spoilers for The Good Place season 1. 

----

In The Good Place, Chidi is shown to have deserved to end up in the "Good" place because whilst he tried to live a good life and do what he thought was right, he was indecisive to the point where it caused harm to his friends and family.  

Tahani lived a life of charity and tried all that she could to help others, however it is revealed that this was overruled by the fact that she did so for selfish reasons. 

Chidi's judgement was based on the notion that how he affected those around him mattered more than his intentions. He never meant to hurt anyone and tried to do what he thought was right, but simply failed to do so in practice. 

Tahani's judgement was based in the notion that her intentions mattered more than what she did. 

The two of them are in direct contrast to each other. One did immense good but for the wrong reasons, and one did harm but unintentionally whilst trying to do what he thought was right.   
If Chidi belongs in the "Good" place then the impact of one's actions matter more than a person's intentions. If Tahani belongs in the "Good" place then the intentions of a person matter more than what they do. 

So CMV, Tahani and Chidi do not both belong in the "Good" place, only one of them does by the rules proposed in the show. 

Edit - people have already made points on the following topics and I will not award deltas for them: 

* The high bar proposed in the brief presentation on how the system works, requiring people to be close to perfect
* We don't know if we can trust anything in the presentation as it could have been a lie by Michael


_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="30889352507.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="False">
    <text>One important thing to remember is that you are basing your belief on how the universe evaluates a person to be good or bad on what Michael told us in Episode 1 - the points system.  We can't take that to be true, however, as it is entirely possible that that system definition was part of the ruse he was selling the humans.  We have only met one truly neutral party (the Judge) thus far (I'm not counting the Doorman) and she didn't give us specifics about how people are evaluated in any real detail.  Everything we know from Michael is suspect.

Your CMV is based on the idea that the universe is a purely utilitarian model, where it is only the outcomes of choices that matter.  However, as many moral philosophers have pointed out, utilitarianism has pretty glaring flaws that make it a poor moral system in a vacuum:

- If we discount the intentions of actions, it is possible that someone who is trying to do good may end up doing bad by no fault of their own.  If you give someone a peanut butter cookie to make them happy, and they end up dying of severe anaphylaxis (despite the fact that neither of you knew of their allergy) you have done a net "bad" and would be morally deserving of punishment for that net bad action.  That hardly seems fair, though, as that net bad was not your _intention_ to do bad.  No one would really blame you for what happened, despite the fact that it still happened.

- It allows for weird edge cases.  One of the critiques of utilitarianism is that it allows for the creation of "utility monsters" - beings that derive so much pleasure or benefit from a specific action that it would justify causing suffering to every other being on the planet.  When one only concerns oneself with "net good" then you can justify any number of horrible things based on how you define "net good".  

It seems that the universe is far more Kantian in practice.  Kant's morality puts all of the focus on the intention of the action and disregards the actual effects.  So long as you intended to do good, then you get the moral points for your intention even if the action results in bad outcomes.  In my cookie example, you would get none of the blame for the person's death, because you did not intend to cause it.

Now, Kantian philosophy has issues as well, which is why universe seems to be a balance between the two - you must intend to do good, and actually do good, for it to count.

In that system, it is clear why both Chidi and Tahani are in the Bad Place.  Tahani is obvious - she did good for purely selfish reasons so, per Kant, she gets no points.  She broke one of the Moral Imperatives - she used people only as a means to her own ends (impressing her parents, showing up her sister) which means that her actions were not moral.  Perhaps they were still "good" but "good" and "moral" are not always the same thing.

Chidi is a bit more difficult to explain, but his motivations were also corrupt.  While he was striving to do the most net good, he disregarded the impact on the people close to him in the process.  His quest to do go resulted in suffering to those who interacted with him and we never see Chidi really caring about that.  He knowingly causes suffering to others and - here is the real kicker - never actually ends up doing any real good at all due to his indecisiveness.  He was the closest to being moral (Michael says as much) but he still doesn't meet our standards in a blended moral system.

Of course, the point of the show seems to be that even this blended system has flaws, so it seems to be pushing the narrative that most people _don't_ deserve to be in the bad place at all.  However, using the system that is in place - however flawed it may be - Tahani and Chidi both make sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889434651.0" user="SirApatosaurus" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;One important thing to remember is that you are basing your belief on how the universe evaluates a person to be good or bad on what Michael told us in Episode 1 - the points system. We can't take that to be true, however, as it is entirely possible that that system definition was part of the ruse he was selling the humans

Very true, and as I awarded a delta to another comment that introduced reasonable doubt on whether it isn't a contradiction. 

&amp;gt;Your CMV is based on the idea that the universe is a purely utilitarian model, where it is only the outcomes of choices that matter.

I didn't mean to make the point that Chidi didn't belong in the bad place, just that one of the two didn't belong if it's a consistent system that values either actions or motivations. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="30889440033.0" user="Ansuz07" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I didn't mean to make the point that Chidi didn't belong in the bad place, just that one of the two didn't belong if it's a consistent system that values either actions or motivations.

If it is a blended system - where both intention and outcomes matter - then it makes sense why both of them were ruled "bad".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
