<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001741813.0" user="Feathring" delta="False">
    <text>Gender dysphoria *is* a recognized mental illness. The medically recognized treatment is transitioning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001756791.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>While I understand what you're saying, this is still a fairly new issue. The previous solutions to mental illness was shock therapy, which I think we all know wasn't exactly proper.

Several sources (which I'll list under this) state that transitioning is -not- effective and does not result in fixing the issue. Many times it leads to regret. If that's the case, how is that a proper treatment? 

Additionally, let's look at the solutions for depression. We can let the person live miserable, we can medicate them, or we can kill them to assist. Which of these do we do, and which is most successful?

http://www.sexchangeregret.com
https://world.wng.org/content/sex_change_regret_silenced
https://www.thepublicdiscourse.com/2016/06/17166/
https://gendertrender.wordpress.com/tag/sex-change-regret/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001768157.0" user="Bladefall" delta="True">
    <text>These are biased, non-scientific sources. Here is a link to a comment with many better sources that say transition drastically improves trans people's lives and health: https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/9beuwu/cmv_i_believe_people_with_gender_dysmorphia/e52jg1t/</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
