<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592218573.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9slarx/cmv_transgender_individuals_have_a_mental_illness/">
    <title>CMV: Transgender individuals have a mental illness. We should be treating and providing help to these people.</title>
    <original_poster>0991906006091990</original_poster>
    <original_post>There have been multiple times in history where people exhibited views, opinions, and beliefs which were later deemed to be mental illnesses. Things such as schizophrenia, gangstalking, multiple personality disorders, etc. are all instances where the precieved individual felt that they were in a situation which was not reality (Voices speaking to them, people out to get them). 

Additionally, disorders and issues are caused by a chemical imbalance. Schizophrenia and depression are both caused this way. We deem these people to have a mental illness, and we treat these people. We don't entertain the notion that they are correct, since that tends to cause more issues than it resolves.

Why do we treat people who believe their a different gender differently. Logically we should be treating them for a chemical imbalance and providing them with mental help - not encouraging and furthering their potentially self destructive way.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31001746429.0" user="Bladefall" delta="False">
    <text>We decide how to treat people based on what's effective at alleviating the symptoms. For example, a person with depression will probably be prescribed an SSRI medication, because that's what works most often in other patients with depression. If that doesn't work, then they're switched to something else. 


In the case of trans people, what's effective is transition. Do you have something else that's effective at alleviating the symptoms of gender dysphoria? If so,  what is it? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001760438.0" user="0991906006091990" delta="False">
    <text>Please see my response above. Studies have shown and transitioning individuals have demonstrated that transitioning does not resolve this and it results in regret. While I'm not a chemist, biologist or a pharmacist, surely there would be some form of medication to "correct" this imbalance and set them "back on track", no? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31001772889.0" user="PennyLisa" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; urely there would be some form of medication to "correct" this imbalance and set them "back on track", no?

No. There isn't. Many things have been tried: Antidepressant medications, antipsychotics, high dose hormones, hormone suppression, ECT, none of it has much of an effect. What actually works is gender affirmative treatment which includes hormone therapy.

The "studies" you quote are just opinions. There's a fairly extensive body of scientific literature on this that largely agrees with gender affirming care.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
