<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="592456991.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9sqeqn/cmv_some_cultural_traditions_dont_deserve_respect/">
    <title>CMV: Some cultural traditions don't deserve respect and outsiders should actively make an attempt to change them.</title>
    <original_poster>armdrag2youback</original_poster>
    <original_post>[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=DKAusMNTNnk)

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I came across this video today, in which brides in a certain culture are kidnapped of the streets and are physically held and forced into marriage by their family (sometimes even just their distant extended family). In many cultures there are many flaws but almost all modern societies don't condone the forced kidnap and eventual rape of women. This culture will continue to cause real tangible and direct harm to individuals unless it is somehow changed from external pressure. This tradition doesn't deserve to be respected and deserves active attempts to destroy it by well meaning outsiders. I am trying to see if there is any argument behind the common view of "we must respect all cultures". I don't see how or why a culture that deprives people of fundamental human rights deserves respect, and how it is not the duty of outsiders to try to stop them. Change my view </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31003403058.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>By what method do you intend to change that practice?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31003409945.0" user="armdrag2youback" delta="False">
    <text>social advocacy, education, funding of women's empowerment groups etc. Not talking about violence </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31003419496.0" user="Grunt08" delta="False">
    <text>Have you considered the incidental costs of interfering in another country's domestic politics and culture?  How do you account for those risks?

And what if nothing can be changed without violence?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31003464854.0" user="armdrag2youback" delta="False">
    <text>If nothing can be changed without violence then at least an effort was made. I am talking about advocacy groups NGOs not governments in who I believe should be doing this work. And I don't see the consequences of interference if done by NGOs in a not violent education oriented approach perhaps you could expand on the incidental costs so I could better understand</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31003495709.0" user="Grunt08" delta="True">
    <text>Well, imagine how some Americans might react if Saudi Arabia decided to lobby the United States not just for favorable foreign policy, but internal cultural change.  Imagine they were advocating subjugation of women and curtailment of their rights through social advocacy and education.

Do you think there might be negative consequences?  That maybe Americans incensed by that kind of cultural interference would be less inclined to favorable foreign policies towards Saudi Arabia?

You seem to think doing this through NGOs shields from these consequences, but would you draw a huge distinction if the education I mentioned was technically administered by a Saudi-funded NGO?

And it intervention doesn't work, why continue? Why not use those resources on something that actually provides a benefit?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
