<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="593993382.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9tnc86/cmv_schools_should_place_as_much_emphasis_on/">
    <title>CMV: Schools should place as much emphasis on developing children's mental health as they do on academic learning.</title>
    <original_poster>Starrcade87</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think the goal of the education system should be to help children grow into healthy adults. 

Academic learning is good, but I would argue that it's actually less important than learning how to take care of yourself and your mental health.  For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

How should this be achieved?  I don't know exactly, but a few ideas:

\- Keep licensed therapists on staff at every school, and give every child at least 1 hour per week of dedicated therapy time, and more for students who are troubled.

\- Allow students to take at least 1 hour of outdoor sports and recreation per day.  Getting exercise and sunshine is vital for us to feel happy as humans.

\- Teach students valuable life skills that they will need as adults.  Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed.  This may seem a bit off topic at first glance, but financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult.

In other words, school shouldn't just about math, reading, and science.  Spend time and effort developing kids as people and not only will they be healthier, they'll learn better too.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31015231283.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; For instance, most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends, but being mentally healthy is something that will serve us all our lives.

Even if people don't spend a lot of time explicitly writing down algebraic equations, "solving for x" is a regular occurrence in my life and the life of most (all?) functioning adults. You realize scaling a recipe is algebra. And so is figuring out the per-unit price of something (e.g. to figure out if it's better to buy the 3, 6, 9, or 12 pack of toilet paper). Calculating (or understanding) interest and rates. Currency conversion. Metric conversion. Figuring out a discount. Figuring if there's enough gas in your car. Buying the correct amount of paint for the walls (and that requires geometry, too!) or of materials for any project. Figuring out how drunk you are as a function of liquor and time. Figuring out when you and a friend need to leave to meet for dinner. Working through how much withholding you should ask for on a W2. Anything involving proportions and ratios. Any calculation remotely touching on affordability. Of the things you listed as "more important," managing finances, actually calculating anything about your nutrition, cooking anything other than exactly what the recipe specifies, and even family planning all absolutely require algebra, even if you don't think of it that way. Understanding the value of an unknown variable is a extremely prevalent and if you wanted to pick a "useless" subject, you failed rather spectacularly. People that I encounter needed to spend more time getting a *better* grasp of algebra, statistics, numerical literacy in general, not less time getting worse. 

The basic tools schools are meant to teach *are valuable life skills.* Literacy (and higher level reading comprehension) are valuable life skills. Algebra and numeracy are valuable life skills. Research and writing are valuable life skills. Speaking new languages and understanding people and their current and historical circumstances are valuable life skills. Scientific reasoning is a valuable life skill. Hell even memorizing a pile of information is a valuable life skill! People who denigrate things like algebra are people who utterly failed to grasp what algebra is and who shouldn't be allowed to talk shit about it. 

And this doesn't even touch on the logistical and ethical problems of actually finding and staffing this many therapists and expecting parents to consent to a stranger they didn't choose advising their child (who is likely perfectly mentally healthy--and you do know therapists don't teach "Things like managing finances, nutrition, cooking, and sex ed. ... financial stability, fitness, and family planning play a huge role in your quality of life as an adult," right?) about their feelings without their input and consent. We need the hours we spend in school to teach kids the skills to actually figure these things out for themselves. Including algebra. 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015295362.0" user="Starrcade87" delta="False">
    <text>Nowhere did I state that algebra is not a good skill to have, or has no real world applications.  You are punching a straw man.

It was just an example -- maybe not the best one -- and I'm not being critical of learning academic fundamentals.  But it's not controversial to say that most people won't benefit from quite a bit of what they were asked to learn in school.  Unless you use something in your career or trade, you won't retain it and it won't benefit you in any material way.

As far as parents go, they don't really get to consent to the teachers who educate their kids so I don't know why therapists should be much different.  There is inevitably going to be conflict here but that doesn't make it a bad idea.

And yes, I am aware that therapists don't teach those topics, but the mental health ramifications shouldn't be ignored.  Adults are not "figuring these things out for themselves" as evidenced by the prevalence of poor lifestyle choices in our country.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31015352209.0" user="mysundayscheming" delta="True">
    <text>No one would ever recommend that an adult who can't cook *see a therpaist*. That's not remotely what they're for. And you made the claim that

&amp;gt; most people will never touch algebra again after their formal education ends

so I hardly think my defense of it is "punching strawmen." Your claim is blatantly false. People touch algebra on a weekly if not daily basis. If you weren't being willfully misleading, it's ignorant or indicating a fundamental misunderstanding of what algebra is. Any and all of which suggest we need to spend more time teaching algebra, not less so we can send our children to therapists who absolutely don't teach cooking, family planning, or financial planning anyway. The mental health ramifications of not being able to take care of yourself can't be staved off in advance, but children don't really suffer from not being able to cook and financially plan until they're responsible for it. So not in elementary school, but in college maybe? After college? The best thing we can do is when they're children is not give them some kind of advance therapy but actually teach them how to do those things, which 1) doesn't happen in therapy at all, and 2) has academic fundamentals underlying it which you think "most people don't touch"

And I would treat my children's teacher and my children's therapists very differently. Someone responsible for teaching my kid algebra forms a very different relationship with them than someone resolving my child's mental illness, potentially diagnosing them, expecting them to be deeply emotionally vulnerable, etc. Find the most ardent supporter of widespread therapy and even they'll be adamant that the therapeutic relationship depends a lot on the personality/methods of the therapist in a way that teaching algebra does not. A bad therapist, or even one that doesn't jive with you, can actively aggravate your mental health problems. A child and their parent need much more control over who provides them professional counseling than who teaches them to read. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
