<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="597970490.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/cmv_bernie_is_almost_as_militarily_hawkish_as/">
    <title>Cmv: Bernie is almost as militarily hawkish as Hillary Clinton.</title>
    <original_poster>eminemski</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to start this off by saying that I was a huge Bernie supporter till about a week ago when I saw his voting history. I believe that, though he voted against the Iraq war, he voted to invade Afghanistan, and he voted for a bill that funds war in the middle East. He also admits to funding four different annual war spending bills over the past 15-20 years. He gave lots of rhetoric which I appreciate about ending the wars in 2016, and aiding war torn countries. Please change my view because I was so hyped for Bernie in 2020, but now I don't see how I can vote for someone who voted for bills that might kill more people than they save. 

Thanks!!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31047087342.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>he is more hawkish then id like. mostly he supports the military because he sees it as a jobs program, rather than supporting the american project of global hegemony. 

but I think the major flaw in your argument is that you underestimate how hawkish hillary clinton is. She is an extreme supporter of american world domination and is a war monger on the lindsey graham/john mccain level. she seems to literally support any possible war. she makes kissenger look like a dove.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047153004.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think she's Ted Cruz and Lindsey Graham level anymore is she? She seems just like an average hawk. And Bernie had no reason to vote to invade Afghanistan and vote for some military spending bills in the 2000s</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047160303.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>name a single military adventure she didnt support? anywhere, ever? she is an uber-hawk.

i agree that he had no reason to vote to invade afghanistan, but he doesnt support it now: [http://feelthebern.org/bernie-sanders-on-afghanistan/](http://feelthebern.org/bernie-sanders-on-afghanistan/)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047190624.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with that, but actions speak louder than words can. He can say as much as he wants, but it won't save the lives of people (including likely many civilians) who died from that invasion. Also, I don't think he apologized for supporting those 4 war spending bills. Also, how do we know he won't support more as president?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047199036.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>we know that hillary clinton is a war monger at the extreme level. she is basically dick cheney. even the NYTimes agrees: https://www.nytimes.com/2016/04/24/magazine/how-hillary-clinton-became-a-hawk.html

so it's hard for you to say that Bernie is as bad as she is. she is in a league of her own.

that said, I dont think bernie is good on war, he's still too much of a hawk for me. but your post was that he is as bad as she is. it's just not true. he basically apologizes in that post from his website. she still wants to suck the blood of the few children that arent yet dead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047205903.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I said he is almost as hawkish, and not as hawkish. Also, how would we know that Bernie wouldn't back more war spending bills as president? I think he backed one in 2008. And I'm not sure that he apologized for Afghanistan in that post .</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047217070.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>he has voted against a lot of military funding, even if he sometimes votes for it. i'll repeat, he considers the military a jobs program so he supports government supported jobs programs. i disagree with this, but it's his view. he basically says there's no other way for a poor person in the usa to get a job then the military, so he thinks it is better than nothing.

but he isnt for every war, and he is often against wars. he was against the iraq war, and that's how we know he isnt for every way. hillary is for every war. they are pretty different, even if bernie is too much of a war supporter, hillary clinton is a true war monger.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047324389.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Supporting militants is not a job though. It incentivizes American usage of said militants. Also, what wars was she for besides Afghanistan and Iraq? What war did she like that Bernie opposed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047329566.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>she overthrew the government in libya, she was the main reason the USA got involved in syria, she supports american involvement in yemen, she has been advocating for the usa attacking iran, she supports the zionists every time they kill palestinians, she supported all the attacks the zionists have done against lebanon, and on and on...</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047522736.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>This will sound annoying (I'm sorry) but can you please provide proof of your claims about Yemen, Iran and zionists etc</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31049631771.0" user="posnfen" delta="False">
    <text>Libya: https://foreignpolicy.com/2016/04/14/hillary-clinton-has-no-regrets-about-libya/

Syria: https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/global-opinions/will-hillary-clinton-deliver-on-her-promise-to-ramp-up-us-involvement-in-syria/2016/10/23/1f2788e4-97bd-11e6-bc79-af1cd3d2984b_story.html

Yemen: https://www.codepink.org/saudi_s_exploding_christmas_gifts

Lebanon: https://www.nytimes.com/2006/07/18/nyregion/18hillary.html

and i could literally keep going on endlessly. she loves war. she is much different than bernie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053227884.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Okay you're right. She is more pro war by a long shot. But why would Bernie want to invade Afghanistan if there was no reason to. Especially if civilians died.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31054494110.0" user="posnfen" delta="True">
    <text>so i changed your view? are you going to give me a delta?

and bernie explains why he voted for the afghanistan war in the post on his website. he thought the option of war was one possible choice, he didnt think they'd do only war.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
