<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="597970490.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/cmv_bernie_is_almost_as_militarily_hawkish_as/">
    <title>Cmv: Bernie is almost as militarily hawkish as Hillary Clinton.</title>
    <original_poster>eminemski</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to start this off by saying that I was a huge Bernie supporter till about a week ago when I saw his voting history. I believe that, though he voted against the Iraq war, he voted to invade Afghanistan, and he voted for a bill that funds war in the middle East. He also admits to funding four different annual war spending bills over the past 15-20 years. He gave lots of rhetoric which I appreciate about ending the wars in 2016, and aiding war torn countries. Please change my view because I was so hyped for Bernie in 2020, but now I don't see how I can vote for someone who voted for bills that might kill more people than they save. 

Thanks!!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31047110001.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>So just went through his voting history. Regarding Afganistan I assume you are talking about June 26, 2008. Iraq and Afganistan war funding, Unemployment Benefits, Extension and GI Bill?

If you read that bill. It is a standard timetable stuff regarding military in mainly Iraq, and partly in Afganistan. A ton of funds went to the funding of security, economical independece and security training in those countries.

By voting no. The GI bill (money to soldiers, veterans, and their families), and the Unembployment benefits would be killed. Well they wouldn't, this bill passed 92-6. All of nay's were republicans. I mean if you are angry they got the 3 bills together to get democrats on board with the other Bills, then I agree. Politics is sleazy.

If this is the worst thing you got on Bernie, then it's really, really cute. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047167206.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I was referring to Bush's AUMF which Bernie voted yes on after 9/11</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047247790.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Bush's AUMF

Literally every single Senator voted yes on that except two Republicans who were not present. Do you have other specific bills that Sanders supported that you think are particularly hawkish? This one hardly counts considering it had wide bipartisan support.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047338793.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>It counts no matter who else supports it. Why would it not count just because it is bipartisan?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047358023.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>You're making a comparison in your OP, saying he is "almost as hawkish as" someone else. Well, Clinton voted yes, Sanders voted yes, and so did everyone else who voted. It had complete Senate support and apparently wasn't controversial at the time, so I'm not sure how it supports your point, unless you are saying everyone who was in the Senate at the time is equally a war hawk. That's manifestly untrue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047524658.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Well that is kinda what I'm saying. What did Sanders vote against on militarily that Hillary supported? Which wars did they disagree on.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047557557.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>When Bernie Sanders was a Congressman and Hillary Clinton was a Senator in 2002, he voted nay and she voted yea on [H J Res 114 - Use of Military Force Against Iraq.](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iraq_Resolution) Sanders has been consistently against the Iraq War, while Clinton obviously supported it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31049393549.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Didn't Clinton apologize though? In 2014?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31049558417.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>The fact remains that Sanders was always against the war and Clinton was not. That fact directly counters the claim in your OP. I cited the specific H.R. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053201906.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Right. But why did he want to invade Afghanistan??</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053226827.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>It was widely believed that Osama Bin Laden was there. The United States wanted to dismantle Al-Qaeda and the Taliban. Your OP says Sanders was almost as were like as Clinton. Sanders never supported the Iraq War, a war started on false pretenses. Clinton did support it, even though it did not enjoy wide bipartisan support as the Afghanistan Invasion did. Therefore, Sanders is not as warlike is Clinton. There are further examples from when Clinton was Secretary of State that would support a claim that she is war-like. Would you like me to provide those examples, or have I sufficiently proven that Clinton is more of a war hawk?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053292960.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>You have proven it. But I'm still curious why a belief that a terrorist lives in against warrants an invasion of the country. Civilians dying in Afghanistan makes this invasion not worth it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053308050.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="True">
    <text>Also, if I've proven than Sanders was not even close to as war hawkish as Clinton, have I changed your view?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053326749.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Absolutely !delta but also, why is it that invading against was worth civilian deaths whereas Iraq wasn't?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053340346.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>We invaded Iraq because Colin Powell, at the behest of Bush/Cheney, told us that Saddam Hussein had weapons of mass destruction. It was a lie. Many of us knew it was a lie, including Sanders. But not all Democrats agreed, so we toppled their government, executed Hussein (who we had previously supported, even armed, when he was fighting our other enemy, Iran), and threw that country into chaos. The Bush administration absolutely committed war crimes there. Sanders was right not to support it. Clinton was wrong. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053368572.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I understand, but under that same logic, you have to agree that Sanders should not have voted to go into Afghanistan</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053374256.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>The premise of the Afghanistan war was not a complete lie. al-Qaeda was located there. The Taliban was a repressive regime. There was good reason to think Osama Bin Laden was based there. Iraq was a complete lie and therefore not an equivalent situation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053405149.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I understand, but can you agree that invading Afghanistan was not worth it because civilians died in that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053481494.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="False">
    <text>By that rationale, there should never be a war, ever. While I agree that is an admirable goal and one that I fully support, we are in the minority. Our global culture is that of nation-states who complete for resources, and when you have a military, you're going to use it. Was Afghanistan a just war? That seems to be your question, and I agree that's a good one. [Here is a decent analysis of the question.](https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1122274/) I agree with their assessment:

&amp;gt; This brief application of modern just war theory to the Afghan conflict suggests that its value as an analytic moral or legal framework is limited. The difficulty in obtaining reliable information makes some assessments impossible. Political biases introduce further complexities. There is, however, one component of the just war theory—the means of war—where international standards and measures do exist and a provisional assessment can be made. This suggests that the United States has missed several opportunities to establish a reassuring normative tone and presiding presence in this conflict. Instead of rooting its engagement in international humanitarian law it has emphasised the dastardly outlaw nature of its enemy to justify a need to keep its tactical options open. With the whole world watching, persistence in this mode may prove to be shortsighted.

I think, at the start of the war, it was framed as a just war, but it devolved into, I believe the technical term is "a shitshow." The example of the Soviet failure there could have been instructive. However, the pressure was high for the US government to do something in response to 9/11. I cannot defend the war in Afghanistan, really. I would be going against my own principles by doing so. That's one of the million reasons why I'm not a Senator. There's no credible way I can tell you Sanders has voted 100% correctly on all issues related to war. Anyone who says they can is not being honest. Being less war-like than Clinton is a low bar, though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053549197.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I see what you're saying. You would say that Bernie believed at the time that invading Afghanistan would save more lives than it would kill but invading iraq would not.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053556152.0" user="PhasmaUrbomach" delta="True">
    <text>That was probably the rationale at the time, along with the massive political pressure to ACT after 9/11 in some way. I don't think that war was properly executed, though. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
