<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="597970490.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/9w0kze/cmv_bernie_is_almost_as_militarily_hawkish_as/">
    <title>Cmv: Bernie is almost as militarily hawkish as Hillary Clinton.</title>
    <original_poster>eminemski</original_poster>
    <original_post>I want to start this off by saying that I was a huge Bernie supporter till about a week ago when I saw his voting history. I believe that, though he voted against the Iraq war, he voted to invade Afghanistan, and he voted for a bill that funds war in the middle East. He also admits to funding four different annual war spending bills over the past 15-20 years. He gave lots of rhetoric which I appreciate about ending the wars in 2016, and aiding war torn countries. Please change my view because I was so hyped for Bernie in 2020, but now I don't see how I can vote for someone who voted for bills that might kill more people than they save. 

Thanks!!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31047110001.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>So just went through his voting history. Regarding Afganistan I assume you are talking about June 26, 2008. Iraq and Afganistan war funding, Unemployment Benefits, Extension and GI Bill?

If you read that bill. It is a standard timetable stuff regarding military in mainly Iraq, and partly in Afganistan. A ton of funds went to the funding of security, economical independece and security training in those countries.

By voting no. The GI bill (money to soldiers, veterans, and their families), and the Unembployment benefits would be killed. Well they wouldn't, this bill passed 92-6. All of nay's were republicans. I mean if you are angry they got the 3 bills together to get democrats on board with the other Bills, then I agree. Politics is sleazy.

If this is the worst thing you got on Bernie, then it's really, really cute. 



</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047167206.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>I was referring to Bush's AUMF which Bernie voted yes on after 9/11</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31047823562.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, it made you sound like you were talking about bills when US was at war, supporting the war with Iraq and/or Afganistan. AKA knowingly support US wars.

But you are talking about the bill. That later turned out to be the catalyst for the justification to invade Afganistan. A non controversial bill with the support of 99.8% (420-1), that authorized US military to be used in cases where country is harboring terrorists's relating to 9.11

Are you more focused on the intent of voting? Or about the consequences of the bills that are voted on?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053223093.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Both are important. However, the Congress should have enough forbearance and insight to realize that any invasion will go wrong. Bipartisanship doesn't mean moral.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053281042.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Both are important. However, the Congress should have enough forbearance and insight to realize that any invasion will go wrong. Bipartisanship doesn't mean moral.

It wasn't an invasion order. The bill authorized the use of limited military force in countries where 9.11 terrorist's are harbored. This will later turned into a catalyst for an invasion, but it isn't one.

Let me draw you a hypothetical. Imagine there is a bill that allows the use of SMG's in SWAT units on combatants that meet certain criteria. Let's say that later that year, there are couple of innocent bystanders killed because of the richote caused by this type of weapon in urban environment, including a mother and a child.

Is it fair that this bill is labelled a child killer bill. Label all politicians who supported it as pro-child-murder. 

Is it fair to require all politicians to be intimately familiar with ballistic theory in urban environment, just in case the makers of the bill didn't made their homework, or had an alterior motive?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053298888.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, since the residence of a terrorist in Afghanistan does not warrant the invasion of the country. Especially since civilians die. It is not worth allowing civilians to die.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053385290.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>Then there is nothing anyone can say to convince you. If you assume omnipresent knowledge to be the base requirement for politicians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053410645.0" user="eminemski" delta="False">
    <text>Well I think it is reasonable to expect politicians to estimate the total civilian deaths that would result in foreign invasions. Besides I've already given a delta. If you can convince me that we were right to invade Afghanistan knowing civilians would die then I can delta you, or if you can convince me that Bernie is much less hawkish, I can delta you. That latter is what I've done.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31053769665.0" user="Gladix" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Well I think it is reasonable to expect politicians to estimate the total civilian deaths that would result in foreign invasions.

Okay, so I'm starting to see where the missunderstanding is. The bill doesn't grant the right to wage war. It grants limited power for military to pursue terrorist's related to 9.11. The AUMF was used in Philippines, Georgiea, Yemen, Djibouti, Kenya, Ethiopia, Eritrea, Iraw, Somalia.

Most of the countries US didn't invade.

US used the AUMF bill to set up resources in Afganistan to communicate with Al-Qaeda, so they would give up bin Laden who was connected with 9.11. And to cease supprting terrorist's against US.

Al-qaeda refused, and the war begun.

The bill was not declaration or war, or authorization for war, do you understand that?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
