<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="632832865.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/agrsyp/cmv_now_that_we_have_evolved_past_the_need_to_eat/">
    <title>CMV: Now that we have evolved past the need to eat meat, it is completely immoral to do so.</title>
    <original_poster>Inquisitive2k</original_poster>
    <original_post>Not a vegan or even a vegetarian, but I still hold this belief. I understand that we have evolved as carnivores, and that eating meat has always been essential to human survival. It holds nutrients you cant find anywhere else like B12, its heavily saturated which makes it an efficient food, and ot tastes damn good (which i would guess has something to do with evolution aswel).

These arguments are still valid in underdeveloped or poor countries, and under extreme conditions. However, in modern day western society's I can't seem to find one ethical argument for eating meat (not to mention the toll it takes on the environment). 

Is everyone just lazy like me, or is there more to it?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31335792602.0" user="grizwald87" delta="False">
    <text>I think most anti-meat arguments are premised on the assumption that we're morally obliged to avoid hurting animals if we can avoid it. I've never understood why humans aren't allowed to participate in the circle of life just like every other animal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335813225.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>Humans are the only animal (as far as i know) with the ability to know right from wrong. This alone i would say counters your argument of circle of life. We are not like other animals. Breeding animals for killing in small enclosures just for our pleasure seems to me like something above and beyond the circle of life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335857507.0" user="grizwald87" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Humans are the only animal (as far as i know) with the ability to know right from wrong. 

What does this mean? Are you suggesting that right and wrong is something inherent to nature, and not something we've invented for our own social purposes? If so, if right and wrong are *provable* propositions, why are we having an argument about what constitutes right and wrong after all these years? Where's your evidence of right and wrong?

&amp;gt;Breeding animals for killing in small enclosures just for our pleasure 

You're moving the goalposts subtly. Forget about factory farming for a moment, and let's imagine the *most* defensible form of meat-eating: going out in the autumn, shooting a moose, and then feeding on it all winter. Yum, moose burgers. What's wrong with that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335935449.0" user="Inquisitive2k" delta="False">
    <text>I am suggesting that right and wrong is something inherent to humans. Like Kant. Of course my views are formed based on social frameworks, but that doesn't make them any less "natural". Our social frameworks are a product of nature.

I did move the goalpost to the most common for of meat consumption. I definitely see that there is a huge difference between factory farming and hunting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31335973035.0" user="grizwald87" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;I am suggesting that right and wrong is something inherent to humans. Like Kant. Of course my views are formed based on social frameworks, but that doesn't make them any less "natural". Our social frameworks are a product of nature.

Kant didn't believe animals had moral rights, so clearly his system is flawed if you're seeking to rely on it for this purpose. Morality is either objective, in which case you should be able to point to evidence that it exists outside of what people believe, or it's subjective, in which case you have to justify why your position is better for society than mine - why does a deer deserve to live if I'm feeling hungry?

&amp;gt;I definitely see that there is a huge difference between factory farming and hunting. 

So do you consider hunting for your meat moral or immoral? If the least abhorrent version of animal-killing for food is morally acceptable, then you have to edit your thesis.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
