<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="634030621.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ahhh5p/cmv_my_unconventional_dietary_habits_of_only/">
    <title>CMV: My unconventional dietary habits of only eating snacks are completely healthy</title>
    <original_poster>chubby_leenock_hugs</original_poster>
    <original_post>I do not actually ever make proper structured meals; rather I eat a lot of raw vegetables in the form of ball peppers, tomatos, oranges, cucumbers, pineapples and grapes throughout the day as well as a lot of instant noodles whenever I feel like it and as far as meat is concerned I might eat some frankfurthers, dry sausage, raw salted herring or make a hamburger and put it in a bun of bread. Essentially I eat "snacks" throughout the entire day.

I should also note that I do this whilst working; I do not take the time to sit down and properly dine and do not own a dining table. You often hear people say you should take the time to eat and sit down but I don't know how true that is.

I believe that in doing so I consume a balanced, varied, diet without the effort of cooking or creating meals; I do not see why concentrating food into three meals per day with breakfast and lunch being bread-based and dinner being warm would make it healthier since the inside of the stomach mashes it up together anyway before nutrients are extracted.**</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31345997037.0" user="finzipasca" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; I do not see why concentrating food into three meals per day with breakfast and lunch being bread-based and dinner being warm would make it healthier since the inside of the stomach mashes it up together anyway before nutrients are extracted. 

Part of it is that you're eating a distinct portion on a regular schedule, so your body becomes more accustomed to a standard amount of food. Cooking a meal from a recipe yields a precise amount of food, while snacking is perpetual until you choose to stop or until you run out, increasing the odds that you overeat. This is also true of eating while distracted by work, television, or some other activity - those who focus on their meals eat less. [Research supports this.](https://www.health.harvard.edu/blog/distracted-eating-may-add-to-weight-gain-201303296037)

Now, looking at what you do eat;

&amp;gt;frankfurthers, dry sausage, raw salted herring or make a hamburger

Herring aside, eating exclusively red meat for your protein is not good for your heart. [Burgers and hot dogs are some of the worst offenders.](https://www.webmd.com/g00/food-recipes/features/the-truth-about-red-meat?i10c.ua=1&amp;amp;i10c.encReferrer=aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuZ29vZ2xlLmNvbS8%3d&amp;amp;i10c.dv=20) Herring is better, but eating it salted is just a direct injection of sodium. Fish and poultry can be prepared in low-sodium, high-protein ways. 

&amp;gt;all peppers, tomatos, oranges, cucumbers, pineapples and grapes 

Bell peppers and cucumbers are good vegetables, but they're so high in water content that you've got to eat a lot for nutritional value. Oranges, pineapples, and grapes aren't unhealthy *per se*, but they're high in sugar, and if they're a large portion of your diet this can be a problem. You're missing leafy greens and root vegetables, where the healthy fiber and vitamins really lie. 

Ultimately, you're right that it all turns to shit when we eat it - but you'd stand to benefit by diversifying your food intake, and establishing some regularity. That regularity does not have to be 3 cooked meals a day, but it *does* have to (1) maintain food diversity (2) meet daily caloric and nutritional needs, and (3) maintain portion control. Snacking as you please, or "grazing" as I like to call it, is a poor method to meet these 3 goals. 

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31346016856.0" user="chubby_leenock_hugs" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Part of it is that you're eating a distinct portion on a regular schedule, so your body becomes more accustomed to a standard amount of food. Cooking a meal from a recipe yields a precise amount of food, while snacking is perpetual until you choose to stop or until you run out, increasing the odds that you overeat. This is also true of eating while distracted by work, television, or some other activity - those who focus on their meals eat less. Research supports this.

That's a fair point I hadn't considered I guess though it certainly doesn't apply in my case as I'm a fairly skinny 55-60kg at 181m but I hadn't considered it !Delta

&amp;gt; Herring aside, eating exclusively red meat for your protein is not good for your heart. Burgers and hot dogs are some of the worst offenders. Herring is better, but eating it salted is just a direct injection of sodium. Fish and poultry can be prepared in low-sodium, high-protein ways.

That's fair but my hamburgers are mostly chicken-based.

&amp;gt; You're missing leafy greens and root vegetables, where the healthy fiber and vitamins really lie.

Do carrots count because I do eat a lot of those?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31346037445.0" user="finzipasca" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; That's a fair point I hadn't considered I guess though it certainly doesn't apply in my case as I'm a fairly skinny 55-60kg at 181m but I hadn't considered it !Delta

Cheers mate. My question would be how old you are. Assuming you're a young man, your metabolism can handle much more right now than it will be able to as you age. These habits won't serve you well in the longer run, even if they don't seem to have an impact now. 

&amp;gt;That's fair but my hamburgers are mostly chicken-based.

Gotcha - hamburgers are conventionally ground beef. Chicken / Turkey burgers are much healthier. 

&amp;gt;Do carrots count because I do eat a lot of those?

I mean, carrots are good for you too, but eating more spinach/kale and potatoes (depending on how you prepare them) will go a long way. 
</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
