<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644178994.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anizoy/cmv_the_government_doesnt_have_any_special_rights/">
    <title>CMV: The government doesn't have any special rights to products that make use of publicly-funded research.</title>
    <original_poster>kuriousgoomba</original_poster>
    <original_post>I typically consider myself fairly fiscally liberal, but I saw two reddit posts in recent days I don't really agree with that garnered a lot of support from other redditors. 

1) [If Software Is Funded from a Public Source, Its Code Should Be Open Source](https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/an43i7/if_software_is_funded_from_a_public_source_its/)

(Note- I don't disagree with the main point of the article, I am all for open standards. I disagree with the idea that a university researcher can't patent software and spin it off as a private company because they are publicly funded).

2) [Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez Calls Out Sexism As Her Big Pharma Knowledge Is Labeled 'Inadequate'](https://www.reddit.com/r/AlexandriaOcasio/comments/anebj0/alexandria_ocasiocortez_calls_out_sexism_as_her/)

(Note- I don't disagree with AOC's claim that her treatment by the media and the op-ed in question is sexist, because it is. Rather, I disagree with her claim during the hearing that government funding justifies public ownership of the final product.)

Both these articles seem to be getting at an idea that because the government initially funds certain ventures, they have a right to mandate public access to the product at either reduced cost (pharma) or for free (open-source code).

I think that I fundamentally disagree with some of the redditors commenting on these posts when I think about the purpose of government research funding. In general, I think the government's role is to fund basic research projects and produce novel ideas that private industry can then use to benefit people in a wide variety of ways. This includes pharmaceuticals, advances in alternative energy, novel algorithms, etc. etc.

In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. Taxpayers don't fund research because they expect a direct financial payout. They finance research because they expect a preponderance of high-quality and creative research programs to lead to welfare-improving products in the end (such as new medicines). There may be other reasons to mandate reduced prices, such as the elasticity of demand when it comes to medicine. But to say that companies are obligated to lower prices because it was initially public-domain research doesn't seem correct to me. 

There are other viable economic systems where the government can, for example, produce energy at cost. But because we live in a capitalist system we ought to use the power of the free market to soak up the innovative ideas that public universities and research programs produce and put them to work developing products people will purchase because they see value in them. 

Is this the correct way to view public-private research relationships? Please, change my view! 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31431843208.0" user="MasterGrok" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;In other words, if government researchers publish open-access research papers about a promising pharmaceutical candidate that a big pharma company eventually develops into a patentable drug, that doesn't seem like a situation where the government can mandate the pharma company sell the drug at production-cost simply because they published the initial research. To me, this seems like a situation where the system is working well. 

But it's actually not working well. I don't have issue with a private company taking publicly funded science and developing it into a product for profit. That's great. However, I also think the government has a perfectly reasonable role in mandating that those products aren't sold at highway robbery rates. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432027965.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>I am certainly with you- Martin Shkreli is no hero of mine!

I am thinking of a scenario more along these lines:

Suppose we have two drugs, A and B. A was initially researched in a public university and was eventually taken up by a pharma company, developed, and patented. B was purely conceived of, developed, and patented at a pharma company. My claim is not that the government has no right to regulate prices for either medicine- rather, I believe that the government has an equal right to regulate prices for *both* drugs. The government should have no special claim to regulating drug A because it utilized publicly-funded research to get started. 

The reason I think this distinction is important is because it informs how we make our public policy. If we think that we can modulate drug prices because of initial public investment then we will discourage the use of public research by private corporations because they will factor this final consideration in when they choose what drug candidates to go after. 

Perhaps this is a contrived scenario or does not adequately challenge your line of reasoning? I am interested to hear your thoughts. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432095225.0" user="dale_glass" delta="False">
    <text>That's a weird way of thinking of it.

To me it's much simpler -- if the public paid for it, the public should own it. Because that's how it works for pretty much anything else. If I pay you to say, build a house, the house is mine. If I pay you to research which building material is best according to some set of parameters, the results of the research are mine.

So if the public paid for a drug to be developed, the drug should belong to the public. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31432718643.0" user="kuriousgoomba" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with this logic in general, but I think there's a twist.

The government has a specific incentive to foster inventions and new products that are successful in the economy. In that sense, you might interpret government research as a sort of 'gift' to the economy, knowing that it will be payed back in increased tax revenue, better welfare for people that use the products, and overall a healthier economy which means people live better lives. Do you think this might be a reasonable way to think of government research? After all, the research is not expressly made to benefit a specific person or company, as is done in your example of researching building materials for a house. Rather, it is made so that anyone can use it to produce things that improve our lives.

What do you think?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433632275.0" user="dale_glass" delta="True">
    <text>I think government funded research should be in the public domain. No entity should own it, rather it should be available to anybody to benefit from. That's because the public paid for it, so the public owns it.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
