<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="644387032.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/anng7s/cmv_respect_for_elders_and_authority_figures/">
    <title>CMV: Respect for elders and authority figures shouldn’t be expected, but rather earned like the rest of the population.</title>
    <original_poster>dyxing</original_poster>
    <original_post>First time poster here :)

The idea that one should always maintain respect for those older than them, or more powerful, doesn’t seem to stand currently. And this can be perceived as largely constructive, as there is no longer blind respect for authority figures, and people are better able to speak out against oppression and injustice, even if having to stand against those older/more powerful. Additionally, this generation seems to be more critical of ideas, values and traditions held by this group of people, and this is essential in ensuring that younger or more vulnerable people aren’t taken advantage of simply because the other party is older or holds more influence.

In this case, respect should be earned, but of course, one would always be expected to remain courteous and acknowledge the fact that age is often correlated with wisdom. However, by the same token, it should be acknowledged that this is not always the case, and so it shouldn’t be expected that their perspectives are final, or correct.

However, the issue with this is that, it seems as though this general lack of respect has been emulated by mostly insolent children/teens, who act in defiance without any rational ideological backing, despite their own conviction. And this seems to be perceived as problematic in and of itself, with parenting a much more onerous task, and with the consequent diminished value of rules, laws and the like. 

So where do we find the balance? </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31433515553.0" user="MisanthropicIceCube" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/amljyk/cmv_elders_dont_deserve_respect_just_for_being_old/

Here's an answer that was awarded a delta:

&amp;gt; [the reason that we do things like designate certain seats or parking spots for the elderly, disabled, pregnant, is that because one important marker of a society is how well it treats the infirm and vulnerable. same with entitlement programs like medicare and social security. it's not saying they're inherently more important. it's saying that our society is so safe and well administered that we can afford to take care of people that can't care for themselves. also the reason that people freak out more when small children get shot in school shootings](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/amljyk/comment/efmuc2r) 

Would you say your CMV would be answered by this one? 
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433526840.0" user="dyxing" delta="False">
    <text>thanks for that! 

But yes I understand why our elders are treated with courtesy/respect, and wouldn’t say that they aren’t worthy of it, especially if they are amongst the vulnerable of society.

I’m referring more to simply those who hold power over those who are younger, or who have less autonomy, and would like to know if there is an alternate viewpoint regarding the respect that we hold for these figures, and the judgement that they pass down. 

So no I would say this CMV is based on a different premise.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433555277.0" user="MisanthropicIceCube" delta="False">
    <text>I also view blind respect as nonsensical, so I won't change your view on that. I have however, found something I disagree with. 

&amp;gt; And this can be perceived as largely constructive, as there is no longer blind respect for authority figures, and people are better able to speak out against oppression and injustice, even if having to stand against those older/more powerful.

I'm not so sure if this is true. Respect isn't what stops us from speaking out, it's fear.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433572613.0" user="dyxing" delta="False">
    <text>Yes you’re right, this inability to speak out would primarily stem from a fear of consequences, so i will award a delta! for that (no idea if i did that correctly).

However I have found that in a lot of circumstances, especially where oppressive judgement is handed down by someone older, it is often expected that we still deal with them respectfully, and anything other than this would be viewed as an act of defiance. 

Is this something we’re supposed to accept do you think? To still treat such people with respect? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31433603658.0" user="MisanthropicIceCube" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; especially where oppressive judgement is handed down by someone older, it is often expected that we still deal with them respectfully, and anything other than this would be viewed as an act of defiance.

Dealing with someone respectfully and respecting them aren't the same thing. You should be amicable, because that's when conversations are fruitful. You're able to ask questions and clarify possible confusions. Losing your temper does not help the situation in any way. That's why we treat people respectfully. 

This applies to authoritative figures as well. If you don't treat those beneath you with respect, you're committing the same offense, namely believing your authority somehow exempts you from basic human decency. Also, you lose out on the bonuses of amicable discussions. 

People that view questioning an authoritative figure as defiance are wrong to do so. There might be a time and place to do so, but nobody is beyond reproach.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
