<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449747381.0" user="Gladix" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was way too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as this where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

How far can we go tho? The cycle of injustices and hate is eternal. I'm not a huge history buff, can we say for certainty, that no wrong has been done onto the relevant parties, which would justify their behavior(objectively, not just subjectively)?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31450290205.0" user="SC2_BUSINESSMAN" delta="False">
    <text>Well they didnt cripple them that badly the second time around. They knew the consequences</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31454057115.0" user="Gladix" delta="True">
    <text>So let's recap. The first world war started as a response to British empire spreading across the globe. After the WW1, nations fucked over Germany. Que WW2.

But what was before. Why were British so imperialistic. Well they were in brutal conflict over the church with Spain. (inquisitions), and was nearly destroyed, if not for the doctrine of strong navy. That naturally evolved into expansion and then trade.

Okay, so why did the Inquisitions happened. Why did the parts of Catholic church rebelled and split?

Because Catholic church was affraid of loosing power, in spite of the blossoming spanish trade (from which nobilities prospered). Most nobles, and powerful people just happened to be Jewish. Que the hunt for the wicked.

We can go further and further, it's just a cycle of hostility, trickery, and responses to previous wrongs. Why do you make the arbitrary dividing line at the Treaty of Versailes?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
