<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="646554790.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/aoxwva/cmv_the_allies_started_ww2/">
    <title>CMV: The Allies started WW2</title>
    <original_poster>SC2_BUSINESSMAN</original_poster>
    <original_post>First of all, the Treaty of Versailles was *way* too harsh, and everyone knew it. The hyperinflation that followed as a result of this Treaty was a huge factor that caused the German economy to collapse. In addition, events such as [this](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occupation_of_the_Ruhr) where France occupied Germany and killed civilians is basically what enabled Hitler to rise to power and garner enough support.

The [Polish Corridor](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polish_Corridor) was also a joke. Lots of ethnic germans were separated from East Germany, and there was no other option than for Germany to start invading or suffer from severe consequences such as economic collapse, overpopulation, and continuing to be bullied by the Allies. 

The only way out of this situation was to create infrastructure geared towards war, which would enable a lot of jobs to be created and for Germany to annex areas such as the Sedetenland and Rhineland which were important strategic areas, as well as reuniting scattered Germans. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31449811833.0" user="efisk666" delta="False">
    <text>You are pointing towards the factors that led to the rise of Hitler. I think the allies recognized these facts, and that’s partly why Chamberlain gave up so much to Hitler. Chamberlain was righting a historical wrong and trying to preserve peace when he unwound Versailles, but in doing so he empowered a monster.

Hitler could have taken what Chamberlain gave him and avoided war by investing in infrastructure, instead he chose to see if he could get away with annexing Poland like he did the Czech republic and Austria. That was the decision that started WW2.

So I think it is more accurate to say that Versailles led to the rise of Hitler, but Hitler alone started the war. Even Mussolini was opposed to ww2 but his hand was forced by Hitler.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31450298322.0" user="SC2_BUSINESSMAN" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Even Mussolini was opposed to ww2 but his hand was forced by Hitler.

Interested about this. Can you explain a bit or tell me why this is?

Will give a delta when i figure it out</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31450976642.0" user="efisk666" delta="False">
    <text>rise and fall of the third reich is the source. as shirer told it, mussolini knew his military was weak at the start of the war. he tried to convince hitler to wait a few years for war so he could have time to strengthen his military, but hitler was in the opposite position- he saw he had a military advantage and wanted to take advantage of it. great book- best view of what went on inside the axis leadership.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31451010495.0" user="SC2_BUSINESSMAN" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks. Didnt the Phoney War basically give Mussolini the time he wanted anyway?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31452491200.0" user="efisk666" delta="True">
    <text>he wanted several years. i forget how many, i think maybe it was 5.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
