<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668369613.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b1xhal/cmv_the_question_of_do_we_live_in_a_simulation/">
    <title>CMV: The question of "do we live in a simulation" doesn't matter</title>
    <original_poster>mix_420</original_poster>
    <original_post>I say this for two reasons:

1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.
2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

Basically what I'm saying here is there's no point in asking this question if you will never have the answer to it, considering the only reason to ask the question is for the knowledge of it, as you'll never achieve it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31604970092.0" user="zomskii" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1. You can't prove it. Can't really think of anything you can't explain with common sense that proves that we live in a simulation.

Doesn't this depend on the quality of the simulation? What if you are the only sentient mind in this simulation, and you can find inconsistencies or errors? 

&amp;gt;2. There's no point in it. I don't see how life changes in any way if you were to know you were in a simulation. I understand that knowledge is a great thing and we should try to get knowledge even if it doesn't matter, but because of #1 it makes it pointless.

This depends on the simulation too. Perhaps things that you think are random are actually planned. Perhaps  people you care about aren't real. Perhaps the simulation will abruptly change or even end. This would be very useful information for making decisions. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31605037693.0" user="mix_420" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Doesn't this depend on the quality of the simulation? What if you are the only sentient mind in this simulation, and you can find inconsistencies or errors? 

The point is I don't see anything in this world that isn't explained away with common sense. I see everything as very consistent and organized.

&amp;gt; This depends on the simulation too. Perhaps things that you think are random are actually planned. Perhaps people you care about aren't real. Perhaps the simulation will abruptly change or even end. This would be very useful information for making decisions. 

Does this directly change anything about one's life though? And more importantly, the first point still stands in that it doesn't matter if the information isn't accessible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31605067343.0" user="zomskii" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;The point is I don't see anything in this world that isn't explained away with common sense. I see everything as very consistent and organized.

If the world were a simulation, it could 
(a) be perfectly indistinguishable from reality, or 
(b) have flaws which allow you to identify it as a simulation.

By saying that you currently haven't found any flaws is not sufficient proof to exclude option (b). On what grounds can you make that claim?

&amp;gt;Does this directly change anything about one's life though?

Yes. I'd talk to my wife very differently if I discovered that she was an element of a simulation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
