<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607129723.0" user="Firmaran" delta="False">
    <text>I would argue that stopping the clock adds additional organizational complexity. Someone has to do the timekeeping. While this may not be a problem for the big leagues, it certainly will be for small local games. Either the task is added to the duties of the referee, who already had a lot of work during those situations, or one of the parents will have to take up the task. Unfortunately only a few people help during local games.

Additionally soccer is very popular in poorer countries because it has simple rules and requires next to no equipment. Adding timekeeping would make playing official games more difficult for them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607264073.0" user="Willaguy" delta="False">
    <text>Isn’t finding out how and keeping track of how much additional time should be added to the clock also organizationally complex?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31607311836.0" user="Firmaran" delta="True">
    <text>The complexity largely depends on how accurate the the keeping of time has to be be. You can probably make a good estimate on how many miles/km it is to your work/school. But if I ask you to be accurate to the feet/meter then you will have to do much more work.

The current system only needs to be accurate to about a minute, so a quick estimate of the referee is more than good enough.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
