<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="668667727.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/b23vbj/cmv_the_clock_in_a_soccer_game_should_be_stopped/">
    <title>CMV: the clock in a soccer game should be stopped for stoppages, rather than adding stoppage time.</title>
    <original_poster>SenseiCAY</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was having a sports-related discussion with my brother in law earlier today and we stumbled on this topic.  Neither of us are big soccer fans, but we both like sports in general. We both watch football (which has its own flaws) and baseball (which also has its flaws). I later found this article:

https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/fancy-stats/wp/2014/06/12/stoppage-time-in-soccer-how-it-works-and-what-it-means/?noredirect=on

I still don’t understand why a referee in charge of timing can’t just stop the clock for things like injuries, goals, and such. My reasoning:

* Other timed sports have this mechanism. The clock stops in American football for various events. The clock stops in hockey for fouls and goals. The clock stops in basketball for fouls (and I believe after baskets later in the game, in some formats). 
* The clock not stopping and leaving it to the referee to determine stoppage length leads to time-wasting that is against the spirit of competition, even if it is not technically against the rules - think of the instances of a player knocking the ball away from an opponent about to throw the ball in, or continuing to dribble the ball away from opponents when it is not their possession. These tactics, along with the prevalence of flopping, IMO, are detrimental to gaining new fans, especially in America.
* Knowing exactly when a game (or period of play) ends is better than the referee deciding it in any semi-arbitrary manner. The article I linked mentions that referees are unlikely to blow the play dead in the middle of an attack. I think that this is bad practice. The clock runs out on American football teams in the middle of a drive all the time. Basketball players are forced to take an unlikely shot because the clock is running out and the ref isn’t going to let them just play out the whole possession after the clock hits zero.
* If guidelines and best practices exist as to when to add stoppage time, including stoppage time during stoppage time, why can’t rules exist regarding stopping the clock? Discretion is a dangerous thing, especially when being influenced by a home crowd. 

CMV, folks. I like sports. I’d like to appreciate soccer more, even if I don’t go out of my way to watch games outside the World Cup,

Edit: I’ve heard the argument about stoppages leading to commercials. I don’t buy that. Soccer stoppages aren’t generally long enough to squeeze in ads. There aren’t timeouts, the (terrible) concept of a TV timeout doesn’t exist like it does in basketball games, you’re not gonna cut away during a penalty kick (where the clock runs), and injuries suck but I don’t see any loss of value if you replace footage of a guy on the turf getting stretchered off with a commercial or two.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="31607515196.0" user="TommoPol" delta="False">
    <text>Part-time referee here, whilst I can accept a number of your points, there are also a number of things you haven’t considered.

One of the things that makes this sport unique is the use of advantage laws. This is to say that if a foul is carried out but the team who were fouled still have the ball, with the discretion of the referee the game can be continued- but called back for the original incident if no advantage is seen. If we were to stop the clock, it would make it very difficult to apply this rule. If the rule was removed in favour of clock stoppages it would encourage players to play for fouls if they had the ball and were in situations they couldn’t get out of, or would encourage defending teams to foul and stop play if they were not in prime defensive positions.

Another thing to be considered here is what actually counts as a stoppage. The game is not considered stopped at the moment the ball is dead, the ball going for a corner or goal kick is considered part of the game, only if the player takes what we deem as an unreasonable amount of time to get the ball back into play do we consider it a stoppage, otherwise it’s just part of the game. Remember, a game is 90 minutes, this is quite a long time and some of that time is because that is set aside for stoppages.

Are you seriously saying that soccer is less attractive than football because of stoppages? Think of a football game, consider the time on the clock and how long the game actually takes to play, there’s an amount of showmanship in stoppage there, whereas in soccer the game does accept a certain amount of gamesmanship- at the discretion of the referee. If a player is taking too long it is up to the referee whether or not to reprimand that player.

If there is an injury, it’s normally monitored either how long the physio is on the field or how long it takes the player to get off the field for treatment. Time keeping isn’t always the most accurate, but the game would be considerably slowed down if there were persistent clock stoppages- knowing that it allowed a break players would be encouraged to take more time than is necessary, whereas with the current rules they don’t have that freedom knowing that the referee can call them out for time wasting.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608180164.0" user="SenseiCAY" delta="False">
    <text>I am not saying soccer is less attractive than football because of anything. One of the flaws of football, in my view, is the constant stoppage and lack of actual action (though the action that exists is pretty exciting).

I am actually pretty happy to hear from a ref who deals with this at field level. The advantage argument is compelling, but hockey already deals with this using the delayed penalty, as I’m sure you know. Additionally, why is it bad to play for fouls? If you have an advantage, the onus is on the defense to make up for it legally, without committing a foul. 

I also ref in a sport (ultimate) where the clock doesn’t really stop (for other logistical reasons). Teams have a strict time limit to continue play during live stoppages (turnovers, etc), and we police dead-disc stoppages to minimize delay. In basketball, you have five seconds to inbound the ball (being guarded) or else you lose it. 

If you can expand on the advantage argument, or provide more situations where stopping the clock adds logistical problems, I might be open to changing a view here.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="31608291378.0" user="TommoPol" delta="True">
    <text>Sportsmanship and gamesmanship have to be considered when it comes to fouls, firstly, it’s not sporting to intentionally commit a foul, however it can be part of gamesmanship. One of the most common fouls that you see at the levels I officiate is a foul to stop a break, this is to say the defending team are backtracking with a numerical disadvantage and rather than risk tackling and straight up losing the ball, they will play for a foul to stop play and allow players to get back into position. At the speed the game is generally played, players are generally keener to stop play than to allow play to continue, in these situations it is rare to play advantage. It’s not bad to play for fouls, however, I would argue that if there was a total clock stoppage it would encourage players to take more time to reset the game and if this happened it could encourage a team to make more fouls to slow down the pace of the game or change momentum- this could become an element of the way players play the game, but I don’t think it would improve the game, if anything it would be detrimental to the quality of the game and the viewers experience.

To be honest I can’t claim to be aware of all the ins and outs of your sport but from what you say it does seem similar, though the time limit is not applied in the same way. Basketball is an interesting example in terms of getting the ball back into play, the ball is often out of reach of the player, it could be in a stand and as we don’t tend to use a multi ball system at most levels it’s not always practical to impose a time limit. The system generally used is discretionary, that is, did the ball make it back onto the field of play within a timely manner, if it did then there is no time added on, if the ball remains in the stands or players are kicking it away then time will be added on. The ball going out of play is expected in the game, I suppose you could allow the clock to run arbitrarily for 10 seconds before stopping it.

Playing advantage is a key part of the game, as I mentioned in the previous paragraph and I think in a response to an earlier comment, timing of an advantage is discretionary. For the referee on the field, or a fourth official- when they are available, to time all stoppages is not necessarily that easy. From refereeing yourself you’ll know that your job as a referee is not just to watch where the play is happening at that point, to keep the pace of play up or to stop infractions on the field, there are so many different jobs involved. I wear a timer on my wrist in all games, it’s pretty simple and I take a look when I make a stoppage and I take a look when the play resumes, I make mental note of that time and generally an off field referee will also keep a note of stoppages, as I said, the period of time for a stoppage varies depending on the situation, so imposing time limits would be difficult. If the clock were to totally stop when the ball was declared dead by the referee and there was a way around stopping the clock in an advantage situation then I would recommend shortening each half.

Also, not all matches can be played with a huge number of officials, it’s the most widely played sport in the world and there isn’t always enough money in the game to have official time keepers at every game. There are also more grey areas in the sport than most others, introduction of VAR, which seems as though it will happen in at least the upper echelons of the game mean that play could be called back, this means that external timekeepers have to track the moment a foul was made, and this means that a device has to simply be created whereby the clock is stopped NOT by the moment a referee blows their whistle which communicates with the timer in the auditorium and the timer on the referees person. It’s not impossible, but logistically this isn’t easy to impose at all levels of the game in all countries.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
