<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254433845.0" user="pietari02" delta="False">
    <text>You claim that r/childfree is used as an echo chamber for hating children. You said there is no thoughtful discussion there and that the subreddit is toxic.

Of course, it is impossible to accurately rate the toxicity of a subreddit, but I read some of the most upvoted and most controversial posts of r/childfree and found the subreddit's users to be respectful of each other most of the time and explain their views in detail. I wouldn't say that r/childfree is toxic, it is just edgy at times.

Many posts showed that the subreddit's users' general view was:
-They don't hate children, they just don't want to, for example, hear babies crying and disturbing their day

-they want parents to be better at parenting and pay more attention to their children

-they want more societal acceptance for choosing not to have babies (for example, less celebration of father's day, as this makes anti-natalists feel left out)

I myself couldn't find any degradatory remarks of children, that weren't just an edgy joke. The subreddit is clearly a space for all kinds of people who don't want to have children to rant about bad parents and the bad behaviour that bad parenting causes, the reasons why they don't want to get children, and their experience of living childfree in a world were that might not always be appreciated by, for example, family.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254460568.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>I remember a few posts a month ago that were dead serious about hating the actual children. The fathers day argument I just find plain stupid, I'm sorry if that sounds disrespectful but thats not fair. People like to celevrate their parents and thinking just because they don't have children is a reason for everyone else to stop appreciating their parents is just dumb, I guess I can understand when companies use it in adverts but still.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254497456.0" user="pietari02" delta="True">
    <text>Well you can go to any subreddit with enough users and I will guarantee you that you will find some extremists who just take the idea of that subreddit a bit too far. Just like you shouldn't judge a book by it's cover, you shouldn't judge a subreddit by a few posts that might have made it to the subreddit's hot section when you were viewing it.

I agree that parents should be celebrated, yet that makes society seem like it favors those who choose to be parents, even if they are bad parents, which can upset those who choose for multiple reasons (climate change, child would live in poor conditions etc..) not to have children. They feel like they did the right decision, but even irresponsible parents are celebrated more than them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
