<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="744855311.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cbgu1b/cmv_rchildfree_is_a_toxic_sub/">
    <title>CMV: r/childfree is a toxic sub</title>
    <original_poster>SosRashneer</original_poster>
    <original_post>childfree is toxic. The sub isn't about being childfree, its about hating children as a whole. When I see a post on childfree its always about someone hating on other peoples "Crotch goblins" or "little brats". Like sometimes the child will be doing nothing at all and they're like "ugh I hate the little fucker so much like keep your crotch goblins inside your own house."
And I never really see any thoughtful discussions going on there I always only see someone hating on some other peoples children. And when someone tries to defend the child they usually get banned or downvoted. And I understand the reasoning of a child being expensive as to not having one, but if you're complaining that they're selfish that's the parents job to fix, and annoying, that can also be fixed by the parent.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32254382756.0" user="pandoraslighthouse" delta="False">
    <text>There are aspects of EVERY sub that are toxic. Even CMV, where occasionally we have racists/homophobes/etc trying to justify themselves. This happens everywhere. 
Childfree has many resources for people who are or wish to be “childfree” but cannot find a doctor to service them due to age, marital, or gender status that are otherwise impossible to find. I have found these resources very comforting to have as someone who wishes to adopt one day, but absolutely would NEVER wish to become pregnant. They premise of the sub itself was positive, but contains toxic people which is in fact different.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254413386.0" user="SosRashneer" delta="False">
    <text>I completely understand, Ive seen people on that sub that think the sub is toxic. This makes sense that the sub isnt meant to be toxic, I feel most peopele are though.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32254430306.0" user="pandoraslighthouse" delta="True">
    <text>Exactly though. Just because a sub contains a minority of loud, loud people that are toxic does mean the silent majority are. The premise of the sub is to lift people up in their decision to be child free despite societal pressure, parental disappointment, relationship conflict etc. it’s deeper than disliking child for 95% of folks and to be honest, it’s a positive resource for many. Those people ruin the atmosphere for those looking for resources just as many toxic people ruin other subs. It’s hard to say an ENTIRE sub is toxic because then every sub on reddit would be toxic under this classification.

Edit: minus woodworking. Woodworking has never been toxic lmao</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
