<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="76196414.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/19d5j2/the_rich_have_no_obligation_to_help_the_poor_cmv/">
    <title>The rich have no obligation to help the poor. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>tokecitybitch</original_poster>
    <original_post>Every now and then, I see the odd post, "If the top 1% gave up their profits, we could cure world hunger" or something ridiculous like that. I dont know why people that have less expect people that have more to help them. Why should they? 

Edit: better example. 

Edit: my C got Ved, /u/amemut explained it in a very pragmatic manner that I could agree with. </original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26643688645.0" user="amemut" delta="False">
    <text>I'll start by agreeing with you. The rich aren't obligated to help the poor. But then again, the poor aren't obligated to buy into our society's notions of property and ownership. There's really no reason that they should continue to see your stuff as "your" stuff. It could easily become their stuff, and there are more of them if it comes to fisticuffs.

The fact is, the things most people take for granted in these sorts of arguments, like property rights, are really concepts that we as a society have invented and agreed to believe in. There's really an implicit bargain being struck here, but if one side takes things too far, the deal is off. Whenever that has happened, those who took your attitude were the first against the wall. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643719586.0" user="tokecitybitch" delta="False">
    <text>Soooo, rich people become rich because of the poor people, so if they are not charitable, the poor people take it back? ... I am sorry I am not entirely sure what you are trying to say :(</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26643733268.0" user="amemut" delta="True">
    <text>Well, I'm just trying to argue from a purely practical standpoint. Practically speaking, why should the rich bother with helping the poor? The frank, rather crass, answer to this, is that if the rich don't do anything to help the poor, the poor will kill them and take their stuff. It has happened many times in the past, and we are never all that far away from its happening again.

You can easily construe this as a threat, but when you think about it a bit more, it really isn't. It's simply the nature of the bargain that most societies have hit upon. The bargain is: "Don't be too much of a shithead, and you get to have stuff and live your life how you want." If someone hoards wealth that they don't need or ever plan to use while people around them suffer from want, that person is a shithead. They aren't keeping their end of the bargain. Whenever there are too many people like them, there will be revolution to shake things up and restore the bargain. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
