<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583620635.0" user="Tino_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1.) The wealth tax

How does this stop capitalism?

&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

Why is this a bad thing?

&amp;gt;3.) Breaking up big tech companies

Again, why bad?

&amp;gt;4.) Medicare-For-All

For a 3rd time, why bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583642229.0" user="ChronoPsyche" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How does this stop capitalism?

I don't think any of this stops capitalism but weakens it. And my concern is that it will lower incentives to innovate.

&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Why is this a bad thing

Well it is a big step toward worker ownership of companies, which is a major component of socialism.

&amp;gt;3.) Breaking up big tech companies  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Again, why bad?

I think that it is a misinformed position. Generally when you break up companies, it is because they have acquired too much of their competition. That is not entirely the case with technology companies. Facebook, for example, isn't the most popular social media site because it has acquired all of its competition, but because it is simply the most popular. Same with Google. It hasn't acquired all the other search engines, it's just the most used and quite frankly, the best. How do you even break these companies up? And if you did, how would that affect the massive number of jobs these companies offer?

&amp;gt;4.) Medicare-For-All  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;For a 3rd time, why bad?

If it ends up being like Sanders plan, then it would get rid of private insurance and with it, millions of jobs. I think this is government overreach in the economy. Also, Medicare tends to pay lousy rates to doctors and if it was the only insurance available, might cause hospitals to close and doctor shortages. It is also prohibitively expensive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583678707.0" user="Tino_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think any of this stops capitalism but weakens it. And my concern is that it will lower incentives to innovate.

In what way?


&amp;gt;Well it is a big step toward worker ownership of companies, which is a major component of socialism.

How does worker ownership change anything? I understand that you see socialism as this boogeyman,  but are you aware that socialism and capitalism can actually exist at the exact same time? One is an econ system and the other is a way of governing. 

&amp;gt;Facebook, for example, isn't the most popular social media site because it has acquired all of its competition, but because it is simply the most popular

You are aware that Facebook does in fact own a massive share if the social media platforms right? They own Facebook,  Instagram and WhatsApp to name a few. 

&amp;gt;Same with Google.

So you might want to do some research into alphabet (Google's parent company) because they own an unbelievable amount of shit.

&amp;gt;How do you even break these companies up?

Get the FCC to tell them to divest their interests and spin off different companies? It's not really rocket science. 


&amp;gt;And if you did, how would that affect the massive number of jobs these companies offer?


Splitting companies would create more jobs if anything because the companies still need to exist, but they have a smaller talent pool to pull from so they in theory need to hire more people to do the jobs that 1 person covered for 5 companies before. Like splitting up monopolies has happened a million times in the past and the world has not ended.

&amp;gt;Medicare-For-All

How is or that every other western country can pull it off but not the US?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583703542.0" user="ChronoPsyche" delta="False">
    <text> 

&amp;gt;I don't think any of this stops capitalism but weakens it. And my concern is that it will lower incentives to innovate.  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;In what way?

Here was my response to another redditor who asked a similar question :  My issue with it is that it is not a tax on their salary but on their net worth, but most of billionaire's and ultra-millionaire's net worth is in investments. So let's take Jeff Bezos for an example. Let's say he is worth $100 billion. Now he is taxed 5% on 99 billion of that (which I believe is what the ultra-millionaire tax would do). That is close to $5 billion, but he might not even have that much money in cash. So then he has to go and sell a ton of his stock to get enough cash to pay that money. Now extend this to all billionaires and ultra-millionaires. If they are all having to sell lots of their stock in order to pay this tax, how does that affect the market? Additionally, what if someone's net worth remains constant? This is a tax on total wealth, not annual income, so if someone isn't increasing their wealth, they could have their wealth consistently reduced every year until they are below the threshold for the tax. 

&amp;gt; How does worker ownership change anything? 

It would be harder for companies to be successful if they are forced to be owned by their workers. Workers might not make decisions that are in the best interest of the company, but in the best interest of themselves. I understand that workers need to have a say, and that's why I support unions, but I think giving them too much power would create problems just as giving corporations too much power would.

&amp;gt; I understand that you see socialism as this boogeyman, but are you aware that socialism and capitalism can actually exist at the exact same time? One is an econ system and the other is a way of governing. 

In what way is public ownership of the means of production compatible with capitalism?

&amp;gt; You are aware that Facebook does in fact own a massive share if the social media platforms right? They own Facebook, Instagram and WhatsApp to name a few. 

Yes, but Instagram and WhatsApp are distinctively different services that wouldn't have offered direct competition. And there are still plenty of other social media services out there that aren't owned by Facebook.

&amp;gt; Splitting companies would create more jobs if anything because the companies still need to exist, but they have a smaller talent pool to pull from so they in theory need to hire more people to do the jobs that 1 person covered for 5 companies before. Like splitting up monopolies has happened a million times in the past and the world has not ended. 

Wouldn't they also have less access to resources, though?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583731653.0" user="Tino_" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;wealth tax

Sorry, you said you were worried that it would stop innovation.  How did anything you say here have anything to do with innovation? It seemed to be a lot of worrying about random stock prices and the total wealth of very specific people...

&amp;gt;In what way is public ownership of the means of production compatible with capitalism?

By having the prices of goods, and the survival of companies dependent on a free market? Who owns the company doesn't matter as long as the market is free to work like it is supposed to.


&amp;gt;It would be harder for companies to be successful if they are forced to be owned by their workers. 

Do you have any proof that this is true, or is it just a feeling you have?


&amp;gt;Wouldn't they also have less access to resources, though?

I mean kinda, but not really? Restructuring companies obviously isn't easy, but it also should not cause them to collapse and lose all of their jobs. If it does then the anti-trust shit failed hard because instead of 2 possible choices you still go back to 1.


&amp;gt;And there are still plenty of other social media services out there that aren't owned by Facebook.

Is a monopoly only a monopoly when it happens on purpose,  or is it possible that the consumer creates a monopoly by accident? And are they the same thing, or is one worse and why?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
