<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="784434824.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/cz15s8/cmv_joe_biden_is_the_only_major_2020_democrat/">
    <title>CMV: Joe Biden is the only major 2020 Democrat candidate who will preserve capitalism.</title>
    <original_poster>ChronoPsyche</original_poster>
    <original_post>I personally believe that capitalism is the best economic system for creating the most amount of wealth for the most people. I do think that it has its flaws and should have government checks to prevent it from getting out of control, but I think overall, it is the best economic system there is. I am a moderate liberal and my concern is that Biden is the only candidate who will preserve this system. This is a concern of mine because I think he is a weak candidate and am worried that his age and lack of focus will not make him an ideal president. Sanders and Warren are both experienced as well, more passionate, more focused, and more driven than Biden, but I am worried that they will lead America in too much of a socialistic direction, especially Sanders. I have been warming up to Warren recently, and I really want to support her, but there are some proposals of hers that I just have trouble coming around to.

1.) The wealth tax

2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

3.) Breaking up big tech companies

4.) Medicare-For-All

How can these proposals work within a capitalistic system, or can they not? Am I right in thinking that Joe Biden is the only one of the major candidates that will preserve capitalism? Note, I'm not asking for my view to be changed on capitalism itself. Let's leave the socialism vs capitalism debate for another time.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32583620635.0" user="Tino_" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;1.) The wealth tax

How does this stop capitalism?

&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

Why is this a bad thing?

&amp;gt;3.) Breaking up big tech companies

Again, why bad?

&amp;gt;4.) Medicare-For-All

For a 3rd time, why bad?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583642229.0" user="ChronoPsyche" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;How does this stop capitalism?

I don't think any of this stops capitalism but weakens it. And my concern is that it will lower incentives to innovate.

&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Why is this a bad thing

Well it is a big step toward worker ownership of companies, which is a major component of socialism.

&amp;gt;3.) Breaking up big tech companies  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;Again, why bad?

I think that it is a misinformed position. Generally when you break up companies, it is because they have acquired too much of their competition. That is not entirely the case with technology companies. Facebook, for example, isn't the most popular social media site because it has acquired all of its competition, but because it is simply the most popular. Same with Google. It hasn't acquired all the other search engines, it's just the most used and quite frankly, the best. How do you even break these companies up? And if you did, how would that affect the massive number of jobs these companies offer?

&amp;gt;4.) Medicare-For-All  
&amp;gt;  
&amp;gt;For a 3rd time, why bad?

If it ends up being like Sanders plan, then it would get rid of private insurance and with it, millions of jobs. I think this is government overreach in the economy. Also, Medicare tends to pay lousy rates to doctors and if it was the only insurance available, might cause hospitals to close and doctor shortages. It is also prohibitively expensive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32583777613.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;2.) 40% of corporate boards elected by employees

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Why is this a bad thing

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Well it is a big step toward worker ownership of companies, which is a major component of socialism.

Corporations, as they currently exist, are not a natural result of the invisible hand. They are not simply a byproduct of capitalism. A business does not become a corporation until the government issues a corporate charter. This allows an organization to act independently as a legal person. 

It also shields investors from liability exceeding their initial investment for anything done with their money. This is known as limited liability. 

There are trade offs for this limited liability though. First and foremost is a corporate income tax. In addition to this there are corporate regulations that must be followed. 

If the government were to determine that 40% worker control of leadership of a corporation as a condition of incorporation would be beneficial to society or the economy or whatever, then I dont really see the problem there. If such a prospect were too onerous, said organization is perfectly welcome to forego the benefits of limited liability. 

&amp;gt;I think that it is a misinformed position. Generally when you break up companies, it is because they have acquired too much of their competition. That is not entirely the case with technology companies. Facebook, for example, isn't the most popular social media site because it has acquired all of its competition, but because it is simply the most popular. Same with Google. It hasn't acquired all the other search engines, it's just the most used and quite frankly, the best. How do you even break these companies up? And if you did, how would that affect the massive number of jobs these companies offer?

[List of acquisitions and mergers by facebook](https://en.m.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_mergers_and_acquisitions_by_Facebook). 76 of them. Including instagram and whatsapp. 

And google is no longer simply a search engine. It hasnt been for ages. In fact, since 2015, google has just been a subsidiary of Alphabet Inc. Which also owns... just so many things. There is a reason they named it alphabet. Google (alphabet) isnt simply a search engine any more than Amazon is a simple textbook retailer

You describe yourself as a moderate liberal. But by the standards of every other developed nation on earth, you are a hardcore conservative.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
