<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="788202184.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d19wp4/cmv_muslim_is_the_superior_ideology/">
    <title>CMV: Muslim is the superior ideology</title>
    <original_poster>eltrutekili</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off I need to preface this by saying that I am a straight white male who was born, baptized, and raised Christian. I've held various thoughts throughout my life, ones you could even consider "Islamophobic".

That being said, I've read and watched a lot of content on the internet about the supposed "decline of Western civilization". Basically, it is the concept that feminism and white displacement is causing the downfall of society. This is due to a variety of factors, not limited to but including single motherhood, promiscuity, and drug abuse.

One of the major side effects of such societal issues is the formation of niche, extremist groups such as incels and MGTOWs. I'm not saying MGTOW = incel, but their core foundations are rooted upon the same premise; pure frustration.

Now here's the kicker, everything I am mentioning is fully solved within majority Muslim populations.

Allow me to explain. I thought about this a while back and was reminded of it tonight. I had just finished watching the UFC fight (Dustin Poirier vs. Khabib Nurmagomedov), and was reminded of Dustin's last fight. After Dustin's last fight, his wife graced the stage to show support for her husband. I just need to say, this woman was wearing an open cut dress showing off her...how shall I put it..."melons".

I got curious, being the testosterone driven young man that I am. I Googled her and found her Instagram. Her Instagram is filled with photos of her wearing very little clothing and receiving a lot of male attention. One comment, however, caught me off guard. It was written by a Muslim who had pointed out that Dustin allows his wife to post all of these sexual photos for attention, but nobody has ever even seen Khabib's wife. Well, you can find pictures of his wedding, but she is in full garment covering everything including her face. This individual then said that this is how it should be, that Khabib is the only man to see her half naked, and you know what? I agree.

Now about my previous statement; the majority Muslim populations solving issues which can be attributed to the "downfall" of our society. Muslims have, for a long time, enforced very strict rules which attempt to not only subdue but control biological urges that are rooted in hedonism, deprivation, and outright evil.

For example, I mentioned incels. Well, arranged marriages not only remove the societal pressure of having to find and court a woman. It also ensures that both parties are pure, and their pair boding has not been demolished by one night stands and "hypergamy". Not to mention removing a lot of the social anxieties around said relationships.

MGTOW? Most of them ended up in this boat because they were completely fucked over by the family court system, or "divorce rape" as they call it. Yeah, divorce isn't a thing in Muslim countries. Once you're married you're married. Cheat on your wife/husband? You're in for hell.

One more note; I also mentioned drug abuse. I watched a Vice documentary on ISIS which followed actual Islamic State militants in order to see how they run things in the various small areas they control. They were riding with one of the leaders through a town. One thing I noticed was that they had stopped to check on a man who was just released from prison for...get this...drinking alcohol. They made sure he was alright and that he was not drinking. They checked his place and everything.

You might be thinking, "this is anti-freedom!", and you might be partially correct. However, I believe this is more a matter of principal. Do you discipline this man for doing something that will clearly destroy him and cause harm to those around him, or do you let him be "free", drink until he has liver damage, and get into violent altercations while intoxicated? 99/100 times I'm going with the former.

Here is where the Muslim superiority really starts kicking in. If you look at major institutions, companies, schools, etc. They all seem to be towing this social justice warrior narrative lately. White males are at the brunt of most accusations, and are being made to feel guilty about all types of things. Things like slavery, patriarchy, etc. It seems weird to me that a white supremacist patriarchal society would allow this type of thing to happen.

The funny part; Muslims have a solution for this too. It's actually quite ironic. All of these different forms of oppression are far more prevalent in these Muslim countries, but you never hear about it from SJWs. Quite the opposite, actually. This label of "Islamophobia" seems to be some type of bizarre shield against any criticism one might have of said cultures.

Which is another point; Muslims would never take this kind of shit. They have their culture locked down so hard that the mere idea of even being criticized by the very people who claim to be oppressed by patriarchy, despite the fact that the Muslim culture is extremely patriarchal, actually causes feminists to rear their heads in defense of said culture. It gets to the point where they even claim that forced garments are "empowering" to women.

That's the thing though. While these women are forced to wear this apparel, there's one thing that is certain; they will never be accused of being raped because of what they are wearing. This is my final point. They've effectively removed male biological urges by forcing the women to cover themselves. This minimizes women being looked at as nothing more than sex objects, and also ensures that their husbands are the only ones who have a truly intimate and unique connection with them.

It is for these reasons listed above that I believe that the Muslim ideology and culture is superior to all others. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32624413466.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[deleted]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625377286.0" user="eltrutekili" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; societies with the liberalism that you deride are infinitely better places to live than highly religious and insular countries

This is nothing more than a personal opinion. Your next few sentences are also just opinions.

&amp;gt; Hong Kong is nicer to live in than China

...really? Have you seen the protests?

&amp;gt; Israel is nicer to live in than Palestine, and more liberal

That might be because of massive foreign influence...

&amp;gt; Saudi Arabia is only wealthy because of dependence on a finite and valuable resource

The same can be said about literally any nation.

&amp;gt; Iran is being choked from all directions by sanctions

This is less about their ideology and more about the resources you mentioned previously.

&amp;gt; Wrong. Islam is more permissive of divorce than Catholicism.

If we look at the actual numbers, the divorce rate in Western countries is above 50% and growing. Compared to Muslim nations, the 2 highest divorce rates (Turkey and Egypt) are a whoppingly low 10%. What does that tell you about how permissive divorce is, or the social structures surrounding said mechanisms?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32625616754.0" user="Thatguysstories" delta="True">
    <text>Well having a low divorce rate is easy when you treat one section of the population as practical property. 

Do you really think that the majority of the women in those countries have a real choice in the matter? Where if they wanted a divorce they could actually get one? 

Firs consider whether the women in some of the countries you are looking up to even have the right to travel outside without being escorted by a male relative. Let alone making it to a court house to file a motion for divorce. 

Secondly consider, even if a women was able to make it to a courthouse and file the papers, would her husband let that be? Or will the husband be mad, and beat his wife and hold her hostage at home for the foreseeable future until she rethinks the divorce. If he doesn't outright kill her in a honor killing. 

That's something this thread has seemed to be missing. 

Do you support honor killings? If a girl sleeps with a men before marriage, should she be killed? If a girl is raped while not being married, should she be forced to marry her rapist? What about children? Do you support child marriages? Hell, even the US has it's own issues with child marriages that we seriously need to fix. But would you support a 11 year old girl, who was raped to be forced to marry a 40 year old man? 

If a women does wear what you would consider revealing clothing, should she be imprisoned? Caned? Stoned? Put to death? 

How do you consider any of this the superior ideology?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
