<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="793889471.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d4nt1b/cmv_the_original_bioshock_is_one_of_the_most/">
    <title>CMV: The original BioShock is one of the most overrated video games of all time, and doesn't deserve a fraction of the praise it receives.</title>
    <original_poster>Chainsmoker88</original_poster>
    <original_post>**tl;dr:** The game had some great ideas. They just weren't executed properly imo. Allow me to elaborate.

BioShock's "Welcome to Rapture" level is one of the best introductions to any game ever. Rapture, Andrew Ryan, the splicers, Big Daddies, Little Sisters, Atlas' character, and plasmids are all explained to you in a perfectly executed 25 minute level. The tone is set for the game, there's a mystery from the very start about your character. Unfortunately, this is the only level in the game in which  the splicers have any personality, a lot of the levels in Rapture lack personality because they all look the same, our character isn't really expanded on until the Rapture Control Room level. To make it worse, the Big Daddies/Little Sisters are all just copied/pasted from level to level, which makes them feel like they're only there so that we can get upgrades and not because they are living, breathing characters.

 Fast-forward some 30 minutes and I am facing my first Big Daddy, and I have absolutely no idea what I'm doing. Nothing I do to it seems to be very effective and it all ends with me running around like a headless chicken, spending about 4-5 medkits and at least as many EVE syringes spray-n-praying through that ordeal. The game, as far as I can see, have given me absolutely no clues as how to deal with this guy, and this is not the first time either. I took this encounter as the worst example of many situations where it seems there simply is no good solution. I mean, the zap+whack works great for 1v1 encounters, but what about when there are multiple enemies with machine guns? I mean, yes, I could waste 40 machine gun bullets taking them down, but that hardly seems like the optimal solution and I also feel like that is not the way it should work as a survival horror. Entering a fight with Mr. Bubbles knowing he will fuck me up and I don't have anything to say in the matter really does not make me wanna continue playing. 

 I also think BioShock is a lazy game with the way that characters are presented. Yes, the characters are well written but unfortunately the creators of BioShock don't understand the old saying, "show, don't tell". Any kind of exposition is given to you in the same format of an audio diary. Don't get me wrong, I do like the inclusions of audio diaries and I think they can be used to great effect, I don't think they should be used to give exposition for every single thing in the game. The amount of character interaction in this game is laughable for a game that is praised for character development and while I understand the lack of characters may be there to give the effect of a horror game, BioShock fails at this due to the game not being able to find its own identity. I mean, does anyone actually consider BioShock a horror game? 

BioShock's story seems interesting enough. However, the way in which it's told is something the game's creators didn't quite get right. There is A LOT of backtracking in BioShock, and the story feels really contrived and convoluted at times. Right after the "Welcome to Rapture" level, you have to go through a whole series of events just to progress the story a tiny amount. You have to go get a plasmid to melt a lump of ice blocking your path so you can get a plasmid that will let you clean obstacles out of your way so you can go Dr Steinman so you can get a key from him so you can open a locked door. If that isn't contrived storytelling, I don't know what is. This isn't the only time this happens in the game, it happens several other times as well.

Then you get to the plot twist, which I won't spoil for anyone who may be reading this, and the game feels like it is hitting a turning point. Will there actually be any character development? Will there be any real interaction? The answer is obviously no. Unfortunately you wake up in Tenenbaum's safe house, yet the exposition is always the same (picture in bottom right with a voice clip played). This is laughable because she's in the other room, but this comes across to me as lazy and takes me out of the game due to the fact that I feel that the characters aren't real. The characters don't seem real, because they don't act like how normal humans would. It wouldn't of hurt them to have Tenenbaum actually talk to the player like a normal human interaction would happen, but it's never face to face in Bioshock, even when it should be which makes it feel very inhuman. 

Then for the second half of the game, Fontaine is constantly throwing insults at the player in a way which reminds me of a moustache twirling villain who is just doing it for the sake of it. This would work but I feel that Fontaine should be doing this much later on (kind of like Malak in KotOR). You do some fetch quests for an hour so that your brain won't tell your heart to shut off (ha!) and then you have to do something which still puzzles me how people let it slide. 

You have to become a Big Daddy. Now while this isn't a bad idea, just like everything else in Bioshock it's executed poorly. You become a Big Daddy to get through to Fontaine (who is a rehashed splicer model, just like everyone else in this game). Sounds fine. Then when you go to face Fontaine, the Big Daddy suit is suddenly gone (No big deal right? not like we just spent the last hour invested in this plot point, which really should have had a big effect.) Maybe it would have been interesting if they wrote it so that turning into a Big Daddy would have had a big emotional effect, where Jack has to sacrifice his free will to stop Fontaine, but no. Nothing at all.

Then the boss fight happens, where the boss can be perma-stunned. I don't even have to explain how bad this boss fight is, as everyone usually agrees about this point. Now to the endings. The good ending, while quite touching is unfortunately extremely short. The moral choice for this game comes from the save/kill little sisters, but this fails because all of the little sisters feel void of character, as they are just copied and pasted between levels, so to have them as the big moral choice is astonishing. Why doesn't anyone discuss how linear this choice is anyway? I mean, you harvest one little sister and you get the bad ending. Is this not the definition of a black and white choice? I'm not even going to discuss the bad ending, because it's so shitty that it's not even worth discussing.

I'll award a delta to anyone who convinces me to give this game another chance, or that any of what I just said is objectively wrong. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32676476279.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="False">
    <text>All I can say about the way the challenge is presented is that I did not have the same experience.  That first Big Daddy wrecked me, but I never felt like he was just smacking me down and I never knew what to do... I felt frantic, like I was running around trying desperately to survive, and I think that's exactly what I was supposed to feel.  I was given this big open space, so staying away from him wasn't too hard.

&amp;gt;  I mean, yes, I could waste 40 machine gun bullets taking them down, but that hardly seems like the optimal solution and I also feel like that is not the way it should work as a survival horror.

It's not survival horror; it's action.

&amp;gt; You have to go get a plasmid to melt a lump of ice blocking your path so you can get a plasmid that will let you clean obstacles out of your way so you can go Dr Steinman so you can get a key from him so you can open a locked door. If that isn't contrived storytelling, I don't know what is.

See... this stuff is just there to teach you how to use the plasmids.  I feel like your two points here contradict one another... they have parts where the story slows down to teach you the gameplay.

&amp;gt; Any kind of exposition is given to you in the same format of an audio diary. Don't get me wrong, I do like the inclusions of audio diaries and I think they can be used to great effect, I don't think they should be used to give exposition for every single thing in the game.

The atmospheric effect of the audio diaries is to present to you that you're in a graveyard.  Everyone's dead.  You're forced to listen to all these tragic stories to get information you need, and you can't do anything to help anyone you're hearing.  (I don't think it works quite as well as in System Shock 2, because it actually gets really unclear how sentient these enemies you're fighting in Bioshock are, but that's the goal.)


&amp;gt; Will there actually be any character development? Will there be any real interaction?

Yyyeahh, I feel like someone misrepresented this game to you, or something.  The game isn't about characters; it's about IDEAS.  It's a theme-focused story.  Of course there's no interaction, because your character's a cipher... he doesn't have an arc, because the PLAYER is meant to have the arc.  You're supposed to go, "Oh wait, huh, all those times I thought I had a choice of what to do, I didn't,  Huh, maybe even outside of video games, choice is an illusion...?"  It's a critique of objectivism: fetishize freedom, and most of the time, you're fetishizing something that doesn't really exist.  


&amp;gt;  Fontaine is constantly throwing insults at the player in a way which reminds me of a moustache twirling villain who is just doing it for the sake of it. 

Again, this is best seen through a thematic lens.  Fontaine is the flaw of objectivism: a smart monster whose ruthless self-interest ends up destroying the self-interest-loving world he lives in.  He's a natural product of Galt's Gulch and Galt's Gulch also cannot survive with him there. 


I do agree with a couple of your criticisms.  Turning into a Big Daddy really is pointless and whatever impact it was supposed to have, it doesn't.  And yeah, there's definitely problems with the endings... though I get what they were going for.  The ONE THING you have choice over is to do the rational Randian thing or to actually be compassionate.  Go the former route, and you're embarking down the Fontaine path. (and I don't have a problem with them being so conservative here.  Yes, killing one little girl SHOULD be damning.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32676780375.0" user="Chainsmoker88" delta="False">
    <text>I appreciate the fact that you analyzed each of my points and made cohesive arguments.

&amp;gt;See... this stuff is just there to teach you how to use the plasmids. I feel like your two points here contradict one another... they have parts where the story slows down to teach you the gameplay.

Alright, but I think they should've done that *after* the interaction with Steinman, rather than making the story super contrived and convoluted. And I have no idea how people let this awful storytelling slide in a game that is praised for its storytelling.

&amp;gt;The atmospheric effect of the audio diaries is to present to you that you're in a graveyard. Everyone's dead. You're forced to listen to all these tragic stories to get information you need, and you can't do anything to help anyone you're hearing. (I don't think it works quite as well as in System Shock 2, because it actually gets really unclear how sentient these enemies you're fighting in Bioshock are, but that's the goal.)

I wasn't referring to the actual audio diaries, I was referring to how interactions between Jack and other characters is done **entirely** by the other person speaking through a system with a picture of them in the bottom right corner. And as I previously mentioned, the Tennenbaum interaction when you wake up is a good example. My point was that there was no face to face interaction.

&amp;gt;Yyyeahh, I feel like someone misrepresented this game to you, or something. The game isn't about characters; it's about IDEAS.

Well what kind of game is that? Not about characters? Really?

&amp;gt;It's a theme-focused story. Of course there's no interaction, because your character's a cipher... he doesn't have an arc, because the PLAYER is meant to have the arc. You're supposed to go, "Oh wait, huh, all those times I thought I had a choice of what to do, I didn't, Huh, maybe even outside of video games, choice is an illusion...?" It's a critique of objectivism: fetishize freedom, and most of the time, you're fetishizing something that doesn't really exist. 

I think you're over-complicating it. It's a simple plot twist: You thought you were free, but you're actually not. It's interesting at first, but like I said, there's no character development and nothing changes. 

&amp;gt;Yes, killing one little girl SHOULD be damning.

For a game that is praised for it's supposed moral choices, the fact that its *only* moral choice is a black-and-white-kill-or-not-kill choice is inexcusable.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32676879289.0" user="PreacherJudge" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Alright, but I think they should've done that after the interaction with Steinman, rather than making the story super contrived and convoluted. And I have no idea how people let this awful storytelling slide in a game that is praised for its storytelling.

Again, I personally didn't find anything about it jarring or confusing when I was playing for the first time.  

&amp;gt; I wasn't referring to the actual audio diaries, I was referring to how interactions between Jack and other characters is done entirely by the other person speaking through a system with a picture of them in the bottom right corner. And as I previously mentioned, the Tennenbaum interaction when you wake up is a good example. My point was that there was no face to face interaction.

Well yeah, that's for two reasons.  They're talking to YOU, the PLAYER. "Interactions" aren't going to happen, because in an interaction *you can choose what to do*.  In a video game, you can't... at best you can choose one of four complete sentences.  The game is partly ABOUT this lack of choice.

 And, it helped them avoid focusing on close-ups of the character models, so they didn't have to waste resources on lip sync or attractive faces.

&amp;gt; Well what kind of game is that? Not about characters? Really?

Yes, really.  Why are you acting like this is weird?  Plenty of narratives are driven by themes and not characters (one author, who went so far as to devote pages to screeds about the way she thought society should go, comes to mind especially easily right now).

&amp;gt; I think you're over-complicating it. It's a simple plot twist: You thought you were free, but you're actually not. It's interesting at first, but like I said, there's no character development and nothing changes.

What about the entire premise of the game, where a guy whose name is almost an anagram of Ayn Rand establishes Galt's Gulch at the bottom of the ocean, and everything goes to hell because there wasn't a government regulating the stuff they were doing down there?  I'm not sure you're on solid ground if you think there isn't a whole lot going on about freedom, choice, and agency, both in video games and in politics.  They sure spend a helluva lot of time talking about it.



&amp;gt; For a game that is praised for it's supposed moral choices, the fact that its only moral choice is a black-and-white-kill-or-not-kill choice is inexcusable.

It's not praised for its moral choices, it's praised for its *thematic examination of morality vis-a-vis freedom*.  ALL video game morality is simplistic... there's a literal formula calculating how good or evil you are!  That's what this game is trying to EXPOSE... all that "freedom" in those other games is an illusion.

Even the most morally complex and interesting games (like KOTOR2 or Planescape: Torment) have absolutely 0 things interesting about the character's ability to choose morality.  They just have good writing when the characters DISCUSS morality.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
