<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="797145031.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/d6ll1j/cmv_capitalism_has_little_to_no_place_in_our/">
    <title>CMV: Capitalism has little to no place in our current world</title>
    <original_poster>s3v3ralmidg3ts</original_poster>
    <original_post>Capitalism was certainly a great boon during the industrial revolution. It spurred the necessary economic development that our worldwide civilization needed to leap into our current state.

That being said, capitalism is doing more harm than good in this era. When things like climate change are significantly tied to corporations, workers being treated as a disposable resource by companies like Amazon, horrendous working conditions being supported by tech companies to mass produce the next iPhone, etc.

Why is capitalism still revered in some circles as the cure all to our problems when that doesn't seem to be the case in practice?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="32702224276.0" user="JohnReese20" delta="False">
    <text>What system to you propose to replace capitalism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702264488.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>I think that would take a much larger discussion, but I think the first step is acknowledging that our current system needs to change.

That said, of existing systems, socialism seems to help alleviate the issues I mentioned above. It would help to shift the focus from "How much money did we make last quarter" to be more human-centric</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702281456.0" user="JohnReese20" delta="False">
    <text>You don't actually have to accept that capitalism is flawed, you just have to accept that there's another system that's better.  And even if capitalism is falwed it might be the best option.  Regardless of which is true you need another system to have any meaningful conversation.  

And what do you mean by socialism?  Do you mean communism or social capitalism?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702312277.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>Why is it necessary to have a fully fleshed out system to have a discussion on whether or not the current system is working to support its population?

And I suppose I'm effectively referring to social capitalism, since that's a much easier leap for most people than jumping straight to theoretical communism.

A world where everyone's basic needs are met seems like it would serve it's people the best when we currently have life saving medications like Insulin costing exorbitant amounts of money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702391156.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="False">
    <text>Because even if the ship your on is junk, that doesn't mean there is a better one to jump to.

The determining factor on weather or not to jump ship is if there is a better one to jump to, not if the one you are in is flawed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702418611.0" user="s3v3ralmidg3ts" delta="False">
    <text>That's a solid point. So the question then changes to, can we do better? Or, if we can't, can some future generation build a better ship?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="32702480875.0" user="Thoth_the_5th_of_Tho" delta="True">
    <text>Maybe. But I doubt it. 

Just about every way to organize a society has been tried over the last 3000 years. The last 100 years of capitalist rule has seen more improvement in the lives of the average person than the previous 3000 combined and the improvements are only getting faster.  

There is certainly a lot of tweaking left to do, but its pretty clear that the current capitalist-democracy model is an outlier.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
