<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26686319922.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's a violation of the 4th amendment. "Receiving government assistance" is not probable cause to search someone for traces of drugs. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686326397.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The objective of the fourth amendment is to make sure the government is promoting the general welfare, and by testing for drugs they are ensuring that everyone is safe. Welfare funds are taxpayer dollars and by implementing drug testing the government is doing a service to taxpayers. People do have a right to their privacy, and if they think that drug testing is violating it, they should apply for some other loan. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686330944.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Unless you want to live in a fascist police state you still need probable cause to search someone. Innocent until proven guilty and all that. 

Should welfare recipients also have to have a camera installed in their living room to make sure they're not breaking any other laws? It would be promoting the general welfare and ensuring people are safe, as you said. If not, what's the difference between that and screening them for drugs?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686333329.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Think of it more as an agreement between the government and the recipient rather than Deputy Doug randomly searching a motor vehicle.

"You get money from us, so you need to piss in this cup as a condition of the agreement."

Same as your employer.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686336542.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>That agreement would violate the 4th amendment and would assume you are guilty of something without probable cause. Your employer is not bound by the 4th amendment. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686340225.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Taxpaying citizens have the right to demand drug testing.  The welfare recipient would only be forced to drug test on the condition of receiving welfare.  They can always choose not to test.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686785050.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>This view runs afoul of the [unconstitutional conditions doctrine.](http://definitions.uslegal.com/u/unconstitutional-conditions-doctrine/) The government cannot condition a benefit on waiver of a constitutionally protected right. This is much easier to understand when you try it with some other rights:

Would it be OK to require welfare recipients to convert to Buddhism?

Would it be OK to require welfare recipients to waive their right to a trial by jury?

Would it be OK to remove the right to free speech from welfare recipients?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687429096.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Welfare is not a right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687496720.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>You have completely missed the point. Nowhere did i say welfare is a right. There is a right to be free from unreasonable searches,  and the benefit of welfare can't be conditioned on waiving it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687504837.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>The definition you linked says:

&amp;gt;This rule states that the government cannot force a person to choose between two constitutionally protected rights.

I see where you're going, though, and the 4th Amendment has been mentioned in other comments.   </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687523023.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>It also states "the government cannot condition a person's receipt of a governmental benefit on the waiver of a constitutionally protected right." The example is about a radio station receiving public funds, which is clearly not itself a right. 

If you want to get more specific about welfare benefits and blood tests, you have to delve into the case law, where is was found unconstitutional by the 6th circuit in [Marchwinski v. Howard](http://www.wlf.org/litigating/case_detail.asp?id=44) and by a Florida district court in [Lebron v. Wilkins.](http://www.clearinghouse.net/chDocs/public/PB-FL-0006-0003.pdf)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687546267.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Well, Marchwinski v. Howard was technically settled on split decision (6-6 with a tie going to the court).

I'm reading Lebron v. Wilkins now:  http://www.ca11.uscourts.gov/opinions/ops/201115258.pdf</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687593116.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="False">
    <text>You can count noses all you want, the fact is the 6th Circuit *en banc* affirmed the district court's finding that the program was unconstitutional. It's unlikely that we will see further challenges because states are giving up on these drug testing programs as being complete wastes of money anyway.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687646962.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Wrong.  The 6th Circuit review affirmed Lebron's right to challenge the mandatory drug test under the 4th Amendment.  They did not examine the merits of the case, but they did decide that it would be difficult for the state to impose mandatory drug testing as a prerequisite for benefits under the 4th Amendment.

They also stated that unless the state could demonstrate a special need to waive 4th Amendment protection, their case would probably not stand up in district court (obviously it didn't).  I do believe that there is a special need to waive an individual's right to privacy in this case because the individual needs to demonstrate that they are responsible enough to effectively make use of government benefits in the case of welfare.  Drug testing is a good way to establish this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26687698517.0" user="EvilNalu" delta="True">
    <text>I think we've reached the productive end of the 4th Amendment discussion. I think the arguments that it is unconstitutional are stronger than those that it is constitutional, but there are arguments on both sides.

Honestly it seems like you just have a problem with the fact of welfare. The funny thing is I don't disagree with you there. It's just that drug testing is a further waste of money. In Florida they spent more money testing than they saved by eliminating people from the welfare rolls.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
