<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="80733377.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1c2e9t/i_think_that_welfare_recipients_should_endure/">
    <title>I think that welfare recipients should endure random drug testing as a condition of receiving benefits. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>batscrotum</original_poster>
    <original_post>99% of jobs I've held have required drug screening at random or as an initial condition of employment.  I think that all adults who receive welfare should be subjected to the same screening process.  This should be a federal addendum to all state welfare programs.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26686588062.0" user="MayoDomo" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you think this? Do you think drugs are a waste of time and money?   What do many well off people do with their money? Do they spend it all efficiently and wisely?  Do you engage in activities that others would consider a waste of time and money? What I'm trying to get at is everyone enjoys different things.  Whether it be videogames, cigarettes, collectors items, trading cards, antiques, gambling, coins, or even drugs, these are all habits/addictions cost money and time.  Should we test the welfare recipients on everything that doesn't directly contribute to their health and quality of life? That would be absurd.  What you are suggesting in its most basic form is to banish a non-productive use of money and time.  You are drawing the line at drugs, although there are hundreds of other activities you probably consider wasteful.  Essentially, in my opinion it's not your right to tell other people what to do with their money.  It is their money, and they should spend it how they want to.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686613188.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's not their money.  It's my money.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686616306.0" user="MayoDomo" delta="False">
    <text>First of all it is their money.  The government takes yours, and gives it to them.  Also assuming it is your money, you should have complete authority over how they spend it? If everyone had different requirements on how they want their money to be spend by people on welfare, no money would ever be able to be spent.  It's silly to try to control it.  Furthermore you don't decide how your taxes are spent, do you also think you should have control over that? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686619976.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I do have an opportunity (albeit a limited opportunity) to decide where my tax dollars are spent through voting.  

Welfare dollars are dollars that I have earned through diligence and hard work so yes, I do think that I should be able to voice my opinion on the prerequisite criteria for receiving my money as a benefit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686626320.0" user="MayoDomo" delta="False">
    <text>Do you not work diligently for your money that is taxed?  They are ultimately the same thing.  Voting for a president who has your policy on welfare dollars is the same influence.  Let me ask if you if your personal welfare money went to someone who did not 'do drugs' would you not have a complaint?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686629482.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I take issue with every individual that is abusing the welfare program whether they use drugs or not.  I think that mandatory drug testing as a prerequisite to receiving welfare will purge a lot of the abusers from the system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686633912.0" user="MayoDomo" delta="False">
    <text>Would you have a problem giving money to gambling addicts, alcoholics, or those who spend it on flashy things like cars? If so I think you have a problem with the system, not the people abusing the system.

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686637889.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>I definitely have a problem with the system, but I also take issue with the irresponsible individuals who willfully abuse charity.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686647021.0" user="MayoDomo" delta="False">
    <text>OK then I'm going to attempt to change your view with 'the irresponsible individuals who willfully abuse charity,' because I agree with your problem with the system.  Willfully abuse charity is a subjective phrase.  You have your own ideas on how money should be spent, particularly for how those who receive welfare benefits should be spent.  You probably think you know what is best for them.  But because spending money is subjective, they would rather spend money on x rather than y.  They perhaps think their quality of life is increased by smoking weed or tripping on acid as opposed to having a healthy, well balanced meal.  Perhaps the pros outweigh the cons in their mind.  Perhaps the thrill of gambling excites them more than 10 hour of watching cable.  Just because they live their life differently than you doesn't mean its irresponsible.  I will give you that in some cases you are right, but you should never categorize all or even most people who have different ways of doing things as irresponsible.  Try to take an objective standpoint and understand that maybe paying 10$ for weed a day helps them escape from their relatively crappy life and is the most optimal way to spend money on happiness.  Try to understand that gambling for 5 hours a day gets may get more excitement than watching cable.  Your way of life should never impose on others in my opinion.  Imagine some of the hobbies you have being taken away from you, just because they are socially unacceptable and considered irresponsible. (Even if they really aren't.) That is what those receiving your benefits would feel.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686655271.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Your way of life should never impose on others in my opinion. 

Welfare is an imposition on my way of life.  It costs me money.  I don't like it.

I don't think that I know what's best for welfare recipients, but I do know that manipulating loopholes in our system so that you (not you you) can stay on permanent welfare while you cash your check for meth or vodka is a drain on society.

I don't have hard numbers, but I'd be willing to bet my yearly contribution to the welfare program that the majority of welfare abusers also use drugs.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26686699717.0" user="sir_mrej" delta="True">
    <text>I'd like to take that bet. Because in Florida last year, it was 2.6%

http://www.miamiherald.com/2012/04/20/2758871/floridas-welfare-drug-tests-cost.html</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
