<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="903350017.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/extxc1/cmv_israel_is_not_the_primary_cause_of_the/">
    <title>CMV: Israel is not the primary cause of the humanitarian crisis in Gaza, nor can they do much to stop it.</title>
    <original_poster>thosewhowait</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've been seeing a lot of people and politicians argue that we need to put pressure on the Israeli government to end the humanitarian crisis in Gaza. There absolutely is a humanitarian crisis going on there; the nearly two million Palestinians living there don't have clean water, building materials, or infrastructure. However, it seems to me that this is largely due to the fact that Hamas is the de-facto ruler of the strip. As I understand it, when Israel decided to pull out of Gaza, they established considerable infrastructure like greenhouses to give the Palestinians a head start, but as soon as they pulled out, Hamas organized parties to destroy the Israeli infrastructure that they left. Also, rather than using building material like concrete to actually build up high quality infrastructure, they use it to build tunnels under Israel so they can conduct terrorist attacks on civilians. Hamas has also been increasingly authoritarian and preventing rival parties to hold any public events, so the people's ability to put a more effective and people-oriented government into power is greatly diminished. Putting aside Hamas's corruption, they are also in a conflict with Isis (which has established strongholds in the Sinai, bordering Gaza) which is further distracting them from increasing the standard of living of their people.

I want to make it clear that I do not at all support Israel's expansion of settlements into Palestinian territory, and I genuinely do believe that some form of two state solution involving Israel and at least the West Bank will be possible, but with Gaza specifically, I'm not really sure what can realistically be done by Israel that would not put their citizens in danger. As I understand it, Israel limits import of construction materials because Hamas continues to use them to build tunnels under Israel, screens shipments to Gaza because of continuous rocket attacks on civilian areas by Hamas, and prevents free movement from Gaza to the West Bank because suicide bombings / stabbings are a serious issue there. It's a lot less infrequent for buses to blow up now, so it seems pretty effective. 

I really do feel that the Gazans are the true victims here, but I think Hamas is currently the main cause of their suffering, not Israel. Regardless, I'm not sure what a concrete, feasible action would be for Israel to help the Gazans that wouldn't open them up to further terrorism.

Also, I just want to clarify that this is about the *current situation*. I think it's another conversation about the events that led up to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict as a whole, but I'm more interested in discussing what Israel could realistically do *right now* that would not compromise their security.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33640720629.0" user="Barnst" delta="False">
    <text>The [World Bank estimates](http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/563181468182960504/pdf/96601-REVISED-WP-Box391464B-AHLC-May-21-Book-fix-footnotes.pdf) that Gaza’s GDP is 50% lower as a result of the Israeli blockade alone.

&amp;gt;	Gaza’s economy has particularly suffered as a result of the 2007 blockade. Israel substantially tightened movement of goods and people in and out of Gaza in 2006 following the January 2006 victory of Hamas and the formation of the Hamas-led PA government in March 2006.15 In 2007 a full blockade was imposed. Consequently, between 2005 and 2008, Gaza’s gross domestic output was reduced by a third, first primarily as a result of a drastic drop in government consumption and investment and then after 2007 also a substantial drop in private consumption and investment, but also a virtual elimination of an already ebbed export sector.

Whether you think it’s justified or not, it’s hard to argue that Israel’s approach to dealing with Hamas *hasn’t* caused significant hardship for Gaza as a whole.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33640922482.0" user="TheFakeChiefKeef" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with this framing is that you've now made it a chicken and egg situation with no end. Like, Israel wouldn't be blockading if it weren't for Hamas, but Hamas wouldn't exist without Israel being militaristic towards Palestinians, but Israel wouldn't be militaristic if it hadn't been for Arab on Israeli violence, etc. etc. to a vague starting point with no clear catalyst. 

I mean like it or not, the blockade is doing exactly what it's intended to do - reduce the violence in Israel coming from Gaza. Obviously the end result is far from ideal and it's fair to say disproportionately harmful to innocent Gazans but if you really want to blame someone for the blockade it has to be Hamas.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33641021066.0" user="Barnst" delta="True">
    <text>I’m trying to avoid the chicken-egg problem of assigning blame for the conflict itself and focus on OP’s idea that Hamas is directly responsible for conditions in Gaza as a result of their supposed choices like destroying greenhouses, and that Israel couldn’t do much about those conditions even if they wanted to.

That simply isn’t true.  The conditions in Gaza exist in large part because Israel has imposed a blockade on it.   They may or may not be *justified* in imposing the blockade, but that wasn’t OP’s original arguement.    Ending the blockade would immediately improve conditions in Gaza.   The impact that would have on Israeli security is a separate question.

Hamas’ poor economic policy may also be terrible and would also leave Gaza poor, but its hard to test that premise under the shadow of the blockade’s effect on the economy.

Edit: Clarifying on rereading—OP *is* arguing that the blockade is justified for security reasons, but he doesn’t really expand on that premise, just accepts the argument.  His title and first paragraph still put most of the concrete blame on Hamas for the material conditions, though.

Edit2: Further reflection on how to stage it more clearly. OP basic idea is that Israel is not the “primary” cause of the humanitarian situation.   It really depends on what is meant by “primary.”   The causal chain basically goes:

Hamas seizes power—&amp;gt;Israel faces a security threat from Hamas—&amp;gt;Israel imposes a blockade with the dual goals of minimizing the threat and pushing Hamas out of power—&amp;gt;the blockade results in humanitarian crisis

I’d argue that Israel “caused” the humanitarian situation through the actions it chose to take after Hamas took power.  Gaza would still be poor without the blockade, but it wouldn’t be absolutely destitute as it is now.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
