<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="941986196.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/fku178/cmv_polyamory_will_never_actually_work/">
    <title>CMV: Polyamory will never actually work.</title>
    <original_poster>AndrewBlue3</original_poster>
    <original_post>You can't have the same intimacy with a person in that kind of relationship. There will be alot of jelaousy and you can choose to ignore it or act upon it and neither is good for you. 
There is a specific kind of people that "succeed" in polyamory and they are always dyed hair liberals and the relationships are really immature. It's always processed fake love and people that go into it expecting some real and eyeopening experience end up gettining hurt.
What is the point in overcoming jelousy or learning to live with it ? It is what i always hear from poly people. Jelousy is a natural reaction and it is there for a reason, if i am not jelous that my girl is fucking with some other guy/girl that means that i don't really care for her that much anymore.
I mean have you ever been in some wider circle of friends. You know how that shit goes. Now imagine that in a relationship, it goes x10 worse.
At the end i think it is all about sex and how much shit you can take in order to have multiple sex partners at once.

Just don use "well you wouldnt eat the same food everyday no matter how much you love it" or "well you do love both of your parents equaly" kind of arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="33912798311.0" user="Sagasujin" delta="True">
    <text>Hi, I'm poly and I barely have an ability to feel jealousy. I can seriously count on my fingers the number of times in my life that I've felt jealousy as an emotion. It's not just in romantic relationships, I just don't get jealous easily. I seriously feel happy when my partners have a great time with someone else. It doesn't mean that I don't care. It means that I barely have the capacity to feel jealous.

I know a good number of people in the poly community that are similar to me and almost never get jealous. Some of them have never felt jealousy in their lives, some just have very few triggers. We're not a huge portion of the human population but we do exist.

Not everyone is meant to be poly. There are absolutely people who work better with monogamous relationships. It's not a flaw, just a different way of doing relationships.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912860272.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="False">
    <text>Ok my view is changed. No joke. I had some bad experiences where i was being set up to be in a poly relationship and it felt awful. I hated the way she was trying to make me "overcome my jealousy" and made me feel guilty if i tried to resist. She was kinda abusive too tbh.
I think that only scenario where i could be in  poly relationship is if i didn't care at all for my partners. And that wouldnt last for long for obvious reasons,
but i guess that, as you said, it's not for everyone.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912897144.0" user="EpicWordsmith123" delta="False">
    <text>If your view is changed, you should award them a delta.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="33912926280.0" user="AndrewBlue3" delta="True">
    <text>How do i do that? I'm new on this thread.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
