<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187266226.0" user="Independent_Coat" delta="False">
    <text>2018 Election Results:

Senate: R gain 2 seats

House: D gain 41 seats

Gubernatorial: D gain 7 Governors

Your premise is proven false: "The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187320487.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I get what your saying, and I believe that it was despite the democrates, it should have been a rouse divisvly taken both the house and the senate. 

I write this because I believe the door has been open for a second term of trump, and that both horrifies and  sickens me. 

Are you telling me that Biden is going to route the Worst President in US history?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187325687.0" user="Independent_Coat" delta="False">
    <text>I'm telling you that the claim that Democrats can't win elections is patently false</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187508422.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Great, then you feel confident Biden will cake walk over trump into the presidency?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187539893.0" user="Independent_Coat" delta="False">
    <text>I feel that the premise of your argument is unsound, therefore rendering the whole argument unsound.

I honestly don't see what my opinions on a potential Biden victory and margin of it have to do with the logical quality of your argument. No matter what I say, it couldn't possibly prove that Democrats are really bad at winning elections. 

The most recent election results prove your premise wrong. That's all I'm saying. It's very straightforward. I'm specifically challenging the soundness of your premise, and nothing more. And saying they should have dominated more is just moving the goalposts. Either give me a delta or explain why you're deflecting like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187634042.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>In 2010 with a popular president, the republicans won 63 seats. Mid term elections always swing. In 2018 the Democrats won 42 seats with a wildly unpopular president and did not take controls of the senate as expected. 

Hillary should have won against trump and that was a direct failing of the Democratic Party that’s as a bust from day one when they decided not to have real primary’s until Bernie spoiled their plans. 

When they did, they actively worked against their own party I order to put Bernie out. If they would have either forced him out form back rooms or let him win or lose, we wouldn’t have been I. The position then where people were vocally not voting in protest. This has also carried over to today’s political  debacle of the Democrats putting up one of the only people that could lose to trump. 

On the face of it, you can quote a few stats that back it up, but every election for the Democrats has under pro formed since 2008. I will give sources when I am not on my phone, but to believe Winnie battles and losing wars is winning, you are mistaken.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187704827.0" user="Independent_Coat" delta="True">
    <text>Thank you, I appreciate the thorough response. You make good points, but I suppose I'm caught up on the strength of the statement. 

"Really bad"

The Hillary debacle certainly fits under this, but other than that, I would say the parties are just about even. Even if Republicans outperform Democrats over whatever timespan and in whatever circumstances, it'd still take more than that for me personally say "really bad."

I guess it's just a matter of semantics at this point. I think "come on, it's not that bad." But if you're comfortable stating it so strongly from your perspective, that's cool.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
