<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="989224860.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/gcyisc/cmv_the_democratic_party_is_really_bad_at_winning/">
    <title>CMV; The Democratic Party is really bad at winning elections and it is hurting the nation (USA)</title>
    <original_poster>FeistyCount</original_poster>
    <original_post>   Edit ; thanks for the discussion. I cannot say my mind was changed, but maybe my initial stance was misleading. 




Full disclosure, I am a republican that has been part of the machine. I have known and exploited the weaknesses of the Democratic Party. I have left the active party since the rise of the tea party fractions. 

I am also repulsed by our current administration, and think Mitch McConnell is probably going to be the most harmful politician in ages. I depend on strong opposition to keep a balanced and fair society. 

That being said, Democrats have lost the ability to win elections. They are fractioned and turn on themselves. In the Republican Party, they are the best way to galvanize a vote. Call my party names and we vote. Republicans call Democrat’s names and they stay home on November 5th in protest. None of this is a secret. We are taught it in winning elections 101. 

Demócratas don’t vote and the party can’t get them to vote. Everyone says money is what is changing politics ( and it is), but no politician is ever going to listen to a non voting blocks concern. I know that voter suppression is a problem, but honestly it is a fringe percentage. Gerrymandering? Democrat’s benefit from it as well. 

In the end, no mater how much outside pressures from money, influence, or bad laws, a large turnout will win on either side always, and the Democratic Party has forgotten how to do that.

It is hurting the nation because losing is causing moderates forced out of the Republican Party doesn’t have to try to capture the middle.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34187191882.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>CMV: there was no point to this post.

Edit: Democrats clearly can and have won elections. Obama, anyone? Also, democratic mayors and governors exist, not to mention members of both chambers of Congress. To say Democrat’s are incapable of winning is false. 

It may be harder for them to win, but I would reply that is due to a number of factors including gerrymandering, poor education (about the party’s actual platforms/goals), and outright stupidity. Plenty of people, even before the current administration, would refuse to Chang their views despite overwhelming evidence poured into their lap.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187229820.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>The point is this is my view, and I would like someone to tell me why I’m wrong.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187250635.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>No one will. I don’t believe you’ve left the GOP, or anything else in this post. Thus, there was no point.

Many/most in the current incarnation of the GOP have problems with lies. Be it Trump, Paul, McConnell, Graham, the list goes on and on. Your post seems not full of lies, but not completely truthful at the same time. Democrats DO win elections, they just didn’t win the last presidential election, regrettably. Turnout does matter, Democrats did have that by about three million is memory serves me. However, that’s not how presidential elections work, is it? The good ole’ Electoral College defied the will of the people and gave us Trump, again to all of our detriment. Republicans are best at one thing, misdirection.

Edit: removal/additions</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187272091.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I didn’t leave the GOP. I left the machine.  Not looking for a fight per se. I want to know how people think elections work. 
When I was getting people elected, we had a 40-20-40 rule. This was local and the numbers are different elsewhere. 40 was a solid base that would vote for the party. 11% out of the middle was all that was required to win. 

I see tons of anti centrist and no body but Bernie out there and I want to under stand.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187378451.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>Why this sub and not r/askreddit? Seems the better place to see if people know/understand how elections work and how to elect their chosen candidate. This method seems rather confrontational.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187415852.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Fair enough, but I know people don’t understand politics, and I’m trying to get a few facts to figure out why. 

I’m not trolling and I think you can see that by my responses. If people are here for deltas, I will hand them out to anyone who can tell me why they think the disaster of the Debbie Shultz Wasserman has changed for the better. 

Winning elections is about winning, not ideals. As I have stated, I am seeing a repeat of 2012 with Hillary and I want to know what I’m missing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187703577.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>What does one do with the win without ideals? Winning for the sake of winning doesn’t do any good for the populace, see present situation for proof. Speaking of, you place no stock in backlash from the terrible federal response to the pandemic, especially in the 65+ demographic which leans more conservative?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34187806877.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>I agree 100%. 
I am embarrassed by the federal response and the backlash. To tell you the truth though, even though I think it was handled badly, i don’t think many politicians are going to come out of this looking good. 

I fight hypocrisy. It is amazes me how when I talk to people, they will diatribe about an issue, and know surprisingly a lot about it, and then tell me they are going to vote for a politician that is going to make it worse. How republicans became the party of god and democrats became the party of morals I will never understand. I thought they were the same. 

I think you have me confused with these people. It isn’t really that hard to understand right from wrong. I will debate about federal  spending and social programs and agree as well as disagree with you. But this world has no moral leadership right now, be it a democrat or republican. 

My point here was to find an answer I was missing and maybe I stated my CMV not clear enough, but there is clearly a gap of understanding of how politics work, and I believe the Democrats are too kind to win.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188008196.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>I may have misunderstood from the beginning, but here we both are. 

I do have you lumped in with “those people” as I don’t believe there are true fiscal conservatives left. They’re all dead. The cult of Trump has taken over, it began with the tea party and this is, I hope, it’s final form. Hypocrites are all that remain in the GOP. Does no one remember “Obama’s death panels”? Now it’s “sacrifice the old and sick to save the economy.” “Obama’s gonna take our guns!” was rumored for the entirety of his presidency, but nobody batted an eyelash when Trump suggested extrajudicially taking people’s guns. 
Socialism for corporations, but not for the people. McConnell’s comments about bankruptcy, when he must know his red KY depends on blue CA and NY for funds.   Kindness isn’t something to be scorned, on the contrary it should be lauded. Cpt. Tom in the UK is a recent example. I’m not trying to say he deserves to be an elected official. However, we clearly need people at the top who are looking out for us as a whole and not just for themselves and their own self interests. That’s what leads to bread riots and the like.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188137996.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>It is a party emboldened with itself. That is my hope of its internal civil war. My post here it that it won’t come from a strong Democrat. 

You don’t know who I am, so that’s ok. I’m hoping civil conversations one at a time will bring us back to any conversations. 

I do think, however, you do yourself a dis service by thinking the vocal minority of the republicans represents all Republicans. I will not be a Democrat  and I am disgusted by my leadership, so what am I to do. Leaving just makes them more concentrated. 

I said this before, a strong Democratic Party makes it easier for us to bring about change, because it takes nonsense things like opposing gay marriage and legalizing drugs off the table, then we can weed out the people who are truly in it for the hate. 

History will not be kind to McConnell and his leadership I believe. 

Honestly, I don’t understand the hate coming from the Republican Party. If anything, I should be worrying about Marxism, but somehow my party is busy with Karen’s and people carrying guns to a rally so they can get their hair cut?  It is a common trick that has been used for centuries to trick people, but the rate they are falling it befuddles me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188265150.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t understand how you can be truly disgusted and not change party. Let them concentrate. As the more concentrated they grow, the smaller they shrink. Small parties become fringe parties and fringe parties die (hopefully). Just ask the Whigs, or the Federalists. You don’t think Pelosi, Schiff, Waters, etc are representing a strong leadership cadre for the Democrats? I’m not saying I want any to be president, but they have all been crucial to holding the line against Trump and his sycophants. 

Also, Marxism? That’s one hell of a leap. Is that supposed to be some sort of trigger? Or do you honestly think the gov’t is suddenly going to seize the all of the means of production and there will be a proletariat revolution? We have nothing left to lose but our chains, Comrade!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188470784.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Again,  i am a fiscal conservative social liberal republican, what they like to call a Rhino.  It in not a Democrat even though I still vote for Democrats in general elections, I’m still able to vote for more liberal republicans in party elections, including for local party offices. 

 I do not think any of those mentioned are unifying leaders. They haven’t shown it so far. 

The Marxism remark was that I’m surprised that the people protesting getting their hair cuts are not protesting the wealth gap. This is the trick my party is pulling right now.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188529659.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="False">
    <text>You refer to it as your party and yet claim to vote for Democrats. This doesn’t add to credibility. LBJ hit the nail on the head many years ago with his remark about poor whites and the Republican Party. It’s proven over and over. People happily vote against their own self interest in order to keep those they see as less than from winning, to borrow a phrase. Disinformation and other dirty tricks straight of the ole’ GOP handbook, but you should know. You were inside “the machine” correct?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34188753538.0" user="FeistyCount" delta="False">
    <text>Sometimes we vote for party loyalty and have to swallow it, but the voting both curtains are closed, and country before party. 

LBJ was a hell of a politician. 

Tricks are not a GOP handbook, they are political handbook, and more for national. 

My elections were always local politics, and I always new the opposition party.  After the election we would literally bury the hatchet. These people are people I would go to happy hour with.  Or agreeing with people and seeing them as the enemy is more a recent invention, IMHO.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34189095926.0" user="Snowsteak" delta="True">
    <text>I agree viewing the opposition as a literal enemy is a recent development. There is no need for as much animosity as exists, in most cases. Some, I think are deserving of all the derision and scorn that can be heaped upon them and more. 
I’m not naive enough to think any politician is completely clean, but also not naive enough to believe that the GOP isn’t the dirtier of the two. 

Party loyalty is what got us to where we are in part, no? Towing the line instead of the voting our conscious or voting based qualifications has allowed fools into the highest sectors of gov’t. How many voters hit straight ticket without looking at any or even half of the names on the ballot? Ignorance is part of the problem, but also apathy. Apathy towards our fellow man. A “fuck you, I got mine” attitude so to speak. 

Perhaps party loyalty should be replaced by loyalty not just to county as an abstract concept, but loyalty to one another. That we can trust we as a group have have our collective best interest at heart. I’m reminded of a quote, I don’t remember the origin, but: “If you want to go fast, go alone. If you want to go far, go together.” (I’m really nervous I picked this up from some dumb movie, but it fits.)</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
