<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="99290486.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1n4512/i_believe_that_if_washington_can_have_the/">
    <title>I believe that if Washington can have the Redskins, I can have a team called the Black People. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>terb99</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel that many people would be offended if a city had a sports team that was called the [insert city] Black People, or even The Blacks, with their logo being a black man's head. However, people (for the most part) accept the fact that the Washington Redskins have all of those same elements, except with a Native American.

 I know that in the past, and perhaps even currently, there has been a movement to get these Native American team names changed, but as we know, mostly nothing has come of this. I feel like if I made a team whose mascot was a black man, that team would receive such outrage that it would never survive. But if the Redskins can exist, the Black People should also be able to exist. CMV.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="26872528725.0" user="fryguy101" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not sure what you're view is... but a team called the "Black People" certainly has the RIGHT to exist.

Just like the [Fighting Whities](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fighting_Whites), the [Fighting Irish](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Notre_Dame_Fighting_Irish), and the [Vikings](http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Minnesota_Vikings).

Of course, what riles people is that "Redskins" is now perceived as a slur (it hasn't always been looked at as such), and therefore they find the name offensive. Meanwhile, teams like the Florida State Seminoles, Kansas City Chiefs and the Cleveland Indians avoid this controversy because their names are simply descriptors for a group of people, without being seen as a slur against a group of people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872724793.0" user="Fire42uck" delta="False">
    <text>In the case of the Irish and the Vikings, those are *actual peoples*, though I'm not sure how (or if) they react to the teams. For Notre Dame specifically, I'm sure there were plenty of Irish people willing to endorse the name, and are proud of its history. 

For the Fighting Whities, well... Look. I'm fairly certain the people who came up with that were white, as was most of the team. The point is, this group gets to choose how to represent themselves: they chose a man in a nice suit with a slick haircut. They didn't choose "white trash," a hillbilly, or a fat guy holding a beer. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872922624.0" user="UncleMeat" delta="False">
    <text>The redskins were named after a famous coach of theirs who was American Indian. It isn't just like a bunch of white people plucked the name out of thin air.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26872965491.0" user="Fire42uck" delta="False">
    <text>That's interesting, I didn't know that. Now, the questions become: 

How did the coach react to being called "redskin?" I'm gonna assume he was alright with it, but I have no way of knowing.

And is this one person an acceptable representative of the Native American population of the US as a whole? Because the term redskin applies to any Native American, not a particular people. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="26873158216.0" user="noziky" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; How did the coach react to being called "redskin?" I'm gonna assume he was alright with it, but I have no way of knowing.

I think you can make a good case that he alright with it and that it wasn't a slur in the 1930's when the team was named. Most obviously, that the team was renamed after he was hired and brought several Indian players to play on the team and he kept coaching. Usually you don't rename a team to insult the coach and not have him quit. See http://tombenjey.com/2013/05/06/redskins-named-in-dietzs-honor/

[By far the best paper on the beginnings of the word](http://anthropology.si.edu/goddard/redskin.pdf) makes a compelling case that it's a term that originated with American Indians. (Also, FWIW, American Indian is the preferred term, not Native American.)

Obviously, this is only anecdotal evidence, but ever example I have ever heard of it being used as a slur comes from after WW2. The earliest are usually being in the 60's at the re-education schools that were used to try to eliminate Indian culture and heritage.

There are also some other examples that indicate the word didn't become a slur until after WW2. For example, this NY Times article from 1912 uses in a headline in reference to Jim Thorpe. http://select.nytimes.com/gst/abstract.html?res=F60C12FC3B5E13738DDDA10A94DC405B828DF1D3. I find it doubtful the NYT would use a racial slur in a headline like that.

You can even find a reference in this 1975 biography of Thorpe to the "noblest redskin" http://books.google.com/books?id=rDV1jOx2P3cC&amp;amp;lpg=PA127&amp;amp;ots=kJ2Qm93PSc&amp;amp;dq=jim%20thorpe%20%22noblest%20redskin%22&amp;amp;pg=PR4#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=jim%20thorpe%20%22noblest%20redskin%22&amp;amp;f=false

The term is clearly supposed to be a compliment. I think the "noblest" adjective is quite racist because of it's use in terms like the "noble savage", but I don't think you can make a similar argument for redskin.

</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
