<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1062071645.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hkbvq5/cmv_youtube_was_right_in_agerestricting_prager_us/">
    <title>CMV: YouTube was right in age-restricting Prager U's videos because a significant portion of their audience were children that didn't know better.</title>
    <original_poster>AneurysmicKidney</original_poster>
    <original_post>TL:DR: &amp;gt;!PragerU was targeting a young audience that didn't understand what they were watching, and YouTube was right in age restricting PragerU's videos.!&amp;lt;

PragerU, a far right-wing media outlet popular on YouTube had it's videos age-restricted by YouTube so that only users &amp;gt;15 years old could watch them.

PragerU claimed that YouTube was censoring them and responded by suing YouTube on the grounds that they were behaving like a publisher while enjoying the protections of a platform.

(The following story should is and should be treated as an anecdote. Because the demographic data of PragerU's viewer base is not public information, this is all I have to go on.)

When I was younger (~9) I came across a video titled "[The] War on Boys". Being a boy myself, I had clicked on the video because of the title and the cartoonish graphics in the thumbnail. Being just over five minutes long, it was perfect for my young, short, attention span.

I have since forgotten the content of the video, but because videos from the same channel as the one you're currently watching are more likely to get suggested, I clicked on a few more blue-background cartoons.

I remember seeing Ben Shapiro, and through the next 3 years I would think of him as some sort of Genius who was always right, because of his childish argument strategies and constant insulting.

I have since disengrained the bullshit that PragerU puts out from my head, but I believe that they were targeting a younger audience with their cartoon drawings, short videos, and simple arguments.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34633383911.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I believe that they were targeting a younger audience with their cartoon drawings, short videos, and simple arguments.

Is it possible they were just targeting a dumb adult audience? This is Prager U we're talking about, their broadest audience is dumb people. And Ben Shapiro is a great example of this, since he's upheld as some kind of prophet by dumb people of all ages, not just children. People have begun to realise he's terrible recently, but for a long time he was viewed as a paragon of right-wing virtue by young and old alike. 

And the trouble with Youtube's decision here is that it's too selective. PragerU is just one element of the global effort to target very young children online. The right wing and left wing both do it in droves, as do groups like the incels. Age-restricting only one channel in this manner (and not even the entire channel, just a tiny portion of their videos) doesn't actually have anything to do with protecting young children from radicalising propaganda when there are the other 900+ videos of Prager U and the countless videos of other propaganda channels to choose from, especially considering that the Youtube algorithm already promotes these channels to anyone, regardless of age, that even accidentally watches something right wing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34633644327.0" user="PM_me_Henrika" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;he was viewed as a paragon of right-wing virtue by young and old alike.

I mean, he *is* a paragon if you compare him to other right wing public figures with the same publicity. He might not be the brightest, but in comparison to others.....at least he is not batshit insane.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34633675800.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>I mean he's either batshit insane or he's lying (i suspect the latter) but if a paragon of virtue is someone who doesn't even agree with those virtues and is just using people's dumbness to make money, that's not exactly a great look. If you look at his argumentative technique for example, it's that which a child would employ - which is why people are beginning to realise he sucks. It's going to be interesting to see where he goes from here though, whether he'll double down until he fades into irrelevancy, change his persona to be more mature at the cost of alienating a significant chunk of his audience, or stop lying and switch to selling himself as "the hyper-conservative who realised he was wrong".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34633684612.0" user="PM_me_Henrika" delta="False">
    <text>He’s a bit crazy, but he’s the *least* batshit insane by far. That just does about shows how far gone the entire paragon spectrum has already went to.

He still sucks.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34637058067.0" user="dtr1984" delta="False">
    <text>Ben Shapiro is one of most intelligent political commentators on either side of the aisle and mopped the floor with Cenk when they debated.

The fact that you have that much hatred for him tells me you’ve never actually listened to him and are just parroting what far left media outlets say.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34638669422.0" user="SoySauceSHA" delta="False">
    <text>He's really not, he just has a good debate strategy, his actual ideas are vague. Look at what happened when he got destroyed on BBC.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34639778731.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>Honestly on a professional debate standard Shapiro isn't even good. It's really good for when you're Ben Shapiro and you need to mask the fact you're arguing from indefensible positions, but it's vulnerable in that the goal is basically to rile the opponent up. If the opponent doesn't get riled up, it backfires, which is why Shapiro lost the BBC debate: He couldn't rile his opponent up, which exposed the nonsense he was spewing for what it was, and made him get riled up instead.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34639959978.0" user="dtr1984" delta="False">
    <text>Um, no.

Shapiro lost the BBC debate  because he argued with a conservative who was more informed on a specific subject and admittedly didn't prepare.

&amp;gt;you need to mask the fact you're arguing from indefensible positions,

[CITATION NEEDED\]

Shapiro is hands down one of the best debaters and one of the better intellectuals of our time. Even many liberals give him due credit on this.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34639995853.0" user="Nephisimian" delta="False">
    <text>You know as well as I do that many liberals are dumb. Shapiro is very good at looking like an intellectual to idiots. To anyone trained in proper debate technique, Shapiro is a moron. Most importantly is that Shapiro never actually changes anyone's minds, particularly not those of his opponents. His job is to rile up the crowd, to make conservatives feel like they're right, and he's very good at doing that, until he ends up facing an opponent that is experienced enough in Shapiro's way of doing things that they can shut him down.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34641475144.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>[removed]</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34645875201.0" user="ihatedogs2" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry, u/dtr1984 – your comment has been removed for breaking Rule 3: 

&amp;gt; **Refrain from accusing OP or anyone else of being unwilling to change their view, or of arguing in bad faith**. Ask clarifying questions instead (see: socratic method). If you think they are still exhibiting poor behaviour, please message us. [See the wiki page for more information](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules#wiki_rule_3).  

If you would like to appeal, review our appeals process [here](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards#wiki_appeal_process), then [message the moderators by clicking this link](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=%2Fr%2Fchangemyview&amp;amp;subject=Rule+3+Appeal+dtr1984&amp;amp;message=dtr1984+would+like+to+appeal+the+removal+of+[his/her+post](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/comments/hkbvq5/-/fwwn1ag/\)+because...) within one week of this notice being posted. Please note that multiple violations will lead to a ban, as explained in our [moderation standards](https://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/modstandards).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34639953332.0" user="dtr1984" delta="False">
    <text>He got destroyed on the BBC because he argued with a conservative who was more informed on a specific subject and admittedly didn't prepare. He's still undefeated against liberals.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
