<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34720709393.0" user="jakezillaface" delta="False">
    <text>Remember that weight is determined by genetics as well as the environment. Obviously I wouldn't tell someone they're amazing simply for being fat, but discriminating against them because of their weight is wrong, as you can't change what genetics you get.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720907816.0" user="applesaucehums" delta="False">
    <text>There are only a few very rare instances where obese people are fat, only because of their genetics. Being overweight is not permanent, unless you're lazy or you eat poorly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720935123.0" user="Awkward-Office" delta="False">
    <text>I’d go as far as saying no one is overweight because of genetics. There is not one body on this planet that wouldn’t lose weight if calories were lowered</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34720958778.0" user="jakezillaface" delta="False">
    <text>Sure this is a good point although you need to remember that although obesity caused solely by genetics does not show the bigger picture. The reality is that the two factors combine to impact obesity. For some with better genetics its easier/harder than others. This journal shows its a combination of the environment and genetics: https://doi.org/10.1038/sj.ijo.0802808</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724046883.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>Some people are born tall and can play basketball and some people are short and it s harder for them but if they work hard enough they can still go pro. Nobody is guilty for his state, but everyone is responsible to make it better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34725977430.0" user="jakezillaface" delta="False">
    <text>Of course, they can but remember: This is the exception. In the 2017-2018 NBA season, the average basketball player was 6’7″ tall (200.4cm) which is almost 10 inches taller than the average American male (5’9 1/2″)! (https://www.thehoopsgeek.com/average-nba-height/) Sure you can find your exceptions but let's not act like its the norm. Of course, all humans should strive for self-improvement, but acting like this is possible (or at least easy to the same extent) for all people is ridiculous.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34726040078.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>Aren't behavioural changes the easiest way of self improvement ? We also talk about an action in exces, so there is no real reason you can't improve this behaviour. The truth is that the biggest reason people are fat is because they had an enabler that allowed them to become like this. Being fat is the product of good life conditions,not bad. It's not like being poor so you can't afford to go to the university, it's like being rich but not wanting to study even if your parents paid for uni.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34726121634.0" user="jakezillaface" delta="True">
    <text>I don't know where you are getting this information from: "Being fat is the product of good life conditions, not bad."
According to https://www.cdc.gov/mmwr/volumes/66/wr/mm6650a1.htm
(In the US): The prevalence of obesity decreased with increasing income in women (from 45.2% to 29.7%), but there was no difference in obesity prevalence between the lowest (31.5%) and highest (32.6%) income groups among men.

What you need to remember is that in today's world healthy food is often more expensive than unhealthy food. McDonalds and Burger King are cheap, poor people will often eat this in replacement of real food. You can argue there is either no association, or a negative association between income and obesity, but arguing a positive correlation between obesity and income in the developed world seems absurd.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
