<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="5" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34721071588.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Being fat in and of itself does not shorten your lifespan, a poor diet over time does. You can get fat by eating too much of a healthy diet during a couple years of your life, calories are calories. If you don’t continue to gain weight and your diet doesn’t get worse, then your health isn’t at risk. 

I recommend looking into the Chinese and Korean food cultures. They don’t have the same stigma around being fat that Americans do, because their diets are in general much healthier and therefore being fat isn’t as much of a health risk. It’s even expected that you’ll gain some weight as you get older.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724035108.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>Fat equals to chronic inflamation of the body , which is a state where Aterosclerosis and insulin resistance build , which are dead. 
Also studies show a direct corelation between the fat% in the body and aging</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724282642.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.healthline.com/health-news/is-there-such-a-thing-as-healthy-obesity#6

This is a good resource with multiple perspectives. The basic medical consensus is that obese people in general are at a higher risk for several diseases, but that there are several mitigating factors obese people can incorporate into their lives other than weight loss that will nullify these risks. 

So basically, the *trend* of obese people being more unhealthy is true. But this doesn’t have much bearing on the health of any one obese person as an individual, they still need to be evaluated on their own. 

The stigma around obesity also leads obese people to prioritize weight loss over other types of healthcare, which isn’t always the best thing for their health. Especially since there are unhealthy ways to lose weight (eating disorders, drug use, excessive cardio, etc.)

This is also beside the point, but if someone wants to be fat, why the hell shouldn’t we let them be fat? Eating a lot of food is fucking awesome. Life is short and it’s one of the few objective pleasures we have. It’s their body and their choice. If we’re not their doctor, I have no idea why we’re making it our business, *especially* since high weight doesn’t *always* mean poor health.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724301704.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>I understand the first part of the post, and let's say I agree with you in a certain sense.
The second part tho : 
If someone wants to do drugs why shouldn't we let them do drugs ? It s a short life and is one of the greatest pleasures one can have. It's their body and their choice.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724476497.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Depending on the drug, yes. I see no issue with civilian use of Marijuana or LSD. As for other, more dangerous drugs, I don’t believe there’s a valid equivalence between meth or heroin use and overeating. We *all* overeat occasionally, and (obviously) we all eat. The problem with drugs like meth or heroin is that they literally alter your brain chemistry, making it impossible for you to feel happiness or be sane without the use of that drug. Quitting these drugs cold turkey can kill you. They’re substantially more dangerous than any level of food consumption can be, so I just don’t think the equivalence is valid. If food had the ability to do the same thing, I would be against overeating. 

I am interested to hear why you agree with my first point, though, as I believe it’s more directly tied to the point OP is making.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724506190.0" user="heathcliph24" delta="False">
    <text>Because after reading what you send me I understood what your "fat =\\= unhealthy" meant. Even so, I partly agree because I know the effects of long term obesity of the body. But for you to understand my point of view, I'd like to add that based on the same considerent I'd also pick on smokers and chronic alcohol consumption.   
We took out substances with a very very very small procentage from foods because they "might" cause cancer. But we don't ban and act of already proven harmfull behaviour</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
