<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1075040167.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/hs1uav/cmv_obese_people_shouldnt_be_appraised_for_their/">
    <title>CMV: Obese people shouldnt be appraised for their size.</title>
    <original_poster>Livves25</original_poster>
    <original_post>[EDIT- PRAISED NOT APPRAISED] Overweight people shouldn’t be told complements about their weights it’s unhealthy and is making their lifespan shorter, I understand there are some people that can’t help their weight due to conditions but there are some people who don’t try to help themselves but are getting complements, more weight puts for pressure on joints causing conditions like arthritis as well as heart conditions, blood conditions and kidney issues, we shouldn’t be lying to people saying that their body is incredible, they can still be pretty believe me there are many over weight people that look nice but what doesn’t look nice is them being winded after walking up a flight of stairs. Don’t discriminate them but stop complements over unhealthy habits.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34720691382.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>I don't see a lot of obese people being praised for being fat.  For their appearance? Yes. For losing weight? Yes. But outside of fat fetishists, I've never heard people say, "Wow, you're so fat! I love it!"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34722530142.0" user="VantoPDX" delta="False">
    <text>It isn't quite like that though, I get OP point in that people praise some obese people by saying things like "you are beautiful the way you are". Which is a nice thing to say, but it's very possible that it creates an incentive to remain that way.

Just to clarify, been a dick to a fat person is also not ok at all. But be real, it ain't healthy</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34723576713.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Which is a nice thing to say, but it's very possible that it creates an incentive to remain that way.

I don't buy that. Every day people are surrounded by incentives to not be fat. Obesity is considered ugly, it's a trait that is frequently mocked, there are entire industries built around nutrition products and diet pills, the negative health effects are well-known and fat people themselves live with joint pain, fatigue and exhaustion in everday life.

A couple friends who say you are beautiful and would say you are beautiful no matter your size, not because of it, is not an incentive to stay the same weight. People stay fat because they have food addictions, lack the energy and confidence to change their habits, don't know how to start losing weight and won't seek the information out, have tried losing weight and given up and/or have a chronic condition that makes it impossible.

 Of all the incentives to be fat, I don't believe there are social ones. The social stigma far and away outweighs compliments from a select few.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724093949.0" user="VantoPDX" delta="False">
    <text>I'll concede that you are most likely right. Let me ask you then, is there a better way to help people with this issues at an individual level?

I say individual because as a society as a much different conversation, one that deals with food deserts, health education and care, urbanism and mental care. All of which are factors that matter but at the individual level aren't full proof</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34724369568.0" user="Love_Shaq_Baby" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Let me ask you then, is there a better way to help people with this issues at an individual level?

Make weight loss a social activity. If you're dieting, invite others to join you. If you're looking for healthy recipes, talk with someone and see if they would would be interested in trading and trying new foods. If you are going to the gym after work, or are involved in a community sports team, invite them to join you. 

You can't really force someone into losing weight, they have to be willing to do it. Some people won't ever try and there's nothing you can do about it. Some people do want to lose weight, but need a friendly push to get them over that hill. Shame, in my experience, isn't a great motivator.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
