<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1102614149.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i8guit/cmv_i_dont_think_ted_cruz_is_eligible_to_be/">
    <title>CMV: I dont think Ted Cruz is eligible to be president of the United State</title>
    <original_poster>PuckSR</original_poster>
    <original_post>Kamala Harris was recently selected as Biden's running mate, and it re-sparked a common misunderstanding of the Constitution. The definition of "natural born citizen". Clearly, Kamala Harris is eligible.

John McCain, however, was not so clearly a "natural born citizen" as he had been born in the Panama Canal Zone to two US citizens. It was contentious enough of an issue that the Senate passed a resolution saying he was eligible. Specifically, McCain was born to two US citizens who were overseas at the direct orders of the US govt. If McCain was ineligible then every child born to US servicemembers overseas would be ineligible and most people agreed that this was not the founders intent.

However, Rafael "Ted" Cruz was born to an American and a Cuban while they worked in Canada for a private company. If Ted Cruz is eligible to be a US president, then basically anyone who has a claim to citizenship is eligible, even if they have never lived in the United States.

*Example: A young woman is born in China. Her mother is American, her father is Chinese. She lives her entire life in China, but claims dual citizenship for legal purposes. At the age of 42, she decides to move to the United States. She becomes a popular politician and runs for President, only 14 years after being elected to the US House of Representatives.*

Would she be eligible? This seems like the exact scenario the founders were trying to prevent. Someone with loyalties to another country taking the reins of power of the USA.If Ted Cruz is eligible, then this woman would be eligible. At that point, why wouldn't we extend the presidency to citizens like Arnold Schwarzenegger?

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause)

Edit: adjusted for the residency requirement

**For all mentions of the Nationality Act of 1790.**The law, as written in 1790 said the following:

* Only free white males could become citizens
* Provided, that the right of [citizenship](https://immigrationhistory.org/item/1790-nationality-act/#) shall not descend to persons whose fathers have never been resident in the United States

First, we obviously don't still have this law on the books. It was fully and totally cancelled and the phrase about "natural born citizen" was removed. You can't point to a law that is not currently applicable as your definition. They clearly felt the need to define the term, and they later rescinded that definition

Further, I think you could make a strong argument that it only applied to children of the father with that definition. This fits with what I have read of citizenship laws in Europe, which stated that citizenship status descended from the paternal line. (I know this because it was a big controversy when people started raping slaves, as it would make the children citizens and free. Most countries made a law explicitly exempting this rule in the case of slave-master relationships)

**Naturalized vs natural born**

The term naturalized wasn't created until the 1940s, when international travel became much more common. The term presently means "conferred after birth", but that term was not used during prior to that period. In fact, "natural born" was used in the US and the UK to imply a citizen granted citizenship by their birth in the USA.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34903170690.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>The process of gaining citizenship is called naturalization. It seems fairly obvious to me that the term natural born citizen is intended to distinguish those who become citizens by birth from those that become citizens via the naturalization process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903233929.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I have a different interpretation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903414132.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>The term naturalization is not defined in the constitution. Rather, the authority to define it is an enumerated power of congress (Article 1, section 8, clause 4). So when the constitution was originally ratified, the uniform naturalization rule had not yet been established. If congress had opted to grant citizenship at birth based on the principle of jus sanguinis (right of blood) instead of jus solei (right of soil), then your interpretation would be rather strange.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903418904.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>and does any applicable law define "natural born US citizen"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903529360.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>There was the naturalization act of 1790 which, among other things, stated that children born abroad when both parents are U.S. citizens "shall be considered as natural born citizens,". That was passed 2 years after the constitution was ratified and many of the framers were congressmen at that time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903637889.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I believe that law was revoked.

I think the only current guidance is this: [http://web.archive.org/web/20080328220007/http:/travel.state.gov/law/info/info\_609.html](http://web.archive.org/web/20080328220007/http:/travel.state.gov/law/info/info_609.html)

Which agrees with you, but I dont think it is as conclusive as a US law</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903730824.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>You are right. It is no longer applicable. My intent in referring a law that is no longer applicable was to show that literally the first attempt by congress to establish a uniform rule of naturalization explicitly stated that someone born outside the US to parents who are citizens can be considered a natural born citizen. 

Clearly that piece of legislation, which was signed into law by the same guy that presided over the constitutional convention (Washington) does not consider birth on US soil necessary to be considered a natural born citizen. 

The page you linked, as far as I can tell, does not define that distinction. But it also doesn't contradict it. Can you point to the specific point at which congress contradicted that and made birth within the US a necessary component of the designation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903869311.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I dont know that they have contradicted it, but I think it is still open to interpretation</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903953882.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>Congress has the authority to make that interpretation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904223588.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>have they clearly and unequivocally made that interpretation?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904468709.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>[Yes. Its pretty unambiguous](http://rs6.loc.gov/cgi-bin/ampage?collId=llsl&amp;amp;fileName=001/llsl001.db&amp;amp;recNum=227)

[After meeting specified requirements for naturalization], thereupon such person shall be considered as **a Citizen of the United States**.  And the children of such person so naturalized, dwelling within the United States, being under the age of twenty one years at the time of such naturalization, shall also be considered as **citizens of the United States**.  And the children of citizens of the United States that may be born beyond Sea, or out of the limits of the United States, shall be considered as **natural born Citizens**:  Provided, that the right of citizenship shall not descend to persons whose fathers have never been resident in the United States .

So after specifying two situations by which one would become a "citizen of the US", it states specifically that if one is born abroad to parents who are citizens that have been residents of the US, they will be considered "natural born citizens".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904487659.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Unless their father has never been a US resident.  

They are clearly allowing a person born to two US citizens to be a "natural born citizen", but exempting people when one parent is not a citizen</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904551258.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;the children of citizens of the United States that may be born beyond Sea, or out of the limits of the United States, shall be considered as natural born Citizens:

I really don't know how anyone could interpret that in such a way that one must be born in the US to be considered a natural born citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904556996.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>because you are leaving out the next line which exempts certain people from "natural born" status  
  
edit: as an aside, I find this type of stuff infuriating. I work with tradespeople every day. Constantly some jackass will provide me code and completely ignore that the next line is an exemption to the line he is quoting.
You can't just pull a sentence out of context.  
  
Maybe he is even right about the code. Maybe you are right about this citizen thing, but your argument is crap.  
Maybe this is an American thing with evangelical Christians, where they like to quote bible verses out of context. I dont know. But you can't say that the phrase is unequivocal when the next sentence is equivocation.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34904814933.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>This is not out of context... and that next line is not an exemption. It is clarification that one cannot inherit citizenship from parents that were never residents of the US. Otherwise you could have people born citizens of the US even if none of their ancestors had been to the US for infinite generations. (So I was born in the US. Lets say I moved away and had a child with another expat. That child would be a citizen automatically. But that child's children would not be conferred the same unless they established residency in the US at some point. 

Regardless, my only point was that being born outside the US does not necessarily preclude one from qualifying as a natural born citizen. If I had a kid with an American citizen that's lived in the US, that kid would be a natural born citizen. Even if they were born on Mars. 

Thats it. Thats all I'm saying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34905551951.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I fundamentally disagree. If a non-American had a child with an American citizen, I don't consider them to be a naturally-born citizen. I interpret a "natural born citizen" to be one born in US, with exceptions for people on military bases and embassies, which are considered US soil for legal purposes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34905880905.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>You can consider them whatever you want. But unfortunately the founders did not have the foresight to include determination of naturalization status in the enumerated powers of /r/pucksr. That is under the purview of congress. 

If you can show me where congress defined natural born citizen the way you have, then that's how it is. Otherwise, natural born citizen means they were citizen at birth.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906053492.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>So, your interpretation is correct by default?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34906128255.0" user="Trythenewpage" delta="False">
    <text>I provided specific legal justification for my view. I am not a lawyer. So if you were to demonstrate why my interpretation is invalid based on the law, I would take it seriously. And if it held water, I'd accept that. But all you've provided is "I disagree". Which isn't a view that can be meaningfully challenged.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
