<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1102614149.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/i8guit/cmv_i_dont_think_ted_cruz_is_eligible_to_be/">
    <title>CMV: I dont think Ted Cruz is eligible to be president of the United State</title>
    <original_poster>PuckSR</original_poster>
    <original_post>Kamala Harris was recently selected as Biden's running mate, and it re-sparked a common misunderstanding of the Constitution. The definition of "natural born citizen". Clearly, Kamala Harris is eligible.

John McCain, however, was not so clearly a "natural born citizen" as he had been born in the Panama Canal Zone to two US citizens. It was contentious enough of an issue that the Senate passed a resolution saying he was eligible. Specifically, McCain was born to two US citizens who were overseas at the direct orders of the US govt. If McCain was ineligible then every child born to US servicemembers overseas would be ineligible and most people agreed that this was not the founders intent.

However, Rafael "Ted" Cruz was born to an American and a Cuban while they worked in Canada for a private company. If Ted Cruz is eligible to be a US president, then basically anyone who has a claim to citizenship is eligible, even if they have never lived in the United States.

*Example: A young woman is born in China. Her mother is American, her father is Chinese. She lives her entire life in China, but claims dual citizenship for legal purposes. At the age of 42, she decides to move to the United States. She becomes a popular politician and runs for President, only 14 years after being elected to the US House of Representatives.*

Would she be eligible? This seems like the exact scenario the founders were trying to prevent. Someone with loyalties to another country taking the reins of power of the USA.If Ted Cruz is eligible, then this woman would be eligible. At that point, why wouldn't we extend the presidency to citizens like Arnold Schwarzenegger?

[https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause)

Edit: adjusted for the residency requirement

**For all mentions of the Nationality Act of 1790.**The law, as written in 1790 said the following:

* Only free white males could become citizens
* Provided, that the right of [citizenship](https://immigrationhistory.org/item/1790-nationality-act/#) shall not descend to persons whose fathers have never been resident in the United States

First, we obviously don't still have this law on the books. It was fully and totally cancelled and the phrase about "natural born citizen" was removed. You can't point to a law that is not currently applicable as your definition. They clearly felt the need to define the term, and they later rescinded that definition

Further, I think you could make a strong argument that it only applied to children of the father with that definition. This fits with what I have read of citizenship laws in Europe, which stated that citizenship status descended from the paternal line. (I know this because it was a big controversy when people started raping slaves, as it would make the children citizens and free. Most countries made a law explicitly exempting this rule in the case of slave-master relationships)

**Naturalized vs natural born**

The term naturalized wasn't created until the 1940s, when international travel became much more common. The term presently means "conferred after birth", but that term was not used during prior to that period. In fact, "natural born" was used in the US and the UK to imply a citizen granted citizenship by their birth in the USA.

&amp;amp;#x200B;</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="34902841066.0" user="rock-dancer" delta="False">
    <text>IT all depends on how you define natural born citizen. Conventionally, it is that that person has citizenship at the time of birth either by being born on US soil or certain holdings. Alternatively, the citizenship can be bestowed via blood. You cannot be 1/2 a citizen, either you are or are not. Either that citizenship was bestowed at birth or it was not. 

Cruz's father was a citizen, therefore he has citizenship bestowed at birth, thus is a natural born citizen. In the scenario you described, that woman would be eligible. However, its with the caveat that she wins. Even hints of ineligibility bring scandal, it would be very hard for her to take the presidency after living abroad for most of her life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902846835.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Ted's mother. But I get your point.  


But then why was there even a "birther" controversy or a controvery around McCain?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902863719.0" user="rock-dancer" delta="False">
    <text>There was a controversy for two reasons.

1. People are idiots and looking for any reason to discredit political opponents
2. Constitutional eligibility is extremely important and Americans are wary of foreigners.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902879680.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I just dont believe that was the accepted definition of "natural born citizen" prior to Ted Cruz</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902901539.0" user="rock-dancer" delta="False">
    <text>Since googling is easy:  [https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen\_clause#Eligibility\_challenges](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#Eligibility_challenges) 

There is a history of eligibility challenges ranging from immigrantt parents to being born outside the united states. The definitions of natural born citizen are pretty established in that you can be born with citizenship in outside the US as long as one parent is American. I don't understand where you disagree.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902921148.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Which challenge involved being born in a foreign country?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34902934204.0" user="rock-dancer" delta="False">
    <text>See George Romney.

Also, several courts decided in Cruz's favor after lawsuits were filed challenging his eligibility. Most notable was probably: 

&amp;gt; Illinois Board of Elections ruled in Cruz's favor, stating, "The candidate is a natural born citizen by virtue of being born in Canada to his mother who was a U.S. citizen at the time of his birth."[\[201\]](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural-born-citizen_clause#cite_note-202)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903024246.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Neither had a court ruling, as far as I know</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903070626.0" user="rock-dancer" delta="False">
    <text>They were all dismissed or unsuccessful because there was either no standing or the courts declined to hear the case. Essentially the challenges were deemed spurious.

I guess the question is, why do you think he is not a natural born citizen? His mother is pretty clearly a citizen.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903116261.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>I think the term means those born in the USA</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903294770.0" user="AureliasTenant" delta="False">
    <text>Why? Natural born citizen implies that at time of birth, the person was a citizen. This can happen one of two ways: one the child was born in the US = instant citizenship. The child was born to a US citizen = instant citizenship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903367094.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, so by your argument, the woman who had lived the majority of her life in a foreign country would be eligible?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903738006.0" user="AureliasTenant" delta="False">
    <text>Anyone who was born a citizen is eligible. Whether they are electable is a different story.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903864903.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>What if your citizenship is revoked?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903874339.0" user="AureliasTenant" delta="False">
    <text> First of all revocation of US citizenship is absurdly rare, and second of all, that would mean the person is no longer a citizen and therefore ineligible.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903881023.0" user="PuckSR" delta="False">
    <text>Everyone who lived in the Philippines had their citizenship revoked. So not that rare</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="34903954952.0" user="AureliasTenant" delta="True">
    <text>The US has this weird (and in my opinion horrible and racist) thing called US nationals, which applies to people born in unincorporated territories of the United States. The Philippines were an unincorporated territory, so people born in the Philippines during whatever the appropriate dates were US nationals. Filipinos has various ways of becoming US citizens (although these were often restricted by racist policies). When the Philippines became independent, non-citizen US nationality was stripped (meaning citizens kept their citizenship but nationals did not keep their US nationality) There are other unincorporated territories of the US like American Samoa that still have this today. The Philippines were not revoked of full citizenship</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
