<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017664755.0" user="DerekReinbold" delta="False">
    <text>Martin Luther King Jr. wrote that the arc of the moral universe is long but it bends towards justice. I believe that to be true.

Think of the problems of the past and of the present. In America, 150 years ago there was slavery. After that, there was segregation and the conditions of life for black Americans was hardly improved until the 1920s, but it was improved, and it has improved since then and it will continue to improve. The arc is long, yes, but eventually justice is achieved. 

What you have to understand is that in today's society there is so much abundance. New farming techniques and water irrigation make it so we can feed the entire planet and then some. The presence of starvation in poor countries is because we do not yet know how to efficiently allocate resources to prevent that kind of death and suffering. But we are getting closer. By almost any metric, this is the best time in recorded history to be alive. More people are living happy, healthy, long lives than at any other point ever.

Progress cannot be stopped for long. We'll find the technology to decrease our imprint on the global environment at a useful scale. If people seem unwilling to convert to solar energy or wind or whatever else would work towards that today, it is because the technology has not quite caught up to the problem yet. But we have achieved many greater things than creating a more efficient car or a better system of irrigation or of lighting.

As for religious conflict, one reason it may seem so prevalent in the modern era is because it makes for interesting news. News companies know that that kind of issue sells, and they report on it every time. But the conflict today is nowhere near the level it used to be in the time of the crusades, or even in the 1940s. Prosperous countries have progressed a long way on getting rid of racism, and sexism, and religious intolerance. More work needs to be done, and it will, but this is not cause for alarm but rather cause for hope.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017669118.0" user="DerekReinbold" delta="False">
    <text>In fact, cause for hope lies within your own statement:

&amp;gt; We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. 

As few as 70 years ago there were dozens of totalitarian or authoritarian regimes in place. Today there are only a handful, and life in many of them is as good as in the most prosperous nations a few decades past. Consider Italy, Germany, Russia, pretty much all of Africa and South America, and even in the United States, government has become more accountable as a result of history. It doesn't happen fast a lot of the time, but it happens.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017705493.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>Italy and Germany are certainly good cases. But from my understanding although life is relatively good for Russians and Americans, the governments they elected (although essentially have no real control over), are perpetuating the problems of the world. Including building and selling weapons, destroying the environment and destabilizing other nations.

It seems to me life has always been relatively good for a small handful of humanity (in ancient times - greece, rome, parts of china. Then Britain/Spain etc.) And perhaps that handful is increasing over time, but I'm not really convinced of that. Because with all the advancements you pointed out have come nuclear weapons, heavily militarized borders (Pakistan-India for example), guerrilla conflicts and massacres on a scale that never would have been possible before (Africa). My understanding is large parts of the world are still in conflict. It's been decades since World War II and yet the intolerance between east asian countries doesn't seem to have subsided much.

I realize it's unfair to simply point out all the bad things and ignore the good things.
I'm not wholly unconvinced by your argument because you make good points about the long arc of justice and environmental technologies.
But I still see the history of the world as sinusoidal rather than a long arc towards justice. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017715173.0" user="DerekReinbold" delta="False">
    <text>Check out this article: http://io9.com/5920871/how-we-died-200-years-ago-compared-to-how-we-die-today

People live longer today than at any point in the past.

I'll ask one question. Would you feel more secure in your livelihood or quality of living at any time in human history than today? I certainly wouldn't, and I see only greater possibility for this to improve in the future.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017728468.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>Yes but that is because we live in the current garden of Eden of humanity. Although the Greeks certainly didn't live as long as us I can't help but imagine they must have pondered similar things to what I'm pondering now and come up with the answer you've given. Not that it's entirely wrong. But for every non-greek was it true? And what of the 2000 years of human history that followed?

I certainly would not want to live in most of the middle east, or most of africa or south america or south east asia. Would you?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017756476.0" user="mrbroscience" delta="False">
    <text>You can still get access to modern medicine, cars, planes, trains, the internet, netflix etc in all those countries. All of which give you a better life than any king in the world ever from 50 years ago or more. 


There are still very terrible places to be in the world, but there are becoming fewer and fewer all the time. 

And the part about hurting the universe is the most hyperbole statement I've ever seen in my life haha.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017813357.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>Sorry I didn't mean to imply we would literally -hurt- the universe, but just spread our own kind of human destruction into it.

Can you get those services in places like Mongolia or Nigeria? I'm not being facetious, I'm actually curious. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27018164445.0" user="mrbroscience" delta="True">
    <text>If there is anything out in the universe capable of being hurt, we most likely won't find it for so long it isn't worth thinking about at this point. If we can ever make it outside of our solar system. 

Well even considering Mongolia is the least populated place on the planet: Mobile phones are common, with provincial capitals all having 3.5G access. Wireless local loop is another technology that has helped Mongolia increase accessibility to telecommunications and bypass fixed-line infrastructure."

also: "Telecommunications network is improving with international direct dialing available in many areas. A fiber-optic network has been installed that is improving broadband and communication services between major urban centers with multiple companies providing inter-city fiber-optic cable services."

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Telecommunications_in_Mongolia


In regards to Nigeria: "The current estimate lies at about 88 million mobile phones as at October 2011, with most people having more than one cellphone."

As for the health care, mongola isn't great but it is imporving and if you can pay they certainly can provide most anything you need especially if you're a traveler and have an embassy. 

As for nigeria "Health care in Nigeria is influenced by different local and regional factors that impacts the quality or quantity present in one location. Due to the aforementioned, the health care system in Nigeria has shown spatial variation in terms of availability and quality of facilities in relation to need. However, this is largely as a result of the level of state and local government involvement and investment in health care programs and education. Also, the Nigerian ministry of health usually spend about 70% of its budget in urban areas where 30% of the population resides. It is assumed by some scholars that the health care service is inversely related to the need of patients" 

So yea they both can use some work, but they have health care. A lot better than anytime before certainly. Where we used to just let people die and cut their limbs off. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
