<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="113567594.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1vm5be/i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_believe_it_is/">
    <title>I have no faith in humanity and believe it is doomed to destroy itself or bring destruction to the universe. CMV.</title>
    <original_poster>KingofRiders</original_poster>
    <original_post>We have 2000+ years of recorded history to learn from as a species. Every variant of evil is recorded to be learned from: totalitarianism, terrorism, communism, imperialism, witch hunts, library burnings, genocides etc. Records of wars for every different reason (ideological, monetary, expansion.) 

We have seen what happens when the environment is not taken care of (Easter Island) or a species is overhunted (Almost all megafauna, the dodo, bison etc.)

And yet humanity does not change. We continue to build weapons, enforce military service in countries across the globe, use child labor/soldiers, encourage violence, find reasons to separate "us" from "them." Even space is on the verge of being militarized, the one last hope for humanity to not bring it's carnage out into the universe. 

Every religion is intolerant of every other religion. Even Buddhists and Atheists are not exempt from this. All they bring is hatred and intolerance.

And despite overwhelming evidence for anthropogenic climate change, shrinking resources, a limited amount of fresh water etc. There is no change. Nothing is really being fixed. Every day I hear more news that makes me think "what hope is there for humanity?"

Please change my view.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27017706203.0" user="ciggey" delta="False">
    <text>Firstly I would point out that we posses no real threat towards the planet (mentioning the universe is just silly). Anything we throw towards the planet is nothing in comparison to what the planet can throw towards us. If Yellowstone erupted it would be a greater catastrophe towards all species on this earth than what we could ever accomplice. 

And yes, humans do bad things, but that's the price we pay. It's like alcohol. Sure there are abusive drunks, but that is a necessary evil compared to the rest of us who just drink beer and play darts and laugh and tell stories. Genocide, torture and hatred is the price we pay for lovers meeting on bridges, for science and laughing and music and friendship. Why do you think that we'll suddenly become victims of our worst qualities when we haven't done so for the past 250,000 years? The hate of men will pass and dictators will die, and all along we'll continue to be kind and happy and clever. You claiming that nothing ever gets fixed is like someone claiming the same during the dark ages. The fact that the world won't be perfect within your lifetime doesn't mean that we're doomed for all eternity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017722592.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>I am not convinced Yellowstone is worse. The holocene extinction event may end up being bigger than several of the other extinction events, even the K-T boundary that wiped the dinosaurs.
http://www.rewilding.org/thesixthgreatextinction.htm

I am not so much worried about my lifetime, because my lifetime will be a very small fraction of human history. But I worry it really won't get better.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27017760608.0" user="ciggey" delta="False">
    <text>But that is what tends to happen. Without the asteroid that wiped out dinosaurs we wouldn't be here. My point is that life will go on and nature will take it's course. We are no less natural than an asteroid or a disease. The biggest threat we can create is towards our selves. 

Sure we make species go extinct, because given a long enough time span that's what tends to happen. Things like global warming or over fishing are scary because they have the potential to screw humanity, not because they can screw the planet. The life on this planet will be fine, because it has millions of years to adjust, a luxury we don't have. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27019862173.0" user="KingofRiders" delta="False">
    <text>That's certainly true and you raise good points but you don't really question the problem of humanity's almost innate evilness.

As someone who thinks about problems far beyond my capabilities or what's even relevant to me, I always keep in mind that in several trillion^x years the universe will die of heat death. So on a long enough time scale it doesn't matter. But on the short scale it really burdens me to think humanity might be evil.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27019874685.0" user="ciggey" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean by innate evilness? Capacity does not equal reality. The fact that I can use a hammer to smash someones head in doesn't make hammers inherently evil. If evilness was our defining characteristic we wouldn't be here right now, we would be extinct. When you walk down the street at home are you afraid that any passer by is evil and will kill you?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
