<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="115882088.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1wzr6w/i_dont_think_factory_farming_is_anywhere_near_as/">
    <title>I dont think factory farming is anywhere near as sadistic as it is claimed to be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jo9008</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ok let me first say that, yes, the conditions of chickens in battery cages is horrendous and I try to only by free range of cage free.

Moving on, I grew up in a rural area and have seen many chicken houses, dairy farms and cattle ranches. It hurts me to hear people demonize farmer based on information that is clearly biased, extremely exaggerated or down right falsified. 

At all these places the animals seem perfectly content. They all had plenty of room to move around, were kept in optimized climate conditions, had unlimited supply of water and food that is formulated to have all the vitamins and minerals they need and they get regular attention from veterinarians who look for any aberration from perfect health. Stress is very bad for the quality of meat produced so farmers/ranchers have a big incentive to keep these animals as happy and comfortable as possible.

With these ideal conditions they have shown to have lower rates of disease, mortality and pathogens that end up in your meat than free range. A lot of that is because they’re not walking around in their own waste. Disease is also more easily transmitted back and forth with outside critters in free range. 

Antibiotic are a big issue but it's not as straight forward as it's made out to be. The FDA highly regulates the levels that go into animals and animals are regularly tested by vets to make sure they are where they need to be. These animals are not like humans. They can’t tell you they are sick. It may be days before they start showing signs and by then they could have passed it on to the entire flock/herd. It is primarily a preventative measure. Antibiotics used for growth are being phased out. No steroids or hormones are ever given to chickens or pigs. The ones given to cattle have shown not to affect the human physiology or to be in such low levels that it is negligible. (estrogen {ng/500g} in tofu 113,500,000 while in beef 7)

Lastly, for pigs, gestation cages are for their own good. Like many animals, pigs establish a hierarchical social order when mixed together. When sows are in groups, dominant sows tend to act aggressively and can even harm their own babies. They are only kept in these cages for a fraction of their lives until they can be re-integrated.

I realized I made a lot of claims there. I'd be happy to provide citations for any of those as requested.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27039874079.0" user="eblue" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;At all these places the animals seem perfectly content. They all had plenty of room to move around, were kept in optimized climate conditions, had unlimited supply of water and food that is formulated to have all the vitamins and minerals they need and they get regular attention from veterinarians who look for any aberration from perfect health.

Is this your anecdotal characterization of the farms to which you were exposed as a kid, or is it an attempt to characterize "factory farms" generally?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27039934288.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Factory farms in general. I dont have statistics but all the chickens around me seem like they are grown are on mom and pop like farms and then delivered to the company that slaughters them. Maybe I just havent seen a real factory farm but I got the impression that the majority of animals were grown in this manor. Perhaps there are much larger locations but I would need to see evidence that they operate in a different way than these places. I dont see why they would.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27039964100.0" user="kellylizzz" delta="False">
    <text>You have not seen a real factory farm. They have such shit conditions because they want as much product as quickly as possible. These farms are not ones you'd be allowed in.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27039996296.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Have you seen a real factory farm? Do you know there are shitty conditions or are you just assuming? There are a lot of reasons they dont let people in(a lot of them actually do) such as not bringing in more sources of contamination. A lot of activist are also looking for ways to intentionally make farmers look bad. If I was them I wouldnt want people coming in and exploting me like that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040046364.0" user="kellylizzz" delta="False">
    <text>I've not, you're right. But I've seen pictures (though those are mitt unbiased). I'm just saying they're very different from rural area medium sized farms because there's a lot more in the way of livestock and a lot more in the way of cutting corners. This includes not letting the animals move so that they gain weight and can be sold more quickly and feeding them corn instead of their natural foods (causing infections).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040070005.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>So google tells me that 75% of poultry comes from farms with 6 or less houses. Mean while 6.6% come from farms with 13-80 houses. 85% of beef comes from farms with less than 200 cows. 75% of dairy farms have  less than 100 cows. Even if large farms have worse conditions which has yet to be shown to me, it seems like they are a minority in the farming business.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040088376.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>Source?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040095257.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>I dont know about the credibility of these sources they were just the first thing I could find through google. I dont see much motivation for fudging these kinds of stats though.

http://thedairymom.blogspot.com/2012/03/dairy-herd-size-increases-while-number.html
http://www2.ca.uky.edu/poultryprofitability/Production_manual/Chapter2_Broiler_production_facts_and_figures/Chapter2_size.html</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040111048.0" user="[deleted]" delta="True">
    <text>The first link you provided seems to suggest the opposite to me: this statistic alone proves the opposite of what you are claiming "The 16,700 dairy farms with a herd size of 100 or more milk cows produced 86.4% of the U.S. milk." Also "The majority of the dairy farmers *exiting* the industry milk 99 or fewer cows." In other words, small farms are dropping out of the game, at least in the case of dairy cows.

Your second link says "Supported by a grant from the Kentucky Agricultural Development Board" there is your motivation for "fudging these kinds of stats." I'm not saying they were, but you have to take these sorts of things into account when you're evaluating sources. I think you may be reading these tables wrong, at any rate.

Check out [this article](http://eatocracy.cnn.com/2012/07/27/who-are-you-calling-rich-a-small-farmer-shares-some-hard-data/) written by a small family farmer. He states "91 percent of the hog and pig inventory is on farms with 2000 or more hogs and pigs on them, which represent the top 0.5 percent of farms." Just like every other business in the U.S., there are a few companies making the majority of the products and money. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
