<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="115882088.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1wzr6w/i_dont_think_factory_farming_is_anywhere_near_as/">
    <title>I dont think factory farming is anywhere near as sadistic as it is claimed to be. CMV</title>
    <original_poster>jo9008</original_poster>
    <original_post>Ok let me first say that, yes, the conditions of chickens in battery cages is horrendous and I try to only by free range of cage free.

Moving on, I grew up in a rural area and have seen many chicken houses, dairy farms and cattle ranches. It hurts me to hear people demonize farmer based on information that is clearly biased, extremely exaggerated or down right falsified. 

At all these places the animals seem perfectly content. They all had plenty of room to move around, were kept in optimized climate conditions, had unlimited supply of water and food that is formulated to have all the vitamins and minerals they need and they get regular attention from veterinarians who look for any aberration from perfect health. Stress is very bad for the quality of meat produced so farmers/ranchers have a big incentive to keep these animals as happy and comfortable as possible.

With these ideal conditions they have shown to have lower rates of disease, mortality and pathogens that end up in your meat than free range. A lot of that is because they’re not walking around in their own waste. Disease is also more easily transmitted back and forth with outside critters in free range. 

Antibiotic are a big issue but it's not as straight forward as it's made out to be. The FDA highly regulates the levels that go into animals and animals are regularly tested by vets to make sure they are where they need to be. These animals are not like humans. They can’t tell you they are sick. It may be days before they start showing signs and by then they could have passed it on to the entire flock/herd. It is primarily a preventative measure. Antibiotics used for growth are being phased out. No steroids or hormones are ever given to chickens or pigs. The ones given to cattle have shown not to affect the human physiology or to be in such low levels that it is negligible. (estrogen {ng/500g} in tofu 113,500,000 while in beef 7)

Lastly, for pigs, gestation cages are for their own good. Like many animals, pigs establish a hierarchical social order when mixed together. When sows are in groups, dominant sows tend to act aggressively and can even harm their own babies. They are only kept in these cages for a fraction of their lives until they can be re-integrated.

I realized I made a lot of claims there. I'd be happy to provide citations for any of those as requested.
</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27040073646.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>First of all, tofu contains phytoestrogrens, which is chemically similar to estrogen but is not the same thing. [source](http://healthyeating.sfgate.com/eating-soy-increase-estrogen-production-2870.html) They act similar to estrogen but in a weaker form. I'm not sure why you brought that up: as a comparison or to state indirectly that even if one is eating tofu instead of meat they are consuming hormones (even though this is false).

As everyone has already brought up, you obviously don't understand what a factory farm is. I suggest educating yourself with a film like Food, Inc. or Earthlings, which you can watch [here](http://earthlings.com). The latter shows just how widespread cruelty to animals is on factory farms and in other situations where animals and humans interact. Most people who are concerned about animals aren't trying to shut down small, family owned farms or demonize these people. They're trying to expose the horrendous, unnecessary treatment of animals in these huge factory farms. 

These aren't places that care about anything but making as much money as possible, at the expense of animal life and risking the health and safety of their workers and consumers. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040117991.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>Far enough. I'll check those out but I am admittedly skeptical since they obviously have an agenda.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040127580.0" user="[deleted]" delta="False">
    <text>It's good to be skeptical and you should always ask questions and evaluate sources. But I think it's important to examine what motivates others agendas. I personally tend to distrust agendas that are obviously geared toward money, and am more open to trusting agendas that seem to have greater interests at heart such as animal rights or environmental concerns. 

But also ask yourself why you hold your beliefs and what YOUR agenda is. There had to have been a reason that you posted this topic on this thread, either to solidify your own opinion or to learn something new. 

There is nothing inherently wrong with being biased, because everyone is to a certain degree. But it's important to keep your mind open and learn from others so you can find your truth. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040139603.0" user="eblue" delta="False">
    <text>your sources ITT consist of personal anecdotes and  "thedairymom.blogspot.com," so at this point we could cite PETA and our sources would still be more credible</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27040157408.0" user="jo9008" delta="False">
    <text>And I said in the post before that I was just doing a google search to continue the conversation and that I did know how valid it was. The rest of the information from my original post can be cited with legitimate sources if youd like.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
