<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="134214340.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/27wog4/cmv_i_believe_a_sustainable_market_for_video/">
    <title>CMV: I Believe a Sustainable Market for Video Games Oriented Towards Women Exists, and that Feminism Would Be Better Served to Develop For It Than Merely Complain About It</title>
    <original_poster>OhCrapADinosaur</original_poster>
    <original_post>E3 took place the past couple of days, and of the various bits of news from the event, Ubisoft announced their Assassin's Creed title. I'm wholly indifferent to the Assassin's Creed games, but apparently this game features 4 person local multiplayer and only includes a slate of male characters. As a result of this news, some of my feminist former-friends posted articles to this effect: http://www.theverge.com/2014/6/11/5799386/no-female-characters-in-assassins-creed-unity-too-much-work

I'm not going to weigh in on the truth of Ubisoft's claims particularly, whether or not their claims were justified, or whether any of the views held by either side is right and just. The general consensus among the feminism crowd seemed to be along the lines that:

* 1. There are many sexist stereotypes prevalent in video games, possibly moreso in mainstream titles, and particularly noticed (by the feminists) are those stereotypes concerning women.
* 2. There is a large and substantial base of female gamers, many of whom would presumably enjoy games that break stereotypes and employ strong female lead characters
* 3. Many popular games today don't necessarily serve female gamers so well

I'm not going to suggest that feminists shouldn't complain (well, I might a little), but from my vantage point that's pretty much all I see get done. If you actually believe 1, 2, and 3 above, then there might be a GOLDEN MARKET OPPORTUNITY FOR YOU and you should invest your ranting energy into developing for this female gamer market (it's also overwhelmingly likely that this is, in fact, already being done and I'm just not particularly aware of it). Barriers to entry have probably never been lower to go develop for almost any platform you like, and indy games that hit it big have the opportunity to hit it REALLY big. You could make the video game equivalent of "Orange is the New Black" and have millions of loving, adoring fans who will cheer and talk about how you helped bring women into the video game mainstream. And hey, money!

Sadly, this attitude didn't much win over my feminist friends, who more or less told me to shut up and go fuck myself. So... yeah, I fail to see the problem with my thinking. Anybody want to help me out?
__________

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27218389327.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are confusing protests against games that perpetuate sexist stereotypes, a valid complaint, with a desire for games oriented to women.  These are two very different things.  

I am sure there is a market for games oriented to women, but actually this goes against a moderate feminist's principles, what a reasonable feminist is criticizing is that the same games could exist without sexist stereotypes, that's all. This means they are geared to all sorts of people regardless of gender.  Gender should not be an issue unless there is a biological or objective justification: pregnancy, pornography, history, etc.  

I am not defending a stupid person that tells you to shut up and fuck off, this is stupid regardless of what they think, I am just clarifying a confusion I seem to see in your position.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218459385.0" user="Bynnar" delta="False">
    <text>I'm just going to point out how futile this is then. The gaming market is just that, a market. If you don't intend to participate, no developer will likely care for what you have to say. For better or for worse, the only way you're going to change how women are portrayed in video games is to make a market that will listen to women, and that means making games for women.

(Also, I find it a bit on the social control side of things when you barge into a community you aren't apart of and tell them to act a certain way and then leave.)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218471726.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>I think you are mixing two things.  No-one is denying the free-market right to develop and publish the game you want.  The economical argument is sound. 

There is the moral argument of a social damage caused by sexist games.  This is not refuting the economical argument, it's another layer.  

I don't need to be a games developer to criticize games, in the same way I don't have to be a smoker or doctor to criticize smoking ad campaigns.  

&amp;gt; the only way you're going to change how women are portrayed in video games is to make a market that will listen to women, and that means making games for women.  

This is not true, removing sexist stereotypes can appeal to women and men, whereas designing games for women should mostly appeal to women.  
Plus, many women are sexist too, it's not just a male-generated issue, and drawing attention to this is beneficial to all.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218510803.0" user="Bynnar" delta="False">
    <text>Oh, I wasn't trying to make a moral argument either way. I was just saying it isn't going to realistically happen unless they have market influence.

&amp;gt;I don't need to be a games developer to criticize games, in the same way I don't have to be a smoker or doctor to criticize smoking ad campaigns.

The difference between criticizing smoking and criticizing sexualized video game characters is that we already presuppose that video games are a fantasy and are prone to being unrealistic. 

You'd might as well be making the argument that video game violence makes people more violent. What makes sexualized characters different is that it's just distasteful, like video game violence against puppies where market forces indicate that people like violence against puppies. 

And really, I'm not sure you can say these characters do any more damage then the constant sexualization in other parts of culture. Whereas when you consider smoking, it is known to cause bodily harm.

&amp;gt;This is not true, removing sexist stereotypes can appeal to women and men, whereas designing games for women should mostly appeal to women.
Plus, many women are sexist too, it's not just a male-generated issue, and drawing attention to this is beneficial to all.

The thing is though, female gamers are a niche part of the more, dare I say, "hardcore" section of gaming. You have a point in that games can be neutrally appealing, but that really wasn't my point. I was trying to point out that you have to be a market force, spouting off political opinions into a community you aren't apart of will get you nowhere fast. More female-friendly games will come mainly because of female gamers, not because of some feminist campaign against the gaming industry.

To address the second point there though, I am aware women can be sexist, but it isn't like there is abundant female sexists in the gaming community. Now I can say that male characters can be "sexualized" in a way, either as per literally or by simply being unrealistic and therefore perpetuated social ideas of masculine power. However, I don't think many gamers really care about that department and neither do I. It doesn't change the fact that games are fantasy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218526944.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>We agree mostly, so I'll focus where we disagree only.  

&amp;gt; What makes sexualized characters different is that it's just distasteful  

Not really, it makes people used to sexist stereotypes and this has a social impact, that's why it's not being called "distasteful stereotypes" but "perpetuation of sexist stereotypes".  

&amp;gt; spouting off political opinions into a community you aren't apart of will get you nowhere fast  

I think the objective is not to bring down the sexist games, but to point out how these stereotypes come out again and again and make gamers notice them and see how uncreative they are, and this might incrementally persuade gamers to appreciate more sexually neutral stereotypes and thus impact the market in the long run. It's like pointing out how fast food abuse makes children and people fat, the attack is not meant to cause people to go on a diet, but to gradually make it known that weak willpower when eating does not go unnoticed.  

&amp;gt; male characters can be "sexualized" in a way  

Sure, but society still gives males the upper hand, so no damage done, unlike perpetuating sexist stereotypes that are unfair towards women.  It's like having all evil characters have british posh accents, you won't see complaints by the royal family, but if all evil characters were black you'd have an uproar!  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218603468.0" user="Bynnar" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Not really, it makes people used to sexist stereotypes and this has a social impact, that's why it's not being called "distasteful stereotypes" but "perpetuation of sexist stereotypes".

I think you missed my point, which is that games are fantasy. The characters can be just as outlandish as the violence. Effort would be better spent where sexualized women are portrayed to be realistic, like in the beauty industry.

&amp;gt;I think the objective is not to bring down the sexist games, but to point out how these stereotypes come out again and again and make gamers notice them and see how uncreative they are, and this might incrementally persuade gamers to appreciate more sexually neutral stereotypes and thus impact the market in the long run. It's like pointing out how fast food abuse makes children and people fat, the attack is not meant to cause people to go on a diet, but to gradually make it known that weak willpower when eating does not go unnoticed.

I'll be honest, gaming is really lacking in quality characters in general. For every bad sexualized character, there are several bad ones that aren't. Character development is still something game developers need to work on in general. Sexualizing a character is just a way to disguise bad writing, but I don't think you'll find many people championing sexualized characters are good models for character development. If someone does, then certainly the person is just a shallow moron with no concept of story telling.

My biggest point here is when feminists that aren't gamers come into a gaming space, declare that their presence is needed, and presume to be some morally superior authority. Which again, is like going into something like a book writing community and then declaring that they don't have enough books that suit your tastes and that all there other books are hateful toward you. It's invading a community and then trying to demand it conform to your standards.

Again, I have nothing wrong with female gamers esposing their opinions toward the gaming industry. They are legitimately invested. But people like Anita Sarkeesian wouldn't care if the gaming industry collapsed overnight. (Not that the death/rape threats were warranted, the internet is a vile place.)

&amp;gt;Sure, but society still gives males the upper hand, so no damage done, unlike perpetuating sexist stereotypes that are unfair towards women. It's like having all evil characters have british posh accents, you won't see complaints by the royal family, but if all evil characters were black you'd have an uproar!

If you don't think that the over-the-top portrayal of some men in video games is just the same as the women's portrayal or today's fashion models, you're deluding yourself. A six pack on any male character is just as unrealistic as a women's hourglass figure. No one takes the evil British guy's accent seriously, I mean it was practically parodied in Star War: The Old Republic, but our society tends to see men as idealized in tough guy gentleman. Either that, or people wouldn't insist women be treated like princesses, rather than humans, nor would they make the "chivalry is dead" comment sound so negative as it was basically the idea that men should serve women and women let men serve them.  Of course, that is not to say that chivalry was especially liberating for women either.

Let's just put it this way, if you don't think male gender roles do damage, just like female gender roles do, I don't know what to say. Suffice it to say, this doesn't affect my original point about this and that is sane people should be able to realize that character portrayal in video games is far from realistic. And this is why I don't view video games as a problem in the aforementioned problems.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218622557.0" user="beer_demon" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I think you missed my point, which is that games are fantasy.  

I don't think it's relevant.  And example is Pacman vs. Miss Pacman.  Pacman is male by default and adding a ribbon, mole and lipstick makes it female.  This is fantasy (you can't get more unrealistic than a pacman) but it projects what we think women to be which is men with decoration.  This wouldn't be harmful it it wasn't because since we are children we are taught that boys look good as they are, but girls must put stuff on to be feminine.  In a society where males and females used a comparable amount of accessories, makeup and decorations (or both wore non at all), the pacman/ms. pacman stereotyping would be a non issue.  

&amp;gt; My biggest point here is when feminists that aren't gamers come into a gaming space, declare that their presence is needed, and presume to be some morally superior authority  

Let me understand your biggest point then.  
1) What if the feminist criticizing a certain stereotype is a gamer?  What makes a gamer, someone who you judge as caring or just someone who researched into the games only to identify the stereotypes?  
2) What if they are not entering a gaming space but using neutral territory like a newspaper, blog or youtube?  
3) Who is able to claim moral superiority and who isn't, apart from the above criteria?  

&amp;gt; Anita Sarkeesian wouldn't care if the gaming industry collapsed overnight  

What if the points she makes are valid regardless?  (example is the pacman described above)  How is the same point different if a gamer states it, even if male?  
I disapprove of Sarkeesian's monetary interest in her activity, more profit-driven than with a true interest in females and males getting on better, but I do admit she did her homework and has many valid points (and many very bad ones).  If someone is a criminal, liar, thief and dishonest says something true, is it less true now?  

&amp;gt; if you don't think male gender roles do damage, just like female gender roles do, I don't know what to say  

As I said before, it's context.  In a male-dominated society, sexist stereotypes against women are more harmful than sexist stereotypes against males.  If it were a female-dominated society then I am sure the same exact game would have other objections and other impact.  Hence the brits-are-evil analogy.  If the brits were a minority that were oppressed and segregated negatively, the death star accents would be unacceptable.  

&amp;gt; character portrayal in video games is far from realistic  

But has an impact in society.  This doesn't mean every other aspect of sexist stereotyping in publicity, fashion, films, books, etc. is more acceptable, it just means that the gaming industry is not immune from criticism about their sexual stereotypes.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218693525.0" user="Bynnar" delta="False">
    <text>Ok, now I'm starting to feel like I'm moving the goalposts so I'm going try to jump back to my original points.

To affect any change, criticism will need to be levied by people in the market. Outside forces won't change anything, it will just cause a lot of annoying bickering on the internet. I think we agree here, but it's probably the biggest reason to discourage criticism under the banner of "feminism" and instead adopt a banner for female gamers.


My argument in favor of female gamers speaking out specifically and not just any feminist, is almost entirely based on Anita Sarkeesian. This is where I'm trying to draw the line, between the Anita Sarkeesians of the world and female gamers that are distraught with how gaming portrays women. It's more likely to get addressed by the gaming industry and it might actually get support from the community. As unlike having feminism invade a community and force change, you have the community changing itself and really it's just the way I see the issue, as intracommunity.

&amp;gt;As I said before, it's context...

You attitude here sounds to me like a sort of cop out. "Patriarchy, therefore your complaint is invalid." While I would agree if you pointed out that men seem to be perfectly OK with their stereotype, and therefore we should work on women, you instead dismissed the issue out of hand. However, as another redditor pointed out to me, the male portrayal here represents a male power fantasy more than a female sexual fantasy, so I'm just going to drop the point as that is entirely correct as I can see.

&amp;gt;But has an impact in society...

It seems I'm slowing being trapped into defending sexualizing women, and again, that's not something I want to do. I am simply trying to say it's not something that necessarily carries out of video games. A video game may say, "go murder those guys with a shotgun, it's tons of fun" and most of us realize that they would never mean to do so in real life. By the same logic, a video game may say, "look at this woman with a large chest, she's hot" but they don't actually mean real women look like that. If you want to say sexualizing characters is stupid, fine that makes sense, but I don't see how it has any affect outside of video games.

It is not really comparable to a commercial where they portray the women as entirely real. I guess I could see some argument for film since there are games that try to display a narrative, so I think that may be valid, but films tend to be portrayed much more realistically since they don't have silly game mechanics breaking suspension of disbelief.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27218962908.0" user="beer_demon" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Outside forces won't change anything  

I think any criticism if well placed or in large quantity will hit well.  

&amp;gt; discourage criticism under the banner of "feminism" and instead adopt a banner for female gamers  

Thing is, female gamers can be sexist and male feminists can be assertive.  I think we should focus on what points are a contribution to the society we want to build.  Unfortunately for you this includes the assertive points Sarkeesian might make.  Sorry about that.  

&amp;gt; men seem to be perfectly OK with their stereotype, and therefore we should work on women, you instead dismissed the issue out of hand  

I admit a well-based bias here.  Some males are upset about the females expectation  of a sixpack or brave attitude in the same way some females are upset about expectation on large breasts or small waists.  I agree with this.  This is the statement of "gender equality" which we agree on.  

A different issue is feminism.  Feminism is more specific than (and can coexist with) gender equality, it focuses on a subset of this which I would describe as "the component of gender inequality that lessens females or puts them at a disadvantage in an already male dominated society".  

So yes, Conan the Barbarian might make a slightly fat black guy, or a small shy nonviolent caucasian uncomfortable, and this is a victimization by stereotype and I criticize this too.  But this is another topic.  The two victims of Conan's stereotype will still have the social advantage of being male.  

Feminism focuses on how this influences against women's place in society, that's all.  These two focuses are not mutually exclusive, but you and I can both understand that those specializing in the issue with the highest number of victims have a point worth considering.  

With the rest of your points I agree with.  Ads, publicity campaigns and hollywood stereotypes are much more relevant than gaming ones, but this doesn't mean gaming ones are good, it just means that the priorities might lie elsewhere.  The fact heroin and cocaine are very harmful doesn't make smoking healthy or good, we can oppose them all and people focusing on smoking are not wrong only because there exists a greater harm.  I consider myself a feminist only in that I am aware of what trends are harmful for females, admitting that a female in New York has it better in every aspect than a male in Congo, but this doesn't mean you should get away with segregating that female in new york.  It's subtle, I admit, but still worth standing for.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
