<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1409948101.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/nbg2x1/meta_clarifying_our_stance_on_trojan_horse_cmvs/">
    <title>META: Clarifying our stance on "Trojan Horse" CMVs</title>
    <original_poster>Poo-et</original_poster>
    <original_post>There has been uptick somewhat recently of posts where OP makes a claim that they do not believe in order to make a thinly veiled attack on something else entirely. This is usually done to illustrate a double standard they feel a certain group has. We would like to remind all posters of rule B which states *"You must personally hold the view"* and say that going forward we will be removing these posts on sight where they appear.  

These "trojan" posts are not suited to CMV because defeating the claim rarely results in a delta and merely unlocks the real view. There's also a lot of marginal rule 3 content that goes in the comment sections which probably should be avoided. I would advise posters to simply report and move on when you see one of these posts.  

You can talk about double standards in your CMV post, but you must make the positive claim you really believe in as part of that. 

If you have questions or more suggestions for the subreddit, I recommend forwarding them to r/ideasforcmv which the mod team is very active on.  

Thanks for making this place cool.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="36883139733.0" user="chefranden" delta="False">
    <text>While you are at it please make a rule against personal preferences like CMV Red wine is better than white wine or x^1 is the best x ever.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883171664.0" user="ThatIowanGuy" delta="False">
    <text>I still think those would fit because someone could make an objective argument in those situations like The Avengers (2012) is better than Justice League (2017) despite being directed by the same person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883216970.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>How can there be objectivity when using subjective descriptors?

I mean, I could see it being argued one was objectivity more critically acclaimed I guess. But one being objectively *better*? I don't believe that's how objectivity works.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883499322.0" user="ThatIowanGuy" delta="True">
    <text>Because public consensus of a movie is an objective statement compared to personal choice which is subjective. I enjoyed Avengers more than Justice league would be a subjective statement while, if there’s data to show it, more people enjoyed Avengers than Justice league would be an objective statement.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883561124.0" user="dublea" delta="False">
    <text>A consensus of public opinion does not equate to something becoming a fact. 

For instance, if a movie had 90% of reviewers stating it's a good movie, that doesn't mean it's an *objectively good* movie.

Hence, why I could understand stating something is objectively more *critically acclaimed* makes sense. 

It's not conveying or utilizing subjective descriptors to make an objective statement. It's using an objective fact as it is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883607598.0" user="ThatIowanGuy" delta="False">
    <text>Can I give a delta in a meta thread? You got me there. I’m just saying that there still is room for CMVs in the style of X is better than Y because public reception, possibly awards from experts, as well as comparing profits are showing that objective measurements do exist for seemingly subjective topics. Maybe you’re right about stating one as more “critically acclaimed” than the other as opposed to one is “better” than the other.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="36883641552.0" user="dublea" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;Can I give a delta in a meta thread?

*What do you get if you cross an Elephant and a Rhino?* /S

I'm not sure but you're welcome to try.

&amp;gt;I’m just saying that there still is room for CMVs in the style of X is better than Y because public reception, possibly awards from experts, as well as comparing profits are showing that objective measurements do exist for seemingly subjective topics.

That's the crux. I agree but I think posters need to address and acknowledge that it is subjective. Even possibly providing a hint as to what may change their view. For instance, having them consider a different show/movie within the same context they didn't consider. But if they accepted and acknowledged the subjectiveness up front, it would reduce/prevent those posts from devolving into a subjective vs objective conversation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
