<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="144404372.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2dz34k/cmv_the_release_of_the_cctv_footage_of_michael/">
    <title>CMV: The release of the CCTV footage of Michael Brown is not character assassination, but a vital component of the incident that helps all parties understand the context of the shooting and the state of mind of the individuals involved.</title>
    <original_poster>Thorax123</original_poster>
    <original_post>First off, let me clarify, I am not defending the actions of Ferguson Police Officer Darren Wilson. I believe that he did use excessive force and the shooting should be thoroughly investigated. This CMV post is not to debate over whether or not Officer Wilson needs to be tried or whether the Ferguson Police is an example of police militarisation in the US. This post is solely to look at the decision to release the CCTV footage of Michael Brown robbing a convenience store.

Now that that's out of the way, I don't really understand why everyone was so angry at the release of the CCTV footage showing what appears to be Michael Brown robbing a convenience store. I see in multiple news sources where people have stated that the footage "'appeared to cast aspersions' on the dead man" or is a form of character assassination.* 

*http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-us-canada-28827304

Finding out that the shooting victim had just returned from robbing a store is critical information, because it provides context for the fact that a police officer confronted him (over something minor and unrelated like obstructing the street) and a violent altercation took place soon after. I see family members and other people saying that he wasn't "perfect," but it seems to me that they're dismissing the fact that he had just committed a crime.* The police officer may not have known of Michael Brown's actions, but it makes sense that Michael Brown would be more on-edge, scared, and impulsive after committing a crime and encountering a police officer so soon after. Thus, this footage provides a critical perspective into Michael Brown's state of mind and his subsequent mannerisms/behavior might have alerted Officer Wilson and escalated the encounter.

*http://www.latimes.com/nation/nationnow/la-na-nn-fergsuon-shooting-police-name-20140815-story.html#page=1

My view is that the CCTV footage was essential information that needed to be provided to the public. While it may have been misconstrued as character assassination, the footage is an invaluable part of the story that helps explain the context and actions of both Officer Wilson and Michael Brown. 

EDIT: Thank you everyone for your comments! I really appreciate it. My view hasn't really changed and while I still believe the footage to be relevant and needed to be shown to the public, the institution releasing the footage should have been more removed from the situation i.e. not FPD, but the FBI/DoJ/even the Prosecutor's Office. Additionally, the footage should have been released alongside other information which was excluded, providing a lop-sided view of the situation which served to inflame tensions rather than using information to allay them.

Edit: Thanks for the gold, stranger!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27321439000.0" user="inquisitive_idgit" delta="False">
    <text>You absolutely have a point--  the video is an important piece of the puzzle of what happened that day.   To see why people are so upset, you have to look at the timing of the release and you have to look at what they're still not doing. 

The community has a right to see the police report on the shooting, the autopsy report, and to know the shooter's record.   Instead, after all this time, the police have still released none of this information.  

What _DID_ they find time to release?   The one video that makes the victim look bad.   

If the police were releasing all the relevant information, people wouldn't be upset.  Instead, they are holding back all information except the information that protects the shooter.   This destroys any illusions that the local police are working for the victim.   

</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321480709.0" user="itzBACON" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think they can release all the information they have while an investigation is underway. Granted I'm no lawyer or investigator, but I feel that doing so could prove to damage the information or interrupt the investigation somehow. If I'm not mistaken, it's common practice to not release all the information immediately, only after the investigation is complete.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321806125.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>Right, they can't release all the information, but by releasing *any* information, they are prejudicing the jury pool.

There *is* a time for all this sort of thing to come out, and that time is *during a trial.*  The fact that they are releasing information that looks bad for the victim and *not* releasing any information that makes them look bad.  That, itself, looks bad.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321880376.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>There are no FOIA exceptions for not releasing reports about prior bad acts so long as they are not active reports.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321906994.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>Wait... is this a prior bad act, in which case it's unrestricted and should not be released because it is of purely prejudicial nature, or is it related to the case, in which case such rules would apply?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321911727.0" user="DaSilence" delta="False">
    <text>Releasing a report to a party under the Sunshine isn't the equivalent of introducing it at trial.

If there is a trial, it will undoubtedly be introduced. It impeaches witness testimony as well as can be argued to show state of mind of why Mr. Brown acted the way he did.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321926895.0" user="MuaddibMcFly" delta="False">
    <text>But why are they releasing it *now* if not to assassinate his character?  It's not part of an argument and model of why things happened, it's just "see, we were right!" sort of bs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27321932295.0" user="DaSilence" delta="True">
    <text>Because they got a Sunshine request, and those requests have to be acted on within 3 days of service or 3 days of a record being opened.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
