<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="154839924.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/2k6r90/cmv_i_consider_the_nordic_model_the_best/">
    <title>CMV: I consider the Nordic model the best socio-economic model to base a country around &amp;amp; the best compromise between the right and left</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nordic_model  
I believe the free market combined with a social safety net reduces poverty which benefits everyone. High level of education, highly efficient administration effectively invests into the society, providing multiple incentives and angles of growth.  

People have trust in their government, in their administration and how their taxes are used. This leads to a high level of security; problems are laid off them and ultimately this leads to a high level of happiness.   

http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_Happiness_Report  

Low level of income inequality, high GDP and PPP per capita, liberal laws, low crime, low corruption, good healthcare, great education, low pollution. What's not to like?  

But all this does not obstruct high profit businesses from investing and all that is asked from businesses is that they treat their employees with respect and pay them enough so they can make a decent living. True, most thrift-based businesses would be discouraged from investing but Imo in the developed country there should be no place for such an exploiting business style.  

My only doubt is whether such a model could adapt to a larger country because in all Nordic cases we deal with low populations, large areas and often, decent levels of natural resources and admittedly this does create conditions for easier administration and sustainable economic growth.  

CMV, thanks in advance!
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="27422207452.0" user="simonask" delta="True">
    <text>Danish citizen here.

It's tempting to want to agree with you, for the simple reason that we do indeed come out on top in most measurements of happiness, wealth, and a number of other statistics.

There are some frequently cited drawbacks, however:

1. The "Jante Law" culture, which is a variant of the "Tall Poppy Syndrome", where excellence is actively discouraged.

2. The sometimes excessive xenophobia, indicating that the model largely works because of a high level of trust between citizens, and between citizens and the state. The introduction of foreign elements, where trust isn't an integral part of the culture, could theoretically sabotage the efficacy of the model.

3. The "Low Expectations" critique — maybe we're so damn happy because we don't expect much of life, and therefore real outcomes tend to match or exceed our expectations. Maybe our culture would create "happiness" under different circumstances as well, indicating that the model itself isn't what's creating these statistics, but rather some other factor, like culture or even genetics (as suggested by some admittedly fringe theories).

4. The wealth of Scandinavian countries is also the result of the same mechanisms that have created wealth in the rest of Europe, including most prominently exploitative colonialism. While Scandinavian countries were only minor colonial powers (most notably Denmark), they all benefited massively from trade with stronger colonial powers, like The Netherlands, United Kingdom, France, and to an extent Germany. The Nordic Model may have served to develop and distribute this wealth in a desirably way, but hasn't necessarily created the wealth in the first place.

I don't particularly agree with all these criticisms, but they're worth considering.

One relevant question, though: Do you think the Nordic Model is *the best possible system* or just *the best we have at the moment*? I think any Swede, Dane and Norwegian would say that they can point to flaws in our individual systems. Someone is always going to be at least a little bit dissatisfied, but allowing yourself to think that "this is the best we can do" is harmful, because our societies *do* have real problems as well, even if they're slightly smaller problems than some other nations face.

One specific problem that I'm familiar with, because I'm Danish, is the fact that Danish societal coherence is largely based on *ethnic* and *cultural* homogeneity. This means that even if Denmark is doing great in the globalised economy, it is facing a massive *cultural* struggle, because there is no concept of Danish national identity that doesn't prescribe a very specific ethnic and cultural background. In a globalised world of many ethnicities, this becomes a real problem that manifests itself both in very high levels of xenophobia, but also in perpetual cultural insecurity, which makes it difficult to interact with people from other backgrounds. This is how the idiom of the "duck pond" (*andedam*) in Danish has emerged, as a metaphor not just for the country itself but for the slightly self-obsessed and self-important mentality of the Danes.

Compare this with American national identity, which is to a large degree grounded in the Constitution of the United States of America, its rights, freedoms, and institutions, rather than any specific ethnicity or culture [although obviously a distinct American culture has emerged over the last century]. This isn't to downplay racial issues in America, but the point is that Danish minority identities aren't even hyphenated. It's "The Danes" and "The Muslims", not "The Danish Muslims".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422288182.0" user="Schoffleine" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; The "Jante Law" culture, which is a variant of the "Tall Poppy Syndrome", where excellence is actively discouraged.

Can you elaborate on that?  How is excellence discouraged?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422297716.0" user="Eye_of_Anubis" delta="False">
    <text>It's an unconscious (mostly) rule of thumb, shortly stated as "Don't think you're the best at something, or even that you're better than most at this thing".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422336469.0" user="WinterSon" delta="False">
    <text>so "be humble"? i must just not be getting it, because it doesn't sound like a bad thing. certainly not compared to the opposite attitude of people being arrogant despite having no accomplishments whatsoever. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422383800.0" user="oldie101" delta="False">
    <text>It's the psyche of contentment. 

Arguably progression is fueled by those who refused to be content.

It appears that the culture in Denmark is one that try's to reinforce the feeling that people should be content. That they need not stray from the norms of society. 

In theory if this was applied universally, we would not have much of what we have today, especially in the sciences and in innovation. It was the people who refused to see the world "as is" and viewed it as a world that could be changed that created much of what we have now. Religion was the obstruction to those choosing to be different, historically. If you were not inline with the religious majority, you were shunned. Similarly in the Danish society it appears that if you are not inline with the Danish culture you too shall be shunned. 

In regards to being humble or being arrogant it's neither. It's more so  adhering to the "status quo". Don't think you are better, because we are striving for a homogeneous society of equals. Straying away from the socially approved behavior, will in turn make you against the Danish way of life. 

The consequence of this is a society that stunts "thinking outside of the box". The "if it isn't broke don't fix it mentality" makes people who try to "fix it" oppressed by those who do not appreciate them for straying from the cultural norm. 

As /u/simonask points out, much of the Danish success was from trade with the colonial powers. As he says "the Nordic Model may have served to develop and distribute this wealth in a desirably way, but hasn't necessarily created the wealth in the first place." The creation of that wealth in a globalized economy is achieved through innovation. One example of this is the progression of alternative energy. If the Oil rich countries continue to rely on the historical cash cow of oil, without exploring new ideas. They will be left behind by those looking for alternatives. Similarly without relying on creation the Danes risk being left behind. 

To summarize, restricting people from wanting to be the best, will restrict them from wanting to go against the norm. Without going against the norm there will be no progression, which can cause a negative affect on society. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422436601.0" user="WinterSon" delta="False">
    <text>thank you for your in depth response, really helps put it in perspective. i was only seeing it as "individual excellence should be celebrated as an accomplishment for the community rather than the individual" and did not consider the other aspects you were kind enough to explain. 

i'm unsure since this wasn't related to the OP, but would this merit a delta? i know deltas can be awarded even if you're not the OP, but it wasn't directly related to the view in the OP, so i'm not exactly sure how it works. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="27422700831.0" user="oldie101" delta="True">
    <text>Apparently you can give a delta. I think someone tried to give it for you but they disallowed it.

EDIT: Never mind they permitted it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
