<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1719432989.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/sfpezh/cmv_adding_rape_as_a_legal_punishment_would_be/">
    <title>CMV: Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society.</title>
    <original_poster>kimagical</original_poster>
    <original_post>This started off as a showerthought but I couldn't find any reason this isn't legit, so here we go.

We need to add rape to the legal system as a viable additional punishment for heinous crimes.

I know what you're thinking. But it's not an unsually cruel punishment.

We already have the death sentence, and if not that, then life sentences of solitary confinement, which virtually all experts-- including official statements from the United Nations-- agree is torture.

And if you're a prisoner today, sometimes you are *already* getting raped. Other times you go "gay for the stay".

So don't tell me adding rape as a legal punishment is anything unusually cruel or sinking lower morally.

If anything, this would help guards regulate "safer" condom-provided prison rape, like how weed became regulated and safer after it was legalized in Canada.

So it's not much of a negative. But why is it a positive?

Here's why: there's a rapidly rising population of involuntary celibates. In the last 10 years alone, the population of these "incels" doubled from 12% of the young male population to 24%.

[https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim](https://ifstudies.org/blog/male-sexlessness-is-rising-but-not-for-the-reasons-incels-claim)

This is 45,000 incels ballooning to over 100,000. These incels have been behind an alarming number of mass murder sprees.

[https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community](https://www.adl.org/blog/online-poll-results-provide-new-insights-into-incel-community)

Every day incels on the dark web discuss organizing terrorism.

There's no fancy peer-reviewed study on that last bit yet-- but I've seen this happening with my own eyes by digging around social media years ago.

I found massive and highly active online communities who worship Elliot Roger and egg each other on to muster up the courage to flatten people with trucks. Buy automatic weapons and kill.

If the population is given free license on their own time to rape any inmates who have been handed the punishment of rape, this could solve some of the incel problem.

It *may* not help; obviously there's no proof in this area. It would be a moral wild west, but there's no time to wait. Innocent people are being shot to death.

It would be far more immoral to not at least try this preventative measure when there are innocents being murdered.

This availability of prison sex slaves with no bodily rights would also directly compete with street prostitution, lowering the demand for a dangerous and morally questionable industry, at best saving two birds with one nest.

At worst, we realize it's not helping and we revert the program. My view is that there is enough reason to try it.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="38864979996.0" user="Hellioning" delta="False">
    <text>'This might work' is not a good reason to legalize rape.

Rape is bad. It shouldn't happen. We do not want it to happen to anyone. The fact that it does happen to inmates so often is a problem to be solved, not an excuse to make it legal.

Like a lot of the cruel and unusual punishments, what happens when an innocent person is wrongly convicted and raped? Do we retroactively decide the person who raped them is now guilty? Do we just apologize and pay for their therapy?

Also, we do not negotiate with terrorists. The response to 'these people aren't getting sex so they want to shoot people' is 'try to get them to understand they aren't owned sex; failing that, try to get them to stop shooting people', not giving them the sex they want. That just encourages people to try and use violence/the threat thereof in order to get the government to cave and give them what they want, because hey, it worked for the incels.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865027480.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>    Like a lot of the cruel and unusual punishments, what happens when an innocent person is wrongly convicted and raped? Do we retroactively decide the person who raped them is now guilty? Do we just apologize and pay for their therapy?

Innocent people are wrongfully murdered by the state too. By adding rape as a punishment this might save some of those death row inmates, giving us at least a chance to correct such a mistake.

The person who raped them is not guilty.

We'd pay for the therapy similarly to how we pay for wrongful incarceration/execution.

&amp;gt;Also, we do not negotiate with terrorists. The response to 'these people aren't getting sex so they want to shoot people' is 'try to get them to understand they aren't owned sex; failing that, try to get them to stop shooting people', not giving them the sex they want. That just encourages people to try and use violence/the threat thereof in order to get the government to cave and give them what they want, because hey, it worked for the incels.

Telling people they aren't owed sex isn't working.

I don't see how your last point follows. Who would start using violence to get what they want and how? It's still illegal so it doesn't benefit them. In fact the person themselves in this scenario might be sentenced to rape if they were a convicted murderer or terrorist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865160612.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>And you think therapy will just magically undo the trauma of being repeatedly raped?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865185332.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>Nope. But it certainly doesn't magically undo the trauma of being imprisoned or executed either.

If anything, less people in total would have to go through the trauma of being wrongfully convicted if this legal punishment results in less total crime (and thereby the need to look for perpetrators).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865292143.0" user="3720-To-One" delta="False">
    <text>Jesus Christ… how many people do you think area prison because of incel-related violence?

The death penalty does not deter crime, why are you so sure that this would?

Your idea is insanely dystopian.

Never mind that you’re just encouraging and enabling incels that violence gets them what they want.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865316124.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Jesus Christ… how many people do you think area prison because of incel-related violence?

Next to none, because incels typically die once they commit a federal offense.

I didn't say the fear of the rape penalty would deter crime.

I said having free government provided sex might.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865327710.0" user="iwfan53" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I don't think the fear of the rape penalty would deter crime.I think having free government provided sex would.

Then why didn't you write a CMV about that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865356675.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>That's what I wrote! Though I must have written it poorly because I seem to be getting misinterpreted a lot.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865554472.0" user="iwfan53" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;That's what I wrote! Though I must have written it poorly because I seem to be getting misinterpreted a lot.

The title of this CMV is "Adding rape as a legal punishment would be good for society." it is not "The government  should provide sex to people as a way to deter crime."

&amp;amp;#x200B;

Am I mistaken?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865665344.0" user="kimagical" delta="False">
    <text>The first statement is the overarching view. The second statement is part of the reasoning for my view (provided it's free).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="38865691209.0" user="iwfan53" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt;The second statement is part of the reasoning for my view (provided it's free).

Why do you think that making it so that prisoners can rape people is a better way of getting people free government sex, then simply have the government hire a bunch of prostitutes and provide them to people as needed?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
