<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1821161756.0" index="9" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/u49tek/cmv_its_extremely_stupid_to_ask_celebrities_to/">
    <title>CMV: It’s extremely stupid to ask celebrities to condemn their fans when they make threats to another celebrity (or other people, in general).</title>
    <original_poster>theguyoverthere50</original_poster>
    <original_post>Recently, I looked up Perez Hilton because I had no idea who he was and I kept hearing his name, and I was annoyed right off the bat. Looks like he tried to fling mud on Ariana Grande (alleging that she took coke at a party) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of her towards Hilton. After a while, she complied with his request and told her fans to chill out.

It drives me nuts that this sort of shit happens as though people that like a certain celebrity are dogs that can be called off of their attack when the center of their infatuation says they want it to end.

It insulates evasive pussy conduct like that of Hilton, and makes celebrities look like the bad guys if they refuse to call the fans off, making it look like the celebrity sicced the fans on them in the first place.

We’re left in this surreal area where celebrity targets are making efforts to protect their shit-talkers, which they should have no obligation to do. Grande sings songs, it’s not like she’s a mob boss.

But this is just a case study, there are probably thousands of examples similar to this.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39475274838.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Looks like ~~he~~ Donald Trump tried to fling mud on ~~Ariana Grande~~ Election of 2020 (alleging that ~~she took coke at a party~~ the votes were rigged) which lead to nasty comments and threats by fans of ~~her~~  his towards ~~Hilton~~ Congress.

I'm curious, do you think Trump had a responsibility to call of the January 6th attacks? It was directly incited by things he said on social media, he knew this was happening, and the reaction was a predictable consequence of what he had said.

How much does scale and intensity matter here? If I make an unsubstantiated rape accusation against someone on social media, do I bear any responsibility for what this inspires others to do? What if it was fake, or alternatively, what if I didn't care if it was true?

How much does effort matter here? It would be trivially easy, making a twitter post, to defuse the situation. Is a social media post really such a burden to alleviate the suffering of others?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476001174.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>On the contrary. Most of Trump’s fans are geriatric fatties who wouldn’t move from their chair unless Oreilly was over. I didn’t expect this, we can say otherwise NOW that it happened.

In the rape hypothetical you’re only guilty of slander if you lied (not the ensuing violence unless there’s clear coordination).

Regarding the last paragraph, I know quelling the mob is easy. But why should someone? I don’t see the obligations to help someone, let alone someone who talked smack to you.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476015464.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>In other words, you believe no one should ever have any responsibility for what they say? I suppose there’s no need for laws regarding defamation, would you agree?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476125494.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I said I was against slander and defamation in my previous comment. There are plenty of opportunities for things you say to come back at you in ways I would accept.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476148310.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>I had assumed you considered inciting violence as worse than inciting the loss of income or reputation. Those are the reasons why defamation and slander are bad.

Its weird you're fine with someone's speech being illegal, with the potential for jail time even, yet are not okay with someone's speech creating more speech.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476206381.0" user="theguyoverthere50" delta="False">
    <text>I don’t catch the meaning of your last paragraph</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39476418608.0" user="Fit-Order-9468" delta="False">
    <text>Well, “holding someone responsible” is really just having and sharing an opinion. You’re saying, well x celebrity didn’t do something, but it’s bad people are sharing their opinions about how they thought that was bad.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
