<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="24" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39755352747.0" user="StandardBandit" delta="False">
    <text>White fragility aside, it's racist to hold someone responsible for someone else's actions just because they have the same skin color, no matter what that skin color is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755794970.0" user="jaam01" delta="False">
    <text>The concept of "white fragility" "argument" should be dismissed right away, because is just a fallacy by itself. It's a Kafkatrap, a sophistical rhetorical device, in which any denial by the accused person, is used as if was evidence of guilt.  
  
Example: "You deny been a witch? Then you're a witch, because that's what a witch would say"  
  
It's circular thinking and a specious way of shifting the burden of proof (because you don't have any evidence to prove your accusation on the first place). Its a gotcha, like "damn you if you do (admitting you are a racist), and also damn you if you don't (deny that you are a racist)"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757872036.0" user="loudbeat69" delta="False">
    <text>It's literally the exact mechanism most of these extreme thinking groups work. It's no different to the BLM and others, "oh you won't accept total responsibility for some cops actions in another state cause your also white, well then you're just as bad as him them" etc etc. 

I get people want to end racism and prejudice but this moral virtue signalling crap is not the way to go about it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39757914977.0" user="AbsolutelyUnlikely" delta="False">
    <text>Meanwhile I'm over here playing FIFA and eating pretzels, how can you want me to accept responsibility for what some cop did 2,000 miles away? I don't even accept enough responsibility to consistently pay my phone bill on time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39920954415.0" user="jaam01" delta="False">
    <text>I would like to add, BLM is based on Critical Race Theories, which IMO is pesudo science masquerading as "scholarship". Unlike real science, CRT start with the conclusion (unless it's beneficial to us, is always racism, somehow) then work backwards to confirm the hypothesis, and contradictory or contrary evidence is dismissed entirely or smeared. Also, their claims can't be falsifiable, because they can't prove it was racism, you must assume that the entire system is racist. If a claim can be proven wrong, it's not science, it's ideology or opinion.
 "What can be asserted without evidence, can also be dismissed without evidence." Hitchens's logical razor.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39759172760.0" user="tchaffee" delta="False">
    <text>You can hold people responsible for not taking action against an oppressive system they benefit from. The responsible thing to do is to give back the benefit you received. Or better, fix the system so no one is oppressed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39827663642.0" user="StandardBandit" delta="False">
    <text>You can falsely hold anyone responsible for anything. It's racist to hold any member of any race who isn't responsible for the racism. You can fight racism with whatever tools you want, just please don't fight it with further racism. Pump money into inner city schools. Don't pretend it's any white kid's fault that people with his same skin color did something you don't like all the way across time and country. It's racism. Trying to hold them responsible for what they took no part in is racism. You're free to try to fight racism with racism. But at least acknowledge you've taken all the legs out from under your argument.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39827874144.0" user="tchaffee" delta="False">
    <text>"When You’re Accustomed to Privilege, Equality Feels Like Oppression"  

&amp;gt; who isn't responsible for the racism

If you're benefiting from an oppressive racist system and not taking action against it, then you are responsible for helping to maintain it. That's racism on your part, whether or not you were the one to create the racist system.

If you find out during a foot race that the starting line was rigged in your favor, and you don't do anything about it, then you are a cheater. Even though you didn't rig the starting line and you knew nothing about it until now. Once you are aware, you need to make a decision. A decision to not fix it is cheating.

&amp;gt; Don't pretend it's any white kid's fault that people with his same skin color did something you don't like all the way across time and country

I don't hold children responsible for much of anything. I'm talking about adults. But anyway you should realize that if the white kid is benefiting from a racist system, then that is racist. I would expect the adults in the kid's life to be actively working to fix it.

&amp;gt; Pump money into inner city schools

How does that help a 12 year old poor black kid in the US? They are already way behind because of racism. This is going to negatively affect them their entire life. That negative effect will have a positive effect on people who did not experience that racism. They will get the better jobs just for example and enjoy an entire lifetime of higher pay. Which really adds up when it comes to building wealth.

Although your suggestion is not a bad starting point, it's not nearly enough.

&amp;gt; You're free to try to fight racism with racism

I'm afraid you'll have to be more specific with concrete examples of what you mean by fighting "racism with racism".</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
