<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39754443310.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Looking at your edit:

Your *reading* of that in that context looks exactly like a *classic* example of "white fragility". 

The context being:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

That's a *deflection* from the fact that racism is alive today and kills people *today*, and the added comment is saying that your kids should reflect on how their contributions to society *today* can help generate a tragedy like that.... today.

It's nothing about the specific actions of a specific person being something that individual people who aren't them should feel guilty about. 

It's about the *gaslighting* of the *fragile white deflection* that "all this was a long time ago". 

You're *entirely missing the point* of that comment. Because it only sounds like it's blaming every individual white people for some one guy's insanity if you ignore the context and look at it from a defensive perspective.

I can't know what's in your head that causes that misreading... but it's entirely unsurprising that it *appears* to some people as "white fragility". 

And let's not even get started on the *fact* that this entire incident was due to the massive white fragility inherent in the bogus "replacement theory" that caused it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754508389.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I agree "replacement theory" is BS and I definitely believe racism is systemic and exists at a personal level throughout society. 

So you don't believe that the OP was saying white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter? That was *exactly* how I read it.

Posting the whole comment:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.

You mention context but I was specifically concerned with the most salient context. The comment was made in a thread about the Buffalo shooter which had happened in the last week. There are approximately 0 universes where one would interpret "what happened in the past week" to be anything other than the shooting referenced in the thread. 

Then "you should feel guilty" referring to "the kids" speaks for itself I believe. What does guilt accomplish?

I don't think I was deflecting but rather wanting to move towards better solutions to the problem OP was talking about (that we likely agree is a problem).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754840280.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Of course it's about the shooting last week. 

That's an *example* of the *bullshit* that is the statement “My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”...

Which is basically: "Oh noes, what horrors, my kids might have to feel guilty/ashamed about something that happened 200 years ago that they are still benefiting from today, in a political environment where racist bullshit conspiracy theories are threatening democracy itself by stirring up racism... whatever will I do?"

As for "what good does guilt/shame do"... Guilt and shame motivate *change*. They motivate not just *rejection* of the bullshit the alt-right is spouting today, but active opposition. They motivate not being a fucking *bystander* while the country descends into racist fascism. 

Because this is a situation where literally if you aren't with us, you're against us. 

Basically: the first comment is basically *parroting* Great Replacement Conspiracy Theory bullshit, and that person's kids should be ashamed of their *parent* for saying it, and not let it stand.

Those kids are in *especial* need to not become radicalized, not just generalized "be a decent human being" levels. 

They're guilty in the sense that they aren't calling out the bullshit, most likely.

So, ok, perhaps "guilty" was a bit intellectually lazy and it should have been "ashamed of their parent", but it's the word the asshole being responded to used, and punchy political statements don't descend into caviling about the narrow semantic difference between guilt and shame.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755023812.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>It's interesting you say that guilt and shame motivate change. For some people I believe that is the case. 

In my experience it's exactly the opposite. When I feel guilty or shameful about something I do my best to ignore whatever that thing was. That doesn't necessarily mean I won't do it again though. It's certainly not motivating me to examine the guilt and shame is my point!

There's another group of people who feel guilt and shame but misdirect it. 

I also know for a fact there is a third group of people are incapable of feeling guilt and shame so it's not a useful tool for/against them either but for that reason instead. 

My final point is that I'm with OP on the goal, ending racism, but not the method (feeling a negative emotion).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755038701.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>Another way of stating the point, though, is:

"If you want to avoid being guilty/ashamed, try actually fighting racism rather than enabling it or being willfully ignorant about it". 

Because the comment that tweet is responding to is *massive* willfully ignorant. It deserves attack, whether that attack is worded to sooth the hurt feelings of white people or not.

In this case, it's not worded that way... and... people lose their minds. What *else* would you call that than "white fragility"?... it's kind of the point of the phrase.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755115539.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>The problem I have is I thought I was being constructive not losing my mind or even reacting negatively. 

I definitely agree that if I had made an angry response or completely deflected from the issue (pervasive white supremacy) or something that would have been white fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755179061.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="False">
    <text>It's the *mindset* that the idea of feeling shame or guilt is so horrible that you might even *consider* ignoring or even fostering the problems of systemic racism... 

That's pretty much the *definition* of "white fragility": white people feeling shame or guilt is so unthinkable they'll do almost anything to avoid it, even ignoring a massive problem or defending people that are deflecting it. 

And again, no one can get in your head and know what you're thinking... all they can do is notice that it *sounds like* white fragility... because it legitimately *does* sound that way.

Edit: TL;DR: it's the narrow laser focus on the "horrors" of the possibility of shame/guilt that's doing that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755221979.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>So if a person interpreted my comment as aimed at society in general and not the specific act of the Buffalo shooter then my comment sounds like white fragility?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39755250949.0" user="hacksoncode" delta="True">
    <text>If a person interpreted it as an attack on a person trying to get through the thick skull of a probably white supremacist, mostly. 

Your comment looks like it's focused on the horrors of the possibility that white people might have to feel shame or guilt, rather than the willful ignorance of the original tweet thinking racism is "long ago". 

Let's rearrange that response and remove the apparent attacks on the person holding the original person accountable for their willful ignorance:

&amp;gt;What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres. It's likely that promoting "guilt" is counterproductive in this effort, because those conservative spaces suffer from white fragility.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
