<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="1865427692.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/uuml7w/cmv_saying_white_people_in_general_shouldnt_feel/">
    <title>CMV: Saying white people in general shouldn't feel guilty for the actions of specific, individual white people isn't an example of white fragility.</title>
    <original_poster>LucidMetal</original_poster>
    <original_post>I was recently banned from /whitepeopletwitter for this comment:

&amp;gt;I don't think "white people" need to feel guilty about this. You're just internalizing an issue over which you don't have control. What we need to do is figure out a way to combat the revisionist history narratives and misinformation that are plaguing conservative spheres (I don't want to say "echo chamber" because let's be honest everyone lives in an echo chamber these days).

I don't care that I was banned to be clear. I do care that the reason seemed incorrect. The reason given was:

&amp;gt;White fragility is racist.

I do believe "white fragility" as a concept exists in America i.e. many white people exhibit a negative reaction including anger, fear, guilt, arguing, silence, or leaving the stress-inducing situation when they encounter discussions of race. I have no idea how pervasive it is because I don't encounter it very frequently but I have encountered it and I know my friends who belong to minority racial groups say it happens frequently for them. 

I don't think the ban was justified (but who cares) and I don't think white fragility is racism (I suppose easy delta here if you can show me why) but I also don't see why my comment is an example of white fragility.

As far as I remember it's the opposite! It was saying OP should not feel guilt when discussing the Buffalo shooter since it was a specific person with a specific worldview not "white people". I can't post the comment I was responding to because it's been deleted but it was along the lines of "white people should feel guilty for the Buffalo shooter".

EDIT: Alright, found the parent using Unddit! This is what I was responding to:

&amp;gt;“My kids shouldn’t feel guilty for slavery two hundred years ago!”

&amp;gt;News flash asshole, they should feel guilty for what happened in the past week.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="39753242044.0" user="TheJuiceIsBlack" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you want your view changed?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753252934.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>I would like my view changed to enhance my understanding of racial issues as I think they're an important topic and ubiquitous in our lives.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753351902.0" user="TheJuiceIsBlack" delta="False">
    <text>Haven’t read her book - but have seen a lecture of her’s on YouTube.  

According to Robin DiAngelo - white fragility covers a wide range of defensive behaviors in response to conversations or statements about race.  This can include (AFAICT) any non-affirming response to a racial statement (such as the one you describe).  

From a NYT article:  

“She taught, throughout the afternoon, that the impulse to individualize is in itself a white trait, a way to play down the societal racism all white people have thoroughly absorbed.” - https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/15/magazine/white-fragility-robin-diangelo.amp.html

“And so a white person is supposed to learn that there are all sorts of things that they can't say. You can't say, "I marched in the civil rights movement," because that would make you too comfortable. You can't say, "I don't see race," because you almost certainly do. You can't say, "it's about class," because it's about race.

And she's got about 25 proscriptions that make it so that any good white person is essentially muzzled. You just have to be quiet.” - https://www.npr.org/2020/07/20/892943728/professor-criticizes-book-white-fragility-as-dehumanizing-to-black-people</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39753748594.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>So I don't think that's what white fragility has come to mean even if she coined it and it sounds like an extreme interpretation.

Are you saying that any time a white person says anything in response to a POC if it doesn't affirm their belief it is white fragility? On the internet how would one even know they are responding to a POC in the first place?

That can't be the definition.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754280657.0" user="hastur777" delta="False">
    <text>The old kafkatrap. Disagreement is just more evidence that I’m right.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754305239.0" user="LucidMetal" delta="False">
    <text>Would you explain? I very much like evidence. I am 99% sure based on what I've learned thus far that "white fragility" is not "any non-affirming response to a racial statement". That is far too broad.

E.g. a POC could say, "black people are inferior to white people" and OP's definition states that not affirming that would mean I'm being fragile, which is absurd since that statement is incorrect and it would be racist to affirm it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="39754339052.0" user="hastur777" delta="True">
    <text>https://www.theatlantic.com/ideas/archive/2020/07/dehumanizing-condescension-white-fragility/614146/

This article does a decent job laying out the issue. Any statement besides agreeing that you’re complicit in systemic racism is white fragility and more evidence of racism.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
