<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971234116.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want.

Why do you think "success" in promiscuity would translate to success in other aspects of life? (And in which direction are you suggesting the causation exists?)

&amp;gt;I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships).

I disagree. It takes one set of skills (including attractiveness as a "skill") to attract people at first, but a separate and (in my opinion) far more difficult set of skills to maintain a good relationship.

What this sounds like to me is that you've bought into the toxic idea that a man's worth is determined by his ability to attract women.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971488431.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I disagree. It takes one set of skills (including attractiveness as a "skill") to attract people at first, but a separate and (in my opinion) far more difficult set of skills to maintain a good relationship.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

Why do you think the skillset is more difficult? I've normally seen it described as easier, so why do you think it's harder?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971671709.0" user="OkDisplay" delta="False">
    <text>Have you been in a long term relationship?  I have two kids and it’s not always easy to keep my wife happy, and it’s not always easy for her to keep me happy.  It’s far more work than keeping fit and going out for no strings sex every weekend.  You don’t have the independence you have when single.  If I want to work out or do one of my hobbies, I need to make sure my wife is ok with it, she’ll have two kids to watch.  Even without kids, there’s a constant consideration of the other person.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971775817.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah I have been in two, 1 year and 2.5 years respectively. Might be something of a grass is always greener on the other side thing on my part. Generally it was easy to keep the other person happy but I got drained by one of them being overly demanding and that's why I ended the 2.5 year relationship.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971825237.0" user="OkDisplay" delta="False">
    <text>10 years and 2 kids for me.  It was easy for the first few years.  It’s been very hard lately.  That doesn’t mean it’s not worth it, but it is a lot of work.  The first few years were effortless for me.  It all came naturally.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972022768.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Are you agreeing casual sex is the harder one then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972035823.0" user="OkDisplay" delta="False">
    <text>I’ve never had casual sex, but being in a long term successful relationship is extremely difficult.  Just wanted to share my perspective and have you give some credit to the difficulty of long term relationships.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972065245.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>I think the genuinely hard part is that people may have innately different aptitudes which will affect which one they find easy. That makes it difficult to make judgments</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971892246.0" user="Milskidasith" delta="False">
    <text>You seem to be agreeing that maintaining a long term relationship is more difficult than casual dating here.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972019934.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Having never done one option vs done the other option for 3.5 years I don’t see how I’m agreeing that the one I haven’t done is easier. Is casual dating something where difficulty remains relatively constant over time after you get started doing it? Like it might be hard to have one casual sexual encounter but it gets easier over time until it reaches a relatively constant difficulty? In contrast to long term relationships getting more complex with time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971695366.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>Basically, to be "successful" at promiscuity you have to be attractive long enough to get someone to have sex with you.

To be "successful" at a long term monogamous relationship, you still have to attract someone, but you also have to be a good partner over a much longer period of time.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971804343.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>I think there's a higher standard of attractiveness for promiscuity as you aren't really bringing anything else to the table. Idk what exactly the difficulty would be since people do have preferences so demographic statistics aren't that useful. If 90% of men don't want casual sex then 10% of men having 90% of the sex partners actually just makes sense logically and doesn't reflect any kind of difficulty in having lots of partners.

I generally think the long term being a good partner things are all just easy, but that might be my personal aptitudes and grass is always greener on the other side thinking affecting it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971896183.0" user="jfpbookworm" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think there's a higher standard of attractiveness for promiscuity as you aren't really bringing anything else to the table.

Perhaps, but how much of that is "skill" and how much is genetics and privilege?

&amp;gt;I generally think the long term being a good partner things are all just easy, but that might be my personal aptitudes and grass is always greener on the other side thinking affecting it.

Have you been in a long term relationship? What do you think being a good partner entails?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971998104.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Well I do consider genetics and privilege to give agency too. One reason why I want universal healthcare to cover plastic surgery and am big on redistributing wealth.

Yeah I’ve been in long term relationship. I think being a good partner basically consists of listening to them, seeing the systems at play, and manipulating the systems at play so everyone is happy. Negative feedback loops generally lead to good stable relationships, and positive feedback loops normally lead to unstable ones. You have to have a confluence of long term desires and be able to communicate them effectively and integrate them with your everyday system of interactions.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
