<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971248195.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life.

I think it is as simple as "Men don't get pregnant". You can have as much sex as you want as a man, and can theoretically never think of each sexual encounter again. Women who are able to become pregnant cannot do this. There is always a chance that they will become pregnant, so they have to include that in their calculations. Even if you remove all other considerations (power dynamics, social expectations, and so on) this would still remain for most heterosexual relationships. The man can screw and dip, the woman might have a situation on her hands. That isn't the man being in more control, it is the man having different considerations.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971440943.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>So you think this doesn't apply to gay and lesbian relationships?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971499199.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;So you think this doesn't apply to gay and lesbian relationships

&amp;gt;&amp;gt; straight male promiscuity

That isn't what we are talking about. I think that promiscuity among straight men is primarily caused by the fact that they can be promiscuous without too many negative outcomes (with the main one being pregnancy), whereas straight women who are able to become pregnant cannot be as promiscuous due to the fact that doing so greatly increases their chance of becoming pregnant.

This does not even take into account how promiscuous men are viewed in general (Studs, Casanovas, Players) and how promiscuous women are (sluts, whores, damaged goods). That alone has a huge impact. A promiscuous man will be lauded. A promiscuous woman shamed.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971519305.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>I agree with all of this, but I don't see how it relates to the notion of promiscuous males having better life skills than monogamous males. Why the situation is in place is different from the fact that the situation is in place.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971538644.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; but I don't see how it relates to the notion of promiscuous males having better life skills than monogamous males.

Uhh... It doesn't? 

My whole point is that I *disagree* with that assertion, and am presenting an alternative hypothesis as to the origin of straight male promiscuity. I do not think promiscuity is the result of, or impacted by, a particular man's social skills or lack thereof. I think straight men are more promiscuous because they don't get pregnant, and because our society encourages male promiscuity.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971812837.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>We're talking at two different levels. I'm talking at an interpersonal level and you're talking at an anthropological/evolutionary level.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971848853.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>So? My argument remains. When a man meets a lady, and sexy times are possible, the man has less negative outcomes to judge against than the woman. He can sleep with her, and then ghost, and possibly never be bothered again. The woman can sleep with him, accidentally get pregnant, and then have to deal with all that come with that. Even individually, this difference in potential negative outcomes will contribute to the man going into the sexual encounter with less concern for the future than the woman.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971921474.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>You’re totally right on this but I just don’t think it’s really related to the topic at hand. This isn’t related to men’s ability to navigate social situations or anything like  that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971968261.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; This isn’t related to men’s ability to navigate social situations or anything like that.

Right, it is about this:

&amp;gt;Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life

I disagree. 

My position is this: "Male promiscuity is associated with the fact that they cannot get pregnant, and that our society lionizes male promiscuity."

I don't think it has anything at all do to with agency, which is your primary claim.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972044708.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>My primary claim is that within the unfair system which exists men who are more promiscuous have more agency than those who aren’t. Gender differences are irrelevant because I’m talking about within a system.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972068609.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>They don't "have more agency". They just exercise their agency with less regard for the social norm of being in monogamous relationships. A person in a monogamous relationship has just as much agency when it comes to how their seek out and form relationships, they just choose to be monogamous. The promiscuous person makes a different choice. They are both making the same choice, just with different outcomes. 

Why is choosing one outcome a sign of greater agency than another. The agency is in the choice making, not the outcome.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972149050.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Why is choosing one outcome a sign of greater agency than another. The agency is in the choice making, not the outcome.

Success in finding new partners is the agency. Not making a lifestyle choice. It demonstrates an ability for them to set and achieve goals.

I don't completely discount this with monogamy, but I see it as being less. However though it may be that monogamous relationships increase in complexity over time as they develop, while promiscuity is relatively constant. In the same way that being president in the 1700s would likely have been a much simpler job than being president now. There are more moving parts in the country today, not to mention over 100 times more people.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972200878.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; Success in finding new partners is the agency

That is the outcome, not the agency. Agency is the ability to make choices for one's self. Both the promiscuous person, and the monogamous one is making the choice to be that thing. That is agency, and it is the *same level* of agency. 

&amp;gt;It demonstrates an ability for them to set and achieve goals.

And, the person who's goal is to be in a monogamous relationship? Do they not achieve their goal by, you know, being in a monogamous relationship instead of chasing tail all the time? 

Both make choices (Agency), and both chase outcomes based on those choices. Neither choice is better or worse; each has its own unique set of challenges. 

&amp;gt;I don't completely discount this with monogamy, but I see it as being less.

This is a personal value judgement that adds little to the discussion. The discussion is what is responsible for  increased promiscuity in men compared to women. That is your top line argument. 

It has, in my view, **nothing at all ** to do with agency. It is instead the result of the fact that men cannot get pregnant, and that our society lionizes male promiscuity. 

That is it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
