<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971211703.0" user="Affectionate_Cod6124" delta="False">
    <text>I've always seen male promiscuity associated with immaturity, and it's often tied to "all men cheat" or something similar.

Also go check out the Mayo clinic's website- promiscuity is a symptom of a *lot* of mental illnesses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971474500.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; I've always seen male promiscuity associated with immaturity, and it's often tied to "all men cheat" or something similar.
&amp;gt; 
&amp;gt; 

I've seen this too but I feel like I need more of an argument for it than just most people believe it</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971539397.0" user="Affectionate_Cod6124" delta="False">
    <text>Cheating has never been seen as a positive trait.

All Cheaters Are Bastards.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971583281.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Yeah it's a bad trait but does it not reflect an increased agency turned to evil?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971633035.0" user="destro23" delta="False">
    <text>They have the same amount of agency as anyone. They just exercise it differently. I, in a committed long term relationship, *can* leave at any time. I have that option. That I do not exercise that option to chase new tail every few months does not mean I have less agency.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971869268.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Do you have that option? This raises metaphysical questions if you don't pursue it. Is it really an option? How do you know? Might it be something you’d completely fail at if you attempted in reality?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971897870.0" user="destro23" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Do you have that option? 

Yeah, that's what my dad did. Found some new tail, and took off for a few years. It happens all the time, and everyone knows that if they really wanted to, they could just fuck off down the road. 

I heard a joke once: "When I got married, I thought 'Now I can never leave'. When I had a kid I thought 'Fuck, I could have left!"

I don't exercise that option because I am happy in my relationship. But, if that ever changed to a great enough degree, I'd still have that option. And, I'd probably use it. I have once before.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
