<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2076541612.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/ycbhrg/cmv_male_promiscuity_is_associated_with_increased/">
    <title>CMV: Male promiscuity is associated with increased agency in life</title>
    <original_poster>their-holiness</original_poster>
    <original_post>I think straight male promiscuity is associated with an increased agency in life. Being more in control and able to do what you want. I think this is the case because compared to other groups getting into the lifestyle is much more difficult for them. I don't have any view one way or the other on other groups for this topic because I don't see myself as knowing enough about their experiences.

  
I think most people likely disagree with this view which makes me optimistic I'll get to see good arguments against it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity essentially has a lower skill floor and a higher skill ceiling compared to monogamy. I'm much more confident about the lower skill floor since I don't exactly know much of the heights of accomplishment for either. I think it requires more social and emotional skills to be continuously promiscuous than to maintain a long-term monogamous relationship (or polyamorous relationships). I think monogamy is generally the easy way out and that's why most men choose it.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

I think promiscuity requires maintaining your health and other things like that a lot more than monogamy, and it requires higher social skills and emotional regulation skills. I think that monogamy requires a narrower range of skills and maintenance, but I'm unsure.

&amp;amp;#x200B;

However, and this is important, my view will be changed if I see evidence suggesting a higher ceiling for monogamy, in that case it would be more like there's a group of highly competent monogamous men distinguished from the lower ones who aren't competent and they deserve to be in their own category which may be equal or higher than the promiscuous men.

EDIT: I messed up my usage of the terms ceiling and floor. Floor is backwards in this post</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="40971872065.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>For this to make sense you have to have an overinflated idea of the role sex plays in "life", the thing you think men have agency in.  I'd suggest your argument is ultimately circular in that you see sexual option as a sign of agency.

I think maintaining relationships is the very height of social and emotional skill. It's not hard to get laid, but it sure is hard for people to be successful in relationships.  For every man who can't get laid, there are 10 who fail at intimate relationships.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40971952571.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Do you consider maintaining relationships to be more complex and require a greater range of skills than entering them? Including things like self control, and learning new skills?

Those are the kinds of things I associate with agency which are unrelated to sexual options. Someone with high agency can both be flexible in their behaviour in response to new conditions but also able to maintain a high degree of consistency and order to their behaviour.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972116640.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>That's where i think you're defining agency as "can get laid", not as "capacity to live the good life".  It's vastly more important to be able to maintain great relationships - social, intimate, family,etc. - than it is to be able to enter into relationships - social, intimate - easily.  It's _harder_.  Further, lacking the capacity to be sexually promiscuous doesn't somehow increase your likelihood of being great at intimate relationship.  

I would grant you that _sexual options_ can be a source of confidence and confidence can feed all sorts of agency, but that's not the same as "sexual promiscuity".  Options - or at least the belief in them - is almost the very definition of agency.  While I'd say there are lots and lots of types of options that increase angency in life and many of them lead to sexual options - career, sport, music, art, cooking and so on - that you've got things pretty inverted here!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972192891.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>So do you think that? Do you consider maintaining relationships to have a higher degree of cumulative complexity than say managing to just maintain a status fitness etc to have frequent causal encounters? Do you consider the nature of the difficulty curve to be different?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972230709.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>I consider them to be independent skills - not comparable really, so..yes, different.  One can't say if being a soccer player takes more skill than being a tennis player.  The sources of agency are myriad, you're hyperfocusing on one of them or even using one of them to define what "agency" is.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972322075.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>You might be able to make a point based on independent skills that they are independent and equally valuable which is probably enough for a delta but I'd really like to see some kind of evidence on promiscuity being associated with lower agency

The complexity accumulation thing I have mentioned probably ten times is one I see as a good point for it, but nobody has actually addressed it so far. I want to see it at least addressed before I am willing to give out a delta</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972361028.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say lower, I said that it's _options_ that matter, not engagement.  I'm saying there are lots of paths to agency.  This means that while it might be associated with agency if it's valued by a person, not being promiscuous isn't going to be correlated with lack of agency in any meaningful way.  Further, at phases of life I'd suggest that the feeling of failure of marriages and relationships from cheating (a form of promiscuity) _decreases_ agency, not increases it.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40972651680.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Incomparable isn’t a view change, but the complexity accumulation point is a view change. Thoughts on it?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973170867.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Again, you ignore _optionality_ being more important than action in agency.  This is true on all things.  Agency as it relates to career doesn't exist because you have lots of jobs, it's because you have lots of options.

Additionally, "incomparable" is the primary reason you should change.  If all things in our lives can bring about or threaten agency, then a correlation of one of them to agency is a meaningless perspective of zero information.  You also seem to ignore that for most adults promiscuity is correlated with negatives and lack of agency - e.g. loss of optionality in a given relationship.  People don't say "i've got so much agency that I cheated on my wife".

I don't know what you're talking about with "complexity accumulation".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973257211.0" user="their-holiness" delta="False">
    <text>Maintaining an ongoing thing is more complex than just repeating casual sex over and over again. So maybe monogamy is harder because it involves more consistency requirements and adapting to changing conditions than say maintaining a workout schedule to help looking good does</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="40973304273.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="True">
    <text>I agree with that.  I'm not sure why it being hard matters.  Isn't the question about agency?  (and..to be clear, it's my contention that being successful i relationships brings about a hell of a lot more agency than getting laid with lots of people.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
