<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="220698466.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3nec0y/cmv_saying_you_dont_care_about_freedom_of_privacy/">
    <title>CMV: Saying you don't care about freedom of privacy because you have nothing to hide is like saying you don't care about freedom of speech because you have nothing to say.</title>
    <original_poster>MoonbirdMonster</original_poster>
    <original_post>I've argued about this with a girlfriend a couple times now. I believe that the freedom of privacy is a kind of pillar of American freedom, along with life, expression, etc. If we do not have privacy we have lost among our most basic of rights. Her argument is that it doesn't matter if we've lost them, because the government (see: any vested interest with control in mind) will just spy in you anyway, even after they've been caught (see: Snowden) because they can always find ways to do it without people knowing. My rebuttal is that the battle isn't over until you say it's over, quite literally in this case, because their only threat is us, the people who do want a right to privacy.

I use the free speech comparison because similar things happen when the rights are infringed upon. If your freedom of speech is taken away, you no longer have the ability to voice opposition. This would result in anybody who is for free speech will be impossible to find. It's somewhat similar to what happens today with social media hugboxes, the opposition gets harder and harder to find, sounds more and more crazy with each day. It's pretty obvious where this leads. I compare this to right to privacy because too much surveillance means somebody is more hesitant to do natural things, like criticize those in power. Especially when your country is like the USA which has a long history with torture, but that's another story. 

The point is, I understand that the idea that we have privacy in this age is laughable, but that very idea is exactly why you can't just roll over for it. It's a constant battle that must be fought; it's somewhat unfortunate that it's that way, but always revel in the fact that those rights even exist in your mind because without them, you'd have no idea what you're missing out on.

Feel free to ignore the rambling and just try to sway me. I am open to thoughts and opinions on this topic, embrace the ability to even have this discussion.

_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28034969194.0" user="Coolaccount2" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that the freedom of privacy is important, but comparing it to free speech is flawed, I think.

If you have nothing to say but are for free speech, that means you have nothing to say, but you want *other* people to be able to say stuff.

If you have nothing [illegal] to hide but are for privacy, that means you have nothing [illegal] to hide, but you want *other* people to be able to hide [illegal] stuff? 

See how these aren't the same concept?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035796393.0" user="Sythin" delta="False">
    <text>I think this misses a key point. It is not just about hiding illegal activity, it is about not wanting somebody else watching over you to make sure you are not doing anything illegal. That ever present entity checking in on you makes a lot of people nervous and, in my opinion, creepy. 

I don't have a daughter, but I still want somebody who does have one to not have to worry about some NSA agent keeping a close eye on their 15 year old daughter's swim suit pictures for "illegal activity."</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28035837921.0" user="Nible" delta="False">
    <text>"It's creepy" must be the weakest argument I've ever heard. If the NSA agent is doing something illegal he should be prosecuted for it.

What's worse, some guy looking at pictures of 15 year olds or a messed up dude shooting 10 people at a school? Which one would you rather have the opportunity to prevent?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036054635.0" user="Sythin" delta="False">
    <text>Seeing as how they don't do a good job preventing mass shootings, I would pick privacy. That's not a very hard choice. There has to be a better way of preventing shootings than mass surveillance and violating people's privacy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036077907.0" user="Nible" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know they don't? Do you have inside information on the amount of prevented shootings? How would you, or even the NSA, go about estimatimg such numbers?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036123741.0" user="Sythin" delta="False">
    <text>I don't have their information. Nobody but them knows. But I believe I can still say with certainty that they do not do a good job because mass shootings [happen all of the time](http://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonkblog/wp/2015/10/01/2015-274-days-294-mass-shootings-hundreds-dead/). According to this article, there were 294 mass shootings as of October 1st. Several other articles I just looked at give a similar number. They more than likely do prevent some shootings. But how many preventions would they need to justify 294 failures in a 9 month period of time? It would have to be a lot and I really doubt they are stopping thousands of mass shootings seeing as how these shootings have become more frequent over the past few years.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036148111.0" user="Nible" delta="False">
    <text>I agree that's an insane number and it's the first time I heard it. If the NSA isn't using their power effectively then maybe we should replace them, but in principle I have yet to see an argument that convinces me that privacy is so fundamentally important that no matter what we gain from giving it up it's never enough.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036256517.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="False">
    <text>I'd like to try to change your view because I think I understand your feelings and it would help me in my own internal debate with this issue.

So, yes, I think the benefits of relinquishing our right to privacy to some benevolent entity can be very seductive and easily understood. It would give them the power to stop that child kidnapper/rapist and it may be hard to see past saving those lives.

However, I'd like you to consider two facts in your thought process. First, that there is currently no such entity that we should have faith to hold that benevolence. The fact that power has a way of corrupting human infrastructure is a truth that can not be ignored.

Second, is that this power can be used as equally for bad as it could be used for good. The most powerful thing I think I can say to this is what if Hitler had the technology that the NSA does today?

There's a few more things I can mention but want to see what your thoughts are on these two points.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036461693.0" user="Nible" delta="False">
    <text>Whether we trust the American government or not is subjective, it seems I have more trust in it than the people arguing against me. It seems unreasonable to expect dishonesty from the government and because of that distrust dismiss what could be a great opportunity to fight all that we think is bad. I'm simply of the belief that the expected reward is greater than those risks.

Hitler might have been even more successful than he was, or not if the means to fight him and this technology would be of the same caliber. A lot of technology can be used for both good and bad, that's not really unique to this, and we still aren't trying to stop a lot of other technological development. We just try to stop people from using it that way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28036829628.0" user="thedarkkni9ht" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Whether we trust the American government or not is subjective, it seems I have more trust in it than the people arguing against me.

It's hard to trust a government that you know is hiding stuff from you. Even right now, we are only able to have this debate because literally one brave man risked his life for truth. Luckily, he knows a little bit about subverting the power he revealed because it is anybody's guess how many others have been silenced with it.

&amp;gt; It seems unreasonable to expect dishonesty from the government

I think the United States constitution is built upon what you think is "unreasonable".

&amp;gt; A lot of technology can be used for both good and bad, that's not really unique to this, and we still aren't trying to stop a lot of other technological development. We just try to stop people from using it that way. 

You're wrong here. There are many technologies that people do fight against regardless of its beneficial potential simply because they think it would be bad. One such technology is stem cell research. I believe it's been hindered for decades because of fear of what might be. I mean, are you paying attention to the society we live in? it's not even hard to think of examples of technologies that are suppressed (regardless of their capability to do good) solely for monetary reasons.

&amp;gt; I'm simply of the belief that the expected reward is greater than those risks.

I believe you are correct in your analysis of what could have happened in Hitler's case. This technology could have been used to stop him sooner or it could have been used to solidify his plans. How are you measuring the potential of the two though? In one case, millions are saved. In the other, millions more can be murdered. 

I understand that you hold a patriotism and that you believe that there are good men and women ready to use this technology for concrete good in our world. However, I ask you to stop and recognize that there are equally bad people ready to use it for its worst potential. The biggest problem with the bad in this scenario is that whoever that bad person/entity is could be doing it without a single person being wise to it until it's too late.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
