<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="223614694.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/3p4u7a/cmv_sugar_is_a_drug_and_thus_should_be/">
    <title>CMV: Sugar is a drug and thus should be regulated(i.e. limited in products for both adults and children, especially the latter)</title>
    <original_poster>kfijatass</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe sugar should be regulated.   
1) First off, Sugar *is* a drug. [It is addictive, it has withdrawal symptoms if you do not consume any over-time and has negative effects on one's health; diabetes, obesity and dental issues being just a few of the issues.](http://authoritynutrition.com/10-disturbing-reasons-why-sugar-is-bad/); even [sugar-free drinks are of dubious effects on health, with acesulfame k, aspartame, sucralose and other artificial sweeteners being proved to be of dubious effects on health, unhealthy in larger quantities and possibly affect cancer/diabetes rate.](http://www.hsph.harvard.edu/nutritionsource/healthy-drinks/artificial-sweeteners/). Saying that the amount of sugar in products is one of the main reasons behind western world's obesity is not unreasonable, especially as the [amount of sugar increased over the years in daily products, shifting a typical man's diet severely](http://authoritynutrition.com/11-graphs-that-show-what-is-wrong-with-modern-diet/).  
2) Sugar is in all daily products, [the sugar industry lobby is strong](http://www.psmag.com/politics-and-law/the-not-so-sweet-side-to-the-sugar-industry). You cannot rely on the market to create a worthy competitor to sugar(unless [L-Sugar](https://www.quora.com/What-happened-to-L-sugar-left-handed-sugar) becomes a thing one day) precisely because sugar is so addictive which make people buy more of the said sugary products. In worst case scenario, the only real competitors would attempt to make their products equally addictive, which is not a good thing for any consumer involved.  
3) You cannot trust people, especially children to make educated decisions on drugs they're addicted to. Especially now, as sugar penetrated the market to the very point adults and children both are addicted to sugar, you cannot trust addicted parents to take care of sugar-free diets for their children; nor can you control children with pocket money in school shops or cafeterias. This is precisely why the move should come from above; if you'd, for instance, try to make an alcoholic a non-alcoholic the first thing you'd do is move away the alcohol from him, not just try to convince him it's unhealthy while he's surrounded by alcohol in every kitchen shelf.  
4) Naturally, sugar regulation would likely have dire short-term effects, especially on the economy, but in the long-term it would help the society, serve to deal with obesity, dental issues, diabetes and more and would as a result yield a healthier, and thus more productive society. It is therefore in the state's interest to intervene on this subject if they care for the long-term economy and society.    
5) That said I am uncertain what would be the most optimal way to regulate sugar; removing sugar from schools and banning selling soft drinks to &amp;lt;13 year olds seem a decent move - something alike was introduced in [Russia](http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2923705/Children-banned-buying-fizzy-drinks-Coca-Cola-Dr-Pepper-Russia.html). ~~Introducing a sugar tax for sugar products could be another way.~~(Nevermind because this would affect raw sugar, not my intent) The most radical but probably the most effective way would be to regulate amount of sugar per 100 ml/100 g/3.5 oz in all products sold and reduce it to a reasonable level like ~5 g/0.2 oz(5%~) with an exception made for pastries and other wholly-sugary products; something alike was introduced, albeit only for children in [UK](http://www.epha.org/a/2554).  
6) *added point to clear confusion* Since sugar is essential to most diets in reasonable amounts, I do not suggest a sugar ban nor a reduction that would affect raw sugar. I merely advocate regulation of added sugar where its presence is not necessary, such as soft drinks and most market foods with added sugar but NOT e.g. pastries and NOT regulate natural sugar products such as fruit/juices. I do NOT wish to regulate carbohydrates, merely added sugars.  
7) Assuming drug regulation of alcohol, cigarettes and other drugs both soft and hard is valid for their respective health and societal concerns, sugar is comparably uncontrolled in terms of regulation and therefore deserves more regulatory attention especially considering comparative health and addiction risks.  
8) I admit I did not consider basic foods in the equation, I mostly was concerned with added sugars in sugary drinks and foods that do not require it in large amounts, such as cereal, yoghurts etc and not basic foods such as bread.

That said I believe sugar should be regulated. CMV :)



_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28061655491.0" user="orochidp" delta="False">
    <text>Sugar is a drug if you rewrite the definition of "drug" to remove the food exclusion. 

Sugars are just as addictive as carbohydrates in general, as they all tend to break down in the body to the same substance. Controlling sugar contents but still selling fries and breads is disingenuous at best, and an absolute waste of time and resources. Two slices of bread have more total carbohydrates than a Snickers bar. Will you limit bread in addition to sugary snacks? 

In summary: Sugar is, in fact, not a drug. Regulating calorie intake in a nation where children are starving is not a wise decision.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061662779.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>I mentioned in other comments, that I do not mean to target raw sugar or the likes of pastries, but mostly target products with added sugars where their presence is not necessary.  
Sugars are not created equal; you will not - as far as I'm concerned - get addicted to sugar by eating bread(unless it's some very sweet bread I guess) - but you can by eating sugary yoghurts, sugary cereals, sugary drinks etc - Nor can you get addicted to fries(that I know of).   
I do not mean to target carbohydrates, merely added sugars and as far as I know that's a big difference.  
Healthy alternatives are too few and won't push out into the mainstream solely because they're not addictive.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061666993.0" user="orochidp" delta="False">
    <text>[Simply incorrect.](http://www.gnolls.org/905/mechanisms-of-sugar-addiction-or-why-youre-addicted-to-bread/)

Eating spoonfuls of sugar or eating the grainiest of whole grain breads, you get "addicted" just the same. Fruits or candy, just the same. Soda or rice, all the same.

EDIT: Meant to post [this](http://ajcn.nutrition.org/content/76/1/5.full), but my clipboard hates me.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061675555.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Hm. Interesting. TIL.  
Surely though, there is merit to regulating sugar whenever possible to products that do not require added sugars for their attractiveness. Otherwise you'll be met with a trend where people crave more sugar and products will eventually have more of them and none of the products will need them but will have them just so they're bought more frequently. This worrying trend for societies and their healthcare and this has to stop *at some point*, agreed?   
Also I still do not understand your argument of sugar not being a drug; sure it's omnipresent in foods, but its drug-like effects and the need to stop the trend of ever more sugary products trend should be dealt with eventually.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061720105.0" user="orochidp" delta="False">
    <text>I disagree still. I don't believe it's my government's responsibility to govern my diet. They've made great strides in giving me the information needed to make the best decisions about my diet, and for that I am grateful. Education is always more valuable than regulation, in my opinion. I feel it's wrong to penalize the majority for the actions of the minority, and that's exactly what would happen. 

&amp;gt; Also I still do not understand your argument of sugar not being a drug; sure it's omnipresent in foods, but its drug-like effects and the need to stop the trend of ever more sugary products trend should be dealt with eventually. 

Sugar is not "in" food, it *is* food. Sugar, in it's purest form, is the main energy source of your body. It's "drug-like" effects include living. Since sugar is a food, it's immediately not a drug based simply on the definition of the word. Having side effects doesn't make something a drug, side effects are a symptom of your body being one giant runaway chemical reaction constantly teetering outside of equilibrium. It's side effects are common across many foods with many different chemical makeups. At it's core, you cannot blame sugar alone for anything you have pinned on it. Obesity can be explained by a shift from physical jobs to sedentary ones, longer commutes requiring vehicles instead of walking, more entertainment sources keeping children indoors instead of playing outside, a media culture that portrays parks and sidewalks as the places where murders happen, and so on and so on. Dental issues can be caused by many things, including tobacco, alcohol, acidic foods, generally poor hygiene, and so on and so on. Diabetes is caused either by genetics or obesity, which, again, has a tenuous link at best to sugar. 

You're blaming complex issues on one source, when the source isn't even as harmful as you expected in the first place. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061744832.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>The fact is the effects  are for the vast majority considering the obesity rate, not of the minority and the trend is towards ever more sugary and thus addictive and more unhealthy products.  
I repeat, I do not consider this a dietary concern, but a society-wide health concern and no education will be effective when most people are addicted and the market is free to feed their cravings without limit, giving them ever more sugar in daily foods as years go on. Much education will do for you when large amounts of sugar are in your daily products. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061778530.0" user="Heroic-Dose" delta="False">
    <text>You don't consider diet a dietary concern?  Education is of course effective, obesity has actually been dropping in the USA. Health food is a major trend as well. If I drink a soda once a day there's no harm at all. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28061794604.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Well I'm european, so obesity has been only growing here. Iirc US has 80%sh overweight, so you really can only improve from there.  
Education surely helps - no doubt about that - but is no long term solution as long as markets are given free reign to add as much sugar as they want to daily products. 
When what you consider daily or normal foods make you gain weight when 20 years ago the same foods in the same amounts would be reasonably healthy, isn't it concerning?  Normally you'd leave such things to the market, but I doubt in its power considering you're dealing with addiction.  
I do not believe in health food; in many cases it's just a tag to make the same things more expensive.(much like "eco" food)   
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062424108.0" user="orochidp" delta="False">
    <text>[Except that "overweight" status is based on long-disproved math.](http://www.npr.org/templates/story/story.php?storyId=106268439)

I'm part of the "overweight" population despite having a low body fat percentage and walking an average of 5 miles a day with lots of working out. My muscular frame isn't accounted for in the math, just height and weight. Purely flawed. [And simply blaming sugar is foolhardy at best.](http://www.cdc.gov/obesity/data/adult.html)

Some races have close to fifty percent, other races have 10%. There's the same amount of sugar available to all. Asians have rice, an incredibly high glycemic index food, as a staple of their diet yet have the lowest body fat in the world. If sugar is the cause, this simply could not be true.

Furthermore, the maps aren't uniform. For the US, the obesity maps trend towards major cities and poverty zones. The poor simply get fatter more than the average. There are many explanations for this (pizza costs the same as a salad but feeds 4x the people, for example), but you really cannot sit there and blame sugar for such a wide-spread issue.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062712915.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Even if you discount for semantics in statistical choices, you'd see that close to half of people are in fact over weight, which is still a significant portion.  
Naturally, socioeconomic/racial factors do take part.  
I did not refer to, due to lack of better term, "natural" sugars you see in e.g. rice, fruit or milk. Rice is very healthy now that you mention it and can be considered one of the main reasons behind asian diet being more successful.  
I was only concerned with added ones, that penetrate daily foods. If there is a trend towards more and more sugary foods in foods that were considered reasonably or totally healthy before and had little to no sugar but now have way beyond healthy daily sugar intake margin portions and there's only more added as time goes on, surely someone has to put a stop to that, correct?  
As far as I'm concerned the increase of sugar in daily products are one of the leading causes of obesity, but of course it's not the only reason. From my understanding you consider another reason to be the main one?
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062838031.0" user="orochidp" delta="False">
    <text>What daily foods are penetrated with sugar, though? Maybe it's different in your country, but... Let's hit the cupboard, shall we?

Meats and cheeses: no added sugars.  
Rice: tons of sugar, but none added.  
Pasta: decent amount of carbs, but no sugar.  
Jarred pasta sauce: sugary, but none added.  
Bread: no sugar added.  
Instant oatmeal: sugar added to the tune of 43 calories. Wowzerz!  
Milk: no sugar added.  
Deli meats: no sugar added.  
Mustard: no sugars at all.  
Vegetables: sugars vary, but none added.

Now, to snacks!

Potato chips: no added sugars.  
Chocolate: obviously sugary.  
Pretzels: sugar added to the tune of 12 calories per serving.  
Cheez-Its: no sugar added.

Where exactly is this demonic sugar drug outbreak? Out of all of the "daily food" I've checked, the sugars are so low that it's a non-issue. Once again, your country may be different, but unless you're eating nothing but candy, sugar will never be a significant calorie source.
</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28062905315.0" user="kfijatass" delta="False">
    <text>Bread has a lot of sugar, actually.  
Yoghurts, cereal, most breakfast foods, all types of soft drinks, energy drinks, those ripoff 20% juices,  to name a few. Most canned,  packaged and processed foods as well. Those especially as they're often much cheaper than healthy raw products.  
Youre kind of derailing to raw produce and those are not my point.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28063196573.0" user="orochidp" delta="True">
    <text>&amp;gt; Bread has a lot of sugar, actually. 

Whoops, you're right. One brand of wheat bread had 2 grams added per two slices, the brand of potato bread had 5 grams per roll. That's a whopping 8 and 20 calories, respectively.

I'm not sure why you think there's so much sugar in everything, though. An average day for me, I consume half a teaspoon of sugar between all sources. If people are subsisting on soda and sweets, of course sugar would contribute to their poor health. That's not a result of "sugar being in everything", it's a result of poor decision making skills. You can't make stupidity illegal.

As for canned and processed foods, their sodium contents should be the issue, not their sugar contents. Sugar contributes to spoilage, so it would be foolish to sugar up canned goods. All of the canned goods in my cupboard contain 3 or less grams of sugar.

As for soda and juice, if those are your main beverages, you've got more to worry about than just the sugar content. The acidity of those will kill your teeth faster than any sugar content. The phosphoric acid, in large doses, will throw off your body's calcium absorption. Juices, pure or not, have way, way more sugars than any soda, and fructose is more harmful to your health than soda. 

I'm really, really struggling to find your point at all. We need to remove sugar from junk food? Why? That's the point of junk food. If people are stupid enough to live on horrible food, then they deserve their misfortune. The only solution is education. 

In essence, the only valid point you've struck is that there's too much sugar in soda. Soda manufacturers have already put out sodas with no sugar, reduced sugar, and sugar alternatives from natural sources such as stevia. Market pressures work way better than any proposed legislation, your point was defeated before it begun. Every other source of sugary-ness comes from dessert and snack foods, and those should never be counted as a "daily food."

It just simply falls flat on its face no matter what angle I look at it from. Soda isn't a daily food. Snack cakes aren't a daily food. Sweet breads aren't a daily food. If sugar is "scary" to you because it's addictive and has health effects, all carbohydrates share this same quality. If you think there's more of it and in more sources than ever, I'm seeing neither an increase in quantity nor an increase in sources. Sugar is no more harmful than anything else you eat, why exactly are you railing against it?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
