<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="8" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477053459.0" user="PM_MeTittiesOrKitty" delta="False">
    <text>You want [Lipstick Lesbians](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lipstick_lesbian). There's enough of them for there to be a wikipedia article about them, and not that this is evidence for a larger group, but I know two "Lipstick" Lesbians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477079274.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>The Wikipedia article covers the idea but not significant lesbians who match that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477108559.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Why do you want anecdotes if you’re making a statement about a general popular ?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477152154.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>To prove the idea of lipstick lesbian is common among the lesbian community.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477312699.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Just check the further reading and references in the Wikipedia page</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477560243.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Can you show me significant sources that prove the existence of lipstick lesbians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477562561.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Did you attempt what I suggested</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477582426.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Lipstick Lesbians

There are too many unrelated sources so find me some clear ones.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477642754.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>https://www.thepinknews.com/2017/08/14/10-problems-every-femme-lesbian-will-relate-to/</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477655123.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;[https://www.thepinknews.com/2017/08/14/10-problems-every-femme-lesbian-will-relate-to/](https://www.thepinknews.com/2017/08/14/10-problems-every-femme-lesbian-will-relate-to/)

It doesn't list particular lesbians who are femme.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477713540.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>Again, why do you want anecdotes? This is better evidence for it in the lesbian community than anecdotes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477736254.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Any sources?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477786938.0" user="Nrdman" delta="False">
    <text>What do you mean?  I asked why you wanted anecdotes instead of an article referencing the femm lesbians</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477795617.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Because then I know from personal stories that they are common and they exist. I'm okay with articles as long as they show accurate scientific data that there are a lot of femme lesbians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477824757.0" user="Nrdman" delta="True">
    <text>You know femme lesbians are common??? What’s the point of your post I’m confused

I don’t think that data exists. I don’t think there’s data on percentage of lesbians who identify as butch either</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
