<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477036085.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>try looking at porn, a lot of long haired feminine lesbians there, and while the clothing tends to go off very fast its usually feminine</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477096403.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Porn is scripted and actors are acting. It's a movie so it doesn't change anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477128643.0" user="jumpup" delta="False">
    <text>porn does have an amateur category,  and how would you refer to a person engaged in lesbian sex exclusively?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477446068.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>Lesbian actors exist.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477598712.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Actors who are femme lesbians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477680319.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>You said porn doesn't count because they're acting. A *ton* of lesbian porn is femme. There's no possible way they're all straight.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477710438.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>What if they are forced to be femme according to the script?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477730928.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>*All* of them? There's way too much lesbian porn for that. The most likely explanation here is just that you don't think attractive lesbians are 'really' lesbian when in truth, women appreciate feminine clothes, grooming and makeup much better than men. A guy typically can't even tell the difference between natural and no makeup make-up. I imagine it's a lot more fun to get dressed up for other women who really see and appreciate the effort.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477744951.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I don't think porn is an accurate representation of the lesbian community. Most lesbians aren't porn stars.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42478040435.0" user="GameProtein" delta="False">
    <text>I didn't say it was. It's also really easy to look up lesbian communities online and see who's in them. Femme is literally a lesbian dating category. You seem to not be interested in that so I presented an alternative.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
