<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="6" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477171139.0" user="Bobbob34" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine.

People believe the Earth is flat. Doesn't make it so.

&gt;, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist.

Do you want to be the one to tell her

[https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/47/Portia\_de\_Rossi.jpg](https://static.wikia.nocookie.net/munster/images/9/97/Portia-de-rossi-picture-1.jpeg/revision/latest?cb=20120727011310)

she doesn't exist?

Or her? [https://parade.com/.image/ar\_1:1%2Cc\_fill%2Ccs\_srgb%2Cfl\_progressive%2Cq\_auto:good%2Cw\_1200/MTk2Mzg5MjQ3MzgzNTEyNzIy/cara-delevingne-nfl-honors.jpg](https://parade.com/.image/ar_1:1%2Cc_fill%2Ccs_srgb%2Cfl_progressive%2Cq_auto:good%2Cw_1200/MTk2Mzg5MjQ3MzgzNTEyNzIy/cara-delevingne-nfl-honors.jpg)

&gt;. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything.

How did you do that? Do you think maybe you're just ridiculously assuming everyone who looks what you're describing as butch is a lesbian and assuming people you don't think fit that are straight?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477200558.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, just because you can't see something doesn't make it less true just like flat earth. However, how do you know that the femme lesbians are not in the minority?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477226166.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="False">
    <text>You're moving the goalpost. You initially said that they didn't exist, now you're attempting to claim they're a minority.

Could you answer what criteria you used when you "searched" for them? What exactly did that process look like?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477307809.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I searched for popular lesbian celebrities.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477407056.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="False">
    <text>That explains a lot.

Reality is, a lot celebrities (especially those who are more traditionally attractive and match the criteria you're looking for) are still closeted when it comes to the public.

A lot of celebs who have come out talked about how they were heavily discouraged to go public or confirm anything.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477418034.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>But where else can you find good sources about the number of femme lesbians aside from looking up famous lesbians?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477459479.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="True">
    <text>Looking out into the real world.

This is the flaw in your criteria. You likely assume any female you see out in the real world is straight is they aren't stereotypically butch. Straight-passing is a very real thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477597190.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>Δ Thanks for pointing out some more flaws in my view. Sexual orientation does not determine the behavior of people and some women may already be lesbian. I'm just unaware of it. However, to prove this is true, I will need a definitive source showing the sheer amount of femme lesbians.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477714053.0" user="HauntedReader" delta="True">
    <text>But that definitive source isn't going to exist because that isn't something that people are really tracking.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
