<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2366753957.0" index="10" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/1353r1h/cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch_looking_very_masculine/">
    <title>CMV: Most lesbians are butch (looking very masculine)</title>
    <original_poster>clavicle524</original_poster>
    <original_post>Many people consider it a negative stereotype that lesbians act very masculine or dress in a masculine way. I disagree. I believe most if not all lesbians are butch and there is no such thing as a lesbian who dresses very feminine. While a lesbian who dresses in a masculine way (short hair, traditional male clothing) and is feminine can exist, a lesbian who looks feminine (long, flowing hair, clear skin, a narrow waist, traditional female dress, and clothing, and little or no body hair or facial hair) does not exist. I’ve searched far and wide for lesbians who look very feminine but I couldn’t find anything. Just to let you guys know, I’m not saying being a butch lesbian or being masculine is bad. I’m merely stating why I believe the stereotype of Lesbians looking masculine is very true.

CMV.

&amp;#x200B;

Edit: I've changed my view now thanks to the sources and the information people gave me. If you wish to challenge another aspect of my view, please read the delta log of my post first ([https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas\_awarded\_in\_cmv\_most\_lesbians\_are\_butch/](https://www.reddit.com/r/DeltaLog/comments/1354bnm/deltas_awarded_in_cmv_most_lesbians_are_butch/)) so you don't use the other arguments the other commentators used before.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="42477377292.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Quite plainly, this just isn't what it's like if you go an hang out with a bunch of lesbians.  I've lived in SF most of my life and there are lesbians of all sorts.  In my circle of friends I would say that most of the gay women are _not_ butch.  

For an easy example, here is a bunch of gay people in photos, selected randomly other than that they are succesful enough to make the article:  https://outstanding.involverolemodels.org/poll/2020-top-100-lgbt-executives/

Here's a list of female lesbian athletes:  https://www.ranker.com/list/famous-lesbian-athletes/lgbt

I'd say the distribution of butch vs. feminine favors fem.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477454876.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>There are too many athletes listed there. Is there a definitive number on how much those are femme?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477576013.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>Since it's an utterly pointless thing to quantify and people do things like change their haircuts all the time I don't think you'll see anyone counting these up in a formal way.  But...a scan of those listed should make it clear that it's not "most" that are butch.

The point here is that you've got a massive bias problem here which is that you SEE people as lesbian when they are butch, but you don't know the sexual orientation of most people you see at all.  So...way more of the people you see and recognize as lesbians are butch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477663745.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I scanned through it, a majority of them are butch.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477724268.0" user="iamintheforest" delta="False">
    <text>ha.  no.

but...perhaps your idea of what is feminine and what is not is different than mine.  which...is part of the problem with your view.  there have been times when what some call "butch" was mainstream hairstyling and others where it was not.

And...this:  https://www.amazon.com/A1CNow-SelfCheck-Analyzer-Test-Strips/dp/B07FMLTTH6/ref=asc_df_B07FMLTTH6/?tag=hyprod-20&amp;linkCode=df0&amp;hvadid=652391633214&amp;hvpos=&amp;hvnetw=g&amp;hvrand=15771823527155563353&amp;hvpone=&amp;hvptwo=&amp;hvqmt=&amp;hvdev=c&amp;hvdvcmdl=&amp;hvlocint=&amp;hvlocphy=9032330&amp;hvtargid=pla-2007235261563&amp;psc=1&amp;gclid=CjwKCAjwxr2iBhBJEiwAdXECw82-8hGNmovHKywFHni80W9pTrFFg7YQXWFTMr4IWYzKeKmnyOykQhoC1fcQAvD_BwE</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="42477749938.0" user="clavicle524" delta="False">
    <text>I admitted my definition of what is feminine is flawed. I think it's pretty much impossible since people have nay different interpretations of what it means to be feminine.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
