<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2512463257.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/15jut21/cmv_québec_was_right_to_ban_prayer_rooms_religion/">
    <title>CMV: Québec was right to ban prayer rooms, religion doesn't belong in schools.</title>
    <original_poster>Watchyobackistan</original_poster>
    <original_post>Public Schools are secular organizations, and no religion should be present there. I apply this equally across all religions. No prayer rooms, no cross necklaces, no hijabs, no sikh turbans, no jew hats. School is not a place for religion, and it does not belong there. You wanna have religion in school, go find a theorcracy. Québec is making the right call to ban the prayer rooms, no religion should be tolerated in schools.

I can't even see how anybody would think otherwise, why would you allow religion in schools? France makes kids take off their hijabs, and nobody who's opinion matters is upset about that.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43236476061.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>So if Muslim students need to leave school now several times per day to pray, is that really a good outcome? Seems like it would be a lot less disruptive to just have a room set aside for "meditation" of many different faiths, or just a space in the library or whatever, and call it a day. 

At the school that I work at smoking is banned. Smoking doesn't belong in schools, we can all agree on that. But we do tolerate a smoking area that we know that students use which is on the edge of school property - because while students smoking is of course not ideal, it would be much worse to have the students who smoke leave school grounds several times per day.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236483328.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>No, they just won't pray during school hours. School is for learning, not praying.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236504217.0" user="kneeco28" delta="False">
    <text>"School is for learning, not shitting, so we got rid of the washrooms" is a good way to make it so school is no longer for learning.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236508486.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>A mandatory bodily function isn't the same as a religion.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236519115.0" user="2-3inches" delta="False">
    <text>Eating isn’t mad story during school hours</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236525786.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Dude, you're missing the point. Eating helps kids durings school, religion doesn't</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236541004.0" user="MercurianAspirations" delta="False">
    <text>How do you know? I would assume that for students for whom religion is very important, not being able to freely exercise it might be quite distressing</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236551229.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>That's a them problem, religion belongs in designated places and at home like in Europe, not in public. In France even wearing a cross outdoors is illegal.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236598137.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="False">
    <text>France is a terrible country, you shouldn’t try to emulate them.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236603984.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>They seem to be doing better than the US</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236613756.0" user="prollywannacracker" delta="False">
    <text>What metrics are you using to conclude that France is doing "better than the US"?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236630846.0" user="Watchyobackistan" delta="False">
    <text>Better QOL, better HDI, free healthcare.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43236652575.0" user="KipchakVibeCheck" delta="True">
    <text>&gt; Better QOL, better HDI, free healthcare.

France has a lower HDI ranking than the USA.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
