<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2547064804.0" index="7" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/164gfs4/cmv_psychology_is_fucked_up/">
    <title>Cmv: Psychology is fucked up</title>
    <original_poster>Feisty-Permission-21</original_poster>
    <original_post>

Any major psychological study done mostly has involved unethical and morally questionable expirements behind it. Sure many good expirements have been done without harming any organism but that doesn't cause leaps in this department of science.


Things such as fear, isolation etc have only been studied by torturing and abusing many animals and humans in the past. The breakthroughs made then make psychology research today seem slow and less conclusive.


Take for example, Harlow’s Pit of Despair or Stanford Prison Expirement or The Trolley Problem  or Milgrim's shocking obidence expirement.


Most will probably know these famous expirements because of their cruelty and discoveries unlike many good and positive expirements. 



It's ironical that the feild of study which needs to understand how the brain works needs a sacrifice of morals to progress quickly.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43428289037.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>So? As long as there are ethical standards now, why does it matter?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428302241.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>It matters as the media doesn't showcase innovation done in this department these days because they are ethical and don't affect the general audience and only affect certain industries.

So most people like me at least remain unaware of latest innovation in this feild unless I google specifically about it unlike the unethical ones which I hear every week or so.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428355050.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>The media is completely separate from the field of psychology. they do not publish what should be published according to the researchers.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428433169.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>I see, That's why in the post I said that since the media causes hype for evil experiments that's why more researchers talk about it and more people are aware.

Unlike good research which doesn't really get talked about much, I find makes me feel that innovation isn't done as much. 

I believe almost any innovation in this field  would be beneficial to humans and should have been talked about more as a whole given that this feild works with the human mind and more in lieu of many of us, unlike some other feilds which stray away from everyday human needs like maths or physics (unless required as a job)</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428619485.0" user="Square-Dragonfruit76" delta="False">
    <text>So you don't have a problem with psychology? Just the way it is reported?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43428648984.0" user="Feisty-Permission-21" delta="False">
    <text>My view of psychology before the post was that, it's not innovative because I was mostly ignorant of the new inventions that I didn't google, unlike the older ones which are often talked about around me and myself consuming such media makes me think that morally grey standards of earlier experiments made more widespread discoveries.


But after getting more knowledge on it, I realised the issue was in the stigma and lack of awareness and reporting of it and not the lack of innovation.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
