<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2549309201.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/165sjkh/cmv_the_us_should_mandate_all_feesexpenses_be/">
    <title>CMV: The US Should Mandate all Fees/Expenses be Disclosed Up Front As Much As Possible</title>
    <original_poster>Front_Many_6231</original_poster>
    <original_post>I believe the United States should legally require ticket sellers like Ticketmaster to provide prices inclusive of all fees and surcharges when shopping for tickets.

Hidden fees distort the free market and make it harder for customers to fairly do price comparisons. These fees are deceptive and can often add up to 40% of the advertised price.

I’m tired of clicking on a $49 dollar ticket for a show to find out it’s really $70 when I go to checkout.  Or a $50/night hotel room having a mandatory $30/night “resort fee”

Similar policy should apply to things like hotel rooms, car rentals, phone bills and all sorts of other consumer purchased goods.

If a fee is variable (like shipping) or taxes, I could see that not being included in an advertised price if they can’t be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.  a TV commercial for a national brand, they could say “$499 + tax” since the tax is different everywhere.

However, for sales where the tax CAN be determined, it should be included in the price.  A hotel room should advertise the total price, since the tax calculation is based on where the hotel is, and can be reasonably determined at the time of advertising.

This greater price transparency would greatly benefit consumers.</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="43441469874.0" user="BOfficeStats" delta="False">
    <text>I think this would be a good idea but any regulation would have to allow for it to be made clear that the fees are different from the "base price" of the product or service.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43441534698.0" user="Front_Many_6231" delta="False">
    <text>Are the fees required?  Then they aren’t meaningfully different than the base price. 

If they want to itemize, that’s fine by me, just don’t tack on stuff at the last minute</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442143070.0" user="Pac_Eddy" delta="False">
    <text>They can break it down all they want as long as they list the total cost first and most prominently.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448636761.0" user="BOfficeStats" delta="False">
    <text>I agree.  That makes sense.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43442552879.0" user="really_random_user" delta="False">
    <text>So basically how it works in most of the world

The "starting from price" is what a customer pays forbthe most basic option

Like for a flight, it's what someone traveling with just a backpack, would pay</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448643877.0" user="BOfficeStats" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Like for a flight, it's what someone traveling with just a backpack, would pay

Yeah, that's a good example.  They are all buying the same base product, just with different fees added on top of it depending on what they want to buy.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43444775306.0" user="Minister_for_Magic" delta="False">
    <text>Why? If the fees are mandated by government then everyone has to pay them. Companies should only be allowed to market the top line price and break out what is paid as "tax".</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43445027845.0" user="NaturalCarob5611" delta="False">
    <text>What if it's state and local government?

I live in a metro area that spans two states, fifteen counties, and something like 85 municipalities. Within a twenty mile radius you can find sales taxes ranging from about 7% up to 11%. Even within the municipality I live in there are three different economic zones with different sales tax rates. If you had a chain in the area that wanted to advertise their price on the radio or TV, they can't do the top line price unless they're going to eat the difference between their more expensive locations and less expensive locations.

It's also an issue for manufacturers that want to print a price on a product. I used to work at a bookstore, and most books would have prices printed on them in USD and Canadian dollars. They'd ship all over two countries and the tax adjustment would be done at the register. For the store I worked in, we just had to take the book out of the box it came in and put it on the shelf - putting price tags on them would have been a lot more work, and repricing everything when the city, state, or county adjusted sales tax by a tenth of a percent would have been a massive undertaking.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43445202597.0" user="NJBarFly" delta="False">
    <text>Why doesn't the base price include the fees? Imagine going to a restaurant that advertised $5 burgers, but then charged a $4 grill fee, $4 table fee, and a $6 plate fee. They should just call it a $19 burger because the fees are made up bullshit.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43445814632.0" user="niberungvalesti" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;$4 grill fee, $4 table fee, and a $6 plate fee

Ah, so what restaurants and bars did after COVID to recoup their losses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446835002.0" user="Chaghatai" delta="False">
    <text>Only the ones ran by assholes</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447682581.0" user="billythesid" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;Ah, so what restaurants and bars ~~did~~ *are still doing* after COVID to recoup their losses.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43446379926.0" user="spiral8888" delta="False">
    <text>I think Italy has something called coperto, which means a flat fee per person eating added to the bill.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447350983.0" user="Vobat" delta="False">
    <text>Isn’t that just what a tip is?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43449609711.0" user="clearlybraindead" delta="False">
    <text>Tips are voluntary</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448631898.0" user="BOfficeStats" delta="False">
    <text>I think it makes sense to separate the "base price" from the fees to make it more clear to customers what they are paying for.  Preventing them from providing a breakdown might make it harder for customers to understand what they are buying and how the price is determined.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448920112.0" user="NJBarFly" delta="False">
    <text>I'm saying there shouldn't be a bunch of made up fees. Those should be part of the base price. I checked out of a hotel last week that charged a "bed fee". A bed is an expected part of the room. There shouldn't be a fee.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447443261.0" user="Equivalent-Peanut-23" delta="False">
    <text>The problem with that is the number of businesses that have converted large portions of the base price into mandatory fees.  Hotels will advertise a room price, but then charge a mandatory "resort fee" for staying at the hotel.  Airlines advertise a base fare, but then charge mandatory fees for issuance of the ticket, use of fuel.  Delivery services will sell membership programs that include $0 delivery fees, but then tack on a service fee.  

If something is externally imposed or optional, it can be a fee.  But otherwise it's just false advertising.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43448656635.0" user="BOfficeStats" delta="False">
    <text>Maybe have it set up so it lists the total price at the top, then below it there can be a breakdown of the extra costs.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="43447623699.0" user="Aviyan" delta="False">
    <text>If the fees are fixed and mandatory then why does it matter? They can list down the breakdown of the cost on the receipt but if they are advertising a price it should include them.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
