<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="258580368.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49y9w0/cmv_to_combat_rape_and_counteract_the_general/">
    <title>CMV: To combat rape and counteract the general physical advantage men have over women, girls should be taught self-defence at school, specifically anti-rape techniques.</title>
    <original_poster>Wonderslave</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____

During a self-defence class I attended, the instructor demonstrated several techniques for women to use when attacked by a rapist. He explained that the positions a male rapist would need to assume to rape a female victim are actually extremely vulnerable from a ground fighting perspective. Correctly applied Brazilian jui-jitsu would use the attacker's weight against him and provide an opportunity for the victim to attack (the eyes, usually) and then escape.

I'm not a martial arts expert but if this is all true, then girls should be taught to defend themselves from rape and assault, possibly in their early teens. It's not a panacea for sexual violence, I admit, but it will empower women physically and be an effective deterrent.  

Edit: Found a Youtube video with the kind of techniques I'm talking about: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6D8r-wH0dkk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28351748453.0" user="Funcuz" delta="False">
    <text>Most people are generally afraid to fight against anybody they perceive as being physically superior. For that reason, I don't think it would do much at all to teach women who don't have confidence in their ability to self-defend how to throw a punch or kick in the right place.

Most women aren't exposed to the harsh realities of being male. What I mean is that men are taught from birth that they'll have to take the pain one way or another and they'll have to take it at %100 ferocity. It's just assumed that in a fight, the beatdown will be relentless. Even women who believe they've experienced the rough and tumble world of men don't realize that they've always been treated with kid gloves. A man who is willing to rape a woman is not going to hold back in any way and it's unlikely that she'll be prepared for the full force of his blows.

The best thing a woman can do is arm herself with something that is quick and works on the first shot. A gun ? Not so sure I'd advocate for arming women simply because they could be raped. By that logic, every male should be armed since the chances of him being murdered or physically assaulted is an order of magnitude higher. Then we've just got a lot more problems.

No, something like a tazer or pepper spray makes the most sense in my view. Not to mention that if it falls into the rapist's hands, he can't kill her with it (which a gun may convince him to do out of convenience)

I've also noticed that people drastically over-estimate just how useful martial arts and self-defense courses are. A hardened street fighter is going to go through a weekend orange belt like butter. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351777856.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;The best thing a woman can do is arm herself with something that is quick and works on the first shot.

The problem is, that weapon does not yet exist, and a firearm is the closest you'll get.

&amp;gt;No, something like a tazer or pepper spray makes the most sense in my view. Not to mention that if it falls into the rapist's hands, he can't kill her with it (which a gun may convince him to do out of convenience)

Tasers are really finicky, and generally a bad idea to rely upon if your life is on the line. If your attacker is wearing thick clothing, it won't work. If the prongs land too close together, it won't work. If you only hit with one prong, it won't work. If the attacker is under the influence of drugs, may not work. Also, if you miss, you only get one shot.

Pepper spray is just as likely to get you as it is your attacker, especially if it's outside and there is any sort of wind. It's also not super incapacitating, and people can be trained to fight through it.

In a situation like that where you NEED to defend your life, if you can draw a taser or pepper spray, you can also draw a gun, and that's what you should be using.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28352001348.0" user="aguafiestas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; In a situation like that where you NEED to defend your life, if you can draw a taser or pepper spray, you can also draw a gun, and that's what you should be using.

Except a gun raises the stakes.  You draw a gun, you have to be willing to kill, not everyone is willing to do that.  And if things go wrong, the chances that you end up being killed go up greatly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28352015656.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;Except a gun raises the stakes.

I think that's heavily dependent on the situation at hand. To me, if you're in a situation where you need a taser in order to stop what is happening to you, that's what I would consider to be life-or-death already. I think both a taser and pepper spray already raise the stakes, especially if it's already violent.

In the situation that /u/Funcuz was describing, with the male attacking a female with basically full force, that is a life-or-death situation and needs to be handled accordingly.

Personally, I'm not a huge fan of relying on the kindness of my attacker to spare my life.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28352035851.0" user="aguafiestas" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;  think that's heavily dependent on the situation at hand. 

I think in most situations a gun clearly raises the stakes.  Obviously if the attacker already has a gun that's a different story, but if the person themselves introduces a gun where there wasn't one before, then the chances of someone getting killed go way up.  

Whether the chances of *you* being killed go up or down is probably situation dependent.

But if we're considering a situation where an assailant surprises someone so they are already physically attacking them at close range, then if you draw a weapon there is a good chance it could be wrested from your grasp and used against you.

Now, if it's a home invasion type of situation that may be different, as you could potentially use the gun to keep the attacker at a distance.

&amp;gt; To me, if you're in a situation where you need a taser in order to stop what is happening to you, that's what I would consider to be life-or-death already.

Why is that?

There are lots of times I would physically defend myself even when my life wasn't at stake.  For a physically weaker person, the use of something like a taser or pepper spray might be the only way they can do that effectively.

When you consider that rapes and other physical assaults occur at much higher rates than murders, I don't think it's a reasonable assumption that if someone is attacking you that they mean to kill you.  (Of course, this may be apparent in some particular situation).</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28352068110.0" user="ryan_m" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt;I think in most situations a gun clearly raises the stakes. Obviously if the attacker already has a gun that's a different story, but if the person themselves introduces a gun where there wasn't one before, then the chances of someone getting killed go way up.

&amp;gt;Whether the chances of you being killed go up or down is probably situation dependent.

&amp;gt;But if we're considering a situation where an assailant surprises someone so they are already physically attacking them at close range, then if you draw a weapon there is a good chance it could be wrested from your grasp and used against you.

Agreed, to an extent.  When you begin to carry a firearm, you should receive professional training on best practices as well as the laws surrounding it's use.  Part of that is knowing when it's safe to draw and when it isn't.  If you're already being physically attacked, you basically fucked up at some point already.  At that point, you have to make a determination about whether your life is in danger, and what you want to do about it.

I don't think that merely carrying a gun is enough to really escalate the situation, as long as it isn't used. Obviously, if the situation is dire enough that it needs to come out, you're already facing death or very serious injury anyways.

&amp;gt;Why is that?

&amp;gt;There are lots of times I would physically defend myself even when my life wasn't at stake. For a physically weaker person, the use of something like a taser or pepper spray might be the only way they can do that effectively.

Disparity of force is a big part of force escalation.  If I (6'4, 220) attacked my girlfriend (5'4, 130 soaking wet), that is very likely a life-or-death situation for her, because she is considerably weaker than I am. Even if I'm not going full force, she still runs a serious risk of a lot of damage being done, potentially lethal damage.

In a situation like that, she would likely be OK to use lethal force in order to stop the attack.  If it were me and another similarly sized person, neither of us would likely be OK unless some other variables change.

If an average woman is being attacked full force by an average man, that is a lethal force encounter and needs to be handled as such. Whether you choose to or not is another question, but the single most effective weapon for handling those situations is a firearm.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351885402.0" user="iheartsagan" delta="False">
    <text>By your logic, the woman's pepper spray or taser could fall into the attacker's hands just as a gun might. Obviously not as fatal, but could be detrimental to the woman's chance of escaping the situation. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
