<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="258580368.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/49y9w0/cmv_to_combat_rape_and_counteract_the_general/">
    <title>CMV: To combat rape and counteract the general physical advantage men have over women, girls should be taught self-defence at school, specifically anti-rape techniques.</title>
    <original_poster>Wonderslave</original_poster>
    <original_post>_____

During a self-defence class I attended, the instructor demonstrated several techniques for women to use when attacked by a rapist. He explained that the positions a male rapist would need to assume to rape a female victim are actually extremely vulnerable from a ground fighting perspective. Correctly applied Brazilian jui-jitsu would use the attacker's weight against him and provide an opportunity for the victim to attack (the eyes, usually) and then escape.

I'm not a martial arts expert but if this is all true, then girls should be taught to defend themselves from rape and assault, possibly in their early teens. It's not a panacea for sexual violence, I admit, but it will empower women physically and be an effective deterrent.  

Edit: Found a Youtube video with the kind of techniques I'm talking about: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6D8r-wH0dkk</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28351659303.0" user="caffeine_lights" delta="False">
    <text>This assumes most rapes are stranger rapes, which is not the case. Most rapes occur between parties where there is an established level of intimacy, in a position where the woman or girl is already vulnerable. Attack positions wouldn't help here.

Admittedly, I'm making an assumption about the kinds of positions which your instructor was referring to. If you would be able to clarify these then I can give you a stronger counter. But I'm assuming that these positions are not things like woman is lying asleep in bed, woman has taken alcohol or other drugs (perhaps without her knowledge) and is compromised because of it. Woman is already in making out position with guy in bed, etc. It also assumes that her attacker doesn't have a weapon, she isn't outnumbered and that she can easily escape from the place she's in, which isn't particularly likely if she's in a private home or hotel room, especially if she is missing some of her clothing or if her children are nearby and she doesn't feel she can leave them.

If my assumption is correct and these positions are more "how a man would approach raping a perfectly sentient woman from a position that she's not engaging in anything sexual to begin with" then this kind of self defence is extremely limited in scope, as it ignores the reality of most rape situations. It also doesn't take into account that the natural response to sexual violence (especially when the victim is already in a vulnerable position) is to freeze and/or stop resisting, sometimes mental dissociation also occurs. Similar to the animal instinct to play dead, this is an unconscious instinct which is designed to minimise trauma by allowing the assault to complete with as little risk of extraneous violence as possible. Since men are usually stronger than women, there is a very real danger that a woman responding with violence or self defence will receive stronger violence in return; in most cases this isn't a smart move unless the weaker person is extremely well trained or has the element of surprise.

There is an argument that it's still useful to teach women self-defence techniques against stranger rape because although these comprise a smaller number of rapes, it still helps against that smaller number, which is better than nothing. I disagree with this and think it is more useful to teach both men and women basic self defence to ward off any kind of attacker, because this would be more useful and would also serve to be protective against rape since if a stranger is about to rape you, it's going to be fairly obvious that he wants to do you some violence whether or not his intent to rape is clear. So general self defence would both fulfil the extremely rare stranger rape scenario and also be useful in other situations, meaning it's more useful than only self defence taught with the goal of avoiding stranger rape.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351677225.0" user="Wonderslave" delta="False">
    <text>I think the wording of the post indicates that the hypothetical victims I'm referring to would be both conscious and in control of their motor functions. Not drugged or sleeping. 

In terms of physical positions, I recall most vividly that of a man on top of a woman facing upwards. I think he had techniques for the others but it was a long time ago (I'm hoping someone more knowledgable on the subject chimes in at some point). It doesn't really matter if there's making out happening already, the goal of the defensive measures would be to prevent penetration. 
Similarly, whether or not the rapist is a stranger is irrelevant to the victim's lack of consent, and to the methods. The physical mechanics of the crime are the same. The defensive actions would be just as effective with a stranger as with a friend or an acquaintance.

The natural response has its purpose, but it shouldn't be the only response available. The training would provide an alternative, more effective method, than the natural response or even a violent response that lacks training.

It may not always be the smart move to fight back but that's any victim's right, and like I said - and I'm not an expert on martial arts - the position a male rapist needs to be in to do the rape, makes him vulnerable to the point that correctly timed action would negate any physical advantage he may have.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351708342.0" user="caffeine_lights" delta="False">
    <text>I think your position (if you'll pardon the pun!) is weakened considerably if you can't even remember what these positions are, but okay.

The physical mechanics of stranger rape might be the same as of rape when the attacker is known to the victim but the psychological effects are extremely different, which does matter. It takes an extraordinary amount of training to have something be so natural and automatic that a person could do it under psychological stress, and this isn't appropriate when the physical mechanics of consensual sex are also the same as rape but don't require any self defence.

&amp;gt; The natural response has its purpose, but it shouldn't be the only response available.

Then you totally misunderstood what I meant. When you're performing an instinctual response, you literally don't have anything else available. Training or not. You'd have to be trained to automatically resist all sex, which most women don't want to do.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351732367.0" user="Wonderslave" delta="False">
    <text>They were the most common rape positions, if that helps. There were techniques for being attacked from behind, on the ground, et cetera. Can't see how that weakens my position when my assertion is about the teaching of these techniques, not the efficacy of individual techniques. 

I'll grant you the fact that psychology is important, which is why it's a big part of self-defence training. And yes, the training must be repeated in order for it to become automatic (they teach that too).

Instinctual responses can be overcome - human beings do have that capacity. A person has a much better chance of overcoming or resisting an instinctual response if they've had training in how to do just that. 
Human instincts are not fixed. The basis of your argument seems to be that this type of training wouldn't be effective with your primary reason being: the instinct to not resist is too strong? You'll need to prove it. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351750976.0" user="caffeine_lights" delta="False">
    <text>The most common rape positions? I smell bullshit here. I can't imagine that such a thing is recorded. Sounds like somebody's IDEA of common rape positions. Unless you can direct me to a source where actual rape positions are documented, I can't accept that this is a thing. It just seems too implausible.

Also, the efficacy of techniques is central to your argument, too, because if the techniques are ineffective, then it becomes illogical to teach them. If the purpose of teaching something is to make a situation safer, then it should actually make that situation safer. If it doesn't, there is no point.

I guess I'm not saying that instinct is too strong to ever be overriden. You're correct that it's not. But to develop something which challenges an instinct as strong as a survival instinct, you almost have to make it so strong that it overrides an instinct and becomes instinct-like itself. To compare, this is like military level training, which seems really extreme in itself. Also, how would this be possible, when rape positions are, essentially, sex positions? The only difference between sex and rape is a lack of consent. How do you develop a new instinct for a situation where most of the time that new instinct is not needed? 

I can only see two possibilities: 

1. Overgeneralisation. You develop the instinct to violently assault anybody who tries to have sex with you ever. This doesn't seem like a good idea to me since most women like sex and want to have sex which is consensual, not avoid all sex.

2. Specialisation. You practice getting into a sexual situation and then introduce an element of fear or psychological trauma, so that the new instinct is associated only with the combination of sex + fear. This seems unhelpful, too, both because it is traumatic in itself, which isn't a great start for something which is supposed to prevent trauma, and it also seems like it would have a pretty high risk of just creating a negative association with sexual situations, which goes back to point #1 - women don't want to be prevented from having sex just because they don't want to get raped.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351879758.0" user="iheartsagan" delta="False">
    <text>I have been in a similar self-defence class like the one OP is describing. It shouldn't matter, but for the purposes of this argument I will disclose that I am a woman in my 20s. My mother was raped twice when she was in her early teens on two separate occasions - both by men that she knew, i.e. not a "stranger attack". It was her who suggested I go to the classes as a way to empower myself. 

There are many things I cannot recall from the classes as it was sometime ago and to my discredit, I do not practice the moves as much as I should. Albeit, I mentally go through what the instructor taught us on a daily basis. I know the basics of what to do in certain positions, and although it seems counter-intuitive, the main lesson is that you aim to get the attacker as close to you as possible. For example, if you are on your back with your attacker attempting the missionary position, your aim is to wrap your legs around him and pull him towards your body. This closeness affords you the opportunity to wrap your arms around his head and use your fingers to gouge out his eyes (ew). 

Thankfully, I have not been in a position to try out these moves but knowing that I have the mental capacity to drive my thoughts to react in this way is an empowering feeling. I am already one-up on my attacker because he is unaware of what I *am* aware of. By thinking about it daily and practicing with a male partner in non-harmful way i.e. just getting the muscle memory in order, a woman can empower her body and her mind to react in a positive, assertive, and strong manner if she finds herself in this situation. 

I'd also like to add that it's irrelevant whether or not the attacker is someone the woman knows or if he (or she) is a stranger. The point that OP is making is that women should be equipped to handle such a situation, although this is not the only way to deal with rape as a society. Sexual repression has got to go. We need open and honest sexual education from an appropriate age. This will take time and money and an allowance of free thinking, but in the meantime we can teach our girls to empower themselves. 

EDIT: Grammar. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351910826.0" user="caffeine_lights" delta="False">
    <text>Thanks, it's useful to know how this kind of class would actually work rather than just going by some vague idea of "a self defence class". I still am not particularly convinced that to roll classes like these out to all women is helpful, but I can now see how such a thing might actually *be* empowering.

Are we supposed to award deltas if we're not the OP? This has changed my view slightly.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28351918789.0" user="iheartsagan" delta="True">
    <text>In what way are you not convinced that these classes would be helpful?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
