<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="2676326580.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/189eyt0/cmv_its_problematic_when_americans_claim_other/">
    <title>CMV: it's problematic when Americans claim other national identities as their own, purely due to their ancestors country of origin.</title>
    <original_poster>liltooter</original_poster>
    <original_post>Trying to understand the American tendancy to say they are Italian/ Irish/ Scottish, even if they've never been there. How much of this is culture, how much of this is upholding damaging stereotypes of other nationalities?

So I know this could be a potentially touchy subject for some, but it's a topic that invokes a lot of different emotions from me, so I'd like to hear some genuine American opinions on this.

As a Scottish person, when I meet Americans that tell me that they are also Scottish I can sometimes find it a but frustrating. Context is key of course, but I've had someone tell me that they are Scottish "too" because an ancestor way back when came from here to America. Its then often met with the American spouting off dated and offensive stereotypes to show me how Scottish they are. 

I don't know how many times I've come across people talking about being from this Clan or the great great great great grandson of a Clan chief. Or people proudly perpetrating redundant perceptions of Scottish people, and feel entitled to do so because they are "Scottish". I just don't like it. Clan history is Scotland is one ancient part of it. God there's so much I can say on that but I'll move on.

I've got a few Irish friends and this seems to be an even bigger phenomenon for them. I think with the troubles and Irish suppression there seems to be more 'cause' to get behind, as well as the identity.

Now don't get me wrong, I can appreciate that America is a melting pot/ salad bowl culture. Your country isn't as old as mine, infact we have universities that outdate your nation. So I guess in that sense communities can retain identities in different ways. Plus a lot of immigrant communities from the old world have grown round where the ships would dock. People settled together with the people they left with. So purely down to those historical/ geographical facts, I get why there is no 'one' American identity.

I know that A LOT of immigrant communities experienced hardship, racism, otherism and were left to live in squalor. These immigrant communities worked hard to build sustainable lives for themselves. Forged careers and businesses that became iconic within America ie Italian food. Irish pubs etc.

I can totally see the relevance to identifying as Scottish American, Italian American or Irish American. Unique communities, with unique identities that are deserving of their own American label. I guess this would make 'American' an umbrella term? 

However, I genuinely find it problematic when Americans equate their ancestral identity as meaning they are entitled to identifying with the stereotypes of the homeland.

To use Scotland as an example. We are a very socialist nation. We have a very complicated national identity within the landscape of the UK. We face serious, and I really do mean serious, issues relating to drug and alcohol abuse. We have contributed to colonialism and we have also been suppressed. What it means to be Scottish changes drastically between the East end of Glasgow and the West End of Edinburgh. I believe my countries issues are often over simplified and over commodified on the international level. I just don't like it when people misinterpret what it means to be Scottish because they are viewing it through the rose tinted glasses of ancestral love.

Don't get me wrong, I appreciate it when Americans take part in our culture. We love that yous love us. I can't speak for other communities but I know across Europe, its widely accepted that its rude when Americans expect to be accepted as a part of the old countries communities. That we are expected to act excited when yous "come home", welcomed "back" so it were. It almost comes across entitled, that you assume you know us so well, when what you know has been passed down to you from generations.

This obviously excludes people who are dual nationality. Or are raised in 1st/2nd and in some cases 3rd gen immigrant households.

I'd also like to note that there IS a distinction between journeying to view the land of your ancestors, and coming to a country and expecting to be viewed as part of that community without little to no assimilation.

So enlighten me, is there more to this I'm missing?</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="44245687754.0" user="crmd" delta="True">
    <text>I’m an Irish-American dual citizen who lives in New York City, so totally get where you’re coming from. Americans saying I’m Italian” or whatever is super cringe to Europeans. 


But I’ll try to explain where Americans are coming from with that. The USA has one of the least coherent national cultures of any country I’ve ever lived or worked in. As an example, here in NYC, nearly half of people speak a language other than English at home, and approx. 25% are not English proficient. New Yorkers speak over 200 languages, according to the dept of city planning. 

Lacking a commmon language and culture, an American saying you’re “Italian”, “Spanish”, “Korean”, etc is shorthand for a shared American subculture - the type of food you ate growing up, the holidays you celebrated, the likely quirks and features of your parents and aunts and uncles. 

TL;DR Americans mean no offense to Europeans when they call themselves X. They’re searching for shared cultural experience with other Americans. And since America is such a huge country, many people here don’t travel internationally often. And when we do, we often put our foot in our mouths. For example, by learning on the spot that “Italians” from Staten Island have absolutely nothing in common with Italians from Europe.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246092609.0" user="splitminds" delta="False">
    <text>Well explained. As you said, I honestly don’t think Americans mean to be offensive by saying what their ancestral heritage is even if they have no direct assimilation. I also understand how it can be irritating to those who are directly from that country/culture. However, I think saying that it is “problematic” is a bit much?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246103104.0" user="crmd" delta="False">
    <text>Yes, “problematic” is the part of OP’s view that I’m trying to change.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246241684.0" user="liltooter" delta="False">
    <text>I think you have changed part of my mind. I think codifing is an informative way to put it. New York is such a classic example for the melting pot apology. 

I guess "problematic" for me comes from when I see people saying they can handle their drink cause their Irish, or they make assumptions about clan culture in Scotland (we've not had clans in hundreds of years) making my country seem primitive.

I think it comes from the imbalance of culture exchange. We know so much about so much different parts of American. Yet yous know so little about my whole continent, never mind my wee country.

I think I would be more patient with it, if I felt there was a genuine appreciation of what our culture actually is. And not just whisky, getting drunk, tartan and willy from the simpsons.

Not to tar all 300 million odd Americans with the same brush. But just my generalised experience.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246434566.0" user="nofftastic" delta="False">
    <text>&gt;I think you have changed part of my mind

Don't forget to award them a delta!

&gt;I guess "problematic" for me comes from when I see...

Have you considered all the things you *don't* see? All the Irish-Americans who tell people they're Irish-American when asked about their heritage then quietly go about their lives not blaming their poor behavior on insulting stereotypes? This sounds like there may be some confirmation bias at play, as you won't be offended by all the times self-identifying Irish-Americans aren't problematic, because you never see the times they aren't problematic.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="44246483321.0" user="liltooter" delta="True">
    <text>How do I delta? 

And that's a really fair point. We don't have loads of Americans walking about in Scotland. Just because in my experience they seemed to have lacked social awareness that their Scottish culture is not my own doesn't mean everyone who identities as such will be just as short sighted. Some generalisations of my own in there.

Don't get me wrong, I really love the way Americans can be fascinated with their history, the way yous can show pride for people long gone is very respectful to your heritage in ways we just don't tend to thing over here. 

I think that my appreciation for that part of your culture has gone, uncommunicated. This genuinely isn't a "I hate America" post. More of a "I'm bothered by the constant misrepresentation of what my culture is" kind of post. 

Thanks for being so respectful, even if you don't agree with me. I've not had the same experience with everyone across this post. Some people take the notion different identities so personally, you lose the subjective nature of it all in the heat of it.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
