<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="295203779.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/4vr8oz/cmv_when_artificial_wombs_are_viable_abortion/">
    <title>CMV: When artificial wombs are viable, abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb.</title>
    <original_poster>KiritosWings</original_poster>
    <original_post>The current argument for the inequality between parental rights between men and women is that a woman is allowed to have an abortion because it's her right to bodily autonomy. While I agree with this argument, I believe that this argument loses all merit when artificial wombs are available. I believe that when artificial wombs are advanced enough to be a viable method of sustaining the fetus, that a pregnant woman should not be able to get an abortion, and must instead get whatever this new procedure. 


I hold this view because of two main reasons. 

1. Parental rights equality would be established by forcing both genders to have no right, post conception, to get out of parenthood.
2. It would appease people who believe that person hood begins at conception while also appeasing the people who believe that a woman's right to bodily autonomy trump the rights of the unborn fetus.

I believe that it is immoral to utilize abortion to get out of parenthood because it causes a parental rights inequality, and I believe this immorality is only tolerated because of the net good done by respecting bodily autonomy. When artificial wombs are viable however, the woman would maintain equivalent bodily autonomy, no longer be able to dictate whether or not someone lives or dies, and would still be on the hook as a parent post conception. 

Edit 1: To clarify, in this system people would still be able to give their children up for adoption and/or have child support payments from an unwilling parent (And in saying that I found a third reason I enjoy this proposal. It would allow for the situation where the father wants to keep the child and the mother doesn't to finally work out). 

Edit 2: I've given out one delta already and I want to put the slightly modified view up here. I still believe that abortion should be outlawed and replaced with moving the fetus to the artificial womb, but that we need to wait until artificial wombs are viable and contraception has reached the point where unintended pregnancies are significantly decreased. 
_____

&amp;gt; *Hello, users of CMV! This is a footnote from your moderators. We'd just like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please remember to* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! If you are thinking about submitting a CMV yourself, please have a look through our* ***[popular topics wiki](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/populartopics)*** *first. Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="28662220768.0" user="theshantanu" delta="False">
    <text>Who pays for raising the baby?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662221890.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>The parents.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662227287.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>Why would they not preform an illegal abortion to avoid that?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662228696.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>It shouldn't matter that people would break the law. And because giving the child up for adoption would be preferable to going to prison. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662230809.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>That is the reason we have abortion legal now, the 21st ammendment, legalization of marijuana in some states, ect. It absolutly does matter

How do you tell the diffrence between an illegal abortion and a miscarriage without treating every misscarriage as a crime scene and every woman who has one as a criminal?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662255251.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>Well there would need to be reasonable suspicion that there was an illegal abortion. Because of the similarities between an illegal abortion and a miscarriage, just the dead fetus would not be enough for reasonable suspicion. It would have to be a higher bar before beginning to investigate that kind of case.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662256136.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="False">
    <text>Ok then, that would let the vast majority of illegal abortions happen if you do that.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662260905.0" user="KiritosWings" delta="False">
    <text>It would, but I would much rather let the majority of illegal abortions happen to mitigate the potential harm of throwing a grieving couple who miscarried through the legal ringer. I am personally a proponent of "I'd rather a 1000 guilty people walk free than a single innocent person jailed" and I extend that to the entire legal process.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="28662264557.0" user="Krieg-The-Psycho1" delta="True">
    <text>So you would have nearly the same ammount of abortions happen as there are now, but increase the risk of the mother dying?</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
