<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="363480636.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/60engc/cmv_the_war_on_drugs_failed_due_to_the/">
    <title>CMV: The War On Drugs failed due to the punishments not being severe enough</title>
    <original_poster>Blood_tree</original_poster>
    <original_post>The War on Drugs could have went significantly better had the DEA been able to request harsher sentences for distribution. Specifically corporal punishment and public executions for distribution would have made the drug problem in the United States negligible had they been enforced. Prison sentences cause people to disassociate the punishment from the crime due to their lengthly and impersonal nature and by contrast caning can be done in full very soon after the crime has been commited and is very personal and intense despite being on a whole less severe than a prison sentence. Public execution within a year of the crime is also a good measure since it will save money (we will be reducing the amount of appeals to one) and it will serve as a vivid denunciation of drug distribution and prevent perpetrators from reoffending. 

_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29214930758.0" user="Vasquerade" delta="False">
    <text>Why should someone be punished for harmless recreational use of a drug?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29214939008.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>This is about distribution not usage.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29215592379.0" user="Boopdelahoop" delta="False">
    <text>Why should someone be punished for sharing harmless recreational drugs with friends?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217300843.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Because they aren't harmless.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217552277.0" user="Boopdelahoop" delta="False">
    <text>What harm is done then?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29217567607.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Many drugs can cause dangerous dependencies and a significant risk of overdose even for first time users and the effects over time are catastrophically bad.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29219542999.0" user="askingdumbquestion" delta="False">
    <text>The same can be said about swimming pools. In fact, swimming pools kill far more people than drugs.

Why aren't you war against swimming pools? Because you're insincere, it's not about drugs, it's about you wanting to control people.

If it was about drugs, we'd look at European countries with the laxest drug laws and see... oh my goodness, they're successful first world countries full of freedom. Singapore? That's a trash country in a trash part of Asia and is full of trash.

Turns out, socialism and freedom work, these are the ingredients to a successful country.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29219957957.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Unlike with swimming pools, they do not cause mass crime epidemics. You are truly delusional if you think there are no societal repercussions for drug usage. If you're a mother who is doing drugs while pregnant, your baby is more likely to be a sped. Society has to restrict certain self-destructive behaviors for the good of society. You might think that "freedom" works, but you fail to realize that we live in a collective and individual actions by other might hurt you. Like the asshole who is obese and you're forced to sit next to him on a plane while his fat rolls are intruding on your seat. Singapore is not a trash society, and it's hilarious you try to pretend that Europe is somehow cleaner than Singapore. Look at the streets of London and Paris and tell me that's it cleaner than Singapore. You probably do not realize there is not even gum on the streets in Singapore. What works is communitarianism and collective self-health</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29221943813.0" user="askingdumbquestion" delta="False">
    <text>&amp;gt; You probably do not realize there is not even gum on the streets in Singapore.

You say that like it's a good thing.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29222569063.0" user="Blood_tree" delta="False">
    <text>Because it is.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
