<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="401821196.0" index="2" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6n8f7w/cmv_lord_of_the_rings_are_great_films_but_it_is/">
    <title>CMV: Lord of the Rings are great films, but it is not a good trilogy</title>
    <original_poster>This_The_Last_Time</original_poster>
    <original_post>This is inspired by a recent Movie Fight debate about what is the best movie trilogy (check it out from YouTube). 

I'd argue, that even though I LOVE Lord of the Rings movies, and have seen them dozens of times, it is not a good movie trilogy. For one simple reason: the movies do not work separately. 

I think for a movie trilogy to be good or better than most, the parts of the trilogy have to work both individually as single movies and as pieces of a greater whole. 

LOTR does not work as individual films. None of the themes or storylines are resolved within a single film, with the exception of characters who are both introduced and killed within one film (Boromir, Shelob). 

LOTR films are individual films only in technical sense: they all have their separate release dates, each one ends with ending credits, etc. But the story contained in these films does not work when viewed as a single piece, because you do not get to see the big picture. LOTR films are really a single film, single story, released in three separate parts. 

I think for a trilogy to be good, or great, any single movie in it has to work without any companion pieces. Sequels should not be requirements. Story cannot be truly great if it does not end. Imagine if Fellowship of the Ring was a box-office bomb, and the two others films were never released. Who would call Fellowship a self-contained, resolved film? It would still be a good film, just without resolution. Audiences would think, what then, only to be answered, nothing. A good story does not ask questions it does not try to answer. 

Then look at Godfather. If Godfather Part 2 was never released, Godfather 1 would still work perfectly on its own. Part 2 enchances the first one, and vice versa, but neither requires the other.  And no one needs the third one. 

Lord of the Rings films are great. But in reality they are a trilogy only in technical terms, as the story within is one single story, not three complementing ones. If you only watch one of the films, but not the others, story is flawed and incomplete. If you watch the films out of chronological order, nothing makes sense. All the plot threads and all the character archs in the trilogy take multiple films to reach their conclusions, with the aforementioned exception of characters who are introduced and killed within a single movie. 

An exceptional trilogy of films should work both individually, where you only see one of them (not necessarily even the first one), and still feel like you got everything you needed and wanted, and as parts of a bigger whole. Lord of the Rings films do not work without the other parts of the trilogy. Without them, story is incomplete, unresolved, and the character archs unfinished. 

CMV. 
_____

&amp;gt; *This is a footnote from the CMV moderators. We'd like to remind you of a couple of things. Firstly, please* ***[read through our rules](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/rules)***. *If you see a comment that has broken one, it is more effective to report it than downvote it. Speaking of which,* ***[downvotes don't change views](http://www.reddit.com/r/changemyview/wiki/guidelines#wiki_upvoting.2Fdownvoting)****! Any questions or concerns? Feel free to* ***[message us](http://www.reddit.com/message/compose?to=/r/changemyview)***. *Happy CMVing!*</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29520191291.0" user="timoth3y" delta="False">
    <text>They LOTR is not and was never intended to be a trilogy. Tolkien saw the books as a single work divided into six volumes, but they were eventually published as three books. Tolkien himself saw it as one work, not a trilogy,


Perhaps knowing that the LOTR is not and was never intended to be a trilogy, will change your view a bit and let you enjoy the movies a bit more.  </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520192999.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>I actually knew that, and that influenced my view. It is a single story, and it always was. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520205577.0" user="timoth3y" delta="False">
    <text>Then why would you want to judge it as a trilogy when it is not one? 


Enjoy the books and the movies for what they are, a single work in three parts.  They are quite good when viewed for what they actually are. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520256854.0" user="This_The_Last_Time" delta="False">
    <text>Because others do. Because people say it's the best trilogy, which I think it's not, hence the argument. I consider it as one, 9 hour movie. 

And yes indeed, they are a single work in three parts. But cutting something in three does not a trilogy make. </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29520915381.0" user="Banazir_Galbasi" delta="False">
    <text>I think you're arguing against something they're not arguing for.  I suspect that OP is arguing along the "trilogy or not-trilogy" angle, not the "good or not-good" side. </text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
