<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410977978.0" index="3" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6soomy/cmv_i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_we_all/">
    <title>CMV: I have no faith in humanity and we all deserve to go extinct.</title>
    <original_poster>rfreymuth</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't even know exactly what to say about anything in relation to this topic. Now, I have no experience of any actual human beings physically hurting me or anything else that would typically make someone lose faith in humanity, but what they did collectively was enough to make ME do so!

First, and most importantly, the election of Donald Trump. Ever since the beginning of his campaign, my parents had been constantly talking about how Trump was so stupid that there would be absolutely no chance that he would win the election based on how people really do think, and based on that, I made a vow to myself that I would lose faith in humanity if he won. I did. I now believe that humanity needs and deserves to go extinct because of this.

But that's not the only reason why I believe we all need and deserve to go extinct. The other reason is the inevitable box office success of The Emoji Movie. Ever since its ANNOUNCEMENT, I thought that it was the worst idea in the history of movies and even the greatest amount of care put into it would still make me never want to watch it. Well, obviously the movie did not have any effort at all, and nearly nobody liked it. I was really very happy about that. But the thing that made me double down on my belief of humanity's extinction being deserved was the fact that it will become a box office hit!

I can't think of any other examples I have gone through right now, but I hope you get what I'm saying! I actually don't care if the World War I Christmas Truce makes someone else restore faith in humanity, or any of the other "being kind to your enemies" scenarios in big-name wars did the same, or anything else that would restore faith in humanity. The fact still remains...

How could humanity be so goddamn STUPID!!! First, the election of a bully, troll, and CRIMINAL as President of the United States, and now the inevitable box office success of the worst idea in the history of movies, which will result in other equally bad ideas like "Damn Daniel: The Movie"!

As a result, we DESPERATELY need to go extinct! We fucking deserve it!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29592160271.0" user="Huntingmoa" delta="False">
    <text>You've listed  examples that are specifically American. 

Shouldn't your view be that you have no faith in Americans and they all deserve to go extinct?

Edit: removed "to" between "listed" and "examples"</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592162596.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>Well, if that's the case, then I think that America is completely broken and that I should move out and live in another country as soon as possible!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592290818.0" user="kkibe" delta="False">
    <text>As a non-american, America is pretty great :) </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592906754.0" user="Nevermore0714" delta="False">
    <text>As an American, Americans hating America is as American as baseball and apple pie.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29593171340.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>That shouldn't make sense to me! I thought that country natives need to love their country, and if they don't, they should move out.

Why is hating America so trivial?!</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29593205926.0" user="Nevermore0714" delta="True">
    <text>I personally don't hate my country, probably because I am *still* convinced that I would be killed for being a gay Capitalist in most other parts of the world.

But, that's one thing I do love about America. It's a young country, we can all hate it. Nothing is illegal about hating America in America. Hell, the majority of comedians make their money from making fun of America here. If you hated Clinton, you could bitch about him over beers with your friends. If you hated Bush, you could do the same. The same for Obama, the same for Trump.

Admittedly, I think that some things are too far, such as insulting soldiers for being soldiers or threatening a politician's life (looking at you, people who burned/hanged imitations of Clinton/Bush/Obama/Trump), but I think that most reasonable people would avoid doing that kind of thing.

America embraces bipartisanship the way that we embrace football rivalries, people will always get a lot of enjoyment and camaraderie out of hating the other party, and some take it as far as hating the country as a whole when the other side is in power.

Do some people take it to far? Yeah, definitely. But, ultimately, Americans have *always* hated on America, because it's the American thing to do.

That's a lot more rambling than it would be if it wasn't past 2 AM.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
