<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="410977978.0" index="4" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/6soomy/cmv_i_have_no_faith_in_humanity_and_we_all/">
    <title>CMV: I have no faith in humanity and we all deserve to go extinct.</title>
    <original_poster>rfreymuth</original_poster>
    <original_post>I don't even know exactly what to say about anything in relation to this topic. Now, I have no experience of any actual human beings physically hurting me or anything else that would typically make someone lose faith in humanity, but what they did collectively was enough to make ME do so!

First, and most importantly, the election of Donald Trump. Ever since the beginning of his campaign, my parents had been constantly talking about how Trump was so stupid that there would be absolutely no chance that he would win the election based on how people really do think, and based on that, I made a vow to myself that I would lose faith in humanity if he won. I did. I now believe that humanity needs and deserves to go extinct because of this.

But that's not the only reason why I believe we all need and deserve to go extinct. The other reason is the inevitable box office success of The Emoji Movie. Ever since its ANNOUNCEMENT, I thought that it was the worst idea in the history of movies and even the greatest amount of care put into it would still make me never want to watch it. Well, obviously the movie did not have any effort at all, and nearly nobody liked it. I was really very happy about that. But the thing that made me double down on my belief of humanity's extinction being deserved was the fact that it will become a box office hit!

I can't think of any other examples I have gone through right now, but I hope you get what I'm saying! I actually don't care if the World War I Christmas Truce makes someone else restore faith in humanity, or any of the other "being kind to your enemies" scenarios in big-name wars did the same, or anything else that would restore faith in humanity. The fact still remains...

How could humanity be so goddamn STUPID!!! First, the election of a bully, troll, and CRIMINAL as President of the United States, and now the inevitable box office success of the worst idea in the history of movies, which will result in other equally bad ideas like "Damn Daniel: The Movie"!

As a result, we DESPERATELY need to go extinct! We fucking deserve it!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29592150219.0" user="ACrusaderA" delta="False">
    <text>What evidence do you have that Donald Trump is a criminal? As far as I know he has never been convicted.

Beyond this you are basing your idea that Humanity as a whole deserves to go extinct off of the fact that 48% of less than 50% of a nation which makes up a mere 5% of the global population supports such a man.

Donald Trump only got 48% of the vote. The total number of people in the US who voted is less than half (128m/326m) of the population. And the USA only has 326 million people in a world with a population over 7 billion.

You are condemning to death a group based on an extreme minority. The exact thing that Trump is often accused with Muslims.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592165191.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>Then I guess I deserve to die for being a Trump myself.......? T_T</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29593113420.0" user="PM_ME_CUTE_PUPPYS" delta="False">
    <text>I'm confused. You say humanity is horrible for voting in Trump, but now are you saying you like him anyways? </text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29593165605.0" user="rfreymuth" delta="False">
    <text>I'm not saying that I like him. I'm saying that I think like him, or I have the same thought process as him.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29592304578.0" user="kublahkoala" delta="False">
    <text>There's a preponderance of evidence showing Trump is a criminal. Just because he hasn't been convicted yet doesn't mean no evidence exists. OJ was never convicted for murder, doesn't mean he is not very obviously a murderer or that the blood in the white Bronco is not evidence.
And if you consider Fraud a crime, he's been sued successfully over Trump University's bogus claims and for failure to pay many of his contractors.</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
