<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<thread>
  <submission id="442068628.0" index="1" link="https://www.reddit.com//r/changemyview/comments/7b72c4/cmv_the_american_political_enviroment_is_hopeless/">
    <title>CMV: The American political enviroment is hopeless.</title>
    <original_poster>BassFight</original_poster>
    <original_post>I feel like the above could increasingly also be said about Dutch politics, but I expect more people can talk about America. 

Basically, at the writing of this post I have a very pessimistic outlook on the future of the democracy, in part due to ongoing discussions that need not be discussuon, including climate change, net neutrality, and whether person with different skin, organs or partners are less human, and in part due to the extremely toxic nature of discord that surrounds these topics and others. Apperant corruption on various sides does not help. 
Regarding political issues, be it immigration policies, taxes or care, I have allways found that the answer is not found by leaning extremely to either right or left and yelling at everyone on the other side. I think 'us vs them' thinking is one of the greatest challenges humans are facing, but I used to believe we can get past it by allowing both sides voices because most humans do what they think is right for the people around them. I still believe the last bit, but I have lost hope that people are able to have a civiliced discussion. I have seen attempts at peaceful mediating responded to with hateful negativity. I am no longer concinced enough people are willing to see other's perspectives and come to a shared conclusion or worldview.

To be clear: I am not looking to discuss the aforementioned discussions. I am specifically looking for arguments that there is still hope that humans can come together, admit to our own and point to other's faults and talk our stuff out effectively and in a way that makes most people happy. I am hoping these will cheer me up as well as change my perspective and maybe other's for the better. Give me hope!! 

For this discussion I have assumed hate is not the answer, as it usually breeds moee hate.


Tl;dr- convince me of the ability of humans to get together and talk about their problems in a healthy and peaceful way without responding to any individual or group with hate. 

EDIT: This got more responses and I have less time than anticipated. I will do my best to read and respond to all comments in the coming day(s) and deal out deltas where deserved. Thanks and sorry for the poor OP-ing!</original_post>
    </submission>
  <comment id="29836287600.0" user="JustinVx2" delta="False">
    <text>Wouldn't you agree that, in the case of Dutch politics, the recent government agreement is a good example? Four political parties with very, very different views about refugees, the environment, assisted suicide, immigration, Dutch culture, etcetera, etcetera. Yet they talk with each other and come up with an agreement about what should happen in the next four years.

On a local level there are even more impressive examples. In Rotterdam there is a coalition between the liberal D66, the christian CDA and the populist Leefbaar Rotterdam. In Amsterdam there is a coalition between the socialist SP, the conservative VVD and the liberal D66. These are political parties with vastly different views on the world and yet they are able to get together, talk peacefully and even come up with policy. In fact I would say both cities are being led exceptionally well.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836444784.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>I admit to now knowing a lot about the local politics, but what I have heard (undoubtedly biased) did not make optimistic. That said, it's not usually because of hate, more due to the attitude of certain political figures. But the voting period was also very negative to me.

EDIT: You did provide an example of different people coming together in the government; ∆.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29836838155.0" user="JustinVx2" delta="False">
    <text>What have you heard and why did it not make you optimistic?

In my opinion the main problem with the political climate right now is that when people perceive a certain amount of anonymity (online or in a big group), they stop seeing the people they disagree with as humans. But it is in no way hopeless. Once you remove that anonymity, once you put two people in a room that disagree with each other and just let them talk (**without** an audience that backs them up), you'll see that people will get along just fine. You can get socialists and conservatives to work together (Amsterdam). You can get populists and liberals to work together (Rotterdam). I always consider [Daryl Davis](http://www.npr.org/2017/08/20/544861933/how-one-man-convinced-200-ku-klux-klan-members-to-give-up-their-robes) to be very inspirational. He showed that a black man can befriend members from the Ku Klux Klan, and convince them to change their minds.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29838150625.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>During the most recent elections, I was genuinely afraid of the PVV. Not that they would destroy the country if they won, but what it would mean if many people voted for it, and also that some people vote VVD just to outpace the PVV. 

More recently, on this week's zondag met lubach (admittedly not a very objective news source, or a news source at all), there was a topic on dividentenbelasting, suddenly being lifted, which had to do with shell's interest, so there was lobbying. These are things that make me feel like there will always be a fundamental gap between citizens and their representatives. Admittedly, that's not really what my OP was about.

To be clear- I usually wouldn't cite ZML as a source, you've just put me on the spot to name an example and I suppose it's difficult to name a specific one.

EDIT: Actually, I've thought of something else- the way nearly everyone around me (admittedly not a representative sample of the population in terms of education) thinks both Geert Wilders and Donals Trump are utterly ridiculous. This is seen as such fact that it is discussed in lectures on psychology subject in terms of 'what can go wrong' in power dynamics or politics, so to say. Yet, apperantly, this is not really fact because a lot of people voted for these people. So I think it's really dangerous that it is not taken serious at all in this way.</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29841832816.0" user="JustinVx2" delta="False">
    <text>I am somewhat confused about your answer. Is the problem that you think people with different political views can not sit down together anymore and have a healthy, peaceful conversation? Or is the problem that lobbyists exists? Or is the problem that there are people in this world, and a growing number, that vote for demagogues? Or all of the above?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29842223726.0" user="BassFight" delta="False">
    <text>Lobbying is a problem to me, but the post is about the first problem- that I feel peaceful discussions are disappearing. But I suppose you've addressed that in an earlier comment, to be fair. Can I add a delta in an edit?</text>
    </comment>
  <comment id="29843002202.0" user="JustinVx2" delta="True">
    <text>If you feel that I've changed your mind, then a delta would be great!</text>
    </comment>
  </thread>
